<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T12:29+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Improve Statistical Machine Translation with Context-Sensitive Bilingual Semantic Embedding Model</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
				<availability status="unknown"><p>Copyright Association for Computational Linguistics</p>
				</availability>
				<date>October 25-29, 2014. 2014</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Haiyang</forename><surname>Wu</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Baidu Inc</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>No. 10, Shangdi 10th Street</addrLine>
									<postCode>100085</postCode>
									<settlement>Beijing</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Daxiang</forename><surname>Dong</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Baidu Inc</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>No. 10, Shangdi 10th Street</addrLine>
									<postCode>100085</postCode>
									<settlement>Beijing</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wei</forename><surname>He</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Baidu Inc</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>No. 10, Shangdi 10th Street</addrLine>
									<postCode>100085</postCode>
									<settlement>Beijing</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xiaoguang</forename><surname>Hu</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Baidu Inc</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>No. 10, Shangdi 10th Street</addrLine>
									<postCode>100085</postCode>
									<settlement>Beijing</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dianhai</forename><surname>Yu</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Baidu Inc</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>No. 10, Shangdi 10th Street</addrLine>
									<postCode>100085</postCode>
									<settlement>Beijing</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hua</forename><surname>Wu</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Haifeng</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Baidu Inc</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>No. 10, Shangdi 10th Street</addrLine>
									<postCode>100085</postCode>
									<settlement>Beijing</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ting</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
							<email>tliu@ir.hit.edu.cn</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Baidu Inc</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>No. 10, Shangdi 10th Street</addrLine>
									<postCode>100085</postCode>
									<settlement>Beijing</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">Harbin Institute of Technology</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Harbin</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Improve Statistical Machine Translation with Context-Sensitive Bilingual Semantic Embedding Model</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2014 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP)</title>
						<meeting>the 2014 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP) <address><addrLine>Doha, Qatar. c</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="142" to="146"/>
							<date type="published">October 25-29, 2014. 2014</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>We investigate how to improve bilingual embedding which has been successfully used as a feature in phrase-based statistical machine translation (SMT). Despite bilingual embedding&apos;s success, the contextual information, which is of critical importance to translation quality, was ignored in previous work. To employ the contextual information, we propose a simple and memory-efficient model for learning bilingual embedding, taking both the source phrase and context around the phrase into account. Bilingual translation scores generated from our proposed bilingual embedding model are used as features in our SMT system. Experimental results show that the proposed method achieves significant improvements on large-scale Chinese-English translation task.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>In Statistical Machine Translation (SMT) sys- tem, it is difficult to determine the translation of some phrases that have ambiguous meanings.For example, the phrase " jieguo" can be trans- lated to either "results", "eventually" or "fruit", depending on the context around it. There are two reasons for the problem: First, the length of phrase pairs is restricted due to the limitation of model size and training data. Another reason is that SMT systems often fail to use contextual information in source sentence, therefore, phrase sense disam- biguation highly depends on the language model which is trained only on target corpus.</p><p>To solve this problem, we present to learn context-sensitive bilingual semantic embedding. Our methodology is to train a supervised model where labels are automatically generated from phrase-pairs. For each source phrase, the aligned target phrase is marked as the positive label whereas other phrases in our phrase table are treated as negative labels. Different from previ- ous work in bilingual embedding learning( <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Zou et al., 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Gao et al., 2014</ref>), our framework is a supervised model that utilizes contextual informa- tion in source sentence as features and make use of phrase pairs as weak labels. Bilingual seman- tic embeddings are trained automatically from our supervised learning task.</p><p>Our learned bilingual semantic embedding model is used to measure the similarity of phrase pairs which is treated as a feature in decoding. We integrate our learned model into a phrase-based translation system and experimental results indi- cate that our system significantly outperform the baseline system. On the NIST08 Chinese-English translation task, we obtained 0.68 BLEU improve- ment. We also test our proposed method on much larger web dataset and obtain 0.49 BLEU im- provement against the baseline.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Related Work</head><p>Using vectors to represent word meanings is the essence of vector space models (VSM). The representations capture words' semantic and syn- tactic information which can be used to measure semantic similarities by computing distance be- tween the vectors. Although most VSMs represent one word with only one vector, they fail to cap- ture homonymy and polysemy of word. <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Huang et al. (2012)</ref> introduced global document context and multiple word prototypes which distinguishes and uses both local and global context via a joint training objective. Much of the research focus on the task of inducing representations for sin- gle languages. Recently, a lot of progress has been made at representation learning for bilin- gual words. Bilingual word representations have been presented by <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Peirsman and Padó (2010)</ref> and <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Sumita (2000)</ref>. Also unsupervised algorithms such as LDA and LSA were used by <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Boyd-Graber and Resnik (2010)</ref>, <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Tam et al. (2007)</ref> and <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Zhao and Xing (2006)</ref>. <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Zou et al. (2013)</ref> learn bilingual em- beddings utilizes word alignments and monolin- gual embeddings result, <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Le et al. (2012)</ref> and <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Gao et al. (2014)</ref> used continuous vector to represent the source language or target language of each phrase, and then computed translation probability using vector distance. Vuli´cVuli´c and Moens (2013) learned bilingual vector spaces from non-parallel data in- duced by using a seed lexicon. However, none of these work considered the word sense disam- biguation problem which <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Carpuat and Wu (2007)</ref> proved it is useful for SMT. In this paper, we learn bilingual semantic embeddings for source content and target phrase, and incorporate it into a phrase- based SMT system to improve translation quality.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Context-Sensitive Bilingual Semantic Embedding Model</head><p>We propose a simple and memory-efficient model which embeds both contextual information of source phrases and aligned phrases in target cor- pus into low dimension. Our assumption is that high frequent words are likely to have multiple word senses; therefore, top frequent words are se- lected in source corpus. We denote our selected words as focused phrase. Our goal is to learn a bilingual embedding model that can capture dis- criminative contextual information for each fo- cused phrase. To learn an effective context sensi- tive bilingual embedding, we extract context fea- tures nearby a focused phrase that will discrimi- nate focused phrase's target translation from other possible candidates. Our task can be viewed as a classification problem that each target phrase is treated as a class. Since target phrases are usu- ally in very high dimensional space, traditional linear classification model is not suitable for our problem. Therefore, we treat our problem as a ranking problem that can handle large number of classes and optimize the objectives with scalable optimizer stochastic gradient descent.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Bilingual Word Embedding</head><p>We apply a linear embedding model for bilin- gual embedding learning. Cosine similarity be- tween bilingual embedding representation is con- sidered as score function. The score function should be discriminative between target phrases and other candidate phrases. Our score function is in the form:</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">f (x, y; W, U) = cos(W T x, U T y)<label>(1)</label></formula><p>where x is contextual feature vector in source sen- tence, and y is the representation of target phrase, W ∈ R |X|×k , U ∈ R |Y|×k are low rank ma- trix. In our model, we allow y to be bag-of-words representation. Our embedding model is memory- efficient in that dimensionality of x and y can be very large in practical setting. We use |X| and |Y| means dimensionality of random variable x and y, then traditional linear model such as max-entropy model requires memory space of O(|X||Y|). Our embedding model only requires O(k(|X| + |Y|)) memory space that can handle large scale vocabu- lary setting. To score a focused phrase and target phrase pair with f (x, y), context features are ex- tracted from nearby window of the focused phrase. Target words are selected from phrase pairs. Given a source sentence, embedding of a focused phrase is estimated from W T x and target phrase embed- ding can be obtained through U T y.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Context Sensitive Features</head><p>Context of a focused phrase is extracted from nearby window, and in our experiment we choose window size of 6 as a focused phrase's con- text. Features are then extracted from the focused phrase's context. We demonstrate our feature extraction and label generation process from the Chinese-to-English example in <ref type="figure">figure 1</ref>. Window size in this example is three. Position features and Part-Of-Speech Tagging features are extracted from the focused phrase's context. The word fruit <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref>: Feature extraction and label generation is the aligned phrase of our focused phrase and is treated as positive label. The phrase results is a randomly selected phrase from phrase table results of . Note that feature window is not well de- fined near the beginning or the end of a sentence. To conquer this problem, we add special padding word to the beginning and the end of a sentence to augment sentence.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3">Parameter Learning</head><p>To learn model parameter W and U, we ap- ply a ranking scheme on candidates selected from phrase table results of each focused phrase. In par- ticular, given a focus phrase w, aligned phrase is treated as positive label whereas phrases extracted from other candidates in phrase table are treated as negative label. A max-margin loss is applied in this ranking setting.</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">I(Θ) = 1 m m i=1 (δ − f (x i , y i ; Θ) − f (x i , y i ; Θ))+<label>(2)</label></formula><p>Where f (x i , y i ) is previously defined, Θ = {W, U } and + means max-margin hinge loss. In our implementation, a margin of δ = 0.15 is used during training. Objectives are minimized through stochastic gradient descent algorithm. For each randomly selected training example, parameters are updated through the following form:</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">Θ := Θ − α ∂l(Θ) ∂Θ<label>(3)</label></formula><p>where Θ = {W, U}. Given an instance with pos- itive and negative label pair {x, y, y }, gradients of parameter W and U are as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">∂l(W, U) ∂W = qsx(W T x) T − pqs 3 x(U T y) (4) ∂l(W, U) ∂U = qsy(U T y) T − pqs 3 y(W T x)<label>(5)</label></formula><p>Where</p><formula xml:id="formula_4">we set p = (W T x) T (U T y), q = 1 ||W T x|| 2 and s = 1 ||U T y|| 2</formula><p>. To initialize our model param- eters with strong semantic and syntactic informa- tion, word vectors are pre-trained independently on source and target corpus through word2vec ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Mikolov et al., 2013)</ref>. And the pre-trained word vectors are treated as initial parameters of our model. The learned scoring function f (x, y) will be used during decoding phase as a feature in log- linear model which we will describe in detail later.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Integrating Bilingual Semantic Embedding into Phrase-Based SMT Architectures</head><p>To incorporate the context-sensitive bilingual embedding model into the state-of-the-art Phrase- Based Translation model, we modify the decoding so that context information is available on every source phrase. For every phrase in a source sen- tence, the following tasks are done at every node in our decoder:</p><p>• Get the focused phrase as well as its context in the source sentence.</p><p>• Extract features from the focused phrase's context.</p><p>• Get translation candidate extracted from phrase pairs of the focused phrase.</p><p>• Compute scores for any pair of the focused phrase and a candidate phrase.</p><p>We get the target sub-phrase using word align- ment of phrase, and we treat NULL as a common target word if there is no alignment for the focused phrase. Finally we compute the matching score for source content and target word using bilingual se- mantic embedding model. If there are more than one word in the focus phrase, then we add all score together. A penalty value will be given if target is not in translation candidate list. For each phrase in a given SMT input sentence, the Bilingual Seman- tic score can be used as an additional feature in log-linear translation model, in combination with other typical context-independent SMT bilexicon probabilities.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Experiment</head><p>Our experiments are performed using an in- house phrase-based system with a log-linear framework. Our system includes a phrase trans- lation model, an n-gram language model, a lexi- calized reordering model, a word penalty model and a phrase penalty model, which is similar to Moses ( <ref type="bibr">Koehn et al., 2007)</ref>. The evaluation metric is BLEU <ref type="figure">(Papineni et al., 2002</ref>).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.1">Data set</head><p>We test our approach on LDC corpus first. We just use a subset of the data available for NIST OpenMT08 task <ref type="bibr">1</ref>   <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>: Results of lowercase BLEU on NIST08 task. LOC is the location feature and POS is the Part-of-Speech feature * or ** equals to sig- nificantly better than our baseline(ρ &lt; 0.05 or ρ &lt; 0.01, respectively) contains 1.5M sentence pairs after we filter with some simple heuristic rules, such as sentence be- ing too long or containing messy codes. As mono- lingual corpus, we use the XinHua portion of the English GigaWord. In monolingual corpus we fil- ter sentence if it contain more than 100 words or contain messy codes, Finally, we get mono- lingual corpus containing 369M words. In order to test our approach on a more realistic scenario, we train our models with web data. Sentence pairs obtained from bilingual website and com- parable webpage. Monolingual corpus is gained from some large website such as WiKi. There are 50M sentence pairs and 10B words monolingual corpus.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.2">Results and Analysis</head><p>For word alignment, we align all of the train- ing data with GIZA++ ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Och and Ney, 2003)</ref>, us- ing the grow-diag-final heuristic to improve recall. For language model, we train a 5-gram modified Kneser-Ney language model and use Minimum Error Rate Training <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(Och, 2003)</ref> to tune the SMT. For both OpenMT08 task and WebData task, we use NIST06 as the tuning set, and use NIST08 as the testing set. Our baseline system is a standard phrase-based SMT system, and a language model is trained with the target side of bilingual corpus. Results on Chinese-English translation task are re- ported in <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>. Word position features and part- of-speech tagging features are both useful for our bilingual semantic embedding learning. Based on our trained bilingual embedding model, we can easily compute a translation score between any bilingual phrase pair. We list some cases in table 2 to show that our bilingual embedding is context sensitive.</p><p>Contextual features extracted from source sen- tence are strong enough to discriminate different Source Sentence 4 Nearest Neighbor from bilingual embedding <ref type="table">(Investors  can only get down to  business in a stable so- cial environment)</ref> will be, can only, will, can (In compe- titions, the Chinese Dis- abled have shown ex- traordinary athletic abil- ities) skills, ability, abilities, tal- ent (In the natu- ral environment of Costa Rica, grapes do not nor- mally yield fruit.) fruit, outcome of, the out- come, result (As a result, Eastern District Council passed a pro- posal) in the end, eventually, as a result, results <ref type="table">Table 2</ref>: Top ranked focused phrases based on bilingual semantic embedding word senses. And we also observe from the word " jieguo" that Part-Of-Speech Tagging fea- tures are effective in discriminating target phrases.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Conlusion</head><p>In this paper, we proposed a context-sensitive bilingual semantic embedding model to improve statistical machine translation. Contextual infor- mation is used in our model for bilingual word sense disambiguation. We integrated the bilingual semantic model into the phrase-based SMT sys- tem. Experimental results show that our method achieves significant improvements over the base- line on large scale Chinese-English translation task. Our model is memory-efficient and practical for industrial usage that training can be done on large scale data set with large number of classes. Prediction time is also negligible with regard to SMT decoding phase. In the future, we will ex- plore more features to refine the model and try to utilize contextual information in target sentences.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" validated="false"><head>. The parallel training corpus</head><label>.</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Method 

OpenMT08 WebData 
BLEU 
BLEU 
Our Baseline 
26.24 
29.32 
LOC 
26.78** 
29.62* 
LOC+POS 
26.82** 
29.81* 

</table></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> LDC2002E18, LDC2002L27, LDC2002T01, LDC2003E07, LDC2003E14, LDC2004T07, LDC2005E83, LDC2005T06, LDC2005T10, LDC2005T34, LDC2006E24, LDC2006E26, LDC2006E34, LDC2006E86, LDC2006E92, LDC2006E93, LDC2004T08(HK News, HK Hansards )</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>We thank the three anonymous reviewers for their valuable comments, and Niu Gang and Wu Xianchao for discussions. This paper is supported by <ref type="bibr">973 program No. 2014CB340505.</ref> </p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Holistic sentiment analysis across languages: Multilingual supervised latent dirichlet allocation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jordan</forename><surname>Boyd</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">-Graber</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Philip</forename><surname>Resnik</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2010 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</title>
		<meeting>the 2010 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing<address><addrLine>Cambridge, MA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010-10" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="45" to="55" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Association for Computational Linguistics</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Improving statistical machine translation using word sense disambiguation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marine</forename><surname>Carpuat</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dekai</forename><surname>Wu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2007 Joint Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing and Computational Natural Language Learning (EMNLP-CoNLL)</title>
		<meeting>the 2007 Joint Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing and Computational Natural Language Learning (EMNLP-CoNLL)<address><addrLine>Prague, Czech Republic</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007-06" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="61" to="72" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Association for Computational Linguistics</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Learning continuous phrase representations for translation modeling</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jianfeng</forename><surname>Gao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xiaodong</forename><surname>He</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Li</forename><surname>Wen-Tau Yih</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Deng</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. ACL</title>
		<meeting>ACL</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Improving word representations via global context and multiple word prototypes</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Eric</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Richard</forename><surname>Socher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christopher</forename><surname>Manning</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Andrew</forename><surname>Ng</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 50th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the 50th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics<address><addrLine>Jeju Island, Korea</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012-07" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="873" to="882" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Long Papers). Association for Computational Linguistics</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Continuous space translation models with neural networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hai-Son</forename><surname>Le</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alexandre</forename><surname>Allauzen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">François</forename><surname>Yvon</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2012 Conference of the North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics: Human Language Technologies</title>
		<meeting>the 2012 Conference of the North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics: Human Language Technologies<address><addrLine>Montréal, Canada</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012-06" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="39" to="48" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Association for Computational Linguistics</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Distributed representations of words and phrases and their compositionality</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tomas</forename><surname>Mikolov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ilya</forename><surname>Sutskever</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kai</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gregory</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Corrado</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jeffrey</forename><surname>Dean</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">NIPS</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3111" to="3119" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A systematic comparison of various statistical alignment models</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Josef</forename><surname>Franz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hermann</forename><surname>Och</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Ney</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Computational Linguistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003-03" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">29</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Minimum error rate training in statistical machine translation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Franz Josef</forename><surname>Och</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 41st Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the 41st Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics<address><addrLine>Japan</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2003-07" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="160" to="167" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Sapporo</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Crosslingual induction of selectional preferences with bilingual vector spaces</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yves</forename><surname>Peirsman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sebastian</forename><surname>Padó</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Human Language Technologies: The 2010 Annual Conference of the North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>California</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2010-06" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="921" to="929" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Lexical transfer using a vectorspace model</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Eiichiro</forename><surname>Sumita</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 38th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the 38th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2000-08" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Bilingual-lsa based lm adaptation for spoken language translation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yik-Cheung</forename><surname>Tam</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ian</forename><surname>Lane</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tanja</forename><surname>Schultz</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 45th Annual Meeting of the Association of Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the 45th Annual Meeting of the Association of Computational Linguistics<address><addrLine>Prague, Czech Republic</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007-06" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="520" to="527" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Association for Computational Linguistics</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Crosslingual semantic similarity of words as the similarity of their semantic word responses</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ivan</forename><surname>Vuli´cvuli´c</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marie-Francine</forename><surname>Moens</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2013 Conference of the North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics: Human Language Technologies</title>
		<meeting>the 2013 Conference of the North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics: Human Language Technologies<address><addrLine>Georgia</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2013-06" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="106" to="116" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Bitam: Bilingual topic admixture models for word alignment</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bing</forename><surname>Zhao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Eric</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Xing</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the COLING/ACL 2006 Main Conference Poster Sessions</title>
		<meeting>the COLING/ACL 2006 Main Conference Poster Sessions<address><addrLine>Sydney, Australia</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006-07" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="969" to="976" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Association for Computational Linguistics</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Bilingual word embeddings for phrase-based machine translation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Will</forename><forename type="middle">Y</forename><surname>Zou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Richard</forename><surname>Socher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Daniel</forename><surname>Cer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christopher</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Manning</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2013 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</title>
		<meeting>the 2013 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing<address><addrLine>Seattle, Washington, USA,</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1393" to="1398" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>October. Association for Computational Linguistics</note>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
