<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T11:45+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Summarizing Online Forum Discussions-Can Dialog Acts of Individual Messages Help?</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
				<availability status="unknown"><p>Copyright Association for Computational Linguistics</p>
				</availability>
				<date>October 25-29, 2014. 2014</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sumit</forename><surname>Bhatia</surname></persName>
							<email>sumit.bhatia@us.ibm.com, {pxb5080, pmitra}@ist.psu.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">IBM Almaden Research Centre</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>650 Harry Road</addrLine>
									<postCode>95123</postCode>
									<settlement>San Jose</settlement>
									<region>CA</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Prakhar</forename><surname>Biyani</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Information Science and Technology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Pennsylvania State University</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>University Park</addrLine>
									<postCode>16802</postCode>
									<region>PA</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Prasenjit</forename><surname>Mitra</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Information Science and Technology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Pennsylvania State University</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>University Park</addrLine>
									<postCode>16802</postCode>
									<region>PA</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Summarizing Online Forum Discussions-Can Dialog Acts of Individual Messages Help?</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2014 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP)</title>
						<meeting>the 2014 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP) <address><addrLine>Doha, Qatar. c</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="2127" to="2131"/>
							<date type="published">October 25-29, 2014. 2014</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>A typical discussion thread in an online forum spans multiple pages involving participation from multiple users and thus, may contain multiple viewpoints and solutions. A user interested in the topic of discussion or having a problem similar to being discussed in the thread may not want to read all the previous posts but only a few selected posts that provide her a concise summary of the ongoing discussion. This paper describes an extractive summariza-tion technique that uses textual features and dialog act information of individual messages to select a subset of posts. Proposed approach is evaluated using two real life forum datasets.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>In recent times, online discussion boards (or fo- rums) have become quite popular as they provide an easily accessible platform to users in different parts of the world to come together, share informa- tion and discuss issues of common interest. The archives of web forums contain millions of discus- sion threads and act as a valuable repository of hu- man generated information that can be utilized for various applications. Oftentimes, the discussions in a thread span multiple pages involving partici- pation from multiple users and thus, may contain multiple view-points and solutions. In such a case, the end-user may prefer a concise summary of the ongoing discussion to save time. Further, such a summary helps the user to understand the back- ground of the whole discussion as well as provides an overview of different view-points in a time ef- ficient manner. In addition to generic forums on the web, automatic forum summarization methods can prove to be useful for various domain specific applications, such as helping students and support- ing tutors in virtual learning environments <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Carbonaro, 2010)</ref>.</p><p>A typical discussion thread in a web forum con- sists of a number of individual posts or messages posted by different participating users. Often, the thread initiator posts a question to which other users reply, leading to an active discussion. As an example, consider the discussion thread shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref> where the thread starter describes his problem about the missing headphone switch in his Linux installation. In the third post in the thread, some other user asks about some clarifying details and in the next post the topic starter pro- vides the requested details that makes the problem clearer. On receiving additional details about the problem, some other user provides a possible so- lution to the problem (fifth post). The topic starter tries the suggested solution and reports his experi- ence in the next post (sixth post). Thus, we see that each individual post in a discussion thread serves a different purpose in the discussion and we posit that identifying the purpose of each such post is essential for creating effective summaries of the discussions. Intuitively, the most important mes- sages in a discussion are the ones that describe the problem being discussed and the solutions being proposed to solve the problem.</p><p>The role of an individual message in a discus- sion is typically specified in terms of dialog acts. There have been efforts to automatically assign dialog acts to messages in online forum discus- sions ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Jeong et al., 2009;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Joty et al., 2011;</ref>) and also using dialog acts for linguis- tic analysis of forum data, such as in subjectiv- ity analysis of forum threads ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Biyani et al., 2014)</ref>. In this paper, we describe our initial efforts towards addressing the problem of automatically creating summaries of such online discussion threads. We frame forum summariza- tion as a classification problem and identify mes- sages that should be included in a summary of the discussion. In addition to textual features, we em- ploy dialog act labels of individual messages for summarization and show that incorporating dialog acts leads to substantial improvements in summa- rization performance. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Definition of Dialog Acts Used</head><p>We use the same set of dialog acts as defined by . Note that based on the appli- cation context and requirements new dialog acts can be defined and added. 1. Question: The poster asks a question which initiates discussion in the thread. This is usually the first post in the thread but not always. Often, the topic initiator or some other user may ask other related questions in the thread. 2. Repeat Question: Some user repeats a previ- ously asked question (e.g. Me too having the same problem.). 3. Clarification: The poster asks clarifying ques- tions in order to gather more details about the problem or question being asked. For example, Could you provide more details about the issue you are facing.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.">Further Details:</head><p>The poster provides more de- tails about the problem as asked by other fellow posters. 5. Solution: The poster suggests a solution to the problem being discussed in the thread. 6. Positive Feedback: Somebody tries the sug- gested solution and provides a positive feedback if the solution worked. 7. Negative Feedback: Somebody tries the sug- gested solution and provides a negative feedback if the solution did not work. 8. Junk: There is no useful information in the post. For example, someone justs posts a smiley or some comments that is not useful to topic being discussed. For example, "bump", "sigh", etc., or messages posted by forum moderators such as this thread is being closed for discussion.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Proposed Approach for Thread Summarization</head><p>In general, text summarization techniques can be classified into two categories, namely extrac- tive Summarization, and Abstractive Summariza- tion <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Hahn and Mani, 2000</ref>). Extractive summa- rization involves extracting salient units of text (e.g., sentences) from the document and then con- catenating them to form a shorter version of the document. Abstractive summarization, on the other hand, involves generating new sentences by utilizing the information extracted from the doc- ument corpus <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Carenini and Cheung, 2008)</ref>, and often involves advanced natural language process- ing tools such as parsers, lexicons and grammars, and domain-specific knowledge bases <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Hahn and Mani, 2000</ref>). Owing to their simplicity and good performance, extractive summarization techniques are often the preferred tools of choice for various summarization tasks (Liu and Liu, 2009) and we also adopt an extractive approach for discussion summarization in this work.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Summarization Unit -Individual Sentence vs Individual Message</head><p>Before we can perform extractive summarization on discussion threads, we need to define an ap- propriate text unit that will be used to construct the desired summaries. For typical summariza- tion tasks, a sentence is usually treated as a unit of text and summaries are constructed by extracting most relevant sentences from a document. How- ever, a typical discussion thread is different from a generic document in that the text of a discus- sion thread is created by multiple authors (users participating in the thread). Further, the text of a discussion can be divided into individual user messages, each message serving a specific role in the whole discussion. In that sense, summa- rizing a discussion thread is similar to the task of multi-document summarization where content of multiple documents that are topically related is summarized simultaneously to construct an inclu- sive, coherent summary. However, we also note that an individual user message in a discussion is much smaller than a stand-alone document (com- pare 3 ∼ 4 sentences in a message to a few dozen sentences in a document). Thus, the sentences in a message are much more coherent and contextually related to each other than in a stand-alone docu- ment. Hence, selecting just a few sentences from a message may lead to loss of context and make the resulting summaries hard to comprehend. There- fore, in this work, we choose each individual mes- sage as a text unit and thus, the thread summaries are created by extracting most relevant posts from a discussion.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Framing Thread Summarization as Post Classification</head><p>We consider the problem of extracting relevant posts from a discussion thread as a binary classifi- cation problem where the task is to classify a given post as either belonging to the summary or not.</p><p>We perform classification in a supervised fashion by employing following features. cates that the post better represents the basic ideas of the thread. 5. Inter Post Similarity: This feature is com- puted by taking the mean of the post's cosine sim- ilarity scores with all the other posts in the thread. 6. Dialog Act Label (Class): This is a set of bi- nary features indicating the dialog act class label of the post. We have one binary feature corre- sponding to each dialog act.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Experimental Evaluation</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">Data Description</head><p>We used the dataset used by  that consists of randomly sampled 100 threads from two different online discussion forums -ubuntuforums.org and tripadvisor. com. There are a total of 556 posts in the 100 threads from Ubuntu dataset and 916 posts in 100 threads from NYC dataset. The associated dialog act labels of individual messages in each of the threads are also available. Next, for creating data for the summarization task, two independent human evaluators (H1 and H2) were recruited to create summaries of the discussion threads in the two datasets. For each thread, the evaluators were asked to read the whole discussion and write a summary of the discussion in their own words. The annotators were requested to keep the length of summaries roughly between 10% and 25% of the original text length. Thus for each thread, we obtain two human written sum- maries.</p><p>These hand-written summaries were then used to identify most relevant posts in a discussion thread in a manner similar to one used by <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Rambow et al. (2004)</ref>. We compute cosine similarity scores for each post in the thread with the corre- sponding thread summary and the top k ranked posts are then selected to be part of the sum- mary of the thread. The number k is deter- mined by the compression factor used for creat- ing summaries. We choose a compression fac- tor of 20%. The top k ranked posts, thus consti- tute the gold summary of each thread. Note that we obtain two gold summaries for each thread - one corresponding to each evaluator. This sum- marization data can be downloaded for research purposes from http://sumitbhatia.net/ source/datasets.html.   <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>: Results of post classification for summarization task. H1 and H2 correspond to the two hu- man evaluators. Percentage improvements obtained by addition of post class label information is also reported.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">Baseline</head><p>As a baseline method, we use a rule based clas- sifier that classifies all the Question and Solution posts in a thread as belonging to the summary and discards the remaining posts.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3">Results and Discussions</head><p>We used Naive Bayes classifier as implemented in the Weka machine learning toolkit ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Hall et al., 2009)</ref> for classification experiments. We trained the classifier on 75% of the data and used the re- maining 25% for testing. <ref type="table">Table 1</ref> reports the clas- sification results using (i) the baseline method,(ii) features 1-5 only, and (iii) using all the features (dialog act labels, in addition to the five features).</p><p>For both the datasets, we observe that incorpo- rating dialog act information along with textual features results in performance gain across all re- ported metrics. The strong performance improve- ments achieved for the two datasets corroborate the proposed hypothesis that knowing the role of each individual message in an online discus- sion can help create better summaries of discus- sion threads. Further, we observe that the preci- sion values are very low for the baseline algorithm (from 0.31 to 0.39) with moderate F-1 values (0.45 to 0.53), indicating a higher recall. This means that even though many of the posts in the gold summaries belong to question and solution cate- gories, not all the posts belonging to these two cat- egories are useful for summarization. Using tex- tual features and dialog act labels in a supervised machine learning framework captures the distin- guishing characteristics of in-summary and out of summary posts and thus, yields a much better clas- sification performance.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Related Work</head><p>Among various applications of text summariza- tion, work on E-Mail thread summarization <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(Rambow et al., 2004;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Cohen et al., 2004</ref>) can be con- sidered as closely related to the problem discussed in this paper. An E-Mail thread is similar to a fo- rum discussion thread in that it involves back and forth communication with the participants, how- ever, the problem of discussion thread summariza- tion is very different (and difficult) due to a rela- tively larger number of participants, highly infor- mal and noisy language, and frequent topic drifts in discussions. <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Zhou and Hovy (2005)</ref> identify clusters in internet relay chats (irc) and then em- ploy lexical and structural features to summarize each cluster. <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Ren et al. (2011)</ref> have proposed a fo- rum summarization algorithm that models the re- ply structures in a discussion thread.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Conclusions and Future Work</head><p>We proposed that dialog act labels of individual messages in an online forums can be helpful in summarizing discussion threads. We framed dis- cussion thread summarization as a binary clas- sification problem and tested our hypothesis on two different datasets. We found that for both the datasets, incorporating dialog act information as features improves classification performance as measured in terms of precision and F-1 measure.</p><p>As future work, we plan to explore various other forum specific features such as user reputation and quality of content to improve summarization per- formance.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: An example thread illustrating different role played by each post in the discussion. Different users are indicated by different colors.</figDesc><graphic url="image-1.png" coords="2,88.37,143.03,185.50,287.91" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Similarity with Title (TitleSim): This feature is computed as the cosine similarity score between the post and the title of the thread. 2. Length of Post (Length): The number of unique words in the post. 3. Post Position (Position): The normalized po- sition of the post in the discussion thread. It is defined as follows: Position of the post in the thread Total # of posts in the thread (1) 4. Centroid Similarity (Centroid): This fea- ture is obtained by computing the cosine similarity score between the post document vector and the vector obtained as the centroid of all the post vec- tors of the thread. Similarity with centroid mea- sures the relatedness of each post with the under- lying discussion topic. A post with a higher sim- ilarity score with the thread centroid vector indi-</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Evaluator</head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc></figure>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Classifying user messages for managing web forum data</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sumit</forename><surname>Bhatia</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Prakhar</forename><surname>Biyani</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Prasenjit</forename><surname>Mitra</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 15th International Workshop on the Web and Databases</title>
		<meeting>the 15th International Workshop on the Web and Databases<address><addrLine>Scottsdale, AZ, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012-05-20" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="13" to="18" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Thread specific features are helpful for identifying subjectivity orientation of online forum threads</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Prakhar</forename><surname>Biyani</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sumit</forename><surname>Bhatia</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Cornelia</forename><surname>Caragea</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Prasenjit</forename><surname>Mitra</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">COLING 2012, 24th International Conference on Computational Linguistics, Proceedings of the Conference: Technical Papers</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Mumbai, India</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012-12-815" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="295" to="310" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Using nonlexical features for identifying factual and opinionative threads in online forums. Knowledge-Based Systems</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Prakhar</forename><surname>Biyani</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sumit</forename><surname>Bhatia</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Cornelia</forename><surname>Caragea</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Prasenjit</forename><surname>Mitra</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="doi">10.1016/j.knosys.2014.04.048</idno>
		<ptr target="http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.knosys.2014.04.048" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<publisher>In Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Towards an automatic forum summarization to support tutoring</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Antonella</forename><surname>Carbonaro</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Technology Enhanced Learning. Quality of Teaching and Educational Reform</title>
		<editor>MiltiadisD. Lytras, Patricia Ordonez De Pablos, David Avison, Janice Sipior, Qun Jin, Walter Leal, Lorna Uden, Michael Thomas, Sara Cervai, and David Horner</editor>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="141" to="147" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Communications in Computer and Information Science</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Extractive vs. nlg-based abstractive summarization of evaluative text: The effect of corpus controversiality</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Giuseppe</forename><surname>Carenini</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jackie Chi Kit</forename><surname>Cheung</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Fifth International Natural Language Generation Conference</title>
		<meeting>the Fifth International Natural Language Generation Conference</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="33" to="41" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Learning to Classify Email into &quot;Speech Acts</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">William</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Cohen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Vitor</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tom</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Carvalho</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Mitchell</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">EMNLP</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACL</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="309" to="316" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The challenges of automatic summarization</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Udo</forename><surname>Hahn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Inderjeet</forename><surname>Mani</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Computer</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">33</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="29" to="36" />
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mark</forename><surname>Hall</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Eibe</forename><surname>Frank</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Geoffrey</forename><surname>Holmes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bernhard</forename><surname>Pfahringer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Peter</forename><surname>Reutemann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ian</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Witten</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">The WEKA Data Mining Software: An Update. SIGKDD Explorations</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<biblScope unit="page">11</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Semi-supervised speech act recognition in emails and forums</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Minwoo</forename><surname>Jeong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chin-Yew</forename><surname>Lin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gary Geunbae</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2009 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</title>
		<meeting>the 2009 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1250" to="1259" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Unsupervised modeling of dialog acts in asynchronous conversations</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Shafiq</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Giuseppe</forename><surname>Joty</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chin-Yew</forename><surname>Carenini</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Lin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">IJCAI</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>IJCAI/AAAI</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1807" to="1813" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">From extractive to abstractive meeting summaries: can it be done by sentence compression?</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Fei</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yang</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the ACLIJCNLP 2009 Conference Short Papers</title>
		<meeting>the ACLIJCNLP 2009 Conference Short Papers</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="261" to="264" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Summarizing email threads</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Rambow</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Shrestha</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Laurdisen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of HLT-NAACL</title>
		<meeting>HLT-NAACL</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Short Papers</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Summarizing web forum threads based on a latent topic propagation process</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jun</forename><surname>Zhaochun Ren</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Shuaiqiang</forename><surname>Ma</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yang</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 20th ACM International Conference on Information and Knowledge Management, CIKM &apos;11</title>
		<meeting>the 20th ACM International Conference on Information and Knowledge Management, CIKM &apos;11<address><addrLine>New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="879" to="884" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Digesting virtual &quot;geek&quot; culture: The summarization of technical internet relay chats</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Liang</forename><surname>Zhou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Eduard</forename><surname>Hovy</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 43rd Annual Meeting on Association for Computational Linguistics, ACL &apos;05</title>
		<meeting>the 43rd Annual Meeting on Association for Computational Linguistics, ACL &apos;05<address><addrLine>Stroudsburg, PA, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="298" to="305" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
