<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T10:32+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">A Cognitive Model of Semantic Network Learning</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
				<availability status="unknown"><p>Copyright Association for Computational Linguistics</p>
				</availability>
				<date>October 25-29, 2014. 2014</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Aida</forename><surname>Nematzadeh</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Toronto</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Afsaneh</forename><surname>Fazly</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Toronto</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Suzanne</forename><surname>Stevenson</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Toronto</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">A Cognitive Model of Semantic Network Learning</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2014 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP)</title>
						<meeting>the 2014 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP) <address><addrLine>Doha, Qatar. c</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="244" to="254"/>
							<date type="published">October 25-29, 2014. 2014</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Child semantic development includes learning the meaning of words as well as the semantic relations among words. A presumed outcome of semantic development is the formation of a semantic network that reflects this knowledge. We present an algorithm for simultaneously learning word meanings and gradually growing a semantic network, which adheres to the cognitive plausibility requirements of incrementality and limited computations. We demonstrate that the semantic connections among words in addition to their context is necessary in forming a semantic network that resembles an adult&apos;s semantic knowledge.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Child semantic development includes the acquisi- tion of word-to-concept mappings (part of word learning), and the formation of semantic connec- tions among words/concepts. There is consid- erable evidence that understanding the semantic properties of words improves child vocabulary ac- quisition. In particular, children are sensitive to commonalities of semantic categories, and this abstract knowledge facilitates subsequent word learning ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Jones et al., 1991;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Colunga and Smith, 2005</ref>). Furthermore, representation of semantic knowledge is significant as it impacts how word meanings are stored in, searched for, and retrieved from memory ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">Steyvers and Tenenbaum, 2005;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Griffiths et al., 2007)</ref>.</p><p>Semantic knowledge is often represented as a graph (a semantic network) in which nodes cor- respond to words/concepts 1 , and edges specify the semantic relations <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Collins and Loftus, 1975;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b30">Steyvers and Tenenbaum, 2005</ref>). <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">Steyvers and Tenenbaum (2005)</ref> demonstrated that a seman- tic network that encodes adult-level knowledge of words exhibits a small-world and scale-free struc- ture. That is, it is an overall sparse network with highly-connected local sub-networks, where these sub-networks are connected through high-degree hubs (nodes with many neighbours).</p><p>Much experimental research has investigated the underlying mechanisms of vocabulary learn- ing and characteristics of semantic knowledge <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">(Quine, 1960;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Bloom, 1973;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Carey and Bartlett, 1978;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Gleitman, 1990;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b26">Samuelson and Smith, 1999;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Jones et al., 1991;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Jones and Smith, 2005</ref>). However, existing computational models focus on certain aspects of semantic acquisition: Some researchers develop computational models of word learning without considering the acqui- sition of semantic connections that hold among words, or how this semantic knowledge is struc- tured <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">(Siskind, 1996;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Regier, 2005;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b34">Yu and Ballard, 2007;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Frank et al., 2009;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Fazly et al., 2010)</ref>. Another line of work is to model formation of semantic categories but this work does not take into account how word meanings/concepts are ac- quired ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Anderson and Matessa, 1992;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Griffiths et al., 2007;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Fountain and Lapata, 2011)</ref>.</p><p>Our goal in this work is to provide a cognitively- plausible and unified account for both acquiring and representing semantic knowledge. The re- quirements for cognitive plausibility enforce some constraints on a model to ensure that it is compa- rable with the cognitive process it is formulating ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Poibeau et al., 2013</ref>). As we model semantic ac- quisition, the first requirement is incrementality, which means that the model learns gradually as it processes the input. Also, there is a limit on the number of computations the model performs at each step.</p><p>In this paper, we present an algorithm for si-multaneously learning word meanings and grow- ing a semantic network, which adheres to the cog- nitive plausibility requirements of incrementality and limited computations. We examine networks created by our model under various conditions, and explore what is required to obtain a structure that has appropriate semantic connections and has a small-world and scale-free structure.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Related Work</head><p>Models of Word Learning. Given a word learn- ing scenario, there are potentially many possible mappings between words in a sentence and their meanings (real-world referents), from which only some mappings are correct (the mapping prob- lem). One of the most dominant mechanisms proposed for vocabulary acquisition is cross- situational learning: people learn word mean- ings by recognizing and tracking statistical reg- ularities among the contexts of a word's usage across various situations, enabling them to nar- row in on the meaning of a word that holds across its usages <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">(Siskind, 1996;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b35">Yu and Smith, 2007;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b29">Smith and Yu, 2008)</ref>. A number of computa- tional models attempt to solve the mapping prob- lem by implementing this mechanism, and have successfully replicated different patterns observed in child word learning <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">(Siskind, 1996;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b34">Yu and Ballard, 2007;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Fazly et al., 2010</ref>). These models have provided insight about underlying mechanisms of word learning, but none of them consider the se- mantic relations that hold among words, or how the semantic knowledge is structured. Recently, we have investigated properties of the semantic structure of the resulting (final) acquired knowl- edge of such a learner ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">Nematzadeh et al., 2014</ref>). However, that work did not address how such structural knowledge might develop and evolve in- crementally within the learning model.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Models of Categorization.</head><p>Computational mod- els of categorization focus on the problem of form- ing semantic clusters given a defined set of fea- tures for words <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Anderson and Matessa, 1992;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Griffiths et al., 2007;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b27">Sanborn et al., 2010</ref>). An- derson and <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Matessa (1992)</ref> note that a cognitively plausible categorization algorithm needs to be in- cremental and only keep track of one potential partitioning; they propose a Bayesian framework (the Rational Model of Categorization or RMC) that specifies the joint distribution on features and category labels, and allows an unbounded number of clusters. <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">Sanborn et al. (2010)</ref> examine differ- ent categorization models based on RMC. In par- ticular, they compare the performance of the ap- proximation algorithm of <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Anderson and Matessa (1992)</ref> (local MAP) with two other approximation algorithms (Gibbs Sampling and Particle Filters) in various human categorization paradigms. <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">Sanborn et al. (2010)</ref> find that in most of the simula- tions the local MAP algorithm performs as well as the two other algorithms in matching human be- havior.</p><p>The Representation of Semantic Knowledge.</p><p>There is limited work on computational models of semantic acquisition that examine the represen- tation of the semantic knowledge. <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">Steyvers and Tenenbaum (2005)</ref> propose an algorithm for build- ing a network with small-world and scale-free structure. The algorithm starts with a small com- plete graph, incrementally adds new nodes to the graph, and for each new node uses a probabilistic mechanism for selecting a subset of current nodes to connect to. However, their approach does not address the problem of learning word meanings or the semantic connections among them. <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Fountain and Lapata (2011)</ref> propose an algorithm for learn- ing categories that also creates a semantic network by comparing all the possible word pairs. How- ever, they too do not address the word learning problem, and do not investigate the structure of the learned semantic network to see whether it has the properties observed in adult knowledge.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">The Incremental Network Model</head><p>We propose here a model that unifies the incre- mental acquisition of word meanings and forma- tion of a semantic network structure that reflects the similarities among those meanings. We use an existing model to learn the meanings of words (Section 3.1), and use those incrementally devel- oping meanings as the input to the algorithm pro- posed here for gradually growing a semantic net- work (Section 3.2).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">The Word Learner</head><p>We use the model of <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Fazly et al. (2010)</ref>; this learn- ing algorithm is incremental and involves limited calculations, thus satisfying basic cognitive plausi- bility requirements. A naturalistic language learn- ing scenario consists of linguistic data in the con- text of non-linguistic data, such as the objects, Utterance: {let, find, a, picture, to, color } Scene: {LET, PRONOUN, HAS POSSESSION, CAUSE, ARTIFACT, WHOLE, CHANGE, . . . } <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>: A sample utterance-scene pair.</p><p>events, and social interactions that a child per- ceives. This kind of input is modeled here as a pair of an utterance (the words a child hears) and a scene (the semantic features representing the meaning of those words), as shown in <ref type="table">Table 1</ref> (and described in more detail in Section 5.1). The word learner is an instance of cross-situational learn- ing applied to a sequence of such input pairs: for each pair of a word w and a semantic feature f , the model incrementally learns P (f |w) from co- occurrences of w and f across all the utterance- scene pairs. For each word, the probability distribution over all semantic features, P (.|w), represents the word's meaning. The estimation of P (.|w) is made possible by introducing a set of latent vari- ables, alignments, that correspond to the possible mappings between words and features in a given utterance-scene pair. The learning problem is then to find the mappings that best explain the data, which is solved by using an incremental version of the expectation-maximization (EM) algorithm <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">(Neal and Hinton, 1998)</ref>. We skip the details of the derivations and only report the resulting for- mulas.</p><p>The model processes one utterance-scene pair at a time. For the input pair processed at time t, first the probability of each possible alignment (align- ment probability) is calculated as: 2</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">P (a ij |u, f i ) = P t−1 (f i |w j ) w ∈u P t−1 (f i |w ) (1)</formula><p>where u is the utterance, and a ij is the alignment variable specifying the word w j that is mapped to the feature f i . P t−1 (f i |w j ) is taken from the model's current learned meaning of word w j . Ini- tially, P 0 (f i |w j ) is uniformly distributed. After calculating the alignment probabilities, the learned meanings are updated as:</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">P t (f i |w j ) = u∈Ut P (a ij |u, f i ) f ∈M u∈Ut P (a ij |u, f )<label>(2)</label></formula><p>where U t is the set of utterances processed so far, and M is the set of features that the model has ob- served. Note that for each w-f pair, the value of the summations in this formula can be incremen- tally updated after processing any utterance that contains w; the summation does not have to be cal- culated at every step.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Growing a Semantic Network</head><p>In our extended model, as we learn words incre- mentally (as above), we also structure those words into a semantic network based on the (partially) learned meanings. At any given point in time, the network will include as its nodes all the word types the word learner has been exposed to. Weighted edges (capturing semantic distance) will connect those pairs of word types whose learned meanings at that point are sufficiently semantically similar (according to a threshold). Since the probabilis- tic meaning of a word is adjusted each time it is observed, a word may either lose or gain connec- tions in the network after each input is processed. Thus, to incrementally develop the network, at each time step, our algorithm must both examine existing connections (to see which edges should be removed) and consider potential new connections (to see which edges should be added).</p><p>A simple approach to achieve this is to examine the current semantic similarity between a word w in the input and all the current words in the net- work, and include edges between only those word pairs that are sufficiently similar. However, com- paring w to all the words in the network each time it is observed is computationally intensive (and not cognitively plausible).</p><p>We present an approach for incrementally grow- ing a semantic network that limits the computa- tions when processing each input word w; see Al- gorithm 1. After the meaning of w is updated, we first check all the words that w is currently (di- rectly) connected to, to see if any of those edges need to be removed, or have their weight adjusted. Next, to look for new connections for w, the idea is to select only a small subset of words, S, to which w will be compared. The challenge then is to se- lect S in a way that will yield a network whose se- mantic structure reasonably approximates the net- work that would result from full knowledge of comparing w to all the words.</p><p>Previous work has suggested picking "impor- tant" words (e.g., high-degree words) indepen- dently of the target word w -assuming these might be words for which a learner might need to understand their relationship to w in the future ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">Steyvers and Tenenbaum, 2005</ref>). Our proposal is instead to consider for S those words that are Algorithm 1 Growing a network after each in- put u.</p><p>for all w in u do update P (.|w) using Eqn. <ref type="formula" target="#formula_1">(2)</ref> update current connections of w select S(w), a subset of words in the network for all w in S(w) do if w and w are sufficiently similar then connect w and w with an edge end if end for end for likely to be similar to w. That is, since the net- work only needs to connect similar words to w, if we can guess what (some of) those words are, then we will do best at approximating the situation of comparing w to all words.</p><p>The question now is how to find semantically similar words to w that are not already connected to w in the network. To do so, we incrementally track semantic similarity among words usages as their meanings are developing. Specifically we cluster word tokens (not types) according to their current word meanings. Since the probabilistic meanings of words are continually evolving, in- cremental clusters of word tokens can capture de- veloping similarities among the various usages of a word type, and be a clue to which words (types) w might be similar to. In the next section, we de- scribe the Bayesian clustering process we use to identify potentially similar words.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3">Semantic Clustering of Word Tokens</head><p>We use the Bayesian framework of <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Anderson and Matessa (1992)</ref> to form semantic clusters. <ref type="bibr">3</ref> Recall that for each word w, the model learns its mean- ings as a probability distribution over all seman- tic features, P (.|w). We represent this probability distribution as a vector F whose length is the num- ber of possible semantic features. Each element of the vector holds the value P (f |w) (which is con- tinuous). Given a word w and its vector F , we need to calculate the probability that w belongs to each existing cluster, and also allow for the pos- sibility of it forming a new cluster. Using Bayes rule we have: <ref type="bibr">3</ref> The distribution specified by this model is equivalent to that of a Dirichlet Process Mixture Model <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">(Neal, 2000).</ref> where k is a given cluster. We thus need to calcu- late the prior probability, P (k), and the likelihood of each cluster, P (F |k). Calculation of Prior. The prior probability that word n + 1 is assigned to cluster k is calculated as:</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">P (k|F ) = P (k)P (F |k) k P (k )P (F |k )<label>(3)</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_3">P (k) = n k n+α n k &gt; 0 α n+α n k = 0 (new cluster)<label>(4)</label></formula><p>where n k is the number of words in cluster k, n is the number of words observed so far, and α is a parameter that determines how likely the creation of a new cluster is. The prior favors larger clusters, and also discourages the creation of new clusters in later stages of learning. Calculation of Likelihood. To calculate the like- lihood P (F |k) in Eqn. <ref type="formula" target="#formula_2">(3)</ref>, we assume that the fea- tures are independent:</p><formula xml:id="formula_4">P (F |k) = f i ∈F P (f i = v|k)<label>(5)</label></formula><p>where P (f i = v|k) is the probability that the value of the feature in dimension i is equal to v given the cluster k. To derive P (f i |k), following An- derson and Matessa (1992), we assume that each feature given a cluster follows a Gaussian distri- bution with an unknown variance σ 2 and mean µ.</p><p>(In the absence of any prior information about a variable, it is often assumed to have a Gaussian distribution.) The mean and variance of this dis- tribution are inferred using Bayesian analysis: We assume the variance has an inverse χ 2 prior, where σ 2 0 is the prior variance and a 0 is the confidence in the prior variance:</p><formula xml:id="formula_5">σ 2 ∼ Inv-χ 2 (a 0 , σ 2 0 )<label>(6)</label></formula><p>The mean given the variance has a Gaussian dis- tribution with µ 0 as the prior mean and λ 0 as the confidence in the prior mean.</p><formula xml:id="formula_6">µ|σ ∼ N(µ 0 , σ 2 λ 0 )<label>(7)</label></formula><p>Given the above conjugate priors, P (f i |k) can be calculated analytically and is a Student's t dis- tribution with the following parameters:</p><formula xml:id="formula_7">P (f i |k) ∼ t a i (µ i , σ 2 i (1 + 1 λ i ))<label>(8)</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_8">λ i = λ 0 + n k (9) a i = a 0 + n k (10) µ i = λ 0 µ 0 + n k ¯ f λ 0 + n k (11) σ 2 i = a 0 σ 2 0 + (n k − 1)s 2 + λ 0 n k λ 0 +n k (µ 0 + ¯ f ) 2 a 0 + n k<label>(12)</label></formula><p>where ¯ f and s 2 are the sample mean and variance of the values of f i in k.</p><p>Note that in the above equations, the mean and variance of the distribution are simply derived by combining the sample mean and variance with the prior mean and variance while considering the confidence in the prior mean (λ 0 ) and variance (a 0 ). This means that the number of computations to calculate P (F |K) is limited as w is only com- pared to the "prototype" of each cluster, which is represented by µ i and σ i of different features. Adding a word w to a cluster. We add w to the cluster k with highest posterior probability, P (k|F ), as calculated in Eqn. (3). <ref type="bibr">4</ref> The parame- ters of the selected cluster (k, µ i , λ i , σ i , and a i for each feature f i ) are then updated incrementally. Using the Clusters to Select the Words in S(w). We can now form S(w) in Algorithm 1 by select- ing a given number of words n s whose tokens are probabilistically chosen from the clusters accord- ing to how likely each cluster k is given w: the number of word tokens picked from each k is pro- portional to P (k|F ) and is equal to P (k|F ) × n s .</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Evaluation</head><p>We evaluate a semantic network in two regards: The semantic connectivity of the network -to what extent the semantically-related words are connected in the network; and the structure of the network -whether it exhibits a small-world and scale-free structure or not.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">Evaluating Semantic Connectivity</head><p>The distance between the words in the network in- dicates their semantic similarity: the more similar a word pair, the smaller their distance. For word pairs that are connected via a path in the network, this distance is the weighted shortest path length between the two words. If there is no path be- tween a word pair, their distance is considered to be ∞ (which is represented with a large number). We refer to this distance as the "learned" semantic similarity.</p><p>To evaluate the semantic connectivity of the learned network, we compare these learned sim- ilarity scores to "gold-standard" similarity scores that are calculated using the WordNet similarity measure of <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">Wu and Palmer (1994)</ref> (also known as the WUP measure). We choose this measure since it captures the same type of similarity as in our model: words are considered similar if they belong to the same semantic category. Moreover, this measure does not incorporate information about other types of similarities, for example, words are not considered similar if they occur in similar con- texts. Thus, the scores calculated with this mea- sure are comparable with those of our learned net- work.</p><p>Given the gold-standard similarity scores for each word pair, we evaluate the semantic con- nectivity of the network based on two perfor- mance measures: coefficient of correlation and the median rank of the first five gold-standard as- sociates. Correlation is a standard way to com- pare two lists of similarity scores <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Budanitsky and Hirst, 2006</ref>). We create two lists, one con- taining the gold-standard similarity scores for all word pairs, and the other containing their corre- sponding learned similarity scores. We calculate the Spearman's rank correlation coefficient, ρ, be- tween these two lists of similarity scores. Note that the learned similarity scores reflect the seman- tic distance among words whereas the WordNet scores reflect semantic closeness. Thus, a nega- tive correlation is best in our evaluation, where the value of -1 corresponds to the maximum correla- tion.</p><p>Following <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Griffiths et al. (2007)</ref>, we also cal- culate the median learned rank of the first five gold-standard associates for all words: For each word w, we first create a "gold-standard" asso- ciates list: we sort all other words based on their gold-standard similarity to w, and pick the five most similar words (associates) to w. Similarly, we create a "learned associate list" for w by sort- ing all words based on their learned semantic simi- larity to w. For all words, we find the ranks of their first five gold-standard associates in their learned associate list. For each associate, we calculate the median of these ranks for all words. We only re- port the results for the first three gold-standard as- sociates since the pattern of results is similar for the fourth and fifth associates; we refer to the me- dian rank of first three gold-standard associates as 1 st , 2 nd , and 3 rd .</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">Evaluating the Structure of the Network</head><p>A network exhibits a small-world structure when it is characterized by short path length between most nodes and highly-connected neighborhoods ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">Watts and Strogatz, 1998</ref>). We first explain how these properties are measured for a graph with N nodes and E edges. Then we discuss how these properties are used in assessing the small-world structure of a graph. 5 .</p><p>Short path lengths. Most of the nodes of a small-world network are reachable from other nodes via relatively short paths. For a connected network (i.e., all the node pairs are reachable from each other), this can be measured as the average distance between all node pairs ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">Watts and Strogatz, 1998</ref>). Since our networks are not connected, we instead measure this property using the median of the distances (d median ) between all node pairs ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">Robins et al., 2005</ref>), which is well-defined even when some node pairs have a distance of ∞.</p><p>Highly-connected neighborhoods. The neigh- borhood of a node n in a graph consists of n and all of the nodes that are connected to it. A neigh- borhood is maximally connected if it forms a com- plete graph -i.e., there is an edge between all node pairs. Thus, the maximum number of edges in the neighborhood of n is k n (k n − 1)/2, where k n is the number of neighbors. A standard metric for measuring the connectedness of neighbors of a node n is called the local clustering coefficient (C) ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">Watts and Strogatz, 1998)</ref>, which calculates the ratio of edges in the neighborhood of n (E n ) to the maximum number of edges possible for that neighborhood:</p><formula xml:id="formula_9">C = E n k n (k n − 1)/2<label>(13)</label></formula><p>The local clustering coefficient C ranges between 0 and 1. To estimate the connectedness of all neighborhoods in a network, we take the average of C over all nodes, i.e., C avg . Small-world structure. A graph exhibits a small-world structure if d median is relatively small and C avg is relatively high. To assess this for a graph g, these values are typically compared to those of a random graph with the same num- ber of nodes and edges as g ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">Watts and Strogatz, 1998;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Humphries and Gurney, 2008)</ref>. The ran- dom graph is generated by randomly rearranging the edges of the network under consideration <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Erdos and Rényi, 1960)</ref>. Because any pair of nodes is equally likely to be connected as any other, the median of distances between nodes is expected to be low for a random graph. In a small-world net- work, this value d median is expected to be as small as that of a random graph: even though the random graph has edges more uniformly distributed, the small-world network has many locally-connected components which are connected via hubs. On the other hand, C avg is expected to be much higher in a small-world network compared to its corre- sponding random graph, because the edges of a random graph typically do not fall into clusters forming highly connected neighborhoods.</p><p>Given these two properties, the "small- worldness" of a graph g is measured as follows <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">(Humphries and Gurney, 2008)</ref>:</p><formula xml:id="formula_10">σ g = C avg (g) C avg (random) d median (g) d median (random) (14)</formula><p>where random is the random graph correspond- ing to g. In a small-world network, it is ex- pected that C avg (g) C avg (random) and d median (g) ≥ d median (random), and thus σ g &gt; 1.</p><p>Note that <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">Steyvers and Tenenbaum (2005)</ref> made the empirical observation that small-world net- works of semantic knowledge had a single con- nected component that contained the majority of nodes in the network. Thus, in addition to σ g , we also measure the relative size of a network's largest connected component having size N lcc :</p><formula xml:id="formula_11">size lcc = N lcc N<label>(15)</label></formula><p>Scale-free structure. A scale-free network has a relatively small number of high-degree nodes that have a large number of connections to other nodes, while most of its nodes have a small de- gree, as they are only connected to a few nodes. Thus, if a network has a scale-free structure, its de- gree distribution (i.e., the probability distribution of degrees over the whole network) will follow a power-law distribution (which is said to be "scale- free"). We evaluate this property of a network by plotting its degree distribution in the logarithmic scale, which (if a power-law distribution) should appear as a straight line. None of our networks ex-hibit a scale-free structure; thus, we do not report the results of this evaluation, and leave it to future work for further investigation.</p><p>5 Experimental Set-up</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.1">Input Representation</head><p>Recall that the input to the model consists of a sequence of utterance-scene pairs intended to re- flect the linguistic data a child is exposed to, along with the associated meaning a child might grasp. As in much previous work <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">(Yu and Ballard, 2007;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Fazly et al., 2010)</ref>, we take child-directed utter- ances from the CHILDES database <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">(MacWhinney, 2000</ref>) in order to have naturalistic data. In partic- ular, we use the Manchester corpus ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">Theakston et al., 2001</ref>), which consists of transcripts of conver- sations with 12 British children between the ages of 1; 8 and 3; 0. We represent each utterance as a bag of lemmatized words (see Utterance in Ta- ble 1).</p><p>For the scene representation, we have no large corpus to draw on that encodes the semantic por- tion of language acquisition data. <ref type="bibr">6</ref> We thus auto- matically generate the semantics associated with an utterance, using a scheme first introduced in <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Fazly et al. (2010)</ref>. The idea is to first create an input generation lexicon that provides a mapping between all the words in the input data and their associated meanings. A scene is then represented as a set that contains the meanings of all the words in the utterance. We use the input generation lexi- con of <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Nematzadeh et al. (2012)</ref> because the word meanings reflect information about their semantic categories, which is crucial to forming the seman- tic clusters as in Section 3.3.</p><p>In this lexicon, the "true" meaning for each word w is a vector over a set of possible seman- tic features for each part of speech; in the vec- tor, each feature is associated with a score for that word (see <ref type="figure">Figure 1)</ref>. Depending on the word's part of speech, the features are extracted from various <ref type="bibr">6</ref> Yu and Ballard (2007) created a corpus by hand-coding the objects and cues that were present in the environment, but that corpus is very small. <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Frank et al. (2013)</ref> provide a larger manually annotated corpus (5000 utterances), but it is still very small for longitudinal simulations of word learn- ing. (Our corpus contains more than 100,000 utterances.) Moreover, the corpus of <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Frank et al. (2013)</ref> is limited be- cause a considerable number of words are not semantically coded. (Only a subset of concrete objects in the environment are coded.) apple: { FOOD:1, SOLID:.72, · · · , PLANT-PART:.22, PHYSICAL-ENTITY:.17, WHOLE:.06, · · · } <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref>: Sample true meaning features &amp; their scores for apple from <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Nematzadeh et al. (2012)</ref>.</p><p>lexical resources such as WordNet 7 , VerbNet <ref type="bibr">8 , and Harm (2002)</ref>. The score for each feature is calcu- lated using a measure similar to tf-idf that reflects the association of the feature with the word and with its semantic category: term frequency indi- cates the strength of association of the feature with the word, and inverse document frequency (where the documents are the categories) indicates how informative a feature is for that category. The se- mantic categories of nouns (which we focus on in our networks) are given by WordNet lex-names 9 , a set of 25 general categories of entities. (We use only nouns in our semantic networks because the semantic similarity of words with different parts of speech cannot be compared, since their seman- tic features are drawn from different resources.)</p><p>The input generation lexicon is used to generate a scene representation for an utterance as follows: For each word w in the utterance, we probabilisti- cally sample features, in proportion to their score, from the full set of features in its true meaning. The probabilistic sampling allows us to simulate the noise and uncertainty in the input a child per- ceives by omitting some meaning features from the scene. The scene representation is the union of all the features sampled for all the words in the utterance (see Scene in <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.2">Methods</head><p>We experiment with our network-growth method that draws on the incremental clustering, and cre- ate "upper-bound" and baseline networks for com- parison. Note that all the networks are created using our Algorithm 1 (page 4) to grow networks incrementally, drawing on the learned meanings of words and updating their connections on the basis of this evolving knowledge. The only difference in creating the networks resides in how the com- parison set S(w) is chosen for each target word w that is being added to the growing network at each time step. We provide more details in the para- graphs below.</p><p>Upper-bound. Recall that one of our main goals is to substantially reduce the number of similar- ity comparisons needed to grow a semantic net- work, in contrast to the straightforward method of comparing each w to all current words. At the same time, we need to understand the impact of the increased efficiency on the quality of the re- sulting networks. We thus need to compare the target properties of our networks that are learned using a small comparison set S, to those of an "upper-bound" network that takes into account all the pair-wise comparisons among words. We cre- ate this upper-bound network by setting S(w) to contain all words currently in the network.</p><p>Baselines. On the other hand, we need to evalu- ate the (potential) benefit of our cluster-driven se- lection process over a more simplistic approach to selecting S(w). To do so, we consider three base- lines, each using a different criteria for choosing the comparison set S(w): The Random baseline chooses the members of this set randomly from the set of all observed words. The Context base- line can be seen as an "informed" baseline that at- tempts to incorporate some semantic knowledge: Here, we select words that are in the recent context prior to w in the input, assuming that such words are likely to be semantically related to w. We also include a third baseline, Random+Context, that picks half of the members of S randomly and half of them from the prior context.</p><p>Cluster-based Methods. We report results for three cluster-based networks that differ in their choice of S(w) as follows: The Clusters-only net- work chooses words in S(w) from the set of clus- ters, proportional to the probability of each clus- ter k given word w (as explained in Section 3.3). In order to incorporate different types of semantic information in selecting S, we also create a Clus- ters+Context network that picks half of the mem- bers of S from clusters (as above), and half from the prior context. For completeness, we include a Clusters+Random network that similarly chooses half of words in S from clusters and half randomly from all observed words.</p><p>We have experimented with several other meth- ods, but they all performed substantially worse than the baselines, and hence we do not report them here. E.g., we tried picking words in S from the best cluster. We also tried a few methods in- spired by <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">(Steyvers and Tenenbaum, 2005</ref>): E.g., we examined a method where if a member of S(w) was sufficiently similar to w, we added the direct neighbors of that word to S. We also tried to grow networks by choosing the members of S according to the degree or frequency of nodes in the network.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.3">Experimental Parameters</head><p>We use 20, 000 utterance-scene pairs as our train- ing data. Recall that we use clustering to help guide our semantic network growth algorithm. Given the clustering algorithm in Section 3.3, we are interested to find the set of clusters that best explain the data. (Other clustering algorithms can be used instead of this algorithm.) We perform a search on the parameter space, and select the parameter values that result in the best clustering, based on the number of clusters and their average F-score. The value of the clustering parameters are as follows: α = 49, λ 0 = 1.0, a 0 = 2.0, µ 0 = 0.0, and σ 0 = 0.05. Two nouns with fea- ture vectors F 1 and F 2 are connected in the net- work if cosine(F 1, F 2) is greater than or equal to 0.6. (This threshold was selected following em- pirical examination of the similarity values we ob- serve among the "true" meaning in our input gen- eration lexicon.) The weight on the edge that con- nects these nouns specifies their semantic distance, which is calculated as 1 − cosine(F 1, F 2).</p><p>Because we aim for a network creation method that is cognitively plausible in performing a lim- ited number of word-to-word comparisons, we need to ensure that all the different methods of selecting the comparison set S(w) yield roughly similar numbers of such comparisons. Keeping the size of S constant does not guarantee this, because each method can yield differing num- bers of connections of the target word w to other words. We thus parameterize the size of S for each method to keep the number of computations similar, based on experiments on the development data. In development work we also found that hav- ing an increasing size of S over time improved the results, as more words were compared as the knowledge of learned meanings improved. To achieve this, we use a percentage of the words in the network as the size of S. In practice, the setting of this parameter yields a number of com- parisons across all methods that is about 8% of the maximum possible word-to-word comparisons that would be performed in the naive (computa- tionally intensive) approach.</p><p>Note that all the Cluster-based, Random and Random+Context methods include a random se- lection mechanism; thus, we run each of these methods 50 times and report the average ρ, me- dian ranks and size lcc (see Section 4). For the net- works (out of 50 runs) that exhibit a small-world structure (small-worldness greater than one), we report the average small-worldness. We also re- port the percentage of runs whose resulting net- work exhibit a small-world structure.  <ref type="bibr">10</ref> Recall that the Upper-bound network is formed from examining a word's similarity to all other (observed) words when it is added to the network. We can see that this network is highly connected (0.85) and has a small-world structure (5.5). There is a statistically significant correlation of the net- work's similarity measures with the gold standard ones (−0.38). For this Upper-bound structure, the median ranks of the first three associates are be- tween 31 and 42. These latter two measures on the Upper-bound network give an indication of the difficulty of learning a semantic network whose knowledge matches gold-standard similarities.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Experimental Results and Discussion</head><p>Considering the baseline networks, we note that the Random network is actually somewhat bet- ter (in connectivity and median ranks) than the Context network that we thought would provide a more informed baseline. Interestingly, the cor- relation value for both networks is no worse than for the Upper-bound. The combination of Ran- dom+Context yields a slightly lower correlation, and no better ranks or connectivity than Random. Note that none of the baseline networks exhibit a small world structure (σ g 1 for all three, except for one out of 50 runs for the Random method).</p><p>Recall that the Random network is not a net- work resulting from randomly connecting word pairs, but one that incrementally compares each target word with a set of randomly chosen words when considering possible new connections. We suspect that this approach performs reasonably well because it enables the model to find a broad <ref type="bibr">10</ref> All the reported co-efficients of correlation (ρ) are statis- tically significant at p &lt; 0.01. range of similar words to the target; this might be effective especially because the learned meanings of words are changing over time.</p><p>Turning to the Cluster-based methods, we see that indeed some diversity in the comparison set for a target word might be necessary to good performance. We find that the measures on the Clusters-only network are roughly the same as on the Random one, but when we combine the two in Clusters+Random we see an improvement in the ranks achieved. It is possible that the selection from clusters does not have sufficient diversity to find some of the valid new connections for a word.</p><p>We note that the best results overall occur with the Clusters+Context network, which combines two approaches to selecting words that have good potential to be similar to the target word. The correlation coefficient for this network is at a re- spectable 0.36, and the median ranks are the sec- ond best of all the network-growth methods. Im- portantly, this network shows the desired small- world structure in most of the runs (77%), with the highest connectivity and a small-world mea- sure well over 1.</p><p>The fact that the Clusters+Context network is better overall than the networks of the Clusters- only and Context methods indicates that both clus- ters and context are important in making "in- formed guesses" about which words are likely to be similar to a target word. Given the small number of similarity comparisons used in our ex- periments (only around 8% of all possible word- to-word comparisons), these observations suggest that both the linguistic context and the evolving relations among word usages (captured by the in- cremental clustering of learned meanings) contain information crucial to the process of growing a se- mantic network in a cognitively plausible way.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7">Conclusions</head><p>We propose a unified model of word learning and semantic network formation, which creates a net- work of words in which connections reflect struc- tured knowledge of semantic similarity between words. The model adheres to the cognitive plau- sibility requirements of incrementality and use of limited computations. That is, when incremen- tally adding or updating a word's connections in the network, the model only looks at a subset of words rather than comparing the target word to all the nodes in the network. We demonstrate that 0.6 0 (0) Cluster-based Methods Clusters-only −0.32 58.6 72.0 71.6 0.7 5.5 (43) Clusters+Context −0.36 53.9 67.6 64.8 0.7 7.2 (77) Clusters+Random −0.35 48.1 61.2 58.1 0.7 6.9 (48) <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table 2</ref>: Connectivity and small-worldness measures for the Upper-bound, Baseline, and Cluster-based network-growth methods; best performances across the Baseline and Cluster-based methods are shown in bold. ρ: co-efficient of correlation between similarities of word pairs in network and in gold-standard; 1 st , 2 nd , 3 rd : median ranks of corresponding gold-standard associates given network similarities; size lcc : proportion of network in the largest connected component; σ g : overall "small-worldness", should be greater than 1; %: the percentage of runs whose resulting networks exhibit a small-world structure. Note there are 1074 nouns in each network.</p><p>using the evolving knowledge of semantic con- nections among words as well as their context of usage enables the model to create a network that shows the properties of adult semantic knowledge. This suggests that the information in the semantic relations among words and their context can effi- ciently guide semantic network growth.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" validated="false"><head>Table 2 presents</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>our results, including the eval-
uation measures explained above, for the Upper-
bound, Baseline, and Cluster-based networks cre-
ated by the various methods described in Sec-
tion 5.2. </table></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> Here we assume that the nodes of a semantic network are word forms and its edges are determined by the semantic features of those words.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="2"> This corresponds to the expectation step of EM.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="4"> This approach is referred to as local MAP (Sanborn et al., 2010); because of the incremental nature of the algorithm, it maximizes the current posterior distribution as opposed to the &quot;global&quot; posterior.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="5"> We take the description of these measures from Nematzadeh et al. (2014)</note>

			<note place="foot" n="7"> http://wordnet.princeton.edu 8 http://verbs.colorado.edu/ ˜ mpalmer/ projects/verbnet.html 9 http://wordnet.princeton.edu/wordnet/ man/lexnames.5WN.html</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>We would like to thank Varada Kolhatkar for valu-able discussion and feedback. We are also grateful for the financial support from NSERC of Canada, and University of Toronto.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Explorations of an incremental, bayesian algorithm for categorization</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">John</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Anderson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Matessa</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Machine Learning</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1992" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="275" to="308" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">One word at a time: The use of single word utterances before syntax</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lois</forename><surname>Bloom</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1973" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">154</biblScope>
			<pubPlace>Mouton The Hague</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Evaluating wordnet-based measures of lexical semantic relatedness</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alexander</forename><surname>Budanitsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Graeme</forename><surname>Hirst</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Computational Linguistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">32</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="13" to="47" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Acquiring a single new word</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Susan</forename><surname>Carey</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Elsa</forename><surname>Bartlett</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1978" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A spreading-activation theory of semantic processing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Allan</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Collins</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Elizabeth</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Loftus</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">82</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">407</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1975" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">From the lexicon to expectations about kinds: A role for associative learning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Eliana</forename><surname>Colunga</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Linda</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Smith</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">112</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="347" to="382" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">On the evolution of random graphs</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Paul</forename><surname>Erdos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alfréd</forename><surname>Rényi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Publ. Math. Inst. Hungar. Acad. Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="17" to="61" />
			<date type="published" when="1960" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A probabilistic computational model of cross-situational word learning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Afsaneh</forename><surname>Fazly</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Afra</forename><surname>Alishahi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Suzanne</forename><surname>Stevenson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognitive Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">34</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1017" to="1063" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Incremental models of natural language category acquisition</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Trevor</forename><surname>Fountain</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mirella</forename><surname>Lapata</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 32st Annual Conference of the Cognitive Science Society</title>
		<meeting>the 32st Annual Conference of the Cognitive Science Society</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Using speakers referential intentions to model early cross-situational word learning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Michael</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Noah</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Frank</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Joshua</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Goodman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Tenenbaum</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Social and discourse contributions to the determination of reference in cross-situational word learning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Michael</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Joshua</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Frank</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Anne</forename><surname>Tenenbaum</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Fernald</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Language Learning and Development</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="24" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The structural sources of verb meanings</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lila</forename><surname>Gleitman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Language Acquisition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3" to="55" />
			<date type="published" when="1990" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Topics in semantic representation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Thomas</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Griffiths</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mark</forename><surname>Steyvers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Joshua</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Tenenbaum</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">114</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">211</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Building large scale distributed semantic feature sets with WordNet</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michael</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Harm</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>PDP.CNS.02.1</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>Carnegie Mellon University</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
<note type="report_type">Technical Report</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Network small-world-ness: a quantitative method for determining canonical network equivalence</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Mark</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kevin</forename><surname>Humphries</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Gurney</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">PLoS One</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">2051</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Object name learning and object perception: a deficit in late talkers</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Susan</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Jones</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Linda</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Smith</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. of Child Language</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">32</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="223" to="240" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Object properties and knowledge in early lexical learning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Susan</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Jones</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Linda</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Smith</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Barbara</forename><surname>Landau</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Child Development</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">62</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="499" to="516" />
			<date type="published" when="1991" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The CHILDES Project: Tools for Analyzing Talk</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Brian</forename><surname>Macwhinney</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">The Database. Erlbaum</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>3rd edition</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A view of the em algorithm that justifies incremental, sparse, and other variants</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Radford</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Geoffrey</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Neal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Hinton</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Learning in graphical models</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="355" to="368" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Markov chain sampling methods for dirichlet process mixture models</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Radford</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Neal</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of computational and graphical statistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="249" to="265" />
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Interaction of word learning and semantic category formation in late talking</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Aida</forename><surname>Nematzadeh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Afsaneh</forename><surname>Fazly</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Suzanne</forename><surname>Stevenson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of CogSci&apos;12</title>
		<meeting>of CogSci&apos;12</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Structural differences in the semantic networks of simulated word learners</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Aida</forename><surname>Nematzadeh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Afsaneh</forename><surname>Fazly</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Suzanne</forename><surname>Stevenson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Computational Modeling as a Methodology for Studying Human Language Learning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Thierry</forename><surname>Poibeau</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Aline</forename><surname>Villavicencio</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Anna</forename><surname>Korhonen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Afra</forename><surname>Alishahi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Word and Object</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Willard</forename><surname>Van Orman Quine</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1960" />
			<publisher>MIT Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The emergence of words: Attentional learning in form and meaning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Terry</forename><surname>Regier</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognitive Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">29</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="819" to="865" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Small and other worlds: Global network structures from local processes1</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Garry</forename><surname>Robins</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Philippa</forename><surname>Pattison</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jodie</forename><surname>Woolcock</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">American Journal of Sociology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">110</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="894" to="936" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Early noun vocabularies: do ontology, category structure and syntax correspond?</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Larissa</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Samuelson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Linda</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Smith</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">73</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="33" />
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Rational approximations to rational models: alternative algorithms for category learning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Adam</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Sanborn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Thomas</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Griffiths</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Daniel</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Navarro</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A computational study of cross-situational techniques for learning word-tomeaning mappings</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jeffery</forename><forename type="middle">Mark</forename><surname>Siskind</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">61</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="39" to="91" />
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Infants rapidly learn word-referent mappings via cross-situational statistics</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Linda</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Smith</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chen</forename><surname>Yu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">106</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1558" to="1568" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The large-scale structure of semantic networks: Statistical analyses and a model of semantic growth. Cognitive science</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mark</forename><surname>Steyvers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Joshua</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Tenenbaum</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">29</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="41" to="78" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The role of performance limitations in the acquisition of verbargument structure: An alternative account</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Anna</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Theakston</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Elena</forename><forename type="middle">V</forename><surname>Lieven</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Julian</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Pine</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Caroline</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Rowland</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. of Child Language</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">28</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="127" to="152" />
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Collective dynamics of small-worldnetworks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Duncan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Steven</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Watts</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Strogatz</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">nature</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">393</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6684</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="440" to="442" />
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Verbs semantics and lexical selection</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Zhibiao</forename><surname>Wu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Martha</forename><surname>Palmer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 32nd annual meeting on Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the 32nd annual meeting on Association for Computational Linguistics</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1994" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="133" to="138" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Association for Computational Linguistics</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A unified model of early word learning: Integrating statistical and social cues</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chen</forename><surname>Yu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dana</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Ballard</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Selected papers from the 3rd International Conference on Development and Learning</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1315" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">70</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2149" to="2165" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Time series prediction competition: the CATS benchmark</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Rapid word learning under uncertainty via cross-situational statistics</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chen</forename><surname>Yu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Linda</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Smith</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">18</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="414" to="420" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
