<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T10:53+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Better Statistical Machine Translation through Linguistic Treatment of Phrasal Verbs</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
				<availability status="unknown"><p>Copyright Association for Computational Linguistics</p>
				</availability>
				<date>October 25-29, 2014. 2014</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kostadin</forename><surname>Cholakov</surname></persName>
							<email>{kostadin.cholakov,kordonieva}@anglistik.hu-berlin.de</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Humboldt-Universität zu Berlin</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Valia</forename><surname>Kordoni</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Humboldt-Universität zu Berlin</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Better Statistical Machine Translation through Linguistic Treatment of Phrasal Verbs</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2014 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP)</title>
						<meeting>the 2014 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP) <address><addrLine>Doha, Qatar. c</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="196" to="201"/>
							<date type="published">October 25-29, 2014. 2014</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>This article describes a linguistically informed method for integrating phrasal verbs into statistical machine translation (SMT) systems. In a case study involving English to Bulgarian SMT, we show that our method does not only improve translation quality but also outperforms similar methods previously applied to the same task. We attribute this to the fact that, in contrast to previous work on the subject, we employ detailed linguistic information. We found out that features which describe phrasal verbs as idiomatic or composi-tional contribute most to the better translation quality achieved by our method.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Phrasal verbs are a type of multiword expressions (MWEs) and as such, their meaning is not deriv- able, or is only partially derivable, from the se- mantics of their lexemes. This, together with the high frequency of MWEs in every day communi- cation (see <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Jackendoff (1997)</ref>), calls for a special treatment of such expressions in natural language processing (NLP) applications. Here, we con- centrate on statistical machine translation (SMT) where the word-to-word translation of MWEs of- ten results in wrong translations ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Piao et al., 2005)</ref>.</p><p>Previous work has shown that the application of dedicated methods to identify MWEs and then integrate them in some way into the SMT pro- cess often improves translation quality. Gener- ally, automatically extracted lexicons of MWEs are employed in the identification step. Further, various integration strategies have been proposed. The so called static strategy suggests training the SMT system on corpora in which each MWE is treated as a single unit, e.g. call off. This im- proves SMT indirectly by improving the align- ment between source and target sentences in the training data. Various versions of this strategy are applied in <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Lambert and Banchs (2005)</ref>, <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Carpuat and Diab (2010)</ref>, and <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Simova and Kordoni (2013)</ref>. In all cases there is some improvement in transla- tion quality, caused mainly by the better treatment of separable PVs, such as in turn the light on.</p><p>Another strategy, which is referred to as dy- namic, is to modify directly the SMT system. <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Ren et al. (2009)</ref>, for example, treat bilingual MWEs pairs as parallel sentences which are then added to training data and subsequently aligned with GIZA++ ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Och and Ney, 2003)</ref>. Other approaches perform feature mining and modify directly the automatically extracted translation table. <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Ren et al. (2009)</ref> and <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Simova and Kordoni (2013)</ref> employ Moses 1 to build and train phrase-based SMT sys- tems and then, in addition to the standard phrasal translational probabilities, they add a binary fea- ture which indicates whether an MWE is present in a given source phrase or not. <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Carpuat and Diab (2010)</ref> employ the same approach but the additional feature indicates the number of MWEs in each phrase. All studies report improvements over a baseline system with no MWE knowledge but these improvements are comparable to those achieved by static methods.</p><p>In this article, we further improve the dynamic strategy by adding features which, unlike all previ- ous work, also encode some of the linguistic prop- erties of MWEs. Since it is their peculiar linguistic nature that makes those expressions problematic for SMT, it is our thesis that providing more lin- guistic information to the translation process will improve it. In particular, we concentrate on a spe- cific type of MWEs, namely phrasal verbs (PVs). We add 4 binary features to the translation table which indicate not only the presence of a PV but also its transitivity, separability, and idiomaticity. We found that PVs are very suitable for this study since we can easily extract the necessary informa-tion from various language resources.</p><p>To prove our claim, we perform a case study with an English to Bulgarian SMT system. Bul- garian lacks PVs in the same form they appear in English. It is often the case that an English PV is translated to a single Bulgarian verb. Such many- to-one mappings cause the so called translation asymmetries which make the translation of PVs very problematic.</p><p>We perform automated and manual evaluations with a number of feature combinations which show that the addition of all 4 features proposed above improves translation quality significantly. Moreover, our method outperforms static and dy- namic methods previously applied to the same test data. A notable increase in performance is ob- served for separable PVs where the verb and the particle(s) were not adjacent in the input English sentence as well as for idiomatic PVs. This clearly demonstrates the importance of linguistic informa- tion for the proper treatment of PVs in SMT.</p><p>We would like to point out that we view the work presented here as a preliminary study towards a more general linguistically informed method for handling similar types of translation asymmetries. The experiments with a single phe- nomenon, namely PVs, serve as a case study the purpose of which is to demonstrate the validity of our approach and the crucial role of properly inte- grated linguistic information into SMT. Our work, however, can be immediately extended to other phenomena, such as collocations and noun com- pounds.</p><p>The remainder of the paper is organised as fol- lows. Section 2 describes the asymmetries caused by PVs in English to Bulgarian translation. Sec- tion 3 provides details about the resources in- volved in the experiments. Section 4 describes our method and the experimental setup. Sec- tion 5 presents the results and discusses the im- provements in translation quality achieved by the method. Sections 6 concludes the paper.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Translation Asymmetries</head><p>We will first illustrate the main issues which arise when translating English PVs into Bulgarian. For more convenience, the Bulgarian phrases are tran- scribed with Latin letters.</p><p>An English PV is usually mapped to a single Bulgarian verb:</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">(1) Toj he otmeni cancelled sreshtata.</formula><p>meeting-the 'He called off the meeting.'</p><p>In the example above the PV called off has to be mapped to the single Bulgarian verb otmeni, i.e. there is many-to-one mapping. Other cases require a many-to-many type of mapping. One such case is the mapping of an English PV to a 'da'-construction in Bulgarian. Such construc- tions are very frequent in Bulgarian every day communication since they denote complex verb tenses, modal verb constructions, and subordinat- ing conjunctions: Here, da skasa should be mapped to the PV break off. Other such cases include Bulgarian reflexive verb constructions.</p><p>Note that such many-to-many mappings in the case of Bulgarian pose an additional challenge for the SMT system because, for a good translation, it needs to guess whether to add a 'da' particle or not which further complicates the treatment of PVs. Also, Bulgarian is a language with rich morphol- ogy and often translations with very good seman- tic quality lack the proper morphological inflec- tion. This affects negatively both automated and manual evaluation of translation quality.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Language Resources</head><p>We employ the data used in the studies reported in <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Simova and Kordoni (2013)</ref>. The authors experi- mented with both static and dynamic methods for handling PVs in an English to Bulgarian SMT sys- tem. This allows us to compare the performance of our linguistically informed approach to that of methods which do not make use of the linguistic properties of PVs.</p><p>The data for the experiments are derived from the SeTimes news corpus 2 which contains par- allel news articles in English and 9 Balkan lan- guages. The training data consist of approximately 151,000 sentences. Another 2,000 sentences are used for the tuning. The test set consists of 800 sentences, 400 of which contain one or more in-stances of PVs. There are 138 unique PVs with a total of 403 instances in the test data. Further, a language model for the target language is created based on a 50 million words subset of the Bul- garian National Reference Corpus. 3 All English data are POS tagged and lemmatised using the TreeTagger ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Schmid, 1994)</ref>. For Bulgarian, these tasks were performed with the BTB-LPP tagger <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">(Savkov et al., 2011</ref> <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Fellbaum, 1998)</ref>, the COMLEX Syntax dictio- nary ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Macleod et al., 1998)</ref>, and the gold standard data used for the experiments in <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">McCarthy et al. (2003)</ref> and <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Baldwin (2008)</ref>. English PVs are iden- tified in the data using the jMWE library ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Kulkarni and Finlayson, 2011</ref>) as well as a post-processing module implemented in the form of a constrained grammar ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Karlsson et al., 1995</ref>) which filters out spurious PV candidates. For the identification of PVs, <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Simova and Kordoni (2013)</ref> report 91% pre- cision (375 correct instances found) and a recall score of 93% for the 800 test sentences.</p><note type="other">). Simova and Kordoni (2013) create automati- cally a lexicon containing English PVs. It is em- ployed for the identification of such verbs in the data used in the experiments. The lexicon is con- structed from a number of resources: the En- glish Phrasal Verbs section of Wiktionary, 4 the Phrasal Verb Demon dictionary, 5 the CELEX Lex- ical Database (Baayen et al., 1995), WordNet (</note><p>The Moses toolkit is employed to build a fac- tored phrase-based translation model which op- erates on lemmas and POS tags. Given the rich Bulgarian morphology, the use of lemma informa- tion instead of surface word forms allows for a better mapping between source and target transla- tion equivalents. The parallel data are aligned with GIZA++. Further, 2 5-gram language models are built using the SRILM toolkit 6 on the monolingual Bulgarian data to model lemma and POS n-gram information. Note that the Bulgarian POS tags are quite complex, so they can account for a variety of morphological phenomena. Automated trans- lation is performed by mapping English lemmas and POS tags to their Bulgarian equivalents and then generating the proper Bulgarian word form by using lemma and POS tag information.  <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">1 PV present  no PV  feature 2 transitive  intransitive  feature 3 separable  inseparable  feature 4</ref> idiomatic (semi-)comp. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Addition of Linguistic Features</head><p>The resources from which the PV lexicon is con- structed also contain various types of linguistic in- formation. Wiktionary provides the most details since the entries there contain information about the valency of the verb (transitive vs intransitive) and whether a particle can be separated from the PV in particle verb constructions. Consider fell off his bike and *fell his bike off vs turn the engine on and turn on the engine.</p><p>Further, Wiktionary indicates whether a given PV is compositional or idiomatic in nature. The meaning of (semi-)compositional PVs can be (par- tially) derived from the meaning of their lexemes, e.g. carry in. The degree of compositionality af- fects the productivity with which verbs and parti- cles combine. Verbs with similar semantics often combine with the same particle, e.g. bring/carry in. This is not the case for fully idiomatic PVs, e.g. get/*obtain over. Therefore, the notion of compo- sitionality plays a very important role in the treat- ment of PVs and MWEs in general. The dataset described in <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">McCarthy et al. (2003)</ref> also indicates whether a PV is idiomatic or not.</p><p>We were able to acquire the PV lexicon and we augmented it with the information obtained from the various resources. Then, once the sys- tem is trained, we add 4 binary features to each entry in the automatically created translation table. The values those features take are shown in <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table  1</ref>. If a given property is not specified for some PV in the lexicon, the value of the corresponding feature is 0. Naturally, if no PV is identified in a source phrase, the value of all 4 features is 0. This is different from previous work where only one feature is added, indicating the presence of a PV. By adding those new features, we want to bias the SMT system towards using phrases that do not "split" PVs during decoding.  <ref type="table">Table 2</ref>: Automatic evaluation of translation qual- ity.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Results and Discussion</head><p>Automatic Evaluation. <ref type="table">Table 2</ref> presents the re- sults from the automatic evaluation, in terms of BLEU ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Papineni et al., 2002</ref>) and NIST <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Doddington, 2002</ref>) scores, of 4 system setups. The base- line has no MWE knowledge, while the static and the dynamic-1 system setups are reproduced from the experiments described in <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Simova and Kordoni (2013)</ref>. Dynamic-1 includes only a single binary feature which indicates the presence of a PV while our method, dynamic-4, includes the 4 features de- scribed in <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table 1</ref>.</p><p>Our method outperforms all other setups in terms of BLEU score, thus proving our point that adding features describing the linguistic properties of PVs improves SMT even further. Also, the re- sults for the 400 sentences without PVs show that the 4 new features do not have a negative impact for PV-free contexts.</p><p>In terms of NIST the static strategy consistently performs best, followed closely by our method. NIST is a measure which weights the translated n-grams according to their informativeness. Due to the nature of this measure, less frequent cor- rectly translated n-grams are given more weight in the evaluation process because NIST considers them "more informative". Such less frequent n- grams, or in our case PVs, are likely to be cap- tured better by the static setup. Therefore, this setup achieves the highest NIST scores. This fact also suggests that dynamic and static strategies in- fluence the SMT process in different ways, with our method tending to capture more frequent (and thus less informative) n-grams. Interestingly, the other dynamic method, dynamic-1, has the worst performance of all setups in terms of NIST.</p><p>Manual evaluation. To get a better insight on how the different setups deal with the translation of PVs, we also performed a manual evaluation. A native speaker of Bulgarian was asked to judge the translations of PVs for the 375 test sentences in good acceptable incorrect baseline 0.21 0.41 0.38 static 0.25 0.5 0.25 dynamic-1 0.24 0.51 0.25 dynamic-4 0.3 0.5 0.2 <ref type="table">Table 3</ref>: Manual evaluation of translation quality.</p><p>which such verbs were correctly identified during the identification step. The human subject takes into account the target PV and a limited context around it and judges the translation as:</p><p>• good -correct translation of the PV, correct verb inflection</p><p>• acceptable -correct translation of the PV but wrong inflection, or wrongly built da-or re- flexive construction</p><p>• incorrect -wrong translation which changes the meaning of the sentence <ref type="table">Table 3</ref> shows the results. Our method dynamic- 4 produces more good translations and less incor- rect ones than all other setups. This illustrates fur- ther the benefits of adding linguistic features to the translation model. The results achieved by the static approach are attributed to the better handling of separable PVs in sentences where the particle was not adjacent to the verb. The dynamic-1 ap- proach and the baseline often interpret the particle literally in such cases which leads to almost twice the amount of wrong translations. Our method, on the other hand, performs slightly lower than the static approach in this respect but still much better than the other 2 setups. Compared to dynamic-1 and the baseline, the static approach also handles better idiomatic PVs but performs slightly worse for sentences with compositional PVs. However, the addition of a specific feature to encode idiomaticity in the trans- lation model enables our method dynamic-4 to achieve the best performance for idiomatic PVs while still handling successfully many composi- tional PVs. To summarise, the improved results of our method in comparison to previous work are attributed to the better handling of separable PVs which occur in a split form and even more to the improved ability to differentiate between compo- sitional and idiomatic PVs.</p><p>Feature combinations. Our method performs best when all 3 linguistic features described above are taken into account by the SMT system. How- ever, we also experimented with different combi- nations of those features in order to get some in- sight of the way each feature influences the trans- lation quality. Adding only the feature denot- ing verb transitiveness did not lead to any sig- nificant improvement compared to the dynamic- 1 setup. Also, the combination which leaves out this feature and uses the remaining ones ranks second, achieving only a slightly worse perfor- mance than dynamic-4, the setup in which all fea- tures are employed. It seems that the transitive- ness feature does not contribute much to the task at hand. Adding only the feature denoting sepa- rable vs inseparable PVs and adding only the one denoting idiomaticity led to results slightly higher than those of the dynamic-1 and static setups but still, those results were significantly lower than the ones presented in <ref type="table">Tables 2 and 3</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Conclusion and Outlook</head><p>In this article, we showed that the addition of lin- guistically informative features to a phrase-based SMT model improves the translation quality of a particular type of MWEs, namely phrasal verbs. In a case study involving SMT from English to Bulgarian, we showed that adding features which encode not only the presence of a PV in a given phrase but also its transitiveness, separability, and idiomaticity led to better translation quality com- pared to previous work which employs both static and dynamic strategies.</p><p>In future research, we will extend our method to other language pairs which exhibit the same type of translation asymmetries when it comes to PVs. Such language pairs include, among others, English-Spanish and English-Portuguese.</p><p>Further, we will apply our linguistically in- formed method to other phenomena which cause similar issues for SMT. Immediate candidate phe- nomena include other types of MWEs, colloca- tions, and noun compounds. When it comes to MWEs, we will pay special attention to the com- positionality aspect since it seems to have con- tributed most to the good performance achieve by our method in the study presented here.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>He should break off with her.'</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" validated="false"><head>Table 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Values for the 4 new features. 

</table></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> http://www.statmt.org/moses/</note>

			<note place="foot" n="2"> http://www.setimes.com</note>

			<note place="foot" n="3"> http://webclark.org/ 4 http://en.wiktionary.org/wiki/ Category:English\_phrasal\_verbs 5 http://www.phrasalverbdemon.com/ 6 http://www-speech.sri.com/projects/ srilm/</note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>H Baayen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Piepenbrock</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Gulikers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">The CELEX lexical database (CD-ROM)</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A resource for evaluating the deep lexical acquisition of english verb-particle constructions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Timothy</forename><surname>Baldwin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the LREC 2008 Workshop: Towards a Shared Task for Multiword Expressions</title>
		<meeting>the LREC 2008 Workshop: Towards a Shared Task for Multiword Expressions<address><addrLine>Marakesh, Morocco</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="2" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Task-based evaluation of multiword expressions: a pilot study in statistical machine translation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marine</forename><surname>Carpuat</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mona</forename><surname>Diab</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Human Language Technologies: The 2010 Annual Conference of the North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics., HLT &apos;10</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Stroudsburg, PA, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="242" to="245" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Automatic evaluation of machine translation quality using n-gram cooccurrence statistics</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">George</forename><surname>Doddington</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the second international conference on Human Language Technology Research</title>
		<meeting>the second international conference on Human Language Technology Research<address><addrLine>San Francisco, CA, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="138" to="145" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">WordNet: An electronic lexical database</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christiane</forename><surname>Fellbaum</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
			<publisher>The MIT press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The Architecture of the Language Faculty</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ray</forename><surname>Jackendoff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
			<publisher>MIT Press</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Cambridge, MA</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Constraint grammar: A language-independent system for parsing unrestricted text</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Fred</forename><surname>Karlsson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Atro</forename><surname>Voutilainen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Juha</forename><surname>Heikkila</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Arto</forename><surname>Anttila</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Natural Language Processing</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
			<biblScope unit="page">4</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">JMWE-a Java toolkit for detecting multiword expressions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nidhi</forename><surname>Kulkarni</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mark</forename><forename type="middle">Alan</forename><surname>Finlayson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2011 Workshop on Multiword Expressions</title>
		<meeting>the 2011 Workshop on Multiword Expressions</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="122" to="124" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Data inferred multi-word expressions for statistical machine translation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Patrik</forename><surname>Lambert</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rafael</forename><surname>Banchs</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the X Machine Translation Summit</title>
		<meeting>the X Machine Translation Summit</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="396" to="403" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">COMLEX Syntax Reference Manual</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Catherine</forename><surname>Macleod</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Adam</forename><surname>Meyers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ralph</forename><surname>Grishman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
			<pubPlace>New York University</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Detecting a continuum of compositionality in phrasal verbs</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Diana</forename><surname>Mccarthy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">John</forename><surname>Keller</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Carroll</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the ACL 2003 Workshop on Multiword Expressions: analysis, acquisition and treatment</title>
		<meeting>the ACL 2003 Workshop on Multiword Expressions: analysis, acquisition and treatment<address><addrLine>Sapporo, Japan</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A systematic comparison of various statistical alignment models</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Josef</forename><surname>Franz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hermann</forename><surname>Och</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Ney</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Computational Linguistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">29</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="19" to="51" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">BLEU: A method for automatic evaluation of machine translation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kishore</forename><surname>Papineni</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Salim</forename><surname>Roukos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Todd</forename><surname>Ward</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Weijing</forename><surname>Zhu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 40th Annual Meeting on Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the 40th Annual Meeting on Association for Computational Linguistics<address><addrLine>Stroudsburg, PA, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="311" to="318" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Comparing and combining a semantic tagger and a statistical tool for MWE extraction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Paul</forename><surname>Scott Songlin Piao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tony Mcenery Dawn</forename><surname>Rayson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Archer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Comuter Speech and Language</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="378" to="397" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Improving statistical machine translation using domain bilingual multiword expressions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yajuan</forename><surname>Zhixiang Ren</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jie</forename><surname>Lu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Qun</forename><surname>Cao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yun</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the ACL Workshop on Multiword Expressions: Identification, Interpretation, Disambiguation and Applications</title>
		<meeting>the ACL Workshop on Multiword Expressions: Identification, Interpretation, Disambiguation and Applications<address><addrLine>Singapore</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="47" to="54" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A web-based morphological tagger for Bulgarian</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Aleksandar</forename><surname>Savkov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Laska</forename><surname>Laskova</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Petya</forename><surname>Osenova</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kiril</forename><surname>Simov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Stanislava</forename><surname>Kancheva</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Sixth International Conference on Natural Language Processing, Multilinguality</title>
		<meeting>the Sixth International Conference on Natural Language Processing, Multilinguality<address><addrLine>Bratislava, Slovakia</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="126" to="137" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Probabilistic part-of-speech tagging using decision trees</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Helmut</forename><surname>Schmid</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the International Conference on New Methods in Language Processing</title>
		<meeting>the International Conference on New Methods in Language Processing<address><addrLine>Manchester, UK</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1994" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Improving English-Bulgarian statistical machine translation by phrasal verb treatment</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Iliana</forename><surname>Simova</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Valia</forename><surname>Kordoni</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of MT Summit XIV Workshop on Multi-word Units in Machine Translation and Translation Technology</title>
		<meeting>MT Summit XIV Workshop on Multi-word Units in Machine Translation and Translation Technology<address><addrLine>Nice, France</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
