<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T10:46+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Morpho-syntactic Lexical Generalization for CCG Semantic Parsing</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date>October 25-29, 2014</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Adrienne</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
							<email>axwang@cs.washington.edu</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tom</forename><surname>Kwiatkowski</surname></persName>
							<email>tomk@allenai.org</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Luke</forename><surname>Zettlemoyer</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Computer Science &amp; Engineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Computer Science &amp; Engineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">University of Washington Seattle</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">Allen Institute for AI</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Seattle</settlement>
									<region>WA, WA</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">University of Washington</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Seattle</settlement>
									<region>WA</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Morpho-syntactic Lexical Generalization for CCG Semantic Parsing</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2014 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP)</title>
						<meeting>the 2014 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP) <address><addrLine>Doha, Qatar. c</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="1284" to="1295"/>
							<date type="published">October 25-29, 2014</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>In this paper, we demonstrate that significant performance gains can be achieved in CCG semantic parsing by introducing a linguistically motivated grammar induction scheme. We present a new morpho-syntactic fac-tored lexicon that models systematic variations in morphology, syntax, and semantics across word classes. The grammar uses domain-independent facts about the English language to restrict the number of incorrect parses that must be considered, thereby enabling effective learning from less data. Experiments in benchmark domains match previous models with one quarter of the data and provide new state-of-the-art results with all available data, including up to 45% relative test-error reduction.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Semantic parsers map sentences to formal representations of their meaning <ref type="bibr">(Zelle and Mooney, 1996;</ref><ref type="bibr">Zettlemoyer and Collins, 2005;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b27">Liang et al., 2011)</ref>. One common approach is to induce a probabilistic CCG grammar, which defines the meanings of individual words and phrases and how to best combine them to an- alyze complete sentences. There has been re- cent work developing learning algorithms for CCG semantic parsers ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Kwiatkowski et al., 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Artzi and Zettlemoyer, 2011</ref>) and using them for applications ranging from question answering <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(Cai and Yates, 2013b;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Kwiatkowski et al., 2013</ref>) to robot control ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">Matuszek et al., 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Krishnamurthy and Kollar, 2013)</ref>.</p><p>One key learning challenge for this style of learning is to induce the CCG lexicon, which lists possible meanings for each phrase and defines a set of possible parses for each sentence.</p><p>Previous approaches have either hand-engineered a small set of lexi- cal templates <ref type="bibr">Collins, 2005, 2007)</ref> or automatically learned such tem- plates ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Kwiatkowski et al., 2010</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b25">Kwiatkowski et al., , 2011</ref>). These methods are designed to learn grammars that overgenerate; they produce spurious parses that can complicate parameter estimation.</p><p>In this paper, we demonstrate that signif- icant gains can instead be achieved by using a more constrained, linguistically motivated grammar induction scheme. The grammar is restricted by introducing detailed syntac- tic modeling of a wider range of constructions than considered in previous work, for example introducing explicit treatments of relational nouns, Davidsonian events, and verb tense. We also introduce a new lexical generalization model that abstracts over systematic morpho- logical, syntactic, and semantic alternations within word classes. This includes, for exam- ple, the facts that verbs in relative clauses and nominal constructions (e.g., "flights departing NYC" and "departing flights") should be in- finitival while verbs in phrases (e.g., "What flights depart at noon?") should have tense. These grammar modeling techniques use uni- versal, domain-independent facts about the English language to restrict word usage to ap- propriate syntactic contexts, and as such are potentially applicable to any semantic parsing application.</p><p>More specifically, we introduce a new morpho-syntactic, factored CCG lexicon that imposes our grammar restrictions during learning. Each lexical entry has (1) a word stem, automatically constructed from Wik- tionary, with part-of-speech and morpholog- ical attributes, (2) a lexeme that is learned and pairs the stem with semantic content that is invariant to syntactic usage, and (3) a lexi- cal template that specifies the remaining syn- tactic and semantic content. The full set of templates is defined in terms of a small set of base templates and template transformations that model morphological variants such as pas- sivization and nominalization of verbs. This approach allows us to efficiently encode a gen- eral grammar for semantic parsing while also eliminating large classes of incorrect analyses considered by previous work.</p><p>We perform experiments in two benchmark semantic parsing datasets: GeoQuery (Zelle and Mooney, 1996) and ATIS ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Dahl et al., 1994)</ref>.</p><p>In both cases, our approach achieves state-of-the-art performance, includ- ing a nearly 45% relative error reduction on the ATIS test set. We also show that the gains increase with less data, including matching previous model's performance with less than 25% of the training data. Such gains are par- ticularly practical for semantic parsers; they can greatly reduce the amount of data that is needed for each new application domain.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Related Work</head><p>Grammar induction methods for CCG seman- tic parsers have either used hand-engineered lexical templates, e.g. ( <ref type="bibr">Collins, 2005, 2007;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Artzi and Zettlemoyer, 2011)</ref>, or algorithms to learn such templates directly from data, e.g. ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Kwiatkowski et al., 2010</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b25">Kwiatkowski et al., , 2011</ref>). Here, we extend the first ap- proach, and show that better lexical general- ization provides significant performance gains.</p><p>Although CCG is a common choice for semantic parsers, many other for- malisms have been studied, including DCS trees ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">Liang et al., 2011</ref>), integer linear pro- grams ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Clarke et al., 2010)</ref>, and synchronous grammars ( <ref type="bibr">Wong and Mooney, 2007;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b18">Jones et al., 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Andreas et al., 2013</ref>). All of these approaches build complete meaning represen- tations for individual sentences, but the data we use has also been studied in related work on cross-sentence reasoning <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">(Miller et al., 1996;</ref><ref type="bibr">Zettlemoyer and Collins, 2009)</ref> and model- ing semantic interpretation as a tagging prob- lem ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Tur et al., 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Heck et al., 2013)</ref>. Al- though we focus on full analysis with CCG, the general idea of using linguistic constraints to improve learning is broadly applicable.</p><p>Semantic parsers are also commonly learned from a variety of different types of supervision, including logical forms ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">Kate and Mooney, 2006;</ref><ref type="bibr">Wong and Mooney, 2007;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b30">Muresan, 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b23">Kwiatkowski et al., 2012)</ref>, question- answer pairs <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Clarke et al., 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b27">Liang et al., 2011</ref>), conversational logs (Artzi and Zettle- moyer, 2011), distant supervision <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">(Krishnamurthy and Mitchell, 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Cai and Yates, 2013b)</ref>, sentences paired with system behav- ior ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Goldwasser and Roth, 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Chen and Mooney, 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Artzi and Zettlemoyer, 2013b)</ref>, and even from database constraints with no explicit semantic supervision <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">(Poon, 2013)</ref>. We learn from logical forms, but CCG learn- ing algorithms have been developed for each case above, making our techniques applicable.</p><p>There has been significant related work that influenced the design of our morpho-syntactic grammars. This includes linguistics stud- ies of relational nouns <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">(Partee and Borschev, 1998;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b13">de Bruin and Scha, 1988)</ref>, Davidsonian events <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Davidson, 1967)</ref>, parsing as abduc- tion ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Hobbs et al., 1988)</ref>, and other more gen- eral theories for lexicons <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">(Pustejovsky, 1991)</ref> and CCG <ref type="bibr" target="#b36">(Steedman, 2011)</ref>. It also includes work on using morphology in CCG syntac- tic parsing <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">(Honnibal et al., 2010</ref>) and more broad-coverage semantics in CCG <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Bos, 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b26">Lewis and Steedman, 2013)</ref>. However, our work is unique in studying the use of related ideas for semantic parsing.</p><p>Finally, there has also been recent progress on semantic parsing against large, open do- main databases such as Freebase <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Cai and Yates, 2013a;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Kwiatkowski et al., 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Berant et al., 2013)</ref>. Unfortuantely, existing Freebase datasets are not a good fit to test our approach because the sentences they include have rela- tively simple structure and can be interepreted accurately using only factoid lookups with no database joins <ref type="bibr">(Yao and Van Durme, 2014</ref>). Our work focuses on learning more syntacti- cally rich models that support compositional reasoning.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Background</head><p>Lambda Calculus We represent the mean- ings of sentences, words and phrases with list one way flights from various cities lambda calculus logical expressions. We use a version of the typed lambda calculus <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Carpenter, 1997</ref>), in which the basic types include en- tities, events, truth values and numbers. Func- tion types are assigned to lambda expressions. The expression λx.f light(x) with type e, t takes an entity and returns a truth value, and represents a set of flights.</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">S/N N/N N P P/N P N P/N N λf.f λf λx.oneway(x) ∧ f (x) λx.f light(x) λxλy.f rom(y, x) λf Ax.f (x) λx.city(x) &gt; N P Ax.city(x) &gt; P P λx.f rom(x, Ay.city(y)) &gt;T N \N λx.f rom(x, Ay.city(y)) &lt; N λx.f light(x) ∧ f rom(x, Ay.city(y)) &gt; N λx.f light(x) ∧ f rom(x, Ay.city(y)) ∧ oneway(x) &gt; S λx.f light(x) ∧ f rom(x, Ay.city(y)) ∧ oneway(x)</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Combinatory</head><p>Categorial Grammar CCG <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">(Steedman, 1996</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b35">(Steedman, , 2000</ref>) is a formalism that tightly couples syntax and semantics, and can be used to model a wide range of linguistic phenomena. A traditional CCG grammar includes a lexicon Λ with lexical entries like the following: where a lexical item w X : h has words w, syntactic category X, and logical expression h.</p><p>CCG uses a small set of combinatory rules to jointly build syntactic parses and semantic representations. Two common combinatory rules are forward (&gt;) and backward (&lt;) application:</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">X/Y : f Y : g ⇒ X : f (g) (&gt;) Y : g X\Y : f ⇒ X : f (g) (&lt;)</formula><p>CCG also includes combinatory rules of for- ward (&gt; B) and backward (&lt; B) composition:</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">X/Y : f Y /Z : g ⇒ X/Z : λx.f (g(x)) (&gt; B) Y \Z : g X\Y : f ⇒ X\Z : λx.f (g(x)) (&lt; B)</formula><p>These rules apply to build syntactic and se- mantic derivations concurrently.</p><p>In this paper, we also implement type raising rules for compact representation of P P (prepositional phrase) and AP (adverbial phrase).</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">P P : g ⇒ N \N : λf λx.f (x) ∧ g(x) (T) AP : g ⇒ S\S : λf λe.f (e) ∧ g(e) (T) AP : g ⇒ S/S : λf λe.f (e) ∧ g(e)</formula><p>(T) <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref> shows an example CCG parse <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">(Steedman, 1996</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b35">(Steedman, , 2000</ref>) where the lexical entries are listed across the top and the output lambda-calculus meaning repre- sentation is at the bottom. This meaning is a function (denoted by λx...) that defines a set of flights with certain properties and includes a generalized Skolem constant (Steedman, 2011) (Ay...) that performs existential quan- tification. Following recent work (Artzi and Zettlemoyer, 2013b), we use meaning repre- sentations that model a variety of linguistic constructions, for example including Skolem constants for plurals and Davidson quantifiers for events, which we will introduce briefly throughout this paper as they appear.</p><p>Weighted CCGs A weighted CCG gram- mar is defined as G = (Λ, Θ), where Λ is a CCG lexicon and Θ ∈ R d is a d-dimensional parameter vector, which will be used to rank the parses allowed under Λ.</p><p>For a sentence x, G produces a set of candi-date parse trees Y = Y(x; G). Given a feature vector Φ ∈ R d , each parse tree y for sentence x is scored by S(y; Θ) = θ ·φ(x, y). The output logical formˆzformˆ formˆz is then defined to be at the root of the highest-scoring parsê y:</p><formula xml:id="formula_4">ˆ y = arg max y∈Y(x;G) S(y; Θ)<label>(1)</label></formula><p>We use existing CKY-style parsing algo- rithms for this computation, implemented with UW SPF (Artzi and Zettlemoyer, 2013a). Section 7 describes the set of features we use in the learned models.</p><p>Learning with GENLEX We will also make use of an existing learning algo- rithm <ref type="bibr">(Zettlemoyer and Collins, 2007</ref>) (ZC07). We first briefly review the ZC07 algorithm, and describe our modifications in Section 7.</p><p>Given a set of training examples D = {(x i , z i ) : i = 1...n}, x i being the ith sentence and z i being its annotated logical form, the al- gorithm learns a set of parameters Θ for the grammar, while also inducing the lexicon Λ.</p><p>The ZC07 learning algorithm uses a function GENLEX(x, z) to define a set of lexical entries that could be used to parse the sentence x to construct the logical form z. For each training example (x, z), GENLEX(x, z) maps all sub- strings x to a set of potential lexical entries, generated by exhaustively pairing the logical constants in z using a set of hand-engineered templates. The example is then parsed with this much bigger lexicon and lexical entries from the highest scoring parses are added to Λ. The parameters Θ used to score parses are up- dated using a perceptron learning algorithm.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Morpho-Syntactic Lexicon</head><p>This section defines our morpho-syntactic lex- ical formalism. <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">Table 1</ref> shows examples of how lexemes, templates, and morphological trans- formations are used to build lexical entries for example verbs. In this section, we formally de- fine each of these components and show how they are used to specify the space of possible lexical entries that can be built for each input word. In the following two sections, we will provide more discussion of the complete sets of templates (Section 5) and transformations (Section 6).  We build on the factored CCG lexicon in- troduced by <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">Kwiatkowski et al. (2011)</ref> but (a) further generalize lexemes to represent word stems, (b) constrain the use of templates with widely available syntactic information, and (c) efficiently model common morphological vari- ations between related words.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Verb, Noun, Preposition, Pronoun, Adjective, Adverb, Conjunction, Numeral, Symbol, Proper Noun, Interjection, Expression</head><p>The first step, given an input word w, is to do morphological and part-of-speech analy- sis with the morpho-syntactic function F . F maps a word to a set of possible morpho- syntactic representations, each containing a triple (s, p, m) of word stem s, part-of-speech p and morphological category m. For exam- ple, F maps the word f lies to two possible representations:</p><formula xml:id="formula_5">F (f lies) = {(f ly, Noun, (plural)),</formula><p>(f ly, Verb, (third, singular, simple, present))} for the plural noun and present-tense verb senses of the word. F is defined based on the stems, part-of-speech types, and morpholog- ical attributes marked for each definition in Wiktionary. 1 The full sets of possible part-of- speech and morphological types required for our domains are shown in <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table 2 and Table 3</ref>.</p><p>Each morpho-syntactic analysis a ∈ F (w) is then paired with lexemes based on stem match. A lexeme (s, c) pairs a word stem s with a list of logical constants c = [c 1 . . . c k ]. <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">Table 1</ref> shows the words 'depart', 'departing', 'departure', which are all assigned the lex- eme (depart, <ref type="bibr">[depart]</ref>). In general, there can Trans Lexical entry depart (depart, <ref type="bibr">[depart]</ref>) : I depart S\N P : λxλe.depart(e, x) departing I departing S\N P : λxλe.depart(e, x) departing ξ S\N P : λxλe.v1(e, x) fpres departing P P : λxλe.depart(e, x) departure fnom departure N : λxλe.depart(e, x) use (use, <ref type="bibr">[airline]</ref>) : I use S\N P/N P : λxλyλe.airline(e, y, x) using I using S\N P/N P : λxλyλe.airline(e, y, x) using ξ S\N P/N P : λxλyλe.v1(e, y, x) fpres using P P/N P : λxλe.airline(e, y, x) use fnom use N/N P : λxλyλe.airline(e, y, x) Trans Template Transformation fpres ξ S\N P/T : λx1..xnλe.v(e, xn..x1) → ξ P P/T : λx1..xnλe.v(e, xn..x1) fnom ξ S\N P/T : λx1..xnλe.v(e, xn..x1) → ξ N/T : λx1..xnλe.v(e, xn..x1) be many different lexemes for each stem, that vary in the selection of which logical constants are included. Given analysis (s, p, m) and lexeme (s, c), we can use a lexical template to construct a lexical entry. Each template has the form:</p><formula xml:id="formula_6">λ(ξ, v).[ξ X : h v ]</formula><p>where ξ and v are variables that abstract over the words and logical constants that will be used to define a lexical entry with syntax X and templated logical form h v .</p><p>To instantiate a template, ξ is filled with the original word w and the constants in c replace the variables v. For example, the template λ(ξ, v).[ξ S\N P : λxλe.v 1 (e, x)] could be used with the word 'departing' and the lexeme (depart, <ref type="bibr">[depart]</ref>) to produce the lexical entry departing S\N P : λxλe.depart(e, x). When clear from context, we will omit the function signature λ p (ξ, v). for all templates, as seen in <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">Table 1</ref>.</p><p>In general, there can be many applicable templates, which we organize as follows. Each final template is defined by applying a mor- phological transformation to one of a small set of possible base templates. The pairing is found based on the morphological analysis (s, p, m), where each base template is associ- ated with part-of-speech p and each transfor- mation is indexed by the morphology m. A transformation f m is a function:</p><formula xml:id="formula_7">f m (λ p (ξ, v).[ξ X : h v ]) = λ p (ξ, v).[ξ X : h v ]</formula><p>that takes the base template as input and pro- duces a new template to model the inflected form specified by m.</p><p>For example, both base templates in Ta- ble 1 are for verbs. The template ξ S\N P : λxλe.v 1 (e, x) can be translated into three other templates based on the transfor- mations I, f pres , and f nom , depending on the analysis of the original words. These transfor- mations generalize across word type; they can be used for the transitive verb 'use' as well as the intransitive 'depart.' Each resulting tem- plate, potentially including the original input if the identity transformation I is available, can then be used to make an output lexical entry, as we described above.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Lexical Templates</head><p>The templates in our lexicon, as introduced in Section 4, model the syntactic and seman- tic aspects of lexical entries that are shared within each word class. Previous approaches have also used hand-engineered lexical tem- plates, as described in Section 2, but we dif- fer by (1) using more templates allowing for more fine grained analysis and (2) using word class information to restrict template use, for example ensuring that words which cannot be verbs are never paired with templates designed for verbs. This section describes the templates used during learning, first presenting those de- signed to model grammatical sentences and then a small second set designed for more el- liptical spoken utterances. <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">Table 4</ref> lists the primary tem- plate set, where each row shows an example with a sentence illustrating its use. Templates are also grouped by the word classes, including adjectives, adverbs, prepositions, and several types of nouns and verbs. While there is not enough space to discuss each row, it is worth</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Base Forms</head><note type="other">word class example usage base template Noun phrase Boston ξ N P : v Noun (regular)</note><p>What flight is provided by delta? ξ N : λx.v(x) Noun (relation) I need fares of flights ξ N/P P : λxλy.v(x, y) delta schedule ξ N \(N/N ) : λf λx.v(Ay.f (λz.true, y), x) Noun (function) size of California ξ N P/N P : λx.v(</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>x) Vintrans</head><p>What flights depart from New York? ξ S\N P : λxλe.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>v(e, x) Vtrans</head><p>Which airlines serve Seattle (active verb) ξ S\N P/N P : λxλyλe.v(e, y, x) What airlines have flights (passive verb) ξ S\N P/N P : λxλyλe.v(e, x, y) V ditrans</p><p>They give him a book ξ S\N P/N P/N P : λxλyλzλe.v(e, z, y,</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>x) Vimperson</head><p>It costs $500 to fly to Boston ξ S\N P/N P/N P : λxλyλzλe.v(e, y,</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>x) Vaux</head><p>The flights have arrived at Boston ξ S\N P/(S\N P ) : λf.f ξ S/N P/(S/N P ) : λf.f Does delta provide flights from Seattle? ξ S/S : λf.f V copula</p><p>The flights are from Boston ξ S\N P/P P : λf λx.f (x) What flight is cheap?</p><p>ξ S\N P/(N/N ) : λf λx.f (λy.true, x) Alaska is the state with the most rivers ξ S\N P/N P : λxλy.equals(y, x) Adjective I need a one way flight ξ N/N :</p><formula xml:id="formula_8">λf λx.f (x) ∧ v(x) Boston flights round trip ξ P P : λx.v(x) How long is mississippi? ξ DEG : λx.v(x) Preposition</formula><p>List flights from Boston ξ P P/N P : λxλy.v(y, x) List flights that go to Dallas ξ AP/N P : λxλe.v(e, x) List flights between Dallas and Boston ξ P P/N P/N P : λxλyλz.v1(z, x) ∧ v2(z, y) What flights leave between 8am and 9am? ξ AP/N P/N P : λxλyλe.v1(e, x) ∧ v2(e, y) Adverb Which flight departs daily? ξ AP : λe.v(e) How early does the flight arrive?</p><formula xml:id="formula_9">ξ DEG : λx.v(x) Determiner</formula><p>Which airline has a flight from Boston?   We model nouns as denoting a set of entities that satisfy a given property. Regular nouns are represented using unary predicates. Rela- tional nouns syntactically function as regular nouns but semantically describe sets of enti- ties that have some relationship with a comple- ment ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">Partee and Borschev, 1998</ref>). For exam- ple, the relational noun fare describes a binary relationship between flights and their price in- formation, as we see in this parse: This analysis differs from previous ap- proaches <ref type="bibr">(Zettlemoyer and Collins, 2007)</ref>, where relational nouns were treated as regu- lar nouns and prepositions introduced the bi- nary relationship. The relational noun model reduces lexical ambiguity for the prepositions, which are otherwise highly polysemous.</p><formula xml:id="formula_10">ξ N P/N : λf Ax.f (x)</formula><p>Adjectives are nominal modifiers that take a noun or a noun phrase as an argument and add properties through conjunction. Preposi- tions take nominal objects and function as ad- jectival modifiers for nouns or adverbial modi- fiers for verbs. Verbs can be subcategorized by their grammatical structures into transi- tive (V trans ), intransitive (V intrans ), imper- sonal (V imperson ), auxiliary (V aux ) and copula (V copula ). Adverbs are verb modifiers defin- ing aspects like time, rate and duration. The adoption of event semantics allows adverbial modifiers to be represented by predicates and linked by the shared events. Determiners pre- cede nouns or noun phrases and distinguish a reference of the noun. Following the gen- eralized Skolem terms, we model determiners, including indefinite and definite articles, as a e, t, e function that selects a unique indi- vidual from a e, t-typed function defining a singleton set.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Missing Words</head><p>The templates presented so far model grammatically correct input. How- ever, in dialogue domains such as ATIS, speak- ers often omit words. For example, speak- ers can drop the preposition "from" in "flights from Newark to Cleveland" to create the ellip- tical utterance "flights Newark to Cleveland". We address this issue with the templates t elliptical illustrated in <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">Table 5</ref>. Each of these adds a binary relation P to a lexeme with a single entity typed constant. For our example, the word "Newark" could be assigned the lexi- cal item N ewark P P : λx.f rom(x, newark) by selecting the first template and P = f rom.</p><p>Another common problem is the use of metonymy. In the utterance "What airlines depart from New York?", the word "airlines" is used to reference flight services operated by a specific airline. This is problematic because the word "depart" needs to modify an event of type flight. We solve this with the t metonymy templates in <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">Table 5</ref>. These introduce a binary predicate P that would, in the case of our ex- ample, map airlines on to the flights that they operate.</p><p>The templates in <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">Table 5</ref> handle the ma- jor cases of missing words seen in our data and are more efficient than the approach taken by <ref type="bibr">(Zettlemoyer and Collins, 2007</ref>) who intro- duced complex type shifting rules and relaxed the grammar to allow every word order.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Morphological Transformations</head><p>Finally, the morpho-syntactic lexicon intro- duces morphological transformations, which are functions from base lexical templates to lexical templates that model the syntactic and semantic variation as the word is inflected. These transformations allow us to compactly model, for example, the facts that argument order is reversed when moving from active to passive forms of the same verb, and that the subject can be omitted. To the best of our knowledge, we are the first to study such trans- formations for semantic parsing. <ref type="table">Table 6</ref> shows the transformations. Each row groups a set of transformations by linguis- tic category, including singular vs. plural num- ber, active vs. passive voice, and so on, and also includes example sentences where the out- put templates could be used. Again, for space, we do not detail the motivation for every class, but it is worth looking at some of the alterna- tions for verbs and nouns as our prototypical example.</p><p>Some verbs can act as noun modifiers. For example, the present participle "using" mod- ifies "flights" in "flights using twa". To model this variation, we use the transforma- tion f present part , a mapping that changes the root of the verb signature S\N P to P P :</p><formula xml:id="formula_11">fpresent part : ξ S\N P/T : λx1..xnλe.v(e, xn..x1) → ξ P P/T : λx1..xnλe.v(e, xn..x1)</formula><p>where T = [, N P, N P/N P ] instantiates this rule for verbs that take different sets of argu- ments, effectively allowing any verb that is in its finite or -ing form to behave syntactically like a prepositional phrase. Intransitive present participles can also act as prenominal adjectival modifiers as in "the departing flight". We add a second mapping that maps the intransitive category S\N P to the noun modifier N/N .</p><formula xml:id="formula_12">fpresent part : ξ S\N P : λxλe.v(e, x) → ξ N/N : λf λxλe.f (x) ∧ v(e, x)</formula><p>Finally, verbal nouns have meanings derived from actions typically described by verbs but syntactically function as nouns. For example, landing in the phrase "landing from jfk" is the gerundive use of the verb land. We add the following mapping to f present part and f nominal :</p><formula xml:id="formula_13">Template transformations fm Example usage Plural Number (f plural ) I flight → early flights ξ N : λx.v(x) → ξ N P : Ax.v(x) city → flights to cities Singular Number (f singular ) I flight → flight Possessive (fpossess) ξ N P : v → ξ N/N : λf λx.f (x) ∧ P (x, v) delta → delta's flights ξ N : λx.v(x) → ξ N/N : λf λx.f (x) ∧ P (x, Ay.v(y))</formula><p>airline → airline's flights Passive Voice (fpassive) ξ Y/N P : λx1..xnλe.v(e, x1..xn) → ξ Y/P P : λx1.. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">xnλe.v(e, xn..x1)</ref> serves →is served by ξ Y/N P : λx1.. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">xnλe.v(e, x1, .</ref>., xn) → ξ Y : λx1..xn− <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">1λe.v(e, xn−1..x1)</ref> name →city named Austin Present Participle (fpresent) ξ S\N P/T : λx1..xnλe.v(e, xn..x1) → ξ P P/T : λx1.. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">xnλe.v(e, xn..x1)</ref> use →flights using twa ξ S\N P : λxλe.v(e, x) → ξ N/N : λf λxλe.f (x) ∧ v(e, x)</p><p>arrive →arriving flights ξ S\N P/T : λx1..xnλe.v(e, xn..x1) → ξ N/T : λx1.. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">xnλe.v(e, xn..x1)</ref> land → landings at jfk Past Participle (fpast) ξ S\N P/N P : λx1..xnλe.v(e, xn..x1) → ξ P P/P P : λx1..xnλe.v(e, x1..xn) use → plane used by</p><formula xml:id="formula_14">Nominalization (f nominal ) ξ S\N P/T : λx1..xnλe.v(e, xn..x1) → ξ N/T : λx1..xnλe.v(e, xn..x1) depart → departure Comparative (fcomp) ξ DEG : λx.v(x) → ξ P P/P P : λxλy.v(y) &lt; v(x) short → shorter ξ DEG : λx.v(x) → ξ P P/P P : λxλy.v(y) &gt; v(x) long → longer Superlative (fsuper) ξ DEG : λx.v(x) → ξ N P/N : λf.argmin(λx.f (x), λx.v(x)) short → shortest ξ DEG : λx.v(x) → ξ N P/N : λf.argmax(λx.f (x), λx.v(x))</formula><p>long → longest  Nouns can be inflected by number to de- note singular and plural forms or by adding an apostrophe to mark a possessive case. The transformation function f singular is an identity transformation. Plurals may have different in- terpretations: one is the generic e, t set rep- resentation, which requires no transformation on the base, or plurals can occur without overt determiners (bare plurals), but semantically imply quantification. We create a plural to singular type shifting rule which implements the e, t, e skolem function to select a unique individual from the set. The possessive trans- formation f possess transfers the base template to a noun modifier, and adds a binary predi- cate P that encodes the relation.</p><p>There are also a number of instances of the identity transformation function I, which does not change the base template. Because the se- mantics we are constructing was designed to answer questions against a static database, it does not need to represent certain phenomena to return the correct answer. This includes more advanced variants of person, tense, as- pect, and potentially many others. Ideally, these morphological attributes should add se- mantic modifiers to the base meaning, for ex- ample, tense can constrain the time at which an event occurs. However, none of our do- mains support such reasoning, so we assign the identity transformation, and leave the explo- ration of these issues to future work.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7">Learning</head><p>One advantage of our morpho-syntactic, fac- tored lexicon is that it can be easily learned with small modifications to existing algo- rithms <ref type="bibr">(Zettlemoyer and Collins, 2007)</ref>. We only need to modify the GENLEX proce- dure that defines the space of possible lexi- cal entries. For each training example (x, z), GENLEX(x, z, F ) first maps each substring in the sentence x into the morphological repre- sentation (s, p, c) using F introduced in Sec- tion 4. A candidate lexeme set L is then gen- erated by exhaustively pairing the word stems with all subsets of the logical constants from z. Lexical templates are applied to the lexemes in L to generate candidate lexical entries for x. Finally, the lexemes that participate in the top scoring correct parse of x are added to the permanent lexicon.</p><p>Initialization Following standard practice, we compile an initial lexicon Λ 0 , which con- sists of a list of domain independent lexical items for function words, such as interrogative words and conjunctions. These lexical items are mostly semantically vacuous and serve par- ticular syntactic functions that are not gener- alizable to other word classes. We also initial- ize the lexemes with a list of NP entities com- plied from the database, e.g., <ref type="bibr">(Boston, [bos]</ref>).</p><p>Features We use two types of features in the model for discriminating parses. Four lex- ical features are fired on each lexical item: φ (s, c) for the lexeme, φ tp for the base tem- plate, φ tm for the morphologically modified template, and φ l for the complete lexical item. We also compute the standard logical expression features ( <ref type="bibr">Zettlemoyer and Collins, 2007)</ref> on the root semantics to track the pair- wise predicate-argument relations and the co- occuring predicate-predicate relations in con- junctions and disjunctions.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="8">Experimental Setup</head><p>Data and Metrics We evaluate perfor- mance on two benchmark semantic pars- ing datasets, Geo880 and ATIS. We use the standard data splits, including 600/280 train/test for Geo880 and 4460/480/450 train/develop/test for ATIS. To support the new representations in Section 5, we sys- tematically convert annotations with existen- tial quantifiers, temporal events and relational nouns to new logical forms with equivalent meanings. All systems are evaluated with ex- act match accuracy, the percentage of fully correct logical forms.</p><p>Initialization We assign positive initial weights to the indicator features for entries in the initial lexicon, as defined in Section 7, to encourage their use. The elliptical template and metonymy template features are initial- ized with negative weights to initially discour- age word skipping.</p><p>Comparison Systems We compare perfor- mance with all recent CCG grammar induc- tion algorithms that work with our datasets. This includes methods that used a limited set of hand-engineered templates for inducing the lexicon, ZC05 <ref type="bibr">(Zettlemoyer and Collins, 2005</ref>) and ZC07 <ref type="bibr">(Zettlemoyer and Collins, 2007)</ref>, and those that learned grammar struc- ture by automatically splitting the labeled log-   </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="9">Results</head><p>Full Models <ref type="table" target="#tab_7">Tables 7 and 8</ref> report the main learning results. Our approach achieves state-of-the-art accuracies on both datasets, demonstrating that our new grammar induc- tion scheme provides a type of linguistically motivated regularization; restricting the algo- rithm to consider a much smaller hypothesis space allows to learn better models. On Geo880 the full method edges out the best systems by 2% absolute on the test set, as compared to other systems with no domain- specific lexical initialization. Although DCS requires less supervision, it also uses external signals including a POS tagger.</p><p>We see similarly strong results for ATIS, outperforming FUBL on the ATIS develop- ment set by 6.8%, and improving the accu- racy on the test set by 7.9% over the previous best system ZC07. Unlike FUBL, which excels at the development set but trails ZC07's tem- plated grammar by almost 2 points on the test set, our approach demonstrates consistent im- provements on both. Additionally, although the unsupervised model (GUSP) rivals previ- ous approaches, we are able to show that more careful use of supervision open a much wider performance gap.</p><p>Learning Curve with Ablations <ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">Figure 2</ref> presents a learning curve for the ATIS domain, demonstrating that the learning improvements become even more dramatic for smaller train- ing set sizes. Our model outperforms FUBL by wide margins, matching its final accuracy with only 22% of the total training examples. Our full model also consistently beats the variants with fewer word class restrictions, although by smaller margins. Again, these results fur- ther highlight the benefit of importing external syntactic resources and enforcing linguistically motivated constraints during learning.</p><p>Learned Lexicon The learned lexicon is also more compact. <ref type="table">Table 9</ref> summarizes statistics on unique lexical entries required to parse the ATIS development set. The</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>System</head><p>Lexical <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Entries Lexemes  FUBL  1019  721  Our Approach 818  495   Table 9</ref>: Lexicon size comparison on the ATIS dev set (460 unique tokens). morpho-syntactic model uses 80.3% of the lex- ical entries and 63.7% of the lexemes that FUBL needs, while increase performance by nearly 7 points. Upon inspection, our model achieves better lexical decomposition by learn- ing shorter lexical units, for example, the adoption of Davidsonian events allows us to learn unambiguous adverbial modifiers, and the formal modeling of nominalized nouns and relational nouns treats prepositions as syntac- tic modifiers, instead of being encoded in the semantics. Such restrictions generalize to a much wider variety of syntactic contexts.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="10">Summary and Future Work</head><p>We demonstrated that significant performance gains can be achieved in CCG semantic pars- ing by introducing a more constrained, linguis- tically motivated grammar induction scheme. We introduced a morpho-syntactic factored lexicon that uses domain-independent facts about the English language to restrict the number of incorrect parses that must be con- sidered and demonstrated empirically that it enables effective learning of complete parsers, achieving state-of-the-art performance. Because our methods are domain indepen- dent they should also benefit other semantic parsing applications and other learning algo- rithms that use different types of supervision, as we hope to verify in future work. We would also like to study how to generalize these gains to languages other than English, by inducing more of the syntactic structure.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: An example CCG parse.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>f</head><label></label><figDesc>lights N : λx.f light(x) f rom P P/N P : λy.λx.f rom(x, y) cities N : λx.city(x)</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>american airline from Denver ξ N : λx.P (x, v) tmetonymy List airlines from Seattle ξ N/P P : λf λx.v(x) ∧ P (Ay.f (y), x)) Shat airlines depart from Seattle? ξ N/(S\N P ) : λf λx.v(x) ∧ P (Ay.f (y), x) fares from miami to New York ξ N/P P : λf λx.v(Ay.f (y), x)</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Ax.f light(x) &gt; N λx.f are(Ay.f light(y), x)</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><head>6 :</head><label>6</label><figDesc>Morphological transformations with examples. T = [, N P, N P/N P ] and Y = [S\N P, S\N P/N P ] allow a single transformation to generalize across word type.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_6"><head>Figure 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2: ATIS Learning Curve</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" validated="true"><head>Table 2 : Part-of-Speech types</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>POS 
Attribute 
Values 
Noun Number 
singular, plural 
Verb 
Person 
first, second, third 
Verb 
Voice 
active, passive 
Verb 
Tense 
present, past 
Verb 
Aspect 
simple, progressive, perfect 
Verb 
Participle 
present participle, 
past participle 
Adj, 
Degree of 
comparative, superlative 
Adv, 
comparison 
Det 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" validated="false"><head>Table 3 : Morphological attributes and values.</head><label>3</label><figDesc></figDesc><table></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" validated="false"><head>Table 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Lexical entries constructed by combining a lexeme, base template, and transformation 
for the intransitive verb 'depart' and the transitive verb 'use'. 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3" validated="false"><head>Table 4 :</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Base templates that define different syntactic roles.</figDesc><table></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4" validated="false"><head>Table 5 :</head><label>5</label><figDesc>Base templates for ungrammatical linguistic phenomena considering nouns as an illustrative example.</figDesc><table></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_5" validated="false"><head>Table</head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><table></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_7" validated="true"><head>Table 7 :</head><label>7</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Exact-match Geo880 test accuracy. 

System 
Dev Test 
ZC07 
74.4 84.6 
UBL 
65.6 71.4 
FUBL 
81.9 82.8 
GUSP 
-
83.5 
TEMP-ONLY 85.5 87.2 
FULL 
87.5 91.3 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_8" validated="false"><head>Table 8 :</head><label>8</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Exact-match accuracy on the ATIS 
development and test sets. 

ical forms, UBL (Kwiatkowski et al., 2010) 
and FUBL (Kwiatkowski et al., 2011). We 
also compare the state-of-the-art for Geo880 
(DCS (Liang et al., 2011) and DCS+ which in-
cludes an engineered seed lexicon) and ATIS 
(which is ZC07). Finally, we include results 
for GUSP (Poon, 2013), a recent unsupervised 
approach for ATIS. 

System Variants We report results for a 
complete approach (Full), and variants which 
use different aspects of the morpho-syntactic 
lexicon. The TEMP-ONLY variant learned 
with the templates from Section 5 but, like 
ZC07, does not use any word class information 
to restrict their use. The TEMP-POS removes 
morphology from the lexemes, but includes the 
word class information from Wiktionary. Fi-
nally, we also include DCS + , which initialize a 
set of words with POS tag JJ, NN, and NNS. 

</table></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> www.wiktionary.com</note>

			<note place="foot">ξ S\N P/T : λx1..xnλe.v(e, xn..x1) → ξ N/T : λx1..xnλe.v(e, xn..x1) with T from above. This allows for reuse of the same meaning across quite different syntactic constructs, including for example &quot;flights that depart from Boston&quot; and &quot;departure from Boston.&quot;</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgements</head><p>The research was supported by the NSF (IIS-1115966, IIS-1252835) and the Intel Center for Pervasive Computing at the Univeristy of Washington. The authors thank Robert Gens, Xiao Ling, Xu Miao, Mark Yatskar and the UW NLP group for helpful discussions, and the anonymous reviewers for helpful com-ments.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="annex">
			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Semantic parsing as machine translation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Andreas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Vlachos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Clark</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Bootstrapping semantic parsers from conversations</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Artzi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Zettlemoyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</title>
		<meeting>the Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">UW SPF: The University of Washington Semantic Parsing Framework</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Artzi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Zettlemoyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Weakly supervised learning of semantic parsers for mapping instructions to actions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Artzi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Zettlemoyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Transactions of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="49" to="62" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Semantic parsing on freebase from question-answer pairs</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Berant</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Chou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Frostig</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Liang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</title>
		<meeting>the Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Wide-coverage semantic analysis with boxer</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Bos</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Conference on Semantics in Text Processing</title>
		<meeting>the Conference on Semantics in Text Processing</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Large-scale semantic parsing via schema matching and lexicon extension</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Q</forename><surname>Cai</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Yates</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Semantic parsing freebase: Towards open-domain semantic parsing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Q</forename><surname>Cai</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Yates</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Joint Conference on Lexical and Computational Semantics</title>
		<meeting>the Joint Conference on Lexical and Computational Semantics</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Type-Logical Semantics. The MITPress</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Carpenter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Learning to interpret natural language navigation instructions from observations</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Mooney</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the National Conference on Artificial Intelligence</title>
		<meeting>the National Conference on Artificial Intelligence</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Driving semantic parsing from the world&apos;s response</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Clarke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Goldwasser</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Chang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Roth</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Conference on Computational Natural Language Learning</title>
		<meeting>the Conference on Computational Natural Language Learning</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Expanding the scope of the atis task: The atis3 corpus</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Dahl</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Bates</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Brown</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Fisher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Hunicke-Smith</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Pallett</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Pao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Rudnicky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Shriberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the workshop on Human Language Technology</title>
		<meeting>the workshop on Human Language Technology</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1994" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The logical form of action sentences. Essays on actions and events</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Davidson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1967" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="105" to="148" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The interpretation of relational nouns</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>De Bruin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Scha</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Conference of the Association of Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the Conference of the Association of Computational Linguistics</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACL</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1988" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="25" to="32" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Learning from natural instructions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Goldwasser</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Roth</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence</title>
		<meeting>the International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Leveraging knowledge graphs for web-scale unsupervised semantic parsing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Heck</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Hakkani-Tür</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Tur</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of the INTERSPEECH</title>
		<meeting>of the INTERSPEECH</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Interpretation as abduction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Hobbs</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Stickel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Martin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Edwards</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the Association for Computational Linguistics</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1988" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Morphological analysis can improve a ccg parser for english</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Honnibal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Kummerfeld</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Curran</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the International Conference on Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the International Conference on Computational Linguistics</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Semantic parsing with bayesian tree transducers</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Jones</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Johnson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Goldwater</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of Association of Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>Association of Computational Linguistics</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Using stringkernels for learning semantic parsers</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Kate</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Mooney</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Conference of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the Conference of the Association for Computational Linguistics</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Jointly learning to parse and perceive: Connecting natural language to the physical world</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Krishnamurthy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Kollar</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Transactions of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Weakly supervised training of semantic parsers</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Krishnamurthy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Mitchell</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Joint Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing and Computational Natural Language Learning</title>
		<meeting>the Joint Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing and Computational Natural Language Learning</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Scaling semantic parsers with on-the-fly ontology matching</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Kwiatkowski</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Choi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Artzi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Zettlemoyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A probabilistic model of syntactic and semantic acquisition from child-directed utterances and their meanings</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Kwiatkowski</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Goldwater</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Zettlemoyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Steedman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Conference of the European Chapter of the Association of Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the Conference of the European Chapter of the Association of Computational Linguistics</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Inducing probabilistic CCG grammars from logical form with higher-order unification</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Kwiatkowski</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Zettlemoyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Goldwater</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Steedman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</title>
		<meeting>the Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Lexical generalization in CCG grammar induction for semantic parsing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Kwiatkowski</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Zettlemoyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Goldwater</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Steedman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</title>
		<meeting>the Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Combined distributional and logical semantics</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Lewis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Steedman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Transactions of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="179" to="192" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Learning dependency-based compositional semantics</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Liang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Jordan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Klein</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Conference of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the Conference of the Association for Computational Linguistics</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A joint model of language and perception for grounded attribute learning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Matuszek</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Fitzgerald</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Zettlemoyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Bo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Fox</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the International Conference on Machine Learning</title>
		<meeting>the International Conference on Machine Learning</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A fully statistical approach to natural language interfaces</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Miller</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Stallard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Bobrow</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Schwartz</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>Association for Computational Linguistics</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Learning for deep language understanding</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Muresan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence</title>
		<meeting>the International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Integrating lexical and formal sematics: Genitives, relational nouns, and type-shifting</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Partee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Borschev</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Second Tbilisi Symposium on Language, Logic, and Computation</title>
		<meeting>the Second Tbilisi Symposium on Language, Logic, and Computation</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Grounded unsupervised semantic parsing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Poon</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL)</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The generative lexicon</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Pustejovsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1991" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Surface Structure and Interpretation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Steedman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
			<publisher>The MIT Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The Syntactic Process</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Steedman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
			<publisher>The MIT Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Taking Scope</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Steedman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<publisher>The MIT Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
