<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T12:56+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Testing for Significance of Increased Correlation with Human Judgment</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
				<availability status="unknown"><p>Copyright Association for Computational Linguistics</p>
				</availability>
				<date>October 25-29, 2014. 2014</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yvette</forename><surname>Graham</surname></persName>
							<email>graham.yvette@gmail.com, tb@ldwin.net</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computing and Information Systems</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">The University of Melbourne</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Timothy</forename><surname>Baldwin</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computing and Information Systems</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">The University of Melbourne</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Testing for Significance of Increased Correlation with Human Judgment</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2014 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP)</title>
						<meeting>the 2014 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP) <address><addrLine>Doha, Qatar. c</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="172" to="176"/>
							<date type="published">October 25-29, 2014. 2014</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Automatic metrics are widely used in machine translation as a substitute for human assessment. With the introduction of any new metric comes the question of just how well that metric mimics human assessment of translation quality. This is often measured by correlation with human judgment. Significance tests are generally not used to establish whether improvements over existing methods such as BLEU are statistically significant or have occurred simply by chance, however. In this paper, we introduce a significance test for comparing correlations of two metrics, along with an open-source implementation of the test. When applied to a range of metrics across seven language pairs, tests show that for a high proportion of metrics, there is insufficient evidence to conclude significant improvement over BLEU.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Within machine translation (MT), efforts are on- going to improve evaluation metrics and find bet- ter ways to automatically assess translation qual- ity. The process of validating a new metric in- volves demonstration that it correlates better with human judgment than a standard metric such as BLEU ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Papineni et al., 2001</ref>). However, although it is standard practice in MT evaluation to mea- sure increases in automatic metric scores with sig- nificance tests <ref type="bibr">(Germann, 2003;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Och, 2003;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Kumar and Byrne, 2004;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Koehn, 2004;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Riezler and Maxwell, 2005;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Graham et al., 2014</ref>), this has not been the case in papers proposing new met- rics. Thus it is possible that some reported im- provements in correlation with human judgment are attributable to chance rather than a systematic improvement.</p><p>In this paper, we motivate and introduce a novel significance test to assess the statistical signifi- cance of differences in correlation with human judgment for pairs of automatic metrics. We ap- ply tests to the WMT-12 shared metrics task to compare each of the participating methods, and find that for a high proportion of metrics, there is not enough evidence to conclude that they signifi- cantly outperform BLEU.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Correlation with Human Judgment</head><p>A common means of assessing automatic MT evaluation metrics is Spearman's rank correlation with human judgments ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Melamed et al., 2003)</ref>, which measures the relative degree of monotonic- ity between the metric and human scores in the range <ref type="bibr">[−1, 1]</ref>. The standard justification for cal- culating correlations over ranks rather than raw scores is to: (a) reduce anomalies due to absolute score differences; and (b) focus evaluation on what is generally the primary area of interest, namely the ranking of systems/translations.</p><p>An alternative means of evaluation is Pearson's correlation, which measures the linear correlation between a metric and human scores ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Leusch et al., 2003)</ref>. Debate on the relative merits of Spear- man's and Pearson's correlation for the evaluation of automatic metrics is ongoing, but there is an in- creasing trend towards Pearson's correlation, e.g. in the recent WMT-14 shared metrics task. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref> presents the system-level results for two evaluation metrics -AMBER ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Chen et al., 2012</ref>) and TERRORCAT ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Fishel et al., 2012)</ref> -over the WMT-12 Spanish-to-English metrics task. These two metrics achieved the joint-highest rank correlation (ρ = 0.965) for the task, but dif- fer greatly in terms of Pearson's correlation (r = 0.881 vs. 0.971, resp.). The largest contributor to this artifact is the system with the lowest human score, represented by the leftmost point in both plots. Consistent with the WMT-14 metrics shared task, we argue that Pearson's correlation is more sensitive than Spearman's correlation. There is still the question, however, of whether an observed difference in Pearson's r is statistically significant, which we address in the next section.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Significance Testing</head><p>Evaluation of a new automatic metric, M new , commonly takes the form of quantifying the cor- relation between the new metric and human judg- ment, r(M new , H), and contrasting it with the cor- relation for some baseline metric, r(M base , H). It is very rare in the MT literature for significance testing to be performed in such cases, however. We introduce a statistical test which can be used for this purpose, and apply the test to the evalua- tion of metrics participating in the WMT-12 metric evaluation task.</p><p>At first gloss, it might seem reasonable to per- form significance testing in the following man- ner when an increase in correlation with human assessment is observed: apply a significance test separately to the correlation of each metric with human judgment, with the hope that the newly proposed metric will achieve a significant correla- tion where the baseline metric does not. However, besides the fact that the correlation between al- most any document-level metric and human judg- ment will generally be significantly greater than zero, the logic here is flawed: the fact that one correlation is significantly higher than zero (r(M new , H)) and that of another is not, does not necessarily mean that the difference between the two correlations is significant. Instead, a specific test should be applied to the difference in corre- lations on the data. For this same reason, con- fidence intervals for individual correlations with human judgment are also not particularly mean- ingful.</p><p>In psychological studies, it is often the case that samples that data are drawn from are independent, and differences in correlations are computed on in- dependent data sets. In such cases, the Fisher r to z transformation is applied to test for signifi- cant differences in correlations. In the case of au- tomatic metric evaluation, however, the data sets used are almost never independent. This means that if r(M base , H) and r(M new , H) are both &gt; 0, the correlation between the metric scores them- selves, r(M base , M new ), must also be &gt; 0. The strength of this correlation, directly between pairs of metrics, should be taken into account using a significance test of the difference in correlation be- tween r(M base , H) and r(M new , H).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Correlated Correlations</head><p>Correlations computed for two separate automatic metrics on the same data set are not independent, and for this reason in order to test the difference in correlation between them, the degree to which the pair of metrics correlate with each other should be taken into account. The Williams test (Williams,  1959) 1 evaluates significance in a difference in de- pendent correlations <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">(Steiger, 1980)</ref>. It is formu- lated as follows, as a test of whether the population correlation between X 1 and X 3 equals the popula- tion correlation between X 2 and X 3 :</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">t(n − 3) = (r 13 − r 23 ) (n − 1)(1 + r 12 ) 2K (n−1) (n−3) + (r 23 +r 13 ) 2 4 (1 − r 12 ) 3 ,</formula><p>where r ij is the Pearson correlation between X i and X j , n is the size of the population, and: The Williams test is more powerful than the equivalent for independent samples (Fisher r to z), as it takes the correlations between X 1 and X 2 (metric scores) into account. All else being equal, the higher the correlation between the met- ric scores, the greater the statistical power of the test.</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">K = 1 −</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Evaluation and Discussion</head><p>Figure 2a is a heatmap of the degree to which au- tomatic metrics correlate with one another when computed on the same data set, in the form of the Pearson's correlation between each pair of met- rics that participated in the WMT-12 metrics task for Spanish-to-English evaluation. Metrics are or- dered in all tables from highest to lowest correla- tion with human assessment. In addition, for the purposes of significance testing, we take the abso- lute value of all correlations, in order to compare error-based metrics with non-error based ones.</p><p>In general, the correlation is high amongst all pairs of metrics, with a high proportion of paired metrics achieving a correlation in excess of r = 0.9. Two exceptions to this are TERRORCAT ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Fishel et al., 2012</ref>) and SAGAN <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Castillo and Estrella, 2012</ref>), as seen in the regions of yellow and white. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 2b</ref> shows the results of Williams sig- nificance tests for all pairs of metrics. Since we are interested in not only identifying significant differences in correlations, but ultimately ranking competing metrics, we use a one-sided test. Here again, the metrics are ordered from highest to low- est (absolute) correlation with human judgment.</p><p>For the Spanish-to-English systems, approxi- mately 60% of WMT-12 metric pairs show a sig- nificant difference in correlation with human judg- ment at p &lt; 0.05 (for one of the two metric di- rections). <ref type="bibr">2</ref> As expected, the higher the correlation with human judgment, the more metrics a given method is superior to at a level of statistical signifi- cance. Although TERRORCAT ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Fishel et al., 2012</ref>) achieves the highest absolute correlation with hu- man judgment, it is not significantly better (p ≥ 0.05) than the four next-best metrics (METEOR ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Denkowski and Lavie, 2011)</ref>  jar, 2011) and POSF <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Popovic, 2012)</ref>). There is not enough evidence to conclude, therefore, that this metric is any better at evaluating Spanish-to- English MT system quality than the next four met- rics. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 3</ref> shows the results of significance tests for the six other language pairs used in the WMT- 12 metrics shared task. 3 For no language pair is there an outright winner amongst the met- rics, with proportions of significant differences be- tween metrics for a given language pair ranging from 3% for Czech-to-English to 82% for English- to-French (p &lt; 0.05). The number of metrics that significantly outperform BLEU for a given lan- guage pair is only 34% (p &lt; 0.05), and no method significantly outperforms BLEU over all language pairs -indeed, even the best methods achieve sta- tistical significance over BLEU for only a small minority of language pairs. This underlines the dangers of assessing metrics based solely on cor- relation numbers, and emphasizes the importance of statistical testing.</p><p>It is important to note that the number of com-peting metrics a metric significantly outperforms should not be used as the criterion for ranking competing metrics. This is due to the fact that the power of the Williams test to identify signifi- cant differences between correlations changes de- pending on the degree to which the pair of met- rics correlate with each other. Therefore, a metric that happens to correlate strongly with many other metrics would be at an unfair advantage, were numbers of significant wins to be used to rank met- rics. For this reason, it is best to interpret pairwise metric tests in isolation. As part of this research, we have made avail- able an open-source implementation of statis- tical tests tailored to the assessment of MT metrics available at https://github.com/ ygraham/significance-williams.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Conclusions</head><p>We have provided an analysis of current method- ologies for evaluating automatic metrics in ma- chine translation, and identified an issue with re- spect to the lack of significance testing. We in- troduced the Williams test as a means of cal- culating the statistical significance of differences in correlations for dependent samples. Analysis of statistical significance in the WMT-12 metrics shared task showed there is currently insufficient evidence for a high proportion of metrics to con- clude that they outperform BLEU.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: Scatter plot of human and automatic scores of WMT-12 Spanish-to-English systems for two MT evaluation metrics (AMBER and TERRORCAT)</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2: (a) Pearson's correlation between pairs of automatic metrics; and (b) p-value of Williams significance tests, where a colored cell in row i (named on y-axis), col j indicates that metric i (named on x-axis) correlates significantly higher with human judgment than metric j; all results are based on the WMT-12 Spanish-to-English data set.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Figure 3: Significance results for pairs of automatic metrics for each WMT-12 language pair.</figDesc></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> Also sometimes referred to as the Hotelling-Williams test.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="2"> Correlation matrices (red) are maximally filled, in contrast to one-sided significance test matrices (green), where, at a maximum, fewer than half of the cells can be filled.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="3"> We omit English-to-Czech due to some metric scores being omitted from the WMT-12 data set.</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>We wish to thank the anonymous reviewers for their valuable comments. This research was sup-ported by funding from the Australian Research Council.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Semantic textual similarity for MT evaluation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Julio</forename><surname>Castillo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Paula</forename><surname>Estrella</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Seventh Workshop on Statistical Machine Translation</title>
		<meeting>the Seventh Workshop on Statistical Machine Translation<address><addrLine>Montréal, Canada</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="52" to="58" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Improving AMBER, an MT evaluation metric</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Boxing</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Roland</forename><surname>Kuhn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">George</forename><surname>Foster</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Seventh Workshop on Statistical Machine Translation</title>
		<meeting>the Seventh Workshop on Statistical Machine Translation<address><addrLine>Montréal, Canada</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="59" to="63" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Meteor 1.3: Automatic metric for reliable optimization and evaluation of machine translation systems</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Denkowski</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alon</forename><surname>Lavie</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Sixth Workshop on Statistical Machine Translation</title>
		<meeting>the Sixth Workshop on Statistical Machine Translation<address><addrLine>Edinburgh, UK</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="85" to="91" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Greedy decoding for statistical machine translation in almost linear time</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mark</forename><surname>Fishel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rico</forename><surname>Sennrich</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Maja</forename><surname>Popovi´cpopovi´c</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ondřej</forename><surname>Bojar</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2003 Conference of the North American Chapter of the Assoc</title>
		<meeting>the 2003 Conference of the North American Chapter of the Assoc<address><addrLine>Montréal, Canada. Ulrich Germann; Edmonton, Canada</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="8" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Proceedings of the Seventh Workshop on Statistical Machine Translation</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Randomized significance tests in machine translation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yvette</forename><surname>Graham</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nitika</forename><surname>Mathur</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Timothy</forename><surname>Baldwin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the ACL 2014 Ninth Workshop on Statistical Machine Translation</title>
		<meeting>the ACL 2014 Ninth Workshop on Statistical Machine Translation<address><addrLine>Baltimore, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="266" to="274" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Statistical significance tests for machine translation evaluation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Philipp</forename><surname>Koehn</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</title>
		<meeting>Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing<address><addrLine>Barcelona, Spain</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="388" to="395" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Minimum Bayes-risk decoding for statistical machine translation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Shankar</forename><surname>Kumar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">William</forename><surname>Byrne</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 4th International Conference on Human Language Technology Research and 5th Annual Meeting of the NAACL (HLT-NAACL 2004)</title>
		<meeting>the 4th International Conference on Human Language Technology Research and 5th Annual Meeting of the NAACL (HLT-NAACL 2004)<address><addrLine>Boston, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="169" to="176" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A novel string-to-string distance measure with applications to machine translation evaluation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gregor</forename><surname>Leusch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nicola</forename><surname>Ueffing</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hermann</forename><surname>Ney</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings 9th Machine Translation Summit (MT Summit IX)</title>
		<meeting>9th Machine Translation Summit (MT Summit IX)<address><addrLine>New Orleans, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="240" to="247" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Approximating a deep-syntactic metric for MT evaluation and tuning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Matouš</forename><surname>Macháček</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ondřej</forename><surname>Bojar</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Sixth Workshop on Statistical Machine Translation</title>
		<meeting>the Sixth Workshop on Statistical Machine Translation<address><addrLine>Edinburgh, UK</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="92" to="98" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Precision and recall of machine translation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dan</forename><surname>Melamed</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ryan</forename><surname>Green</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Joseph</forename><surname>Turian</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2003 Conference of the North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics on Human Language Technology (HLTNAACL 2003)-Short Papers</title>
		<meeting>the 2003 Conference of the North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics on Human Language Technology (HLTNAACL 2003)-Short Papers<address><addrLine>Edmonton, Canada</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="61" to="63" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Minimum error rate training in statistical machine translation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Franz Josef</forename><surname>Och</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 41st Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the 41st Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics<address><addrLine>Japan</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="160" to="167" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Sapporo</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">BLEU: A method for automatic evaluation of machine translation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kishore</forename><surname>Papineni</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Salim</forename><surname>Roukos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Todd</forename><surname>Ward</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Weijing</forename><surname>Zhu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>RC22176 (W0109-022</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
			<pubPlace>IBM Research, Thomas J. Watson Research Center</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
<note type="report_type">Technical Report</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Class error rates for evaluation of machine translation output</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Maja</forename><surname>Popovic</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Seventh Workshop on Statistical Machine Translation</title>
		<meeting>the Seventh Workshop on Statistical Machine Translation<address><addrLine>Montréal, Canada</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="71" to="75" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">On some pitfalls in automatic evaluation and significance testing for mt</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Stefan</forename><surname>Riezler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">John</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Maxwell</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the ACL Workshop on Intrinsic and Extrinsic Evaluation Measures for Machine Translation and/or Summarization</title>
		<meeting>the ACL Workshop on Intrinsic and Extrinsic Evaluation Measures for Machine Translation and/or Summarization<address><addrLine>Ann Arbor, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="57" to="64" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Tests for comparing elements of a correlation matrix</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">James</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Steiger</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Bulletin</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">87</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">245</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1980" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Evan</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Williams</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Regression Analysis</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>New York, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Wiley</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1959" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
