<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T11:36+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Detecting Disagreement in Conversations using Pseudo-Monologic Rhetorical Structure</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
				<availability status="unknown"><p>Copyright Association for Computational Linguistics</p>
				</availability>
				<date>October 25-29, 2014. 2014</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kelsey</forename><surname>Allen</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of British Columbia Vancouver</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>V6T 1Z4</postCode>
									<region>BC</region>
									<country key="CA">Canada</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Giuseppe</forename><surname>Carenini</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of British Columbia Vancouver</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>V6T 1Z4</postCode>
									<region>BC</region>
									<country key="CA">Canada</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Raymond</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Ng</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of British Columbia Vancouver</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>V6T 1Z4</postCode>
									<region>BC</region>
									<country key="CA">Canada</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Detecting Disagreement in Conversations using Pseudo-Monologic Rhetorical Structure</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2014 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP)</title>
						<meeting>the 2014 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP) <address><addrLine>Doha, Qatar. c</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="1169" to="1180"/>
							<date type="published">October 25-29, 2014. 2014</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Casual online forums such as Reddit, Slashdot and Digg, are continuing to increase in popularity as a means of communication. Detecting disagreement in this domain is a considerable challenge. Many topics are unique to the conversation on the forum, and the appearance of disagreement may be much more subtle than on political blogs or social media sites such as twitter. In this analysis we present a crowd-sourced annotated corpus for topic level disagreement detection in Slashdot, showing that disagreement detection in this domain is difficult even for humans. We then proceed to show that a new set of features determined from the rhetorical structure of the conversation significantly improves the performance on disagreement detection over a baseline consisting of unigram/bigram features, discourse markers, structural features and meta-post features.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>How does disagreement arise in conversation? Be- ing able to detect agreement and disagreement has a range of applications. For an online educator, dissent over a newly introduced topic may alert the teacher to fundamental misconceptions about the material. For a business, understanding dis- putes over features of a product may be helpful in future design iterations. By better understanding how debate arises and propagates in a conversa- tion, we may also gain insight into how authors' opinions on a topic can be influenced over time.</p><p>The long term goal of our research is to lay the foundations for understanding argumentative structure in conversations, which could be applied to NLP tasks such as summarization, information retrieval, and text visualization. Argumentative structure theory has been thoroughly studied in both psychology and rhetoric, with negation and discourse markers, as well as hedging and dis- preferred responses, being known to be indicative of argument <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(Horn, 1989;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Brown and Levinson, 1987)</ref>. As a starting point, in this paper we focus on the detection of disagreement in casual con- versations between users. This requires a gener- alized approach that can accurately identify dis- agreement in topics ranging from something as mundane as whether GPS stands for galactic po- sitioning system or global positioning system, to more ideological debates about distrust in science.</p><p>Motivated by the widespread consensus in both computational and theoretical linguistics on the utility of discourse markers for signalling prag- matic functions such as disagreement and personal opinions <ref type="bibr" target="#b38">(Webber and Prasad, 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Abbott et al., 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr">J. E. Fox-Tree, 2010</ref>), we introduce a new set of features based on the Discourse Tree (DT) of a conversational text. Discourse Trees were formalized by <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">Mann and Thompson (1988)</ref> as part of their Rhetorical Structure Theory (RST) to represent the structure of discourse. Although this theory is for monologic discourse, we propose to treat conversational dialogue as a collection of linked monologues, and subsequently build a rela- tion graph describing both rhetorical connections within user posts, as well as between different users. Features obtained from this graph offer sig- nificant improvements on disagreement detection over a baseline consisting of meta-post features, lexical features, discourse markers and conversa- tional features. Not only do these features improve disagreement detection, but the discovered impor- tance of relations known to be theoretically rele- vant to disagreement detection, such as COMPAR- ISON <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(Horn, 1989)</ref>, suggest that this approach may be capturing the essential aspects of the conversa- tional argumentative structure.</p><p>As a second contribution of this work, we pro- vide a new dataset consisting of 95 topics anno- tated for disagreement. Unlike the publicly avail- able ARGUE corpus based on the online debate forum 4forums.com <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Abbott et al., 2011</ref>), our cor- pus is based on Slashdot, which is a general pur- pose forum not targeted to debates. Therefore, we expect that detecting disagreement may be a more difficult task in our new corpus, as certain topics (like discussing GPS systems) may be targeted to- wards objective information sharing without any participants expressing opinions or stances. Be- cause of this, our corpus represents an excellent testbed to examine methods for more subtle dis- agreement detection, as well as the major differ- ences between news-style and argument-style dia- logue.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Related Work</head><p>In the past decade, there have been a number of computational approaches developed for the task of disagreement and controversy detection, partic- ularly in synchronous conversations such as meet- ings ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">Somasundaran et al., 2007;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b29">Raaijmakers et al., 2008)</ref> and in monologic corpora such as news collections <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Awadallah et al., 2012</ref>) and reviews ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">Popescu et al., 2005;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Mukherjee and Liu, 2012)</ref>.</p><p>In the domain of synchronous conversations, prosodic features such as duration, speech rate and pause have been used for spoken dialogue ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">Wang et al., 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Galley et al., 2004</ref>). <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Galley et al. (2004)</ref> found that local features, such as lexical and structural features, as well as global contex- tual features, were particularly useful for identify- ing agreement/disagreement in the ICSI meeting corpus. <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Germesin and Wilson (2009)</ref> also showed accuracies of 98% in detecting agreement in the AMI corpus using lexical, subjectivity and dia- logue act features. However, they note that their system could not classify disagreement accurately due to the small number of training examples in this category. <ref type="bibr">Somasundaran et al. additionally</ref> show that dialogue act features complement lexi- cal features in the AMI meeting corpus <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">(Somasundaran et al., 2007</ref>). These observations are taken into account with our feature choices, and we use contextual, discourse and lexical features in our analysis.</p><p>In the monologic domain, <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Conrad et al. (2012)</ref> recently found rhetorical relations to be useful for argument labelling and detection in articles on the topic of healthcare. Additionally, discourse mark- ers and sentiment features have been found to as- sist with disagreement detection in collections of news documents on a particular topic, as well as reviews ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Choi et al., 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Awadallah et al., 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b27">Popescu et al., 2005</ref>).</p><p>In the asynchronous domain, there has been re- cent work in disagreement detection, especially as it pertains to stance identification. Content based features, including sentiment, duration, and dis- course markers have been used for this task <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">(Yin et al., 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b32">Somasundaran and Wiebe, 2009;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b33">Somasundaran and Wiebe, 2010)</ref>. The structure of a conversation has also been used, although these approaches have focused on simple rules for disagreement identification <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">(Murakami and Raymond, 2010)</ref>, or have assumed that adjacent posts always disagree ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Agrawal et al., 2003)</ref>. More re- cent work has focused on identifying users' atti- tudes towards each other ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Hassan et al., 2010)</ref>, in- fluential users and posts <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">(Nguyen et al., 2014</ref>), as well as identifying subgroups of users who share viewpoints ( <ref type="bibr">Abu-Jbara et al., 2010)</ref>. In Slashdot, the h-index of a discussion has been used to rank articles according to controversiality, although no quantitative evaluation of this approach has been given, and, unlike in our analysis, they did not consider any other features ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Gomez et al., 2008)</ref>. Content based features such as polarity and co- sine similarity have also been used to study influ- ence, controversy and opinion changes on micro- blogging sites such as Twitter ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Lin et al., 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b28">Popescu and Pennacchiotti, 2010)</ref>.</p><p>The simplified task of detecting disagreement between just two users (either a question/response pair <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Abbott et al., 2011</ref>) or two adjacent para- graphs ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">Misra and Walker, 2013)</ref>) has also been re- cently approached on the ARGUE corpus. <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Abbott et al. (2011)</ref> use discourse markers, generalized dependency features, punctuation and structural features, while Misra and Walker (2013) focus on n-grams indicative of denial, hedging and agree- ment, as well as cue words and punctuation. Most similar to our work is that by <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Mishne and Glance (2006)</ref>. They performed a general analysis of we- blog comments, using punctuation, quotes, lexi- con counts, subjectivity, polarity and referrals to detect disputative and non-disputative comments. Referrals and questions, as well as polarity mea- sures in the first section of the post, were found to be most useful. However, their analysis did not take into account many features that have been subsequently shown to be relevant, such as dis- course markers and conversational structure, and was hampered by a severe imbalance in the test set (with very few disputative comments).</p><p>Our method takes advantage of insights from many of these previous studies, focusing on dis- cussion thread structure as well as text based fea- tures to form our basic feature set. It is unlike Mishne and Glance's work in that we incorporate several new features, have a balanced testing and training set, and only use comments from one type of online blog. Furthermore, it is a very different task from those so far performed on the ARGUE corpus, as we consider topics discussed by more than two users. We aim to compare our features to those found to be previously useful in these related tasks, and expect similar feature sets to be useful for the task of disagreement detection in this new corpus.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Corpus</head><p>The corpus stems from the online forum Slash- dot. 1 Slashdot is a casual internet forum, includ- ing sections for users to ask questions, post arti- cles, and review books and games. For the task of disagreement detection, we focus our analysis on the section of the site where users can post arti- cles, and then comment either on the article or re- spond to other users' posts. This results in a tree- like dialogue structure for which the posted arti- cle is the root, and branches correspond to threads of comments. Each comment has a timestamp at the minute resolution as well as author information (although it is possible to post on the forum anony- mously). Additionally, other users can give differ- ent posts scores (in the range -1 to 5) as well as cat- egorizing posts under "funny", "interesting", "in- formative", "insightful", "flamebait", "off topic", or "troll". This user moderation, as well as the 1 www.slashdot.org formalized reply-to structure between comments, makes Slashdot attractive over other internet fo- rums as it allows for high-quality and structured conversations.</p><p>In a previous study, Joty et al. <ref type="formula">(2013)</ref> selected 20 articles and their associated comments to be an- notated for topic segmentation boundaries and la- bels by an expert Slashdot contributor. They de- fine a topic as a subset of the utterances in a con- versation, while a topic label describes what the given topic is about (e.g., Physics in videogames). Of the 98 annotated topics from their dataset, we filtered out those with only one contributing user, for a total of 95 topics. Next, we developed a Human Intelligence Task (HIT) using the crowd- sourcing platform Crowdflower. <ref type="bibr">2</ref> The objective of this task was to both develop a corpus for testing our disagreement detection system, as well as to investigate how easily human annotators can de- tect disagreement in casual online forums. For training, users were shown 3 sample topics, la- belling them as containing disagreement or not. In each round, annotators were shown 5 topics, with a set of radio buttons for participants to choose "Yes", "No", or "Not sure" in response to asking whether or not the users in the conversation dis- agree on the topic. In order to limit the number of spam responses, users were shown test questions, which consisted of topics where there was obvi- ous disagreement, as well as topics where there was obviously no disagreement (either agreement, or more news-style information sharing). We re- quired that users correctly identify 4 of these test topics before they were allowed to continue with the task. Users were also shown test questions throughout the task, which, if answered incor- rectly, would reduce the amount of money they re- ceived for the task, and ultimately disqualify them.</p><p>For each topic, five different judgements were obtained. We consider the trust of each partici- pant as the fraction of test questions which they answered correctly. Then, each topic is assigned a score according to a weighted average of the re- sponses, with the weight being the trust of each participant:</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">score = A users ( test correct test total ) user i × (0, 0.5, 1)</formula><p>(1) where 0, 0.5 and 1 represent the answers "No", "Not sure" and "Yes" to the question of disagree- ment existence, and A is a normalization factor. If the score is less than 0.5, its confidence would be 1 − score towards "No disagreement", whereas greater than 0.5 would be a confidence of score towards "Disagreement". The average confidence score across all topics was 0.73. Our corpus con- sists of 49 topics without disagreement and 46 top- ics with disagreement. Interestingly, 22 topics had confidence scores below 55%, which suggests that subtle disagreement detection is a subjective and difficult task. Further statistics for the developed corpus are given in <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table 1</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Features for Disagreement Detection</head><p>The features we use in our experiments combine information from conversational structure, rhetor- ical relations, sentiment features, n-gram models, Slashdot meta-features, structural features, and lexicon features.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">Rhetorical Relation Graphs</head><p>Discourse markers have been found to aid in argument and disagreement detection, and for tasks such as stance identification <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Abbott et al., 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b23">Misra and Walker, 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b32">Somasundaran and Wiebe, 2009)</ref>. We aim to improve over dis- course markers by capturing the underlying dis- course structure of the conversation in terms of discourse relations.</p><p>In Rhetorical Structure Theory, Discourse trees are a hierarchical representation of document structure for monologues <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">(Mann and Thompson, 1988)</ref>. At the lowest level, Elementary Discourse Units (EDUs) are connected by discourse rela- tions (such as ELABORATION and COMPARISON), which in turn form larger discourse units that are also linked by these relations. Computational sys- tems (discourse parsers) have been recently devel- oped to automatically generate a discourse tree for a given monologue ( . Although theoretically the rhetorical relations expected in dialogues are different from those in monologues <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">(Stent and Allen, 2000</ref>), no sophisticated compu- tational tools exist yet for detecting these relations reliably. The core idea of this work is that some useful (although noisy) information about the dis- course structure of a conversation can be obtained by applying state-of-the-art document level dis- course parsing to parts of the conversation.</p><p>More specifically, posts on a particular topic are concatenated according to their temporal order. This pseudo-monologic document is then fed to a publicly available document level discourse parser ( . A discourse tree such as that seen in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1a</ref> is output by the parser. Then, we extract the novel relation graph <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">(Figure 1b)</ref> from the discourse tree. In this graph, each node (N1, N2, N3) corresponds to a post (P1, P2, P3) and links aim to capture the argumentative struc- ture. There are three cases when a link is added between two nodes in the relation graph. Firstly, links existing between two posts directly, such as the COMPARISON relation between P2 and P3, are added between the corresponding nodes in the re-lation graph (N2 and N3). Secondly, links existing between fractions of posts in the discourse tree are added to the relation graph (e.g. if (S2,P2) was connected to (S1,P3) directly, N2 and N3 would have an additional link with that label). Finally, when posts are connected through internal nodes (such as P1 and I1 in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1a)</ref>, a labelled link is added for each post in the internal node to the re- lation graph (N1-&gt;N2 and N1-&gt;N3 in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1b</ref>). This relation graph allows for the extraction of many features that may reflect argumenta- tive structure, such as the number of connec- tions, the frequency of each rhetorical relation in the graph per post (diff per post), and the frequency as a percentage of all rhetorical rela- tions (diff percentage). For example, COMPAR- ISON relations are known to indicate disagree- ment <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(Horn, 1989)</ref>, so we expect higher fre- quencies of this relation if the conversation con- tains argument. Features from the discourse tree such as the average depth of each rhetorical re- lation are also added to reflect the cohesiveness of conversation. Moreover, features combining the graph and tree representations, such as the ra- tio of the frequency of a rhetorical relation occur- ring between different posts to the average depth ( CONTRAST between different posts Average depth of CONTRAST ), called avg ratio are implemented. These reflect the hypothesis that relations connecting larger chunks of text (or whole posts) may be more important than those connecting sentences or only partial posts.</p><p>Finally, the sub-trees corresponding to individ- ual posts are used to extract the average frequency of rhetorical relations within a post (same per post) and the average frequency of a rhetorical re- lation with respect to other rhetorical relations in the post (same percentage). A measure of how often a rhetorical relation connects different users compared to how often it connects discourse units in the same post (same to diff ), is also added. These capture the intuition that certain rhetorical relations such as CAUSE, EVIDENCE and EXPLA- NATION are expected to appear more within a post if users are trying to support their perspective in an argument. In total, there are 18 (rhetorical relations)×7 (avg ratio, avg depth, same per post, same percentage, diff percentage, diff per post, same to diff ) + 1 (number of connections) = 127 features.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">Discourse Markers</head><p>Motivated by previous work, we include a fre- quency count of 17 discourse markers which were found to be the most common across the ARGUE corpus ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Abbott et al., 2011</ref>). Furthermore, we hy- pothesize that individual discourse markers might have low frequency counts in the text. Therefore, we also include an aggregated count of all 17 dis- course markers in each fifth of the posts in a topic (e.g. the count of all 17 discourse markers in the first fifth of every post in the topic). Altogether, there are 5 aggregated discourse marker features in addition to the 17 frequency count features.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3">Sentiment Features</head><p>Sentiment polarity features have been shown to be useful in argument detection ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Mishne and Glance, 2006</ref>). For this work, we use four sentiment scoring categories: the variance, average score, number of negative sentences, and controversiality score <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Carenini and Cheung, 2008</ref>) of sentences in a post. These are determined using SoCAL (Taboada et al., 2011), which gives each sentence a polarity score and has been shown to work well on user-generated content.</p><p>Overall, we have two main classes of sentiment features. The first type splits all the posts in a topic into 4 sections corresponding to the sentences in each quarter of the post. The sentiment scores de- scribed above are then applied to each section of the posts (e.g. one feature is the number of neg- ative sentences in the first quarter of each post). As a separate feature, we also include the scores on just the first sentence, as <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Mishne and Glance (2006)</ref> previously found this to be beneficial. This gives a total of 4×5 = 20 features. We refer to this set as "sentiment".</p><p>Motivated by the rhetorical features, our sec- ond main class of sentiment features aims to iden- tify "more important" posts for argument detec- tion by applying the four categories of sentiment scores to only those posts connected by each of our 18 rhetorical relations. This is done for both posts with an inner rhetorical connection (iden- tified by the sub-tree for that post), as well as for posts connected by a rhetorical relation in the relation graph. This results in a total of (4 sentiment categories)×(2 (different + same post connections))×(18 rhetorical relations) = 144 fea- tures. This set is referred to as "RhetSent".</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.4">Fragment Quotation Graphs</head><p>As previously noted in <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">(Murakami and Raymond, 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Gomez et al., 2008)</ref>, the structure of dis- cussion threads can aid in disagreement detec- tion. In online, threaded conversations, the stan- dard approach to extracting conversational struc- ture is through reply-to relations usually present in online forums. However, if users strongly dis- agree on a topic (or sub-topic), they may choose to quote a specific paragraph (defined as a frag- ment) of a previous post in their reply. Being able to determine which specific fragments are linked by relations may then be useful for more targeted content-based features, helping to reduce noise. In order to address this, we use the Fragment Quo- tation Graph (FQG), an approach previously de- veloped by <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Carenini et al. (2007)</ref> for dialogue act modelling and topic segmentation <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">(Joty et al., 2011;</ref>).</p><p>For our analysis, the FQG is found over the entire Slashdot article. We then select the sub- graph corresponding to those fragments in the tar- get topic. From the fragment quotation sub-graph, we are then able to extract features for disagree- ment detection such as the number of connections, total number of fragments, and the average path length between nodes which we hypothesize to be useful. We additionally extract the h-index ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Gomez et al., 2008)</ref> and average branching ratio per fragment of the topic from the simpler reply-to conversational structure. In total, there are 8 FQG features.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.5">N-gram models</head><p>As noted previously ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">Somasundaran and Wiebe, 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b36">Thomas et al., 2006</ref>), it is often difficult to outperform a unigram/bigram model in the task of disagreement and argument detection. In this anal- ysis, because of the very small number of sam- ples, we do not consider dependency or part-of- speech features, but do make a comparison with a filtered unigram/bigram model. In the filtering, we remove stop words and any words that occur in fewer than three topics. This helps to prevent topic specific words from being selected, and limits the number of possible matches slightly. Additionally, we use a lexicon of bias-words ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">Recasens et al., 2013</ref>) to extract a bias-word frequency score over all posts in the topic as a separate feature.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.6">Structural Features</head><p>Length features have been well documented in the literature to provide useful information about whether or not arguments exist, especially in on- line conversations that may be more informative than subjective ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Biyani et al., 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b39">Yin et al., 2012)</ref>. In this work, length features include the length of the post in sentences, the average num- ber of words per sentence, the average number of sentences per post, the number of contributing au- thors, the rate of posting, and the total amount of time of the conversation. This results in a total of 9 features.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.7">Punctuation</head><p>Like many other features already described, fre- quency counts of '?','!','"','", and '.' are found for each fifth of the post (the first fifth, second fifth, etc.). These counts are then aggregated across all posts for a total of 5×5 = 25 features.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.8">Referrals</head><p>Referrals have been found to help with the detec- tion of disagreement ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Mishne and Glance, 2006</ref>), especially with respect to other authors. Since there are no direct referrals to previous authors in this corpus, references to variations of "you", "they", "us", "I", and "he/she" in each fifth of the post are included instead, for a total of 5×5 = 25 features.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.9">Meta-Post Features</head><p>Slashdot allows users to rank others' posts with the equivalent of a "like" button, changing the "score" of the post (to a maximum of 5). They are also encouraged to tag posts as either "Interesting", "Informative", "Insightful", "Flamebait", "Troll", "Off-topic" or "Funny". Frequency counts of these tags as a percentage of the total number of comments are included as features, as well as the overall fraction of posts which were tagged with any category. The average score across the topic, as well as the number of comments with a score of 4 or 5, are also added. These are expected to be informative features, since controversial topics may encourage more up and down-voting on spe- cific posts, and generally more user involvement. This results in 9 meta-post features.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>1174</head><p>Feature Set <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Random Forest  SVM  P  R  F1  A  ROC-AUC  P  R  F1  A  ROC-AUC  N-</ref>  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Experiments</head><p>Experiments were all performed using the Weka machine learning toolkit. Two different types of experiments were conducted -one using all an- notated topics in a binary classification of con- taining disagreement or not, and one using only those topics with confidence scores greater than 0.75 (corresponding to the more certain cases). All results were obtained by performing 10 fold cross- validation on a balanced test set. Additionally, in- fold cross-validation was performed to determine the optimal number of features to use for each fea- ture set. Since this is done in-fold, a paired t-test is still a valid comparison of different feature sets to determine significant differences in F-score and accuracy.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.1">Classifiers</head><p>Two classifiers were used for this task: Random Forest and SVM. Random Forest was selected be- cause of its ability to avoid over-fitting data despite large numbers of features for relatively few sam- ples. For all runs, 100 trees were generated in the Random Forest, with the number of features to use being determined by in-fold optimization on the F- score. For the SVM classifier, we use the normal- ized poly-vector kernel with a maximum exponent of 2 (the lowest possible), and a C parameter of 1.0 (Weka's default value). This was chosen to avoid over-fitting our data. We additionally use a supervised in-fold feature selection algorithm, Chi-Squared, to limit over-fitting in the SVM. The number of features to be used is also optimized us- ing in-fold cross-validation on the F-score. Both the SVM classifier and the Random Forest classi- fier were tested on the same training/testing fold pairs, with a total of 10 iterations.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Results</head><p>The results of the experiments are shown in Ta- bles 2 and 3. In order to compare to previous anal- yses, unigram and bigram features are shown, as well as a combination of the basic features with the n-grams. When performing the experiments, we noticed that the n-gram features were hurting the performance of the classifiers when included with most of our other feature sets (or not chang- ing results significantly), and therefore those re- sults are not shown here. As seen in the table,  <ref type="table">Table 3</ref>: Precision, recall, F1, accuracy and ROC-AUC scores for the simpler task of identifying the cases deemed "high confidence" in the crowd-sourcing task. the best performing feature sets are those that in- clude rhetorical features under the SVM+χ 2 clas- sifier. In fact, these feature sets perform signifi- cantly better than a unigram/bigram baseline ac- cording to a paired t-test between the best clas- sifiers for each set (p &lt; 0.0001). The inclusion of rhetorical structure also significantly outper- forms the "basic" and "basic+N-grams" feature baselines (which includes discourse markers, re- ferrals, punctuation, bias word counts and struc- tural features) with respect to both the F-score and accuracy (p &lt; 0.02 for all feature sets with rhetorical features). Overall, the feature sets "Ba- sic+RhetAll" and "All" under the SVM+χ 2 clas- sifier perform best. This performance is also bet- ter than previously reported results for the ARGUE Corpus (Abbott et al., 2011), even though the ba- sic and unigram/bigram features perform similarly to that reported in previous analyses.</p><p>As an additional check, we also conduct exper- iments on the "high confidence" data (those topics with a confidence score greater than 0.75). These results are shown in <ref type="table">Table 3</ref>. Clearly the basic features perform better on this subset of the sam- ples, although the addition of rhetorical structure still provides significant improvement (p &lt; 0.001). Overall, this suggests that the rhetorical, sentiment and FQG features help more when the disagree- ment is more subtle.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7">Analysis and Discussion</head><p>In order to examine the quality of our features, we report on the rhetorical features selected, and show that these are reasonable and in many cases, theoretically motivated. Furthermore, we check whether the commonly selected features in each of our feature categories are similar to those found to be useful over the ARGUE corpus, as well as within other argument detection tasks in online fo- rums.</p><p>The rhetorical features that are consistently se- lected are very well motivated in the context of ar- gument detection. From the rhetorical structural features, we find COMPARISON relation features to be most commonly selected across all rhetorical feature sets. Other highly ranked features include the proportion of JOINT relations linking different authors, EXPLANATION relations between differ- ent authors, and the average depth of ELABORA- TION relations.</p><p>The COMPARISON relations are expected to in-</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Structural</head><p>Length of topic in sentences, to- tal number of authors, quotes in first sentence, quotes in second sentence, questions in first sen- tence, questions in second sen- tence, referrals to you and they in first half of post Meta Number of comments with la- bels, number of comments la- belled 'Flamebait', number of comments with scores of 4 or 5 FQG Number of connections, Num- ber of fragments, Maximum number of links from one node RhetStruct COMPARISON (same to diff, diff per post, diff percentage, avg ratio, same per post, same per- centage), EXPLANATION (avg ratio, diff per post), JOINT (diff percentage), ELABORA- TION (average depth) Discourse Markers Aggregated first sentence, Ag- gregated middle, 'and', 'oh', 'but' frequency counts N-grams 'don't ?', 'plus', 'private', 'anti', 'hey', 'present', 'mak- ing', 'developers'</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">RhetSent ELABORATION (variance in same post), ATTRIBUTION (variance in same post), CONTRAST (range in same post) Sentiment</formula><p>Range of sentiment scores in first sentence of all posts, range of sentiment scores over all posts <ref type="table">Table 4</ref>: Features found to be commonly selected over dif- ferent iterations of the classifiers dicate disagreement as motivated by theoretical considerations <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(Horn, 1989)</ref>. The importance of other rhetorical relation features can also be ex- plained by examining conversations in which they appear. In particular, EXPLANATION relations of- ten link authors who share viewpoints in a debate, especially when one author is trying to support the claim of another. The JOINT relations are also very well motivated. In the extreme case, conversations with a very high number of JOINT relations be- tween different users are usually news based. The high proportion of these relations indicates that many users have added information to the conver- sation about a specific item, such as adding new suggested videogame features to an ongoing list. Fewer JOINT relations seem to indicate disagree- ment, especially when found in conjunction with COMPARISON relations between different users. This appears to generally indicate that users are taking sides in a debate, and commenting specifi- cally on evidence which supports their viewpoint.</p><p>The average depth of ELABORATION relations reveals how deep the perceived connections are between users in a conversation over time. Deeper ELABORATION connections seem to indicate that the conversation is more cohesive. Alone, this does not signify disagreement/agreement but does seem to signify argument-style over news-style di- alogues. This is particularly helpful for differ- entiating between articles with many COMPARI- SON relations, as COMPARISON may be present in both news-style dialogues (e.g. comparing ci- tation styles) as well as argument style dialogues (e.g. arguing over which of two operating systems is superior).</p><p>For the combined sentiment and rhetorical rela- tions, range and variance in ELABORATION, CON- TRAST and ATTRIBUTION within the same post are found to be the most informative features. Ad- ditionally, neither ATTRIBUTION nor CONTRAST are useful features when only their structural in- formation is considered. In the case of ATTRI- BUTION, we hypothesize that the added sentiment score within the post differentiates between a neu- tral attribution (which would not signify disagree- ment) and a negative or positive attribution (which may signify disagreement). For CONTRAST, the added sentiment helps to distinguish between re- sponses such as "We will be trying the Microsoft software. We won't, however, be able to test the Apple equivalent." and "We will be trying the Mi- crosoft software. We won't, however, be trying the inferior Apple equivalent." where the second ex- ample more likely signals, or even provokes, dis- agreement.</p><p>Outside of the rhetorical features, the discourse markers which are found to be the most useful in our experiments agree with those found in the AR- GUE corpus <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Abbott et al., 2011</ref>). Namely, 'oh', 'but', 'because' and 'and' are discovered to be the most informative features. We also find the aggre- gated discourse marker frequency count in the first part of each post to be useful.</p><p>Previous analysis on Slashdot as a social net- work ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Gomez et al., 2008)</ref> suggests that the h- index of the conversation is relevant for detecting controversy in a posted article. We include the h-index as part of the Fragment Quotation Graph feature set, but surprisingly do not find this to be a useful feature. This may be due to our corpus involving relatively shallow conversational trees - the maximum h-index across all topics is three.</p><p>Comparing to Mishne and Glance's work, we also find quotations, questions and sentiment range near the beginning of a post to be very in- formative features. These are often selected across all feature sets which include the "basic" set.</p><p>The topics most often misclassified across all feature sets are those with relatively few sen- tences. In these cases, the rhetorical structure is not very well defined, and there is much less content available for detecting quotes, punctuation and referrals. Additionally, the feature sets which only use rhetorical and sentiment features consis- tently misclassify the same set of conversations (those that have lower quality discourse trees with few connections). When combined with the "ba- sic" feature set, these errors are mitigated, and the topics which the "basic" features miss are picked up by the rhetorical features. This leads to the best overall accuracy and F-score.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7.1">Discourse Parser</head><p>A major source of error in detecting disagreement arises because of inaccuracies in our discourse parser. In particular, document-level discourse parsing is a challenging task, with relatively few parsers available at the time of this analysis ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Hernault et al., 2010)</ref>. We chose to use the discourse parser developed by Joty et al. which both identifies elementary discourse units in a text, and then builds a document-level discourse tree using Conditional Random Fields. Because their approach uses an optimal parsing algorithm as opposed to a greedy parsing algorithm, they are able to achieve much higher accuracies in rela- tion and structure identification than other avail- able parsers. Here, results from their parser on the standard RST-DT dataset are presented since there is no currently available dialogic corpora to com- pare to.  <ref type="table">Table 5</ref>: Joty et al. document-level parser accuracy of the parser used in this paper. The parser was originally tested on two corpora: RST-DT and Instructional. HILDA was the state-of-the-art parser at that time. Span and Nuclearity met- rics assess the quality of the structure of the resulting tree, while the Relation metric assesses the quality of the relation labels.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>RST-DT Instructional</head><p>Examining the relation labels confusion matrix for the discourse parser in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 2</ref>, some of the chosen rhetorical features make even more sense.</p><p>In particular, the confusion of ELABORATION and EXPLANATION may account for the perceived im- portance of ELABORATION relations in the analy- sis. Likewise, CAUSE (which may be present when users attribute positive or negative qualities to an entity, signalling disagreement) is often confused with JOINT and ELABORATION which were often picked as important features by our classifiers.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="8">Conclusions and Future Work</head><p>In this paper, we have described a new set of fea- tures for detecting disagreement in online blog fo- rums. By treating a written conversation as a series of linked monologues, we can apply a document level discourse parser to extract a discourse tree for the conversation. We then aggregate this infor- mation in a relation graph, which allows us to cap- ture post-level rhetorical relations between users. Combining this approach with sentiment features shows significantly improved performance in both accuracy and F-score over a baseline consisting of structural and lexical features as well as re- ferral counts, punctuation, and discourse markers. In building our new crowd-sourced corpus from Slashdot, we have also shown the challenges of detecting subtle disagreement in a dataset that con- tains a significant number of news-style discus- sions.</p><p>In future work, we will improve sentiment fea- tures by considering methods to detect opinion- topic pairs in conversation, similar to <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">Somasundaran and Wiebe (2009)</ref>. Additionally, we will incorporate generalized dependency and POS fea- tures <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Abbott et al., 2011</ref>), which were not used in this analysis due to the very small number of training samples in our dataset. The fragment quo- tation graph features did not perform as well as we expected, and in future work we would like to in- vestigate this further. Furthermore, we will also explore how to create a discourse tree from the thread structure of a conversation (instead of from its temporal structure), and verify whether this im- proves the accuracy of the relation graphs, espe- cially when the temporal structure is not represen- tative of the reply-to relationships.</p><p>Finally, we plan to apply our novel feature set to other corpora (e.g., ARGUE) in order to study the utility of these features across genres and with re- spect to the accuracy of the discourse parser. This may provide insights into where discourse parsers can be most effectively used, as well as how to modify parsers to better capture rhetorical rela- tions between participants in conversation.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: Discourse tree (left) with extracted relation graph (right) for a sample conversation involving three users with three different posts P1, P2 and P3. N1, N2 and N3 are the corresponding nodes in the relation graph.</figDesc><graphic url="image-2.png" coords="4,353.96,104.43,171.72,82.79" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2: Confusion matrix for relation labels on RST-DT. The X-axis represents predicted relations, while the Y-axis corresponds to true values. The relations are Topic-Change (T-C), Topic-Comment (T-CM), Textual Organization (TO), Manner-Means (M-M), Comparison (CMP), Evaluation (EV), Summary (SU), Condition (CND), Enablement (EN), Cause (CA), Temporal (TE), Explanation (EX), Background (BA), Contrast (CO), Joint (JO), Same-Unit (S-U), Attribution (AT) and Elaboration (EL).</figDesc><graphic url="image-3.png" coords="10,72.00,62.81,218.26,176.11" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" validated="false"><head>Table 1 : Characteristics of the four categories determined from the crowd-sourced annotation. All values except for the number of topics in the category are given as the average score per topic across all topics in that category. Key: C and NC:</head><label>1</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Type 

Num P/A 
S/P 
W/P 
Num Authors 
W/S 
TBP 
TT 
TP 
Length 
Disagreement -C 
19.00 1.02 3.21 65.86 
15.84 
20.47 4.60 50.90 16.21 
49.11 
Disagreement -NC 
27.00 1.00 3.08 59.80 
14.07 
19.33 3.89 42.29 14.11 
42.26 
No disagreement -NC 28.00 1.03 2.85 57.25 
10.29 
19.94 6.83 50.12 10.50 
28.00 
No disagreement -C 
21.00 1.00 3.69 69.66 
6.29 
20.22 6.14 18.22 
6.29 
19.81 

Confident 
(score ≥ 0.75) and Not confident (score &lt; 0.75), Num: Number of topics in category, P/A: Posts per author, S/P: Sentences 
per post, W/P: Words per post, Num Authors: Number of authors, W/S: Words per sentence, TBP: Time between posts 
(minutes), TT: Total time in minutes, TP: Total posts, and Length: Length of topic in sentences 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" validated="false"><head>Table 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Basic: Meta-post, all structural, bias words, discourse markers, referrals, punctuation RhetAll: Structural and sen-
timent based rhetorical features All: Basic, all rhetorical, sentiment and FQG features. The N-gram models include unigrams 
and bi-grams. All feature sets in the bottom part of the table include rhetorical reatures. 

</table></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="2"> www.Crowdflower.com</note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">How can you say such things?!?: Recognizing Disagreement in Informal Political Argument</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rob</forename><surname>Abbott</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marilyn</forename><surname>Walker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Pranav</forename><surname>Anand</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jean</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Fox Tree</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Robeson</forename><surname>Bowmani</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Joseph</forename><surname>King</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of LSM</title>
		<meeting>LSM</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2" to="11" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Subgroup detection in ideological discussions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Amjad</forename><surname>Abu-Jbara</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mona</forename><surname>Diab</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Pradeep</forename><surname>Dasigi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dragomir</forename><surname>Radev</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of ACL</title>
		<meeting>ACL</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="399" to="409" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Mining newsgroups using networks arising from social behavior</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rakesh</forename><surname>Agrawal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ramakrishnan</forename><surname>Sridhar Rajagopalan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yirong</forename><surname>Srikant</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Xu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of WWW</title>
		<meeting>WWW</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="529" to="535" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Harmony and Dissonance: Organizing the People&apos;s Voices on Political Controversies</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rawia</forename><surname>Awadallah</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Maya</forename><surname>Ramanath</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gerhard</forename><surname>Weikum</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of WSDM</title>
		<meeting>WSDM</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="523" to="532" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Using non-lexical features for identifying factual and opinionative threads in online forums</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Prakhar</forename><surname>Biyani</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sumit</forename><surname>Bhatia</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Cornelia</forename><surname>Caragea</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Prasenjit</forename><surname>Mitra</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Knowledge-Based Systems</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>in press</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Politeness: Some universals in language usage</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Penelope</forename><surname>Brown</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Stephen</forename><surname>Levinson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1987" />
			<publisher>Cambridge University Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Extractive vs. NLG-based Abstractive Summarization of Evaluative Text: The Effect of Corpus Controversiality</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Giuseppe</forename><surname>Carenini</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jackie</forename><surname>Cheung</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of INLG</title>
		<meeting>INLG</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="33" to="41" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Summarizing Email Conversations with Clue Words</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Giuseppe</forename><surname>Carenini</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Raymond</forename><surname>Ng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xiaodong</forename><surname>Zhou</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of WWW</title>
		<meeting>WWW</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="91" to="100" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Identifying controversial issues and their subtopics in news articles</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yoonjung</forename><surname>Choi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yuchul</forename><surname>Jung</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sung-Hyon</forename><surname>Myaeng</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of PAISI</title>
		<meeting>PAISI</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="140" to="153" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Recognizing Arguing Subjectivity and Argument Tags</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alexander</forename><surname>Conrad</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Janyce</forename><surname>Wiebe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rebecca</forename><surname>Hwa</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ACL Workshop on ExtraPropositional Aspects of Meaning</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="80" to="88" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Discourse markers across speakers and settings</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jean</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Fox Tree</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Language and Linguistics Compass</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="113" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Identifying agreement and disagreement in conversational speech: Use of bayesian networks to model pragmatic dependencies</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michel</forename><surname>Galley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kathleen</forename><surname>Mckeown</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Julia</forename><surname>Hirschberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Elizabeth</forename><surname>Shriberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of ACL</title>
		<meeting>ACL</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
			<biblScope unit="page">669</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Agreement Detection in Multiparty Conversation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sebastian</forename><surname>Germesin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Theresa</forename><surname>Wilson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of International Conference on Multimodal Interfaces</title>
		<meeting>International Conference on Multimodal Interfaces</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="7" to="14" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Statistical Analysis of the Social Network and Discussion Threads in Slashdot</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Vicenc</forename><surname>Gomez</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Andreas</forename><surname>Kaltenbrunner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Vicente</forename><surname>Lopez</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of WWW</title>
		<meeting>WWW</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="645" to="654" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">What&apos;s with the attitude?: identifying sentences with attitude in online discussions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ahmed</forename><surname>Hassan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Vahed</forename><surname>Qazvinian</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dragomir</forename><surname>Radev</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of EMNLP</title>
		<meeting>EMNLP</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1245" to="1255" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">HILDA: A Discourse Parser Using Support Vector Machine Classification</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hugo</forename><surname>Hernault</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Helmut</forename><surname>Prendinger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Duverle</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mitsuru</forename><surname>Ishizuka</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Dialogue and Discourse</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="33" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">A natural history of negation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Laurence</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Horn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1989" />
			<publisher>Chicago University Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Unsupervised modeling of dialog acts in asynchronous conversations</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Shafiq</forename><surname>Joty</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Giuseppe</forename><surname>Carenini</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chin-Yew</forename><surname>Lin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of IJCAI</title>
		<meeting>IJCAI</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1807" to="1813" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Combining Intra-and Multisentential Rhetorical Parsing for Document-level Discourse Analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Shafiq</forename><surname>Joty</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Giuseppe</forename><surname>Carenini</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Raymond</forename><surname>Ng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yashar</forename><surname>Mehdad</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of ACL</title>
		<meeting>ACL</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Topic Segmentation and Labeling in Asynchronous Conversations</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Shafiq</forename><surname>Joty</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Giuseppe</forename><surname>Carenini</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Raymond</forename><surname>Ng</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of AI Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">47</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="521" to="573" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Topical Positioning: A New Method for Predicting Opinion Changes in Conversation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ching-Sheng</forename><surname>Lin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Samira</forename><surname>Shaikh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jennifer</forename><surname>Stromergalley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jennifer</forename><surname>Crowley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tomek</forename><surname>Strzalkowski</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Veena</forename><surname>Ravishankar</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of LASM</title>
		<meeting>LASM</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="41" to="48" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Rhetorical structure theory: Toward a functional theory of text organization</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>William</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sandra</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Mann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Thompson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Text</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="243" to="281" />
			<date type="published" when="1988" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Leave a reply: An analysis of weblog comments</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gilad</forename><surname>Mishne</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Natalie</forename><surname>Glance</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of WWW</title>
		<meeting>WWW</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Topic Independent Identification of Agreement and Disagreement in Social Media Dialogue</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Amita</forename><surname>Misra</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marilyn</forename><surname>Walker</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of SIGDIAL</title>
		<meeting>SIGDIAL</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="41" to="50" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Modeling review comments</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Arjun</forename><surname>Mukherjee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bing</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of ACL</title>
		<meeting>ACL</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="320" to="329" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Support or Oppose? Classifying Positions in Online Debates from Reply Activities and Opinion Expressions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Akiko</forename><surname>Murakami</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rudy</forename><surname>Raymond</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the International Conference on Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the International Conference on Computational Linguistics</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="869" to="875" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Modeling topic control to detect influence in conversations using nonparametric topic models</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jordan</forename><surname>Viet-An Nguyen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Philip</forename><surname>Boyd-Graber</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Deborah</forename><surname>Resnik</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jennifer</forename><surname>Cai</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yuanxin</forename><surname>Midberry</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Machine Learning</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">95</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="381" to="421" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Extracting Product Features and Opinions from Reviews</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ana-Maria</forename><surname>Popescu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Oren</forename><surname>Etzioni</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of HLT/EMNLP</title>
		<meeting>HLT/EMNLP</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="339" to="346" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Detecting controversial events from twitter</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ana-Maria</forename><surname>Popescu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marco</forename><surname>Pennacchiotti</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of CIKM</title>
		<meeting>CIKM</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1873" to="1876" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Multimodal subjectivity analysis of multiparty conversation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Stephan</forename><surname>Raaijmakers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Khiet</forename><surname>Truong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Theresa</forename><surname>Wilson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of EMNLP</title>
		<meeting>EMNLP</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="466" to="474" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Linguistic Models for Analyzing and Detecting Biased Language</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marta</forename><surname>Recasens</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Cristian</forename><surname>Danescu-Niculescu-Mizil</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dan</forename><surname>Jurafsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of ACL</title>
		<meeting>ACL</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page">16501659</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Detecting Arguing and Sentiment in Meetings</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Swapna</forename><surname>Somasundaran</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Josef</forename><surname>Ruppenhofer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Janyce</forename><surname>Wiebe</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of SIGDIAL Workshop on Discourse and Dialogue</title>
		<meeting>SIGDIAL Workshop on Discourse and Dialogue</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Recognizing stances in online debates</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Swapna</forename><surname>Somasundaran</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Janyce</forename><surname>Wiebe</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of ACL</title>
		<meeting>ACL</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="226" to="234" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Recognizing stances in ideological on-line debates</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Swapna</forename><surname>Somasundaran</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Janyce</forename><surname>Wiebe</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of NAACL, Workshop on Computational Approaches to Analysis and Generation of Emotion in Text</title>
		<meeting>NAACL, Workshop on Computational Approaches to Analysis and Generation of Emotion in Text</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<biblScope unit="page">116124</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Annotating Argumentation Acts in Spoken Dialog</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Amanda</forename><surname>Stent</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">James</forename><surname>Allen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
<note type="report_type">Technical Report</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Lexicon-based methods for sentiment analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Maite</forename><surname>Taboada</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Julian</forename><surname>Brooke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Milan</forename><surname>Tofiloski</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kimberly</forename><surname>Voll</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Manfred</forename><surname>Stede</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Computational Linguistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">37</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="267" to="307" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Get out the vote: Determining support or opposition from Congressional floor-debate transcripts</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Matt</forename><surname>Thomas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bo</forename><surname>Pang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lillian</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of EMNLP</title>
		<meeting>EMNLP</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="327" to="335" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Detection of agreement and disagreement in broadcast conversations</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wen</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sibel</forename><surname>Yaman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kristen</forename><surname>Precoda</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Colleen</forename><surname>Richey</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Geoffrey</forename><surname>Raymond</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of ACL</title>
		<meeting>ACL</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="374" to="378" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Sentenceinitial discourse connectives, discourse structure and semantics</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bonnie</forename><surname>Webber</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rashmi</forename><surname>Prasad</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Workshop on Formal and Experimental Approaches to Discourse Particles and Modal Adverbs</title>
		<meeting>the Workshop on Formal and Experimental Approaches to Discourse Particles and Modal Adverbs</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Unifying local and global agreement and disagreement classification in online debates</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jie</forename><surname>Yin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Paul</forename><surname>Thomas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nalin</forename><surname>Narang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Cecile</forename><surname>Paris</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of Computational Approaches to Subjectivity and Sentiment Analysis</title>
		<meeting>Computational Approaches to Subjectivity and Sentiment Analysis</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="61" to="69" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
