<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T12:54+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Semi-Supervised Chinese Word Segmentation Using Partial-Label Learning With Conditional Random Fields</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date>October 25-29, 2014</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Fan</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
							<email>fan.yang@nuance.com</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Nuance Communications Inc</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">Nuance Communications Inc</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Paul</forename><surname>Vozila</surname></persName>
							<email>paul.vozila@nuance.com</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Nuance Communications Inc</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">Nuance Communications Inc</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Semi-Supervised Chinese Word Segmentation Using Partial-Label Learning With Conditional Random Fields</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2014 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP)</title>
						<meeting>the 2014 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP) <address><addrLine>Doha, Qatar. c</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="90" to="98"/>
							<date type="published">October 25-29, 2014</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>There is rich knowledge encoded in on-line web data. For example, punctuation and entity tags in Wikipedia data define some word boundaries in a sentence. In this paper we adopt partial-label learning with conditional random fields to make use of this valuable knowledge for semi-supervised Chinese word segmenta-tion. The basic idea of partial-label learning is to optimize a cost function that marginalizes the probability mass in the constrained space that encodes this knowledge. By integrating some domain adaptation techniques, such as EasyAdapt, our result reaches an F-measure of 95.98% on the CTB-6 corpus, a significant improvement from both the supervised baseline and a previous proposed approach, namely constrained decode.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>A general approach for supervised Chinese word segmentation is to formulate it as a character se- quence labeling problem, to label each charac- ter with its location in a word. For example, <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Xue (2003)</ref> proposes a four-label scheme based on some linguistic intuitions: 'B' for the beginning character of a word, 'I' for the internal characters, 'E' for the ending character, and 'S' for single- character word. Thus the word sequence "洽谈会 很 成功" can be turned into a character sequence with labels as 洽\B 谈\I 会\E 很\S 成\B 功\E. A machine learning algorithm for sequence label- ing, such as conditional random fields (CRF) <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Lafferty et al., 2001)</ref>, can be applied to the labelled training data to learn a model.</p><p>Labelled data for supervised learning of Chi- nese word segmentation, however, is usually ex- pensive and tends to be of a limited amount. Re- searchers are thus interested in semi-supervised learning, which is to make use of unlabelled data to further improve the performance of supervised learning. There is a large amount of unlabelled data available, for example, the Gigaword corpus in the LDC catalog or the Chinese Wikipedia on the web.</p><p>Faced with the large amount of unlabelled data, an intuitive idea is to use self-training or EM, by first training a baseline model (from the supervised data) and then iteratively decoding the unlabelled data and updating the baseline model. <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Jiao et al. (2006)</ref> and <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Mann and McCallum (2007)</ref> further propose to minimize the entropy of the predicted label distribution on unlabeled data and use it as a regularization term in CRF (i.e. entropy reg- ularization). Beyond these ideas, <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Liang (2005)</ref> and Sun and Xu (2011) experiment with deriv- ing a large set of statistical features such as mu- tual information and accessor variety from un- labelled data, and add them to supervised dis- criminative training. <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">Zeng et al. (2013b)</ref> experi- ment with graph propagation to extract informa- tion from unlabelled data to regularize the CRF training. <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Yang and Vozila (2013)</ref>, <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">Zhang et al. (2013)</ref>, and <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Zeng et al. (2013a)</ref> experiment with co-training for semi-supervised Chinese word seg- mentation. All these approaches only leverage the distribution of the unlabelled data, yet do not make use of the knowledge that the unlabelled data might have integrated in.</p><p>There could be valuable information encoded within the unlabelled data that researchers can take advantage of. For example, punctuation creates natural word boundaries ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Li and Sun, 2009)</ref>: the character before a comma can only be labelled as either 'S' or 'E', while the character after a comma can only be labelled as 'S' or 'B'. Fur- thermore, entity tags (HTML tags or Wikipedia tags) on the web, such as emphasis and cross refer- ence, also provide rich information for word seg- mentation: they might define a word or at least give word boundary information similar to punc- tuation. <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Jiang et al. (2013)</ref> refer to such structural information on the web as natural annotations, and propose that they encode knowledge for NLP. For Chinese word segmentation, natural annotations and punctuation create a sausage 1 constraint for the possible labels, as illustrated in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref>. In the sentence "近年来，人工智能和机器学习迅 猛发展。", the first character 近 can only be la- belled with 'S' or 'B'; and the characters 来 before the comma and 展 before the Chinese period can only be labelled as 'S' or 'E'. "人工智能" and "机 器学习" are two Wikipedia entities, and so they define the word boundaries before the first char- acter and after the last character of the entities as well. The single character 和 between these two entities has only one label 'S'. This sausage con- straint thus encodes rich information for word seg- mentation.</p><p>To make use of the knowledge encoded in the sausage constraint, <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Jiang et al. (2013)</ref> adopt a con- strained decode approach. They first train a base- line model with labelled data, and then run con- strained decode on the unlabelled data by binding the search space with the sausage; and so the de- coded labels are consistent with the sausage con- straint. The unlabelled data, together with the labels from constrained decode, are then selec- tively added to the labelled data for training the final model. This approach, using constrained de- code as a middle step, provides an indirect way of leaning the knowledge. However, the middle step, constrained decode, has the risk of reinforc- ing the errors in the baseline model: the decoded labels added to the training data for building the final model might contain errors introduced from the baseline model. The knowledge encoded in the data carrying the information from punctuation and natural annotations is thus polluted by the er- rorful re-decoded labels.</p><p>A sentence where each character has exactly one label is fully-labelled; and a sentence where each character receives all possible labels is zero- labelled. A sentence with sausage-constrained la- bels can be viewed as partially-labelled. These partial labels carry valuable information that re- searchers would like to learn in a model, yet the normal CRF training typically uses fully-labelled sentences. Recently, <ref type="bibr">Täckström et al. (2013)</ref> pro- pose an approach to train a CRF model directly from partial labels. The basic idea is to marginal- ize the probability mass of the constrained sausage in the cost function. The normal CRF training us- ing fully-labelled sentences is a special case where the sausage constraint is a linear line; while on the other hand a zero-labelled sentence, where the sausage constraint is the full lattice, makes no con- tribution in the learning since the sum of proba- bilities is deemed to be one. This new approach, without the need of using constrained re-decoding as a middle step, provides a direct means to learn the knowledge in the partial labels.</p><p>In this research we explore using the partial- label learning for semi-supervised Chinese word segmentation. We use the CTB-6 corpus as the labelled training, development and test data, and use the Chinese Wikipedia as the unlabelled data. We first train a baseline model with labelled data only, and then selectively add Wikipedia data with partial labels to build a second model. Because the Wikipedia data is out of domain and has dis- tribution bias, we also experiment with two do- main adaptation techniques: model interpolation and EasyAdapt <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Daumé III, 2007)</ref>. Our result reaches an F-measure of 95.98%, an absolute im- provement of 0.72% over the very strong base-line (corresponding to 15.19% relative error re- duction), and 0.33% over the constrained decode approach (corresponding to 7.59% relative error reduction). We conduct a detailed error analy- sis, illustrating how partial-label learning excels constrained decode in learning the knowledge en- coded in the Wikipedia data. As a note, our result also out-performs ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Wang et al., 2011</ref>) and (Sun and Xu, 2011).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Partial-Label Learning with CRF</head><p>In this section, we review in more detail the partial-label learning algorithm with CRF pro- posed by <ref type="bibr">(Täckström et al., 2013)</ref>. CRF is an exponential model that expresses the conditional probability of the labels given a sequence, as Equation 1, where y denotes the labels, x denotes the sequence, Φ(x, y) denotes the feature func- tions, and θ is the parameter vector.</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">Z(x) = ∑ y exp(θ T Φ(x, y)) is the normalization term. p θ (y|x) = exp(θ T Φ(x, y)) Z(x)<label>(1)</label></formula><p>In full-label training, where each item in the se- quence is labelled with exactly one tag, maximum likelihood is typically used as the optimization tar- get. We simply sum up the log-likelihood of the n labelled sequences in the training set, as shown in Equation 2.</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">L(θ) = n ∑ i=1 log p θ (y|x) = n ∑ i=1 (θ T Φ(x i , y i ) − log Z(x i )) (2)</formula><p>The gradient is calculated as Equation 3, in which the first term 1 n ∑ n i=1 Φ j is the empirical expectation of feature function Φ j , and the second term E[Φ j ] is the model expectation. Typically a forward-backward process is adopted for calculat- ing the latter.</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">∂ ∂θ j L(θ) = 1 n n ∑ i=1 Φ j − E[Φ j ]<label>(3)</label></formula><p>In partial-label training, each item in the se- quence receives multiple labels, and so for each sequence we have a sausage constraint, denoted asˆY asˆ asˆY (x, ˜ y). The marginal probability of the sausage is defined as Equation 4.</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">p θ ( ˆ Y (x, ˜ y)|x) = ∑ y∈ˆYy∈ˆ y∈ˆY (x,˜ y) p θ (y|x)<label>(4)</label></formula><p>The optimization target thus is to maximize the probability mass of the sausage, as shown in Equa- tion 5.</p><formula xml:id="formula_4">L(θ) = n ∑ i=1 logp θ ( ˆ Y (x i , ˜ y i )|x i )<label>(5)</label></formula><p>A gradient-based approach such as L-BFGS ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Liu and Nocedal, 1989)</ref> can be employed to op- timize Equation 5. The gradient is calculated as Equation 6, where</p><formula xml:id="formula_5">E ˆ Y (x,˜ y) [Φ j ]</formula><p>is the empirical ex- pectation of feature function Φ j constrained by the sausage, and E[Φ j ] is the same model expectation as in standard CRF.</p><formula xml:id="formula_6">E ˆ Y (x,˜ y) [Φ j ]</formula><p>can be calculated via a forward-backward process in the constrained sausage.</p><formula xml:id="formula_7">∂ ∂θ j L(θ) = E ˆ Y (x,˜ y) [Φ j ] − E[Φ j ]<label>(6)</label></formula><p>For fully-labelled sentences,</p><formula xml:id="formula_8">E ˆ Y (x,˜ y) [Φ j ] = 1 n ∑ n i=1</formula><p>Φ j , and so the standard CRF is actually a special case of the partial-label learning.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Experiment setup</head><p>In this section we describe the basic setup for our experiments of semi-supervised Chinese word segmentation.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Data</head><p>We use the CTB-6 corpus as the labelled data. We follow the official CTB-6 guideline in splitting the corpus into a training set, a development set, and a test set. The training set has 23420 sentences; the development set has 2079 sentences; and the test set has 2796 sentences. These are fully-labelled data.</p><p>For unlabelled data we use the Chinese Wikipedia. The Wikipedia data is quite noisy and asks for a lot of cleaning. We first filter out references and lists etc., and sentences with ob- viously bad segmentations, for example, where every character is separated by a space. We also remove sentences that contain mostly En- glish words. We then convert all characters into full-width. We also convert traditional Chinese characters into simplified characters using the tool mediawiki-zhconverter 2 . We then randomly select 7737 sentences and reserve them as the test set.</p><p>To create the partial labels in the Wikipedia data, we use the information from cross-reference, emphasis, and punctuation. In our pilot study we found that it's beneficial to force a cross-reference or emphasis entity as a word when the item has 2 or 3 characters. That is, if an entity in the Wikipedia has three characters it receives the la- bels of "BIE"; and if it has two characters it is la- belled as "BE". <ref type="bibr">3</ref> </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Supervised baseline model</head><p>We create the baseline supervised model by using an order-1 linear CRF with L2 regularization, to label a character sequence with the four candidate labels "BIES". We use the tool wapiti ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Lavergne et al., 2010)</ref>. Character-level features :</p><formula xml:id="formula_9">• Character unigrams: c −2 , c −1 , c 0 , c 1 , c 2 • Character bigrams: c −2 c −1 , c −1 c −0 , c 0 c 1 , c 1 c 2 • Consecutive character equivalence: ?c −2 = c −1 , ?c −1 = c −0 , ?c 0 = c 1 , ?c 1 = c 2 • Separated character equivalence: ?c −3 = c −1 , ?c −2 = c 0 , ?c −1 = c 1 , ?c 0 = c 2 , ?c 1 = c 3 • Whether the current character is a punc- tuation: ?Punct(c 0 ) • Character sequence pattern: T (C −2 )T (C −1 )T (C 0 )T (C 1 )T (C 2 ).</formula><p>We classify all characters into four types. Type one has three characters '年' (year) '月' (month) '日' (date). Type two includes number characters. Type three includes English characters. All others are Type four characters. Thus "去年三月S" would generate the character sequence pattern "41213".</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Word-level features :</head><p>• The identity of the string c[s : i] (i−6 &lt; s &lt; i), if it matches a word from the list of word unigrams; multiple features could be generated.</p><p>• <ref type="bibr">, 2011</ref>). If the current character c 0 and its surrounding context compose an idiom, we generate a feature for c 0 of its position in the idiom. For example, if c −1 c 0 c 1 c 2 is an idiom, we generate fea- ture "Idiom-2" for c 0 .</p><note type="other">The identity of the string c[i : e] (i &lt; e &lt; i+6), if it matches a word; multiple features could be generated. • The identity of the bi-gram c[s : i − 1]c[i : e] (i − 6 &lt; s, e &lt; i + 6), if it matches a word bigram; multiple fea- tures could be generated. • The identity of the bi-gram c[s : i]c[i + 1 : e] (i − 6 &lt; s, e &lt; i +6), if it matches a word bigram; multiple features could be generated. • Idiom. We use the idiom list from (Sun and Xu</note><p>The above features together with label bigrams are fed to wapiti for training. The supervised base- line model is created with the CTB-6 corpus with- out the use of Wikipedia data.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3">Partial-label learning</head><p>The overall process of applying partial-label learn- ing to Wikipedia data is shown in Algorithm 1. Following ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Jiang et al., 2013)</ref>, we first train the supervised baseline model, and use it to estimate the potential contribution for each sentence in the Wikipedia training data. We label the sentence with the baseline model, and then compare the labels with the constrained sausage. For each character, a consistent label is defined as an ele- ment in the constrained labels. For example, if the constrained labels for a character are "SB", the label 'S' or 'B' is consistent but 'I' or 'E' is not. The number of inconsistent labels for each sentence is then used as its potential contribution to the partial-label learning: higher number indi- cates that the partial-labels for the sentence con- tain more knowledge that the baseline system does not integrate, and so have higher potential contri- bution. The Wikipedia training sentences are then ranked by their potential contribution, and the top K sentences together with their partial labels are then added to the CTB-6 training data to build a new model, using partial-label learning. <ref type="bibr">4</ref> In our experiments, we try six data points with K = 100k, 200k, 300k, 400k, 500k, 600k. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 2</ref> gives a rough idea of the knowledge encoded in Wikipedia for these data points with inconsistency ratio and label reduction. Inconsistency ratio is the percentage of characters that have inconsistent la- bels; and label reduction is the percentage of the labels reduced in the full lattice.</p><p>We modify wapiti to implement the partial-label learning as described in Section 2. Same as base- line, L2 regularization is adopted.</p><p>Algorithm 1 Partial-label learning 1. Train supervised baseline model M 0 2. For each sentence x in Wiki-Train:</p><formula xml:id="formula_10">3. y ← Decode(x, M 0 ) 4. diff ← Inconsistent(y, ˆ Y (x, ˜ y)) 5. if diff &gt; 0: 6. C ← C ∪ ( ˆ Y (x, ˜ y), diff) 7</formula><p>. Sort(C, diff, reverse) 8. Train model M pl with CTB-6 and top K sen- tences in C using partial-label learning</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.4">Constrained decode</head><p>Jiang et al. (2013) implement the constrained de- code algorithm with perceptron. However, CRF is generally believed to out-perform perceptron, yet the comparison of CRF vs perceptron is out <ref type="bibr">4</ref> Knowledge is sparsely distributed in the Wikipedia data. Using the Wikipedia data without the CTB-6 data for partial- label learning does not necessarily guarantee convergence. Also the CTB-6 training data helps to learn that certain la- bel transitions, such as "B B" or "E E", are not legal. of the scope of this paper. Thus for fair compar- ison, we re-implement the constrained decode al- gorithm with CRF.</p><p>Algorithm 2 shows the constrained decode im- plementation. We first train the baseline model with the CTB-6 data. We then use this baseline model to run normal decode and constrained de- code for each sentence in the Wikipedia training set. If the normal decode and constrained decode have different labels, we add the constrained de- code together with the number of different labels to the filtered Wikipedia training corpus. The fil- tered Wikipedia training corpus is then sorted us- ing the number of different labels, and the top K sentences with constrained decoded labels are then added to the CTB-6 training data for building a new model using normal CRF.</p><p>Algorithm 2 Constrained decode 1. Train supervised baseline model M 0 2. For each sentence x in Wiki-Train:</p><formula xml:id="formula_11">3. y ← Decode(x, M 0 ) 4. ¯ y ← ConstrainedDecode(x, M 0 ) 5. diff ← Difference(y, ¯ y) 6. if diff &gt; 0: 7.</formula><p>C ← C ∪ (¯ y, diff) 8. Sort(C, diff, reverse) 9. Train model M cd with CTB-6 and top K sen- tences in C using normal CRF</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Evaluation on Wikipedia test set</head><p>In order to determine how well the models learn the encoded knowledge (i.e. partial labels) from the Wikipedia data, we first evaluate the mod- els against the Wikipedia test set. The Wikipedia test set, however, is only partially-labelled. Thus the metric we use here is consistent label accu- racy, similar to how we rank the sentences in Sec- tion 3.3, defined as whether a predicted label for a character is an element in the constrained la- bels. Because partial labels are only sparsely dis- tributed in the test data, a lot of characters receive all four labels in the constrained sausage. Eval- uating against characters with all four labels do not really represent the models' difference as it is deemed to be consistent. Thus beyond evaluating against all characters in the Wikipedia test set (re- ferred to as Full measurement), we also evaluate against characters that are only constrained with less than four labels (referred to as Label mea- surement). The Label measurement focuses on en-coded knowledge in the test set and so can better represent the model's capability of learning from the partial labels.</p><p>Results are shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Figure 3</ref> with the Full measurement and in <ref type="figure">Figure 4</ref> with the Label mea- surement. The x axes are the size of Wikipedia training data, as explained in Section 3.3. As can be seen, both constrained decode and partial- label learning perform much better than the base- line supervised model that is trained from CTB-6 data only, indicating that both of them are learning the encoded knowledge from the Wikipedia train- ing data. Also we see the trend that the perfor- mance improves with more data in training, also suggesting the learning of encoded knowledge. Most importantly, we see that partial-label learn- ing consistently out-performs constrained decode in all data points. With the Label measurement, partial-label learning gives 1.7% or higher abso- lute improvement over constrained decode across all data points. At the data point of 600k, con- strained decode gives an accuracy of 97.14%, while partial-label learning gives 98.93% (base- line model gives 87.08%). The relative gain (from learning the knowledge) of partial-label learning over constrained decode is thus 18% ((98.93 − 97.14)/(97.14 − 87.08)). These results suggest that partial-label learning is more effective in learning the encoded knowledge in the Wikipedia data than constrained decode.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">CTB evaluation 5.1 Model adaptation</head><p>Our ultimate goal, however, is to determine whether we can leverage the encoded knowledge in the Wikipedia data to improve the word seg- mentation in CTB-6. We run our models against the CTB-6 test set, with results shown in <ref type="figure">Fig- ure 5</ref>. Because we have fully-labelled sentences in the CTB-6 data, we adopt the F-measure as our evaluation metric here. The baseline model achieves 95.26% in F-measure, providing a state- of-the-art supervised performance. Constrained decode is able to improve on this already very strong baseline performance, and we see the nice trend of higher performance with more unlabeled data for training, indicating that constrained de- code is making use of the encoded knowledge in the Wikipedia data to help CTB-6 segmentation.</p><p>When we look at the partial-label model, how- ever, the results tell a totally different story.  , it actually performs worse than the base- line model, and the more data added to train- ing, the worse the performance is. In the previ- ous section we show that partial-label learning is more effective in learning the encoded knowledge in Wikipedia data than constrained decode. So, what goes wrong? We hypothesize that there is an out-of-domain distribution bias in the partial la- bels, and so the more data we add, the worse the in-domain performance is. Constrained decode actually helps to smooth out the out-of-domain distribution bias by using the re-decoded labels with the in-domain supervised baseline model. For example, both the baseline model and con- strained decode correctly give the segmentation "提供/了/运输/和/给 给 给排 排 排水 水 水/之/便", while partial- label learning gives incorrect segmentation "提 供/了/运 输/和/给 给 给/排 排 排 水 水 水/之/便". Looking at the Wikipedia training data, 排水 is tagged as an en- tity 13 times; and 给 排 水, although occurs 13 times in the data, is never tagged as an entity. Partial-label learning, which focuses on the tagged entities, thus overrules the segmentation of 给排 水. Constrained decode, on the other hand, by us- ing the correctly re-decoded labels from the base- line model, observes enough evidence to correctly segment 给排水 as a word.</p><p>To smooth out the out-of-domain distribution bias, we experiment with two approaches: model interpolation and EasyAdapt <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Daumé III, 2007)</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.1.1">Model interpolation</head><p>We linearly interpolate the model of partial-label learning M pl with the baseline model M 0 to create the final model M pl + , as shown in Equation 7. The interpolation weight is optimized via a grid search between 0.0 and 1.0 with a step of 0.1, tuned on the CTB-6 development set. Again we modify wapiti so that it takes two models and an interpo- lation weight as input. For each model it creates a search lattice with posteriors, and then linearly combines the two lattices using the interpolation weight to create the final search space for decod- ing. As shown in <ref type="figure">Figure 5</ref>, model M pl + consis- tently out-performs constrained decode in all data points. We also see the trend of better performance with more training data.</p><formula xml:id="formula_12">M pl + = λ * M 0 + (1 − λ) * M pl (7)</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.1.2">EasyAdapt</head><p>EasyAdapt is a straightforward technique but has been shown effective in many domain adaptation tasks <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Daumé III, 2007)</ref>. We train the model M pl ea with feature augmentation. For each out-of- domain training instance &lt; x o , y o &gt;, where x o is the input features and y o is the (partial) labels, we copy the features and file them as an additional feature set, and so the training instance becomes &lt; x o , x o , y o &gt;. The in-domain training data remains the same. Consistent with <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Daumé III, 2007)</ref>, EasyAdapt gives us the best performance, as show in <ref type="figure">Figure 5</ref>. Furthermore, unlike in ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Jiang et al., 2013</ref>) where they find a plateau, our results show no harm adding more training data for partial-label learning when integrated with domain adaptation, although the performance seems to saturate after 400k sentences.</p><p>Finally, we search for the parameter setting of best performance on the CTB-6 development set, which is to use EasyAdapt with K = 600k sen- tences of Wikipedia data. With this setting, the performance on the CTB-6 test set is 95.98% in F-measure. This is 0.72% absolute improve- ment over supervised baseline (corresponding to 15.19% relative error reduction), and 0.33% ab- solute improvement over constrained decode (cor- responding to 7.59% relative error reduction); the differences are both statistically significant (p &lt; 0.001). 5 As a note, this result out-performs (Sun and Xu, 2011) (95.44%) and ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Wang et al., 2011</ref>) (95.79%), and the differences are also statistically significant (p &lt; 0.001).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.2">Analysis with examples</head><p>To better understand why partial-label learning is more effective in learning the encoded knowledge, we look at cases where M 0 and M cd have the in- correct segmentation while M pl (and its domain adaptation variance M pl + and M pl ea ) have the cor- rect segmentation. We find that the majority is due to the error in re-decoded labels outside of en- coded knowledge. For example, M 0 and M cd give the segmentation "地震/为/里 里 里/氏 氏 氏/6.9/ 级", yet the correct segmentation given by partial-label learn- ing is "地 震/为/里 里 里 氏 氏 氏/6.9/ 级". Looking at the Wikipedia training data, there are 38 tagged enti- ties of 里氏, but there are another 190 mentions of 里氏 that are not tagged as an entity. Thus for con- strained decode it sees 38 cases of "里\B 氏\E" and 190 cases of "里\S 氏\S" in the Wikipedia training data. The former comes from the encoded knowledge while the latter comes from re-decoded labels by the baseline model. The much bigger number of incorrect labels from the baseline re- decoding badly pollute the encoded knowledge. This example illustrates that constrained decode reinforces the errors from the baseline. On the other hand, the training materials for partial-label learning are purely the encoded knowledge, which is not impacted by the baseline model error. In this example, partial-label learning focuses only on the 38 cases of "里\B 氏\E" and so is able to learn that 里氏 is a word.</p><p>As a final remark, we want to make a point that, although the re-decoded labels serve to smooth out the distribution bias, the Wikipedia data is indeed not the ideal data set for such a purpose, because it itself is out of domain. The performance tends to degrade when we apply the baseline model to re-decode the out-of-domain Wikipedia data. The errorful re-decoded labels, when being used to train the model M cd , could lead to further er- rors. For example, the baseline model M 0 is able to give the correct segmentation "电脑/元 元 元器 器 器件 件 件" in the CTB-6 test set. However, when it is ap- plied to the Wikipedia data for constrained de- code, for the seven occurrences of 元器件, three of which are correctly labelled as "元\B 器\I 件\E", but the other four have incorrect labels. The fi- nal model M cd trained from these labels then gives incorrect segmentation "两/市/生 产/的/电 脑/元 元 元/器 器 器件 件 件/大量/销往/世界/各地" in the CTB- 6 test set. On the other hand, model interpolation or EasyAdapt with partial-label learning, focusing only on the encoded knowledge and not being im- pacted by the errorful re-decoded labels, performs correctly in this case. For a more fair comparison between partial-label learning and constrained de- code, we have also plotted the results of model in- terpolation and EasyAdapt for constrained decode in <ref type="figure">Figure 5</ref>. As can be seen, they improve on con- strained decode a bit but still fall behind the cor- respondent domain adaptation approach of partial- label learning.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Conclusion and future work</head><p>There is rich information encoded in online web data. For example, punctuation and entity tags de- fine some word boundaries. In this paper we show the effectiveness of partial-label learning in digest- ing the encoded knowledge from Wikipedia data for the task of Chinese word segmentation. Unlike approaches such as constrained decode that use the errorful re-decoded labels, partial-label learn- ing provides a direct means to learn the encoded knowledge. By integrating some domain adap- tation techniques such as EasyAdapt, we achieve an F-measure of 95.98% in the CTB-6 corpus, a significant improvement from both the supervised baseline and constrained decode. Our results also beat ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Wang et al., 2011</ref>) and ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Sun and Xu, 2011)</ref>.</p><p>In this research we employ a sausage constraint to encode the knowledge for Chinese word seg- mentation. However, a sausage constraint does not reflect the legal label sequence. For exam- ple, in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref> the links between label 'B' and label 'S', between 'S' and 'E', and between 'E' and 'I' are illegal, and can confuse the machine learning. In our current work we solve this issue by adding some fully-labelled data into training. Instead we can easily extend our work to use a lat- tice constraint by removing the illegal transitions from the sausage. The partial-label learning stands the same, by executing the forward-backward pro- cess in the constrained lattice. In future work we will examine partial-label learning with this more enforced lattice constraint in depth.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: Sausage constraint (partial labels) from natural annotations and punctuation</figDesc><graphic url="image-1.png" coords="2,72.00,94.71,444.84,95.70" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Following Sun et al. (2009), Sun (2010), and Low et al. (2005), we extract two types of fea- tures: character-level features and word-level fea- tures. Given a character c 0 in the character se- quence ...c −2 c −1 c 0 c 1 c 2 ...:</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2: Encoded knowledge: inconsistency ratio and label reduction</figDesc><graphic url="image-2.png" coords="5,72.00,106.60,220.80,128.40" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>Figure 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Figure 3: Wiki label evaluation results: Full</figDesc><graphic url="image-3.png" coords="6,307.28,104.11,207.56,120.94" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head>First</head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> Also referred to as confusion network.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="2"> https://github.com/tszming/mediawiki-zhconverter 3 Another possibility is to label it as &quot;SS&quot; but we find that it&apos;s very rare the case.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="5"> Statistical significance is evaluated with z-test using the standard deviation of √ F * (1 − F )/N , where F is the Fmeasure and N is the number of words.</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>The authors would like to thank Wenbin Jiang, Xi-aodong Zeng, and Weiwei Sun for helpful discus-sions, and the anonymous reviewers for insightful comments.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Frustratingly easy domain adaptation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hal</forename><surname>Daumé</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Iii</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Annual meetingassociation for computational linguistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="256" to="263" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Discriminative learning with natural annotations: Word segmentation as a case study</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wenbin</forename><surname>Jiang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Meng</forename><surname>Sun</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yajuan</forename><surname>Lv</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yating</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Qun</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of The 51st Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>The 51st Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="761" to="769" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Semisupervised conditional random fields for improved sequence segmentation and labeling</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Feng</forename><surname>Jiao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Shaojun</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chi-Hoon</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Russell</forename><surname>Greiner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dale</forename><surname>Schuurmans</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 21st International Conference on Computational Linguistics and the 44th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics, ACL-44</title>
		<meeting>the 21st International Conference on Computational Linguistics and the 44th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics, ACL-44</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="209" to="216" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Conditional random fields: Probabilistic models for segmenting and labeling sequence data</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">John</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Lafferty</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Andrew</forename><surname>Mccallum</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Fernando</forename><forename type="middle">C N</forename><surname>Pereira</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Eighteenth International Conference on Machine Learning</title>
		<meeting>the Eighteenth International Conference on Machine Learning<address><addrLine>San Francisco, CA, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="282" to="289" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Practical very large scale CRFs</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Thomas</forename><surname>Lavergne</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Olivier</forename><surname>Cappé</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">François</forename><surname>Yvon</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings the 48th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL)</title>
		<meeting>the 48th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2010-07" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="504" to="513" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Punctuation as implicit annotations for Chinese word segmentation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Zhongguo</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Maosong</forename><surname>Sun</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Computational Linguistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">35</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="505" to="512" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Semi-supervised learning for natural language</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Percy</forename><surname>Liang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005-05" />
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>MASSACHUSETTS INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
	<note>Master&apos;s thesis</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">On the limited memory bfgs method for large scale optimization</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Nocedal</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Mathematical Programming</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">45</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="503" to="528" />
			<date type="published" when="1989-12" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A maximum entropy approach to chinese word segmentation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jin</forename><forename type="middle">Kiat</forename><surname>Low</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hwee</forename><forename type="middle">Tou</forename><surname>Ng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wenyuan</forename><surname>Guo</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Fourth SIGHAN Workshop on Chinese Language Processing</title>
		<meeting>the Fourth SIGHAN Workshop on Chinese Language Processing<address><addrLine>San Francisco, CA, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="161" to="164" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Efficient computation of entropy gradient for semisupervised conditional random fields</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gideon</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Mann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Andrew</forename><surname>Mccallum</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Human Language Technologies 2007: The Conference of the North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics; Companion Volume, Short Papers, NAACL-Short &apos;07</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="109" to="112" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Enhancing chinese word segmentation using unlabeled data</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Weiwei</forename><surname>Sun</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jia</forename><surname>Xu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2011 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</title>
		<meeting>the 2011 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing<address><addrLine>Edinburgh, Scotland, UK.</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011-07" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="970" to="979" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A discriminative latent variable Chinese segmenter with hybrid word/character information</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xu</forename><surname>Sun</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yaozhong</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Takuya</forename><surname>Matsuzaki</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yoshimasa</forename><surname>Tsuruoka</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jun&amp;apos;ichi</forename><surname>Tsujii</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of Human Language Technologies: The 2009 Annual Conference of the North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>Human Language Technologies: The 2009 Annual Conference of the North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="56" to="64" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Word-based and character-based word segmentation models: comparison and combination</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Weiwei</forename><surname>Sun</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 23rd International Conference on Computational Linguistics: Posters</title>
		<meeting>the 23rd International Conference on Computational Linguistics: Posters</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1211" to="1219" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Token and type constraints for cross-lingual part-of-speech tagging</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Oscar</forename><surname>Täckström</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dipanjan</forename><surname>Das</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Slav</forename><surname>Petrov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ryan</forename><surname>Mcdonald</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Joakim</forename><surname>Nivre</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Transactions of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="12" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Improving chinese word segmentation and POS tagging with semi-supervised methods using large auto-analyzed data</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yiou</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yoshimasa</forename><surname>Jun&amp;apos;ichi Kazama</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wenliang</forename><surname>Tsuruoka</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 5th International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing</title>
		<meeting>the 5th International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="309" to="317" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Yujie Zhang, and Kentaro Torisawa</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Chinese word segmentation as character tagging</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nianwen</forename><surname>Xue</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Computational Linguistics and Chinese Language Processing</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="29" to="48" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">An empirical study of semi-supervised Chinese word segmentation using co-training</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Fan</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Paul</forename><surname>Vozila</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2013 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</title>
		<meeting>the 2013 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing<address><addrLine>Seattle, Washington, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013-10" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1191" to="1200" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Association for Computational Linguistics</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Co-regularizing characterbased and word-based models for semi-supervised chinese word segmentation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xiaodong</forename><surname>Zeng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Derek</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Wong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lidia</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Chao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Isabel</forename><surname>Trancoso</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of The 51st Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>The 51st Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="171" to="176" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Graph-based semisupervised model for joint chinese word segmentation and part-of-speech tagging</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xiaodong</forename><surname>Zeng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Derek</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Wong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lidia</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Chao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Isabel</forename><surname>Trancoso</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of The 51st Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>The 51st Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="770" to="779" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Exploring representations from unlabeled data with co-training for Chinese word segmentation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Longkai</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Houfeng</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xu</forename><surname>Sun</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mairgup</forename><surname>Mansur</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2013 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</title>
		<meeting>the 2013 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing<address><addrLine>Seattle, Washington, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2013-10" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="311" to="321" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
