<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T11:34+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Asymmetric Features of Human Generated Translation</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
				<availability status="unknown"><p>Copyright Association for Computational Linguistics</p>
				</availability>
				<date>October 25-29, 2014. 2014</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sauleh</forename><surname>Eetemadi</surname></persName>
							<email>saulehe@microsoft.com</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kristina</forename><surname>Toutanova</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Michigan State University</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>East Lansing</settlement>
									<region>MI</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">Microsoft Research</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Redmond</settlement>
									<region>WA</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="institution">Microsoft Research Redmond</orgName>
								<address>
									<region>WA</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Asymmetric Features of Human Generated Translation</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2014 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP)</title>
						<meeting>the 2014 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP) <address><addrLine>Doha, Qatar. c</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="159" to="164"/>
							<date type="published">October 25-29, 2014. 2014</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Distinct properties of translated text have been the subject of research in linguistics for many year (Baker, 1993). In recent years computational methods have been developed to empirically verify the linguistic theories about translated text (Ba-roni and Bernardini, 2006). While many characteristics of translated text are more apparent in comparison to the original text, most of the prior research has fo-cused on monolingual features of translated and original text. The contribution of this work is introducing bilingual features that are capable of explaining differences in translation direction using localized linguistic phenomena at the phrase or sentence level, rather than using mono-lingual statistics at the document level. We show that these bilingual features out-perform the monolingual features used in prior work (Kurokawa et al., 2009) for the task of classifying translation direction.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>It has been known for many years in linguis- tics that translated text has distinct patterns com- pared to original or authored text <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Baker, 1993)</ref>. The term "Translationese" is often used to refer to the characteristics of translated text. Patterns of Translationese can be categorized as follows ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Volansky et al., 2013</ref>):</p><p>1. Simplification: The process of translation is often coupled with a simplification process at several levels. For example, there tends to be less lexical variety in translated text and rare words are often avoided. 2. Explicitation: Translators often have to be more explicit in their translations due to lack of the cultural context that speakers of the source language have. Another manifesta- tion of this pattern is making arguments more explicit which can be observed in the heavy use of cohesive markers like "therefore" and "moreover" in translated text ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Koppel and Ordan, 2011</ref>). 3. Normalization: Translated text often con- tains more formal and repeating language. 4. Interference: A translator is likely to pro- duce a translation that is structurally and grammatically closer to the source text or their native language.</p><p>In <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref> the size of a word in the "Translated" section is proportional to the difference between the frequency of the word in original and in the translated text <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Fellows, 2013)</ref>. For example, it is apparent that the word "the" is over-represented in translated English as noted by other research ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Volansky et al., 2013</ref>). In addition, cohesive markers are clearly more common in translated text.</p><p>In the past few years there has been work on ma- chine learning techniques for identifying Trans- lationese. Standard machine learning algorithms like SVMs ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Baroni and Bernardini, 2006</ref>) and Bayesian Logistic Regression ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Koppel and Ordan, 2011</ref>) have been employed to train classifiers for one of the following tasks:</p><p>i. Given a chunk of text in a specific language, classify it as "Original" or "Translated". ii. Given a chunk of translated text, predict the source language of the translation. iii. Given a text chunk pair and their languages, predict the direction of translation.</p><p>There are two stated motivations for the tasks above: first, empirical validation of linguistic the- ories about Translationese ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Volansky et al., 2013)</ref>, and second, improving statistical machine trans- lation by leveraging the knowledge of the trans- lation direction in training and test data (Lember-   the accuracy drops by 15 percentage points or more ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Kurokawa et al., 2009</ref>). Fig- ure 2 shows how detection accuracy drops with the reduction of the input text chunk size. Since parallel data are often available at the sentence level or small chunks of text, existing detection methods aren't suitable for this type of data. Motivated by these limitations, in this work we focus on improving sentence-level classification accuracy by using non-domain-specific bilingual features at the sentence level. In addition to im- proving accuracy, these fine-grained features may be better able to confirm existing theories or dis- cover new linguistic phenomena that occur in the translation process. We use a fast linear classi- fier trained with online learning, Vowpal Wabbit ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Langford et al., 2007</ref>). The Hansard French- English dataset ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Kurokawa et al., 2009</ref>) is used for training and test data in all experiments.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Related Work</head><p>While distinct patterns of Translationese have been studied widely in the past, the work of Ba- roni and <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Bernardini (2006)</ref> is the first to intro- duce a computational method for detecting Trans- lationese with high accuracy. Prior work has shown in-domain accuracy can be very high at the chunk-level if fully lexicalized features are used ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Volansky et al., 2013</ref>), but then the phenom- ena learned are clearly not generalizable across domains. For example, in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref>, it can be observed that content words like "commission", "council" or "union" can be used effectively for classification while they do not capture any gen- eral linguistic phenomena and are unlikely to scale to other corpora. This is also confirmed by an average human performance of 72.7% precision with 82.1% recall on a similar task where the test subjects were not familiar with the domain and were not able to use domain-specific lexical fea- tures ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Baroni and Bernardini, 2006</ref>). A more gen- eral feature set still with high in-domain accuracy is POS tags with lexicalization of function words ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Baroni and Bernardini, 2006;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Kurokawa et al., 2009)</ref>. We build on this feature set and explore bilingual features.</p><p>The only work to consider features of the two parallel chunks (one original, one translated) is the work of <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Kurokawa et al. (2009)</ref>. They simply used the union of the n-gram mixed-POS 3 features of the two sides; these are monolingual features of the original and translated text and do not look at translation phenomena directly. Their work is also the only work to look at sentence level detection accuracy and report 15 percentage points drop in accuracy when going from chunk level to sentence level classification.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Bilingual Features for Translation Direction Classification</head><p>We are interested in learning common localized linguistic phenomena that occur during the trans- lation process when translating in one direction but not the other.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">POS Tag MTUs</head><p>Minimal translation units (MTUs) for a sentence pair are defined as pairs of source and target word sets that satisfy the following conditions <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(Quirk and Menezes, 2006</ref> To obtain POS MTUs from a parallel corpus, first, the parallel corpus is word aligned. Next, the source and target side of the corpus are tagged independently. Finally, words are replaced with their corresponding POS tag in word-aligned sentence pairs. MTUs were ex- tracted from the POS tagged word-aligned sen- tence pairs from left to right and listed in source order. Unigram, bi-gram, and higher order n- gram features were built over this sequence of POS MTUs. For example, for the sentence pair in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Figure 3</ref>, the following POS MTUs will be ex- tracted: VBZ⇒D, PRP⇒(N,V), RB⇒ADV, JJ⇒N, .⇒PUNC.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Distortion</head><p>In addition to the mapping of linguistic structures, another interesting phenomenon is the reordering of linguistic structures during translation. One hy- pothesis is that when translating from a fixed-order to a free-order language, the order of the target will be very influenced by the source (almost mono- tone translation), but when translating into a fixed order language, more re-ordering is required to ensure grammaticality of the target. To capture this pattern we add distortion to POS Tag MTU features. We experiment with absolute distortion (word position difference between source and tar- get of a link) as well as HMM distortion (word position difference between the target of a link and the target of the previous link). We bin the distor- tions into three bins: "= 0", "&gt; 0" and "&lt; 0", to reduce sparsity.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Experimental Setup</head><p>For the translation direction detection task ex- plained in section 1, we use a fast linear classi- fier trained with online learning, Vowpal Wabbit ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Langford et al., 2007)</ref>. Training data and classi- fication features are explained in section 4.1 and 4.2. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">Data</head><p>For this task we require a parallel corpus with sen- tence pairs available in both directions (sentences authored in language A and then translated to lan- guage B and vice versa). While the customized version of <ref type="bibr">EuroParl (Islam and Mehler, 2012</ref>) con- tains sentence pairs for many language pairs, none of the language pairs have sentence pairs available in both directions (e.g., it does contain sentences authored in English and translated into French but not vice versa). The Canadian Hansard corpus on the other hand fits the requirement as it has 742,408 sentence pairs translated from French to English and 2,203,504 sentences pairs that were translated from English to French ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Kurokawa et al., 2009</ref>). We use the Hansard data for training classifiers. For training the HMM word alignment model used to define features, we use a larger set of ten billion words of parallel text from the WMT English-French corpus.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">Preprocessing and Feature Extraction</head><p>We used a language filter 4 , deduplication filter 5 and length ratio filter to clean the data. After fil- tering we were left with 1,890,603 English-French sentence pairs and 640,117 French-English sen- tence pairs. The Stanford POS tagger <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">(Toutanova and Manning, 2000</ref>) was used to tag the English and the French sides of the corpus. The HMM alignment model ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Vogel et al., 1996</ref>) trained on WMT data was used to word-align the Hansard corpus while replacing words with their corre- sponding POS tags. Due to differences in word breaking between the POS tagger tool and our word alignment tool there were some mismatches. For simplicity we dropped the entire sentence pair whenever a token mismatch occurred. This left us with 401,569 POS tag aligned sentence pairs in the French to English direction and 1,184,702 pairs in the other direction. We chose to create a balanced dataset and reduced the number of English-French sentences to 401,679 with 20,000 sentence pairs held out for testing in each direction.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Results</head><p>The results of our experiments on the translation direction detection task are listed in <ref type="table">Table 4</ref>. We would like to point out several results from the table. First, when using only unigram features, the highest accuracy is achieved by the "POS- MTU + HMM Distortion" feature, which uses POS minimal translation units together with dis- tortion. The highest accuracy overall if obtained by a "POS-MTU" trigram model, showing the ad- vantage of bilingual features over prior work us- ing only a union of monolingual features (repro- duced by the "English-POS + French-POS" con- figuration). While higher order features generally show better in-domain accuracy, the advantage of low-order bilingual features might be even higher in cross-domain classification.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>POS MTU (E⇒F) FE# EF# Example 1 NNPS⇒(N,C) 336 12 quebecers(NNPS) ⇒ québécoises(N) et(C) des québécois 2 IN⇒(CL,V) 69 1027 a few days ago(IN) ⇒ il y(CL) a(V) quelques 3 PRP⇒(N,V)</head><p>18 663 he(PRP) is ⇒ le député(N) ` a(V) 4 (NNP,POS)⇒A 155 28 quebec(NNP) 's(POS) history ⇒ histoire québécoises(A) 5 (FW,FW)⇒ADV 7 195 pro(FW) bono(FW) work ⇒ bénévolement(ADV) travailler 6 (RB,MD)⇒V 2 112 money alone(RB) could(MD) solve ⇒ argent suffirait(V) ` a résoudre <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>: POS MTU features with highest weight. FE# indicates the number of times this feature ap- peared when translating from French to English. <ref type="bibr">6</ref> </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Analysis</head><p>An interesting aspect of this work is that it is able to extract features that can be linguistically inter- preted. Although linguistic analysis of these fea- tures is outside the scope of this work, we list POS MTU features with highest positive or neg- ative weights in <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>. Although the top feature, NNPS⇒(N,C) 7 , in this context is originating from a common phrase used by French speaking members of the Canadian Parliament, québécoises et des québécois, it does highlight an underlying linguistic phenomenon that is not specific to the Canadian Parliament. When translating a plural noun from English to French it is likely that only the masculine form of the noun appears, while if it was authored in French with both forms of the nouns, a single plural noun would appear in En- glish as English doesn't have masculine and femi- nine forms of the word. A more complete form of this feature would have been NNPS⇒(N,C,N), but since word alignment models, in general, dis- courage one-to-many alignments, the extracted MTU only covers the first noun and conjunction.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7">Conclusion and Future Work</head><p>In this work we introduce new features for transla- tion direction detection that leverage word align- ment, source POS and target POS in the form of POS MTUs. POS MTUs are a powerful tool for capturing linguistic interactions between lan- guages during the translation process. Since POS MTUs are not lexical features they are more likely to scale across corpora and domains compared to lexicalized features. Although most of the high weight POS MTU features used in classification <ref type="table">(Table 1)</ref> are not corpus specific, unfortunately, due to lack of training data in multiple domains, experiments were not run to validate this claim. In future work, we intend to obtain training data 7 NNPS: Plural Noun, N: Noun, C:Conjunction from multiple domains that enables us to verify cross-domain scalability of POS-MTUs. In addi- tion, observing linguistic phenomena that occur in one translation direction but not the other can be very informative in improving statistical machine translation quality. Another future direction for this work is leveraging sentence level translation direction detection to improve statistical machine translation output quality. Finally, further investi- gation of the linguistic interpretation of individual feature that are most discriminating between op- posite translation directions can lead to discovery of new linguistic phenomena that occur during the translation process.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: EuroParl Word Cloud Data Visualization (Translated vs Original) 1 sky et al., 2012a; Lembersky et al., 2013; Lembersky et al., 2012b). Few parallel corpora including a customized version of EuroParl (Islam and Mehler, 2012) and a processed version of Hansard (Kurokawa et al., 2009) are labeled for translated versus original text. Using these limited resources, it has been shown that taking the translation direction into account when training a statistical machine translation system can improve translation quality (Lembersky et al., 2013). However, improving statistical machine translation using translation direction information has been limited by several factors. 1. Limited Labeled Data: The amount of labeled data is limited by language and domain and therefore by itself is not enough to make a significant improvement in statistical machine translation. 2. Cross-Domain Scalability: Current methods of Translationese detection do not scale across different corpora. For example, a classifier trained on EuroParl corpus (Koehn, 2005) had in-domain accuracy of 92.7% but out-of-domain accuracy of 64.8% (Koppel and Ordan, 2011). 3. Text Chunk Size: The reported high accuracy of Translationese detection is based on relatively large (approximately 1500 tokens) text chunks (Koppel and Ordan, 2011). When similar tasks are performed at the sentence</figDesc><graphic url="image-1.png" coords="2,90.43,62.81,181.42,186.38" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>level</head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2: Effects of Chunk Size on Translationese Detection Accuracy 2 Motivated by these limitations, in this work we focus on improving sentence-level classification accuracy by using non-domain-specific bilingual features at the sentence level. In addition to improving accuracy, these fine-grained features may be better able to confirm existing theories or discover new linguistic phenomena that occur in the translation process. We use a fast linear classifier trained with online learning, Vowpal Wabbit (Langford et al., 2007). The Hansard FrenchEnglish dataset (Kurokawa et al., 2009) is used for training and test data in all experiments.</figDesc><graphic url="image-2.png" coords="2,307.68,184.02,217.46,93.20" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>Figure 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Figure 3: POS Tagged Aligned Sentence Pairs</figDesc><graphic url="image-3.png" coords="3,122.99,66.20,351.56,82.08" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head>Figure 4 :</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Figure 4: Sentence level translation direction detection precision using different features with n-gram lengths of 1 through 5.</figDesc><graphic url="image-4.png" coords="4,72.00,62.81,453.60,186.24" type="bitmap" /></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="2"> This is a reproduction of the results of Koppel and Ordan (2011) using function word frequencies as features for a logistic regression classifier. Based on the description of how text chunks were created, the results of the paper (92.7% accuracy) are based on text chunk sizes of approximately 1500 tokens.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="3"> Only replacing content words with their POS tags while leaving function words as is.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="4"> A character n-gram language model is used to detect the language of source and target side text and filter them out if they do not match their annotated language. 5 Duplicate sentences pairs are filtered out.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="6"> For description of English POS tags see (Marcus et al., 1993) and (Abeillé et al., 2003) for French</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgement</head><p>The authors would like to thank Lee Schwartz for analyzing classification features and providing lin-guistic insight for them. We would like to also ac-knowledge the thoughtful comments and detailed feedback of the reviewers which helped us im-prove the paper.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Building a treebank for french</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Anne</forename><surname>Abeillé</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lionel</forename><surname>Clément</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">François</forename><surname>Toussenel</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Text, Speech and Language Technology</title>
		<editor>Anne Abeillé</editor>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="165" to="187" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mona</forename><surname>Baker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Corpus linguistics and translation studies: Implications and applications. Text and technology: in honour of John Sinclair</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">233</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">250</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A new approach to the study of translationese: Machinelearning the difference between original and translated text</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marco</forename><surname>Baroni</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Silvia</forename><surname>Bernardini</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Literary and Linguistic Computing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">21</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="259" to="274" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ian</forename><surname>Fellows</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>wordcloud: Word Clouds. R package version 2.4.</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Customization of the europarl corpus for translation studies</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Zahurul</forename><surname>Islam</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alexander</forename><surname>Mehler</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">LREC</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2505" to="2510" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Europarl: A Parallel Corpus for Statistical Machine Translation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Philipp</forename><surname>Koehn</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Conference Proceedings: the tenth Machine Translation Summit</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Phuket, Thailand. AAMT, AAMT</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="79" to="86" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Translationese and its dialects</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Moshe</forename><surname>Koppel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Noam</forename><surname>Ordan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 49th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics: Human Language Technologies</title>
		<meeting>the 49th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics: Human Language Technologies</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1318" to="1326" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The twelfth Machine Translation Summit International Association for Machine Translation hosted by the Association for Machine Translation in the Americas</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Kurokawa</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Cyril</forename><surname>Goutte</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Pierre</forename><surname>Isabelle</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proceedings. MT Summit XII</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Automatic detection of translated text and its impact on machine translation</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Vowpal wabbit online learning project</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Langford</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Adapting translation models to translationese improves SMT</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gennadi</forename><surname>Lembersky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Noam</forename><surname>Ordan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Shuly</forename><surname>Wintner</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 13th Conference of the European Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the 13th Conference of the European Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="255" to="265" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Language models for machine translation: Original vs</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gennadi</forename><surname>Lembersky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Noam</forename><surname>Ordan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Shuly</forename><surname>Wintner</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Computational Linguistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">38</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="799" to="825" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>translated texts</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Improving statistical machine translation by adapting translation models to translationese</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gennadi</forename><surname>Lembersky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Noam</forename><surname>Ordan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Shuly</forename><surname>Wintner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Building a large annotated corpus of english: The penn treebank</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mitchell</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Marcus</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mary</forename><forename type="middle">Ann</forename><surname>Marcinkiewicz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Beatrice</forename><surname>Santorini</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Comput. Linguist</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="313" to="330" />
			<date type="published" when="1993-06" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Do we need phrases?: Challenging the conventional wisdom in statistical machine translation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chris</forename><surname>Quirk</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Arul</forename><surname>Menezes</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Main Conference on Human Language Technology Conference of the North American Chapter of the Association of Computational Linguistics, HLTNAACL &apos;06</title>
		<meeting>the Main Conference on Human Language Technology Conference of the North American Chapter of the Association of Computational Linguistics, HLTNAACL &apos;06<address><addrLine>Stroudsburg, PA, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="9" to="16" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Enriching the knowledge sources used in a maximum entropy part-of-speech tagger</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kristina</forename><surname>Toutanova</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Christopher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Manning</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2000 Joint SIGDAT Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing and Very Large Corpora: Held in Conjunction with the 38th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the 2000 Joint SIGDAT Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing and Very Large Corpora: Held in Conjunction with the 38th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics<address><addrLine>Stroudsburg, PA, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="63" to="70" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Association for Computational Linguistics</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Hmm-based word alignment in statistical translation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Stephan</forename><surname>Vogel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hermann</forename><surname>Ney</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christoph</forename><surname>Tillmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 16th conference on Computational linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the 16th conference on Computational linguistics</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="836" to="841" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">On the features of translationese. Literary and Linguistic Computing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Vered</forename><surname>Volansky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Noam</forename><surname>Ordan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Shuly</forename><surname>Wintner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page">31</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
