<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T11:50+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Unsupervised Template Mining for Semantic Category Understanding</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
				<availability status="unknown"><p>Copyright Association for Computational Linguistics</p>
				</availability>
				<date>October 25-29, 2014. 2014</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lei</forename><surname>Shi</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Institute of Software</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">State Key Laboratory of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Chinese Academy of Sciences</orgName>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">University of Chinese Academy of Sciences</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Shuming</forename><surname>Shi</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="institution">Microsoft Research</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chin-Yew</forename><surname>Lin</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="institution">Microsoft Research</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yi-Dong</forename><surname>Shen</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Institute of Software</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">State Key Laboratory of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Chinese Academy of Sciences</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yong</forename><surname>Rui</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="institution">Microsoft Research</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Unsupervised Template Mining for Semantic Category Understanding</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2014 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP)</title>
						<meeting>the 2014 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP) <address><addrLine>Doha, Qatar. c</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="799" to="809"/>
							<date type="published">October 25-29, 2014. 2014</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>We propose an unsupervised approach to constructing templates from a large collection of semantic category names, and use the templates as the semantic representation of categories. The main challenge is that many terms have multiple meanings, resulting in a lot of wrong templates. Statistical data and semantic knowledge are extracted from a web corpus to improve template generation. A nonlinear scoring function is proposed and demonstrated to be effective. Experiments show that our approach achieves significantly better results than baseline methods. As an immediate application, we apply the extracted templates to the cleaning of a category collection and see promising results (preci-sion improved from 81% to 89%).</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>A semantic category is a collection of items shar- ing common semantic properties. For example, all cities in Germany form a semantic category named "city in Germany" or "German city". In Wikipedia, the category names of an entity are manually edited and displayed at the end of the page for the entity. There have been quite a lot of approaches <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Hearst, 1992;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Pantel and Ravichandran, 2004;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b25">Van Durme and Pasca, 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b27">Zhang et al., 2011</ref>) in the literature to automatically extract- ing category names and instances (also called is-a or hypernymy relations) from the web.</p><p>Most existing work simply treats a category name as a text string containing one or multiple words, without caring about its internal structure. In this paper, we explore the semantic structure of category names (or simply called "categories").</p><p>For example, both "CEO of General Motors" and "CEO of Yahoo" have structure "CEO of <ref type="bibr">[company]</ref>". We call such a structure a category tem- plate. Taking a large collection of open-domain categories as input, we construct a list of category templates and build a mapping from categories to templates. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 1</ref> shows some example semantic categories and their corresponding templates.</p><p>Templates can be treated as additional features of semantic categories. The new features can be exploited to improve some upper-layer applica- tions like web search and question answering. In addition, by linking categories to templates, it is possible (for a computer program) to infer the se- mantic meaning of the categories. For example in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 1</ref>, from the two templates linking to cat- egory "symptom of insulin deficiency", it is rea- sonable to interpret the category as: "a symptom of a medical condition called insulin deficiency which is about the deficiency of one type of hor- mone called insulin." In this way, our knowledge about a category can go beyond a simple string and its member entities. An immediate application of templates is removing invalid category names from a noisy category collection. Promising re- sults are observed for this application in our ex- periments.</p><p>An intuitive approach to this task (i.e., extract- ing templates from a collection of category names) national holiday of South Africa national holiday of <ref type="bibr">[country]</ref> symptom of cortisol deficiency  contains two stages: category labeling, and tem- plate scoring.</p><p>Category labeling: Divide a category name into multiple segments and replace some key seg- ments with its hypernyms. As an example, as- sume "CEO of Delphinus" is divided to three seg- ments "CEO + of + Delphinus"; and the last seg- ment (Delphinus) has hypernyms "constellation", "company", etc. By replacing this segment with its hypernyms, we get candidate templates "CEO of <ref type="bibr">[constellation]</ref>" (a wrong template), "CEO of <ref type="bibr">[company]</ref>", and the like.</p><p>Template scoring: Compute the score of each candidate template by aggregating the information obtained in the first phase.</p><p>A major challenge here is that many segments (like "Delphinus" in the above example) have mul- tiple meanings. As a result, wrong hypernyms may be adopted to generate incorrect candidate templates (like "CEO of [constellation]"). In this paper, we focus on improving the template scor- ing stage, with the goal of assigning lower scores to bad templates and larger scores to high-quality ones.</p><p>There have been some research efforts <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">(Third, 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Fernandez-Breis et al., 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr">QuesadaMartınez et al., 2012</ref>) on exploring the structure of category names by building patterns. However, we automatically assign semantic types to the pattern variables (or called arguments) while they do not. For example, our template has the form of "city in <ref type="bibr">[country]</ref>" while their patterns are like "city in <ref type="bibr">[X]</ref>". More details are given in the related work section.</p><p>A similar task is query understanding, including query tagging and query template mining. Query tagging ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Li et al., 2009;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b19">Reisinger and Pasca, 2011</ref>) corresponds to the category labeling stage described above. It is different from template gen- eration because the results are for one query only, without merging the information of all queries to generate the final templates. Category template construction are slightly different from query tem- plate construction. First, some useful features such as query click-through is not available in cat- egory template construction. Second, categories should be valid natural language phrases, while queries need not. For example, "city Germany" is a query but not a valid category name. We discuss in more details in the related work section.</p><p>Our major contributions are as follows.</p><p>1) To the best of our knowledge, this is the first work of template generation specifically for cate- gories in unsupervised manner.</p><p>2) We extract semantic knowledge and statisti- cal information from a web corpus for improving template generation. Significant performance im- provement is obtained in our experiments.</p><p>3) We study the characteristics of the scoring function from the viewpoint of probabilistic evi- dence combination and demonstrate that nonlinear functions are more effective in this task. 4) We employ the output templates to clean our category collection mined from the web, and get apparent quality improvement (precision im- proved from 81% to 89%).</p><p>After discussing related work in Section 2, we define the problem and describe one baseline ap- proach in Section 3. Then we introduce our ap- proach in Section 4. Experimental results are re- ported and analyzed in Section 5. We conclude the paper in Section 6.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Related work</head><p>Several kinds of work are related to ours.</p><p>Hypernymy relation extraction: Hypernymy relation extraction is an important task in text min- ing. There have been a lot of efforts <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Hearst, 1992;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Pantel and Ravichandran, 2004;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b25">Van Durme and Pasca, 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b27">Zhang et al., 2011</ref>) in the literature to extract hypernymy (or is-a) relations from the web. Our target here is not hypernymy extraction, but discovering the semantic structure of hypernyms (or category names).</p><p>Category name exploration: Category name patterns are explored and built in some ex- isting research work.</p><p>Third (2012) pro- posed to find axiom patterns among category names on an existing ontology.</p><p>For ex- ample, infer axiom pattern "SubClassOf(AB, B)" from "SubClassOf(junior school school)" and "SubClassOf(domestic mammal mammal)". <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Fernandez-Breis et al. (2010)</ref> and Quesada- <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">Martınez et al. (2012)</ref> proposed to find lexical pat- terns in category names to define axioms (in med- ical domain). One example pattern mentioned in their papers is " <ref type="bibr">[X]</ref> binding". They need man- ual intervention to determine what X means. The main difference between the above work and ours is that we automatically assign semantic types to the pattern variables (or called arguments) while they do not.</p><p>Template mining for IE: Some research work in information extraction (IE) involves patterns. <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">Yangarber (2003)</ref> and <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Stevenson and Greenwood (2005)</ref> proposed to learn patterns which were in the form of <ref type="bibr">[subject, verb, object]</ref>. The category names and learned templates in our work are not in this form. Another difference between our work and their work is that, their methods need a super- vised name classifer to generate the candidate pat- terns while our approach is unsupervised. Cham- bers and Jurafsky (2011) leverage templates to de- scribe an event while the templates in our work are for understanding category names (a kind of short text).</p><p>Query tagging/labeling: Some research work in recent years focuses on segmenting web search queries and assigning semantic tags to key seg- ments. <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Li et al. (2009)</ref> and <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Li (2010)</ref> employed CRF (Conditional Random Field) or semi-CRF models for query tagging. A crowdsourcing- assisted method was proposed by <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Han et al. (2013)</ref> for query structure interpretation. These super- vised or semi-supervised approaches require much manual annotation effort. Unsupervised meth- ods were proposed by <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Sarkas et al. (2010)</ref> and <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">Reisinger and Pasca (2011)</ref>. As been discussed in the introduction section, query tagging is only one of the two stages of template generation. The tagging results are for one query only, without ag- gregating the global information of all queries to generate the final templates.</p><p>Query template construction: Some existing work leveraged query templates or patterns for query understanding. A semi-supervised random walk based method was proposed by <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Agarwal et al. (2010)</ref> to generate a ranked templates list which are relevant to a domain of interest. A predefined domain schema and seed information is needed for this method. <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Pandey and Punera (2012)</ref> proposed an unsupervised method based on graphical mod- els to mine query templates. The above methods are either domain-specific (i.e., generating tem- plates for a specific domain), or have some degree of supervision (supervised or semi-supervised). <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Cheung and Li (2012)</ref> proposed an unsupervised method to generate query templates by the aid of knowledge bases. An approach was proposed in <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">(Szpektor et al., 2011</ref>) to improve query recom- mendation via query templates. Query session in- formation (which is not available in our task) is needed in this approach for templates generation. <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Li et al. (2013)</ref> proposed an clustering algorithm to group existing query templates by search intents of users.</p><p>Compared to the open-domain unsupervised methods for query template construction, our ap- proach improves on two aspects. First, we propose to incorporate multiple types of semantic knowl- edge (e.g., term peer similarity and term clusters) to improve template generation. Second, we pro- pose a nonlinear template scoring function which is demonstrated to be more effective.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Problem Definition and Analysis</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Problem definition</head><p>The goal of this paper is to construct a list of cat- egory templates from a collection of open-domain category names.</p><p>Input: The input is a collection of category names, which can either be manually compiled (like Wikipedia categories) or be automatically ex- tracted. The categories used in our experiments were automatically mined from the web, by fol- lowing existing work <ref type="bibr">(Hearst, 1992, Pantel and</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Ravichandran 2004;</ref><ref type="bibr">Snow et al., 2005;</ref><ref type="bibr">Talukdar et al., 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b27">Zhang et al., 2011</ref>). Specifically, we applied Hearst patterns (e.g., "NP [,] (such as | including) {N P, } * {and|or} NP") and is- a patterns ("NP (is|are|was|were|being) (a|an|the) NP") to a large corpus containing 3 billion En- glish web pages. As a result, we obtained a term→hypernym bi-partite graph containing 40 million terms, 74 million hypernyms (i.e., cate- gory names), and 321 million edges (e.g., one example edge is "Berlin"→"city in Germany", where "Berlin" is a term and "city in Germany" is the corresponding hypernym). Then all the multi- word hypernyms are used as the input category collection.</p><p>Output: The output is a list of templates, each having a score indicating how likely it is valid. A template is a multi-word string with one headword and at least one argument. For example, in tem- plate "national holiday of [country]", "holiday" is the headword, and " <ref type="bibr">[country]</ref>" is the argument. We only consider one-argument templates in this paper, and the case of multiple arguments is left as future work. A template is valid if it is syntacti- cally and semantically correct. "CEO of [constel- lation]" (wrongly generated from "CEO of Del- phinus", "CEO of Aquila", etc.) is not valid be- cause it is semantically unreasonable.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Baseline approach</head><p>An intuitive approach to this task contains two stages: category labeling and template scoring. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Figure 2</ref> shows its workflow with simple exam- ples.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2.1">Phase-1: Category labeling</head><p>At this stage, each category name is automatically segmented and labeled; and some candidate tem- plate tuples (CTTs) are derived based on the la- beling results. This can be done in the following steps.</p><p>Category segmentation: Divide each cate- gory name into multiple segments (e.g., "holi- day of South Africa" to "holiday + of + South Africa"). Each segment is one word or a phrase appearing in an entity dictionary. The dictionary used in this paper is comprised of all Freebase (www.freebase.com) entities.</p><p>Segment to hypernym: Find hypernyms for every segment (except for the headword and some trivial segments like prepositions and articles), by referring to a term→hypernym mapping graph. Following most existing query labeling work, we derive the term→hypernym graph from a dump of Freebase. Below are some examples of Freebase types (hypernyms), German city (id: /location/de city) Italian province (id: /location/it province) Poem character (id: /book/poem character) Book (id: /book/book) To avoid generating too fine-grained templates like "mayor of [Germany city]" and "mayor of [Italian city]" (semantically "mayor of <ref type="bibr">[city]</ref>" is more desirable), we discard type modifiers and map terms to the headwords of Freebase types. For example, "Berlin" is mapped to "city". In this way, we build our basic version of term→hypernym mapping which contains 16.13 million terms and 696 hypernyms. Since "South Africa" is both a country and a book name in Free- base, hypernyms "country", "book", and others are assigned to the segment "South Africa" in this step.</p><p>CTT generation: Construct CTTs by choosing one segment (called the target segment) each time and replacing the segment with its hypernyms. An CTT is formed by the candidate template (with one argument), the target segment (as an argument value), and the tuple score (indicating tuple qual- ity). Below are example CTTs obtained after the last segment of "holiday + of + South Africa" is processed, U 1 : (holiday of <ref type="bibr">[country]</ref>, South Africa, w 1 ) U 2 : (holiday of <ref type="bibr">[book]</ref>, South Africa, w 2 )</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2.2">Phase-2: Template scoring</head><p>The main objective of this stage is to merge all the CTTs obtained from the previous stage and to compute a final score for each template. In this stage, the CTTs are first grouped by the first ele- ment (i.e., the template string). For example, tu- ples for "holiday of <ref type="bibr">[country]</ref>" may include,</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">U 1 : (holiday of [country], South Africa, w 1 ) U 2 : (holiday of [country], Brazil, w 2 ) U 3 : (holiday of [country], Germany, w 3 ) ...</formula><p>Then a scoring function is employed to calcu- late the template score from the tuple scores. For- mally, given n tuples U =(U 1 , U 2 ..., U n ) for a tem- plate, the goal is to find a score fusion function F ( U ) which yields large values for high-quality templates and small (or zero) values for invalid ones.</p><p>Borrowing the idea of TF-IDF from information retrieval, a reasonable scoring function is,</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">F ( U ) = n i=1 w i · IDF (h)<label>(1)</label></formula><p>where h is the argument type (i.e., the hypernym of the argument value) of each tuple. TF means the "term frequency" and IDF means the "inverse document frequency". An IDF function assigns lower scores to common hypernyms (like person and music track which contain a lot of entities). Let DF (h) be the number of entities having hy- pernym h, we test two IDF functions in our exper- iments,</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">IDF 1 (h) = log 1 + N 1 + DF (h) IDF 2 (h) = 1/sqrt(DF (h))<label>(2)</label></formula><p>where N is total number of entities in the entity dictionary.</p><p>The next problem is estimating tuple score w i . Please note that there is no weight or score infor- mation in the term→hypernym mapping of Free- base. So we have to set w i to be constant in the baseline,  </p><formula xml:id="formula_3">w i = 1<label>(3)</label></formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Approach: Enhancing Template Scoring</head><p>In our approach, we follow the same framework as in the above baseline approach, and focus on improving the template scoring phase (i.e., phase- 2). We try three techniques: First, a better tuple score w i is calculated in Section 4.1 by performing statistics on a large corpus. The corpus is a collec- tion of 3 billion web pages crawled in early 2013 by ourselves. During this paper, we use "our web corpus" or "our corpus" to refer to this corpus.</p><p>Second, a nonlinear function is adopted in Sec- tion 4.2 to replace the baseline tuple fusion func- tion (Formula 1). Third, we extract term peer sim- ilarity and term clusters from our corpus and use them as additional semantic knowledge to refine template scores.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">Enhancing tuple scoring</head><p>Let's examine the following two template tuples, U 1 : (holiday of <ref type="bibr">[country]</ref>, South Africa, w 1 ) U 2 : (holiday of <ref type="bibr">[book]</ref>, South Africa, w 2 ) Intuitively, "South Africa" is more likely to be a country than a book when it appears in text. So for a reasonable tuple scoring formula, we should have w 1 &gt; w 2 .</p><p>The main idea is to automatically calculate the popularity of a hypernym given a term, by referring to a large corpus. Then by adding the popularity information to (the edges of) the term→hypernym graph of Freebase, we obtain a weighted term→hypernym graph. The weighted graph is then employed to enhance the estimation of w i .</p><p>For popularity calculation, we apply Hearst patterns <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Hearst, 1992)</ref> and is-a patterns ("NP (is|are|was|were|being) (a|an|the) NP") to every sentence of our web corpus. For a (term, hyper- nym) pair, its popularity F is calculated as the number of sentences in which the term and the hy- pernym co-occur and also follow at least one of the patterns.</p><p>For a template tuple U i with argument type h and argument value v, we test two ways of esti- mating the tuple score w i ,</p><formula xml:id="formula_4">w i = log (1 + F (v, h))<label>(4)</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_5">w i = F (v, h)) λ + h j ∈H F (v, h j )<label>(5)</label></formula><p>where F (v, h) is the popularity of the (v, h) pair in our corpus, H is the set of all hypernyms for v in the weighted term→hypernym graph. Parame- ter λ (=1.0 in our experiments) is introduced for smoothing purpose. Note that the second formula is the conditional probability of hypernym h given term v.</p><p>Since it is intuitive to estimate tuple scores with their frequencies in a corpus, we treat the approach with the improved w i as another baseline (our strong baseline).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">Enhancing tuple combination function</head><p>Now we study the possibility of improving the tu- ple combination function (Formula 1), by examin- ing the tuple fusion problem from the viewpoint of probabilistic evidence combination. We first demonstrate that the linear function in Formula 1 corresponds to the conditional independence as- sumption of the tuples. Then we propose to adopt a series of nonlinear functions for combining tuple scores.</p><p>We define the following events: T : Template T is a valid template; T : T is an invalid template; E i : The observation of tuple U i .</p><p>Let's compute the posterior odds of event T , given two tuples U 1 and U 2 . Assuming E 1 and E 2 are conditionally independent given T or T , according to the Bayes rule, we have,</p><formula xml:id="formula_6">P (T |E 1 , E 2 ) P (T |E 1 , E 2 ) = P (E 1 , E 2 |T ) · P (T ) P (E 1 , E 2 |T ) · P (T ) = P (E 1 |T ) P (E 1 |T ) · P (E 2 |T ) P (E 2 |T ) · P (T ) P (T ) = P (T |E 1 ) · P (T ) P (T |E 1 ) · P (T ) · P (T |E 2 ) · P (T ) P (T |E 2 ) · P (T ) · P (T ) P (T )<label>(6)</label></formula><p>Define the log-odds-gain of T given E as,</p><formula xml:id="formula_7">G(T |E) = log P (T |E) P (T |E) − log P (T ) P (T )<label>(7)</label></formula><p>Here G means the gain of the log-odds of T af- ter E occurs. By combining formulas 6 and 7, we get</p><formula xml:id="formula_8">G(T |E 1 , E 2 ) = G(T |E 1 ) + G(T |E 2 )<label>(8)</label></formula><p>It is easy to prove that the above conclusion holds true when n &gt; 2, i.e.,</p><formula xml:id="formula_9">G(T |E 1 , ..., E n ) = n i=1 G(T |E i )<label>(9)</label></formula><p>If we treat G(T |E i ) as the score of template T when only U i is observed, and G(T |E 1 , ..., E n ) as the template score after the n tuples are observed, then the above equation means that the combined template score should be the sum of w i · IDF (h), which is exactly Formula 1. Please keep in mind that Equation 9 is based on the assumption that the tuples are conditional independent. This assump- tion, however, may not hold in reality. The case of conditional dependence was studied in <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">(Zhang et al., 2011)</ref>, where a group of nonlinear combina- tion functions were proposed and achieved good performance in their task of hypernymy extrac- tion. We choose p-Norm as our nonlinear fusion functions, as below,</p><formula xml:id="formula_10">F ( U ) = p n i=1 w p i · IDF (h) (p &gt; 1)<label>(10)</label></formula><p>where p (=2 in experiments) is a parameter. Experiments show that the above nonlinear function performs better than the linear function of Formula 1. Let's use an example to show the intuition. Consider a good template "city of <ref type="bibr">[country]</ref>" corresponding to CTTs U A and a wrong tem- plate "city of <ref type="bibr">[book]</ref>" having tuples U B . Sup- pose | U A | = 200 (including most countries in the world) and | U B | = 1000 (considering that many place names have already been used as book names). We observe that each tuple score corre- sponding to "city of <ref type="bibr">[country]</ref>" is larger than the tuple score corresponding to "city of <ref type="bibr">[book]</ref>". For simplicity, we assume each tuple in U A has score 1.0 and each tuple in U B has score 0.2. With the linear and nonlinear (p=2) fusion functions, we can get, Linear:</p><formula xml:id="formula_11">F ( U A ) = 200 * 1.0 = 200 F ( U B ) = 1000 * 0.2 = 200<label>(11)</label></formula><p>Nonlinear:</p><formula xml:id="formula_12">F ( U A ) = 14.1 F ( U B ) = 6.32<label>(12)</label></formula><p>In the above settings the nonlinear function yields a much higher score for the good template (than for the invalid template), while the linear one does not.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3">Refinement with term similarity and term clusters</head><p>The above techniques neglect the similarity among terms, which has a high potential to improve the template scoring process. Intuitively, for a toy set {"city in Brazil", "city in South Africa","city in China", "city in Japan"}, since "Brazil", "South Africa", "China" and "Japan" are very similar to each other and they all have a large probability to be a "country", so we have more confidence that "city in <ref type="bibr">[country]</ref>" is a good template. In this sec- tion, we propose to leverage the term similarity information to improve the template scoring pro- cess.</p><p>We start with building a large group of small and overlapped clusters from our web corpus.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3.1">Building term clusters</head><p>Term clusters are built in three steps.</p><p>Mining term peer similarity: Two terms are peers if they share a common hypernym and they are semantically correlated. For example, "dog" and "cat" should have a high peer similarity score. Following existing work <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Hearst, 1992;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Kozareva et al., 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b21">Shi et al., 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Agirre et al., 2009;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Pantel et al., 2009</ref>), we built a peer similarity graph containing about 40.5 million nodes and 1.33 bil- lion edges.</p><p>Clustering: For each term, choose its top-30 neighbors from the peer similarity graph and run a hierarchical clustering algorithm, resulting in one or multiple clusters. Then we merge highly du- plicated clusters. The algorithm is similar to the first part of CBC ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Pantel and Lin, 2002</ref>), with the difference that a very high merging threshold is adopted here in order to generate small and over- lapped clusters. Please note that one term may be included in many clusters.</p><p>Assigning top hypernyms: Up to two hyper- nyms are assigned for each term cluster by major- ity voting of its member terms, with the aid of the weighted term→hypernym graph of Section 4.1. To be an eligible hypernym for the cluster, it has to be the hypernym of at least 70% of terms in the cluster. The score of each hypernym is the aver- age of the term→hypernym weights over all the member terms.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3.2">Template score refinement</head><p>With term clusters at hand, now we describe the score refinement procedure for a template T hav- ing argument type h and supporting tuples U =(U 1 , U 2 ..., U n ). Denote V = {V 1 , V 2 , ..., V n } to be the set of argument values for the tuples (where V i is the argument value of U i ).</p><p>By computing the intersection of V and every term cluster, we can get a distribution of the argu- ment values in the clusters. We find that for a good template like "holiday in [country]", we can often find at least one cluster (one of the country clus- ters in this example) which has hypernym h and also contains many elements in V . However, for invalid templates like "holiday of <ref type="bibr">[book]</ref>", every cluster having hypernym h (="book" here) only contains a few elements in V . Inspired by such an observation, our score refinement algorithm for template T is as follows,</p><p>Step-1. Calculating supporting scores: For each term cluster C having hypernym h, compute its supporting score to T as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_13">S(C, T ) = k(C, V ) · w(C, h)<label>(13)</label></formula><p>where k(C, V ) is the number of elements shared by C and V , and w(C, h) is hypernym score of h to C (computed in the last step of building clus- ters).</p><p>Step-2. Calculating the final template score: Let term cluster C * has the maximal supporting score to T , the final template score is computed as,</p><formula xml:id="formula_14">S(T ) = F ( U ) · S(C * , T )<label>(14)</label></formula><p>where F ( U ) is the template score before refine- ment.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Experiments</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.1">Experimental setup</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.1.1">Methods for comparison</head><p>We make a comparison among 10 methods.</p><p>SC: The method is proposed in (Cheung and Li, 2012) to construct templates from queries. The method firstly represents a query as a matrix based on Freebase data. Then a hierarchical clustering algorithm is employed to group queries having the same structure and meaning. Then an intent sum- marization algorithm is employed to create tem- plates for each query group.</p><p>Base: The linear function in Formula 1 is adopted to combine the tuple scores. We use IDF 2 here because it achieves higher precision than IDF 1 in this setting.</p><p>LW: The linear function in Formula 1 is adopted to combine the tuple scores generated by Formula 4. IDF 1 is used rather than IDF 2 for better performance.</p><p>LP: The linear function in Formula 1 is adopted to combine the tuple scores generated by Formula 5. IDF 2 is used rather than IDF 1 for better per- formance.</p><p>NLW: The nonlinear fusion function in For- mula 10 is used. Other settings are the same as LW.</p><p>NLP: The nonlinear fusion function in Formula 10 is used. Other settings are the same as LP.</p><p>LW+C, LP+C, NLW+C, NLP+C: All the set- tings of LW, LP, NLW, NLP respectively, with the refinement technology in Section 4.3 applied.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.1.2">Data sets, annotation and evaluation metrics</head><p>The input category names for experiments are au- tomatically extracted from a web corpus (Section 3.1). Two test-sets are built for evaluation from the output templates of various methods.</p><p>Subsets: In order to conveniently compare the performance of different methods, we create 20 sub-collections (called subsets) from the whole in- put category collection. Each subset contains all the categories having the same headword (e.g., "symptom of insulin deficiency" and "depression symptom" are in the same subset because they share the same headword "symptom"). To choose the 20 headwords, we first sample 100 at ran- dom from the set of all headwords; then manu- ally choose 20 for diversity. The headwords in- clude symptom, school, food, gem, hero, weapon, model, etc. We run the 10 methods on these sub- sets and sort the output templates by their scores. Top-30 templates from each method on each sub- set are selected and mixed together for annotation.</p><p>Fullset: We run method NLP+C (which has the best performance according to our subsets experiments) on the input categories and sort the output templates by their scores. Then we split the templates into 9 sections according to their ranking position. The sections are: <ref type="bibr">180K∼200K]</ref>. Then 40 templates are randomly chosen from each section and mixed together for annotation.</p><formula xml:id="formula_15">[1∼100], (100∼1K], (1K∼10K], (10K∼100K], (100K,120K], (120K∼140K], (140K∼160K], (160K∼180K], (</formula><p>The selected templates (from subsets and the fullset) are annotated by six annotators, with each template assigned to two annotators. A template is assigned a label of "good", "fair", or "bad" by an annotator. The percentage agreement between the annotators is 80.2%, with kappa 0.624.</p><p>For the subset experiments, we adopt <ref type="bibr">Precision@k (k=10,20,30)</ref> to evaluate the top templates generated by each method. The scores for "good", "fair", and "bad" are 1, 0.5, and 0. The score of each template is the average annotation score over two annotators (e.g., if a template is annotated "good" by one annotator and "fair" by another, its score is (1.0+0.5)/2=0.75). The evaluation score of a method is the average over the 20 subsets. For the fullset experiments, we report the precision for each section.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.2">Experimental results</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.2.1">Results for subsets</head><p>The results of each method on the 20 subsets are presented in <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>. A few observations can be made. First, by comparing the per- formance of baseline-1 (Base) and the methods adopting term→hypernym weight (LW and LP), we can see big performance improvement. The bad performance of baseline-1 is mainly due to the lack of weight (or frequency) information on term→hypernym edges. The results demonstrate that edge scores are critical for generating high quality templates. Manually built semantic re- sources typically lack such kinds of scores. There- fore, it is very important to enhance them by de- riving statistical data from a large corpus. Since it is relatively easy to have the idea of adopt- ing a weighted term→hypernym graph, we treat LW and LP as another (stronger) baseline named baseline-2. As the second observation, the results show that the nonlinear methods (NLP and NLW) achieve performance improvement over their linear ver- sions (LW and LP).</p><p>Third, let's examine the methods with template scores refined by term similarity and term clus- ters (LW+C, NLW+C, LP+C, NLP+C). It is shown that the refine-by-cluster technology brings addi- tional performance gains on all the four settings (linear and nonlinear, two different ways of calcu- lating tuple scores). So we can conclude that the peer similarity and term clusters are quite effective in improving template generation.</p><p>Fourth, the best performance is achieved when the three techniques (i.e., term→hypernym weight, nonlinear fusion function, and refine-by- cluster) are combined together. For instance, by comparing the P@20 scores of baseline-2 and NLP+C, we see a performance improvement of 14.3% (from 0.734 to 0.839). Therefore every technique studied in this paper has its own merit in template generation.</p><p>Finally, by comparing the method SC (Cheung and Li, 2012) with other methods, we can see that SC is slightly better than baseline-1, but has much lower performance than others. The major reason may be that this method did not employ a weighted term→hypernym graph or term peer similarity in- formation in template construction.  Are the performance differences between meth- ods significant enough for us to say that one is bet- ter than the other? To answer this question, we run paired two-tailed t-test on every pair of methods. We report the t-test values among methods in ta- bles 2, 3 and 4.</p><formula xml:id="formula_16">Base SC LP NLP LP+C SC ∼ LP &gt; * * &gt; * * P@10 NLP &gt; * * &gt; * * &gt; LP+C &gt; * * &gt; * * &gt; * * ∼ NLP+C &gt; * * &gt; * * &gt; * * &gt; * * &gt; Base SC LP NLP LP+C SC ∼ LP &gt; * * &gt; * * P@20 NLP &gt; * * &gt; * * &gt; * * LP+C &gt; * * &gt; * * &gt; * * ∼ NLP+C &gt; * * &gt; * * &gt; * * &gt; * * &gt; * * Base SC LP NLP LP+C SC ∼ LP &gt; * * &gt; * * P@30 NLP &gt; * * &gt; * * &gt; * * LP+C &gt; * * &gt; * * &gt; * * ∼ NLP+C &gt; * * &gt; * * &gt; * * &gt; ∼</formula><formula xml:id="formula_17">Base SC LW NLW LW+C SC ∼ LW &gt; * * &gt; * * P@10 NLW &gt; * * &gt; * * &gt; * LW+C &gt; * * &gt; * * &gt; * * &gt; * * NLW+C &gt; * * &gt; * * &gt; * * &gt; * * &gt; * Base SC LW NLW LW+C SC ∼ LW &gt; * * &gt; * * P@20 NLW &gt; * * &gt; * * &gt; * * LW+C &gt; * * &gt; * * &gt; * * &gt; * * NLW+C &gt; * * &gt; * * &gt; * * &gt; * * &gt; * * Base SC LW NLW LW+C SC ∼ LW &gt; * * &gt; * * P@30 NLW &gt; * * &gt; * * &gt; * * LW+C &gt; * * &gt; * * &gt; * * &gt; * * NLW+C &gt; * * &gt; * * &gt; * * &gt; * * &gt; * *</formula><p>The meaning of the symbols in the tables are, ∼: The method on the row and the one on the column have similar performance. &gt;: The method on the row outperforms the method on the column, but the performance dif- ference is not statistically significant (0.05 ≤ P &lt; 0.1 in two-tailed t-test).</p><p>&gt; * : The performance difference is statistically significant (P &lt; 0.05 in two-tailed t-test).</p><p>&gt; * * : The performance difference is statisti- cally highly significant (P &lt; 0.01 in two-tailed t-test).  </p><formula xml:id="formula_18">P@10 P@20 P@30 LP V.S. LW &gt; * * &gt; * * &gt; * * NLP V.S. NLW &gt; * * &gt; * * &gt; * * LP+C V.S. LW+C ∼ ∼ ∼ NLP+C V.S. NLW+C ∼ ∼ ∼</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.2.2">Fullset results</head><p>As described in the Section 5.1.2, for the fullset experiments, we conduct a section-wise evalua- tion, selecting 40 templates from each of the 9 sec- tions of the NLP+C results. The results are shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Figure 3</ref>. It can be observed that the precision for each section decreases when the section ID in- creases. The results indicate the effectiveness of our approach, since it can rank good templates in top sections and bad templates in bottom sections. According to the section-wise precision data, we are able to determine the template score threshold for choosing different numbers of top templates in different applications.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.2.3">Templates for category collection cleaning</head><p>Since our input category collection is automati- cally constructed from the web, some wrong or invalid category names is inevitably contained. In this subsection, we apply our category templates to clean the category collection. The basic idea is that if a category can match a template, it is more likely to be correct. We compute a new score for every category name H as follows,</p><formula xml:id="formula_19">S new (H) = log(1 + S(H)) · S(T * )<label>(15)</label></formula><p>where S(H) is the existing category score, deter- mined by its frequency in the corpus. Here S(T * ) is the score of template T * , the best template (i.e., the template with the highest score) for the cate- gory.</p><p>Then we re-rank the categories according to their new scores to get a re-ranked category list. We randomly sampled 150 category names from the top 2 million categories of each list (the old list and the new list) and asked annotators to judge the quality of the categories. The annotation results show that, after re-ranking, the precision increases from 0.81 to 0.89 (i.e., the percent of invalid cate- gory names decreases from 19% to 11%).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Conclusion</head><p>In this paper, we studied the problem of build- ing templates for a large collection of category names. We tested three techniques (tuple scor- ing by weighted term→hypernym mapping, non- linear score fusion, refinement by term clusters) and found that all of them are very effective and their combination achieves the best performance. By employing the output templates to clean our category collection mined from the web, we get apparent quality improvement. Future work in- cludes supporting multi-argument templates, dis- ambiguating headwords of category names and ap- plying our approach to general short text template mining.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>(</head><label></label><figDesc>instances: Heritage Day, Christmas…) national holiday of Brazil (instances: Carnival, Christmas…)</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>(</head><label></label><figDesc>instances: low blood sugar…) symptom of insulin deficiency (instances: nocturia, weight loss…) symptom of [hormone] deficiency symptom of [medical condition] school in Denver school in Houston school in [place] school in [city] Semantic Categories Category templates football player basketball player [sport] player</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: Examples of semantic categories and their corresponding templates.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>Figure 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2: Problem definition and baseline approach.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head>Figure 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Figure 3: Precision by section in the fullset.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" validated="false"><head>Table 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Paired t-test results on subsets. 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3" validated="false"><head>Table 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Paired t-test results on subsets. 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4" validated="false"><head>Table 4 : Paired t-test results on subsets.</head><label>4</label><figDesc></figDesc><table></table></figure>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>We would like to thank the annotators for their ef-forts in annotating the templates. Thanks to the anonymous reviewers for their helpful comments and suggestions. This work is supported in part by China National 973 program 2014CB340301 and NSFC grant 61379043.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Towards rich query interpretation: walking back and forth for mining query templates</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ganesh</forename><surname>Agarwal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Govind</forename><surname>Kabra</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kevin Chenchuan</forename><surname>Chang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 19th international conference on World wide web</title>
		<meeting>the 19th international conference on World wide web</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="10" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A study on similarity and relatedness using distributional and wordnet-based approaches</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Eneko</forename><surname>Agirre</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Enrique</forename><surname>Alfonseca</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Keith</forename><surname>Hall</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jana</forename><surname>Kravalova</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of Human Language Technologies</title>
		<meeting>Human Language Technologies</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>The</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Marius Pas¸caPas¸ca, and Aitor Soroa</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
				<title level="m">Annual Conference of the North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="19" to="27" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Association for Computational Linguistics</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nathanael</forename><surname>Chambers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dan</forename><surname>Jurafsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Template-based information extraction without the templates</title>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 49th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics: Human Language Technologies</title>
		<meeting>the 49th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics: Human Language Technologies</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="976" to="986" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Association for Computational Linguistics</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Sequence clustering and labeling for unsupervised query intent discovery</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jackie</forename><forename type="middle">Chi</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kit</forename><surname>Cheung</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xiao</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the fifth ACM international conference on Web search and data mining</title>
		<meeting>the fifth ACM international conference on Web search and data mining</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="383" to="392" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Enriching the gene ontology via the dissection of labels using the ontology pre-processor language</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jesualdo Tomas</forename><surname>Fernandez-Breis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Luigi</forename><surname>Iannone</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ignazio</forename><surname>Palmisano</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alan</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Rector</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Robert</forename><surname>Stevens</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Knowledge Engineering and Management by the Masses</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="59" to="73" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jun</forename><surname>Han</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ju</forename><surname>Fan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lizhu</forename><surname>Zhou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Crowdsourcing-assisted query structure interpretation</title>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Twenty-Third international joint conference on Artificial Intelligence</title>
		<meeting>the Twenty-Third international joint conference on Artificial Intelligence</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>AAAI Press</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2092" to="2098" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Automatic acquisition of hyponyms from large text corpora</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Marti</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Hearst</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 14th conference on Computational linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the 14th conference on Computational linguistics<address><addrLine>Stroudsburg, PA, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1992" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="539" to="545" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>COLING &apos;92. Association for Computational Linguistics</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Semantic class learning from the web with hyponym pattern linkage graphs</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Zornitsa</forename><surname>Kozareva</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ellen</forename><surname>Riloff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Eduard</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Hovy</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ACL</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1048" to="1056" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Extracting structured information from user queries with semi-supervised conditional random fields</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xiao</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ye-Yi</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alex</forename><surname>Acero</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 32nd international ACM SIGIR conference on Research and development in information retrieval</title>
		<meeting>the 32nd international ACM SIGIR conference on Research and development in information retrieval</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="572" to="579" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Unsupervised identification of synonymous query intent templates for attribute intents</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yanen</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bo-June Paul</forename><surname>Hsu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chengxiang</forename><surname>Zhai</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 22nd ACM international conference on Conference on information &amp; knowledge management</title>
		<meeting>the 22nd ACM international conference on Conference on information &amp; knowledge management</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2029" to="2038" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Understanding the semantic structure of noun phrase queries</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xiao</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 48th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the 48th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1337" to="1345" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Unsupervised extraction of template structure in web search queries</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sandeep</forename><surname>Pandey</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kunal</forename><surname>Punera</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 21st international conference on World Wide Web</title>
		<meeting>the 21st international conference on World Wide Web</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="409" to="418" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Discovering word senses from text</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Patrick</forename><surname>Pantel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dekang</forename><surname>Lin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the eighth ACM SIGKDD international conference on Knowledge discovery and data mining</title>
		<meeting>the eighth ACM SIGKDD international conference on Knowledge discovery and data mining</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="613" to="619" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Automatically labeling semantic classes</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Patrick</forename><surname>Pantel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Deepak</forename><surname>Ravichandran</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">HLTNAACL</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="321" to="328" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Web-scale distributional similarity and entity set expansion</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Patrick</forename><surname>Pantel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Eric</forename><surname>Crestan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Arkady</forename><surname>Borkovsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Anamaria</forename><surname>Popescu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Vishnu</forename><surname>Vyas</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2009 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</title>
		<meeting>the 2009 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="938" to="947" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Association for Computational Linguistics</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Enrichment of owl ontologies: a method for defining axioms from labels</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Manuel</forename><surname>Quesada-Martınez</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jesualdo</forename><surname>Tomás Fernández-Breis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Robert</forename><surname>Stevens</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the First International Workshop on Capturing and Refining Knowledge in the Medical Domain (K-MED 2012</title>
		<meeting>the First International Workshop on Capturing and Refining Knowledge in the Medical Domain (K-MED 2012<address><addrLine>Galway, Ireland</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="10" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Finegrained class label markup of search queries</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Joseph</forename><surname>Reisinger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marius</forename><surname>Pasca</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ACL</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1200" to="1209" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Structured annotations of web queries</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nikos</forename><surname>Sarkas</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2010 ACM SIGMOD International Conference on Management of data</title>
		<meeting>the 2010 ACM SIGMOD International Conference on Management of data</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="771" to="782" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Stelios Paparizos, and Panayiotis Tsaparas</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Corpus-based semantic class mining: distributional vs. pattern-based approaches</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Shuming</forename><surname>Shi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Huibin</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xiaojie</forename><surname>Yuan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jirong</forename><surname>Wen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 23rd International Conference on Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the 23rd International Conference on Computational Linguistics</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="993" to="1001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A semantic approach to ie pattern induction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mark</forename><surname>Stevenson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Mark</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Greenwood</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 43rd Annual Meeting on Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the 43rd Annual Meeting on Association for Computational Linguistics</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="379" to="386" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Improving recommendation for long-tail queries via templates</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Idan</forename><surname>Szpektor</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Aristides</forename><surname>Gionis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yoelle</forename><surname>Maarek</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 20th international conference on World wide web</title>
		<meeting>the 20th international conference on World wide web</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="47" to="56" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Hidden semantics: what can we learn from the names in an ontology?</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Allan</forename><surname>Third</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Seventh International Natural Language Generation Conference</title>
		<meeting>the Seventh International Natural Language Generation Conference</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="67" to="75" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Finding cars, goddesses and enzymes: Parametrizable acquisition of labeled instances for open-domain information extraction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Benjamin</forename><surname>Van Durme</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marius</forename><surname>Pasca</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">AAAI</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1243" to="1248" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Counter-training in discovery of semantic patterns</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Roman</forename><surname>Yangarber</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 41st Annual Meeting on Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the 41st Annual Meeting on Association for Computational Linguistics</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="343" to="350" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Nonlinear evidence fusion and propagation for hyponymy relation mining</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Fan</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Shuming</forename><surname>Shi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jing</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Shuqi</forename><surname>Sun</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chin-Yew</forename><surname>Lin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ACL</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1159" to="1168" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
