<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T12:13+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Exploiting Community Emotion for Microblog Event Detection</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
				<availability status="unknown"><p>Copyright Association for Computational Linguistics</p>
				</availability>
				<date>October 25-29, 2014. 2014</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gaoyan</forename><surname>Ou</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Ministry of Education</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">Key Laboratory of High Confidence Software Technologies</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">School of Electronics Engineering and Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Peking University</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wei</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Ministry of Education</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">Key Laboratory of High Confidence Software Technologies</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">School of Electronics Engineering and Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Peking University</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tengjiao</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Ministry of Education</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">Key Laboratory of High Confidence Software Technologies</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">School of Electronics Engineering and Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Peking University</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Zhongyu</forename><surname>Wei</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="department">Shenzhen Research Institute</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">The Chinese University of Hong Kong</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Binyang</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Ministry of Education</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">Key Laboratory of High Confidence Software Technologies</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff3">
								<orgName type="department">Dept. of Information Science &amp; Technology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of International Relations</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dongqing</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Ministry of Education</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">Key Laboratory of High Confidence Software Technologies</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">School of Electronics Engineering and Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Peking University</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kam-Fai</forename><surname>Wong</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Ministry of Education</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">Key Laboratory of High Confidence Software Technologies</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="department">Shenzhen Research Institute</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">The Chinese University of Hong Kong</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Exploiting Community Emotion for Microblog Event Detection</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2014 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP)</title>
						<meeting>the 2014 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP) <address><addrLine>Doha, Qatar. c</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="1159" to="1168"/>
							<date type="published">October 25-29, 2014. 2014</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Microblog has become a major platform for information about real-world events. Automatically discovering real-world events from microblog has attracted the attention of many researchers. However , most of existing work ignore the importance of emotion information for event detection. We argue that people&apos;s emotional reactions immediately reflect the occurring of real-world events and should be important for event detection. In this study, we focus on the problem of community-related event detection by community emotions. To address the problem, we propose a novel framework which include the following three key components: mi-croblog emotion classification, community emotion aggregation and community emotion burst detection. We evaluate our approach on real microblog data sets. Experimental results demonstrate the effectiveness of the proposed framework.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Microblog has become a popular and convenient platform for people to share information about so- cial events in real time. When an external even- t occurs, it will be quickly propagated between microblog users. During propagation process of an event, sufficient amount of users will express their emotions. Taking Sina Weibo 1 as an exam- ple, more than 12 percent of users use emoticons 2 when reposting an event-related microblog mes- sage.</p><p>The emotion information can not only help us better understand a given event, but also be u- tilized to discover new events.  Earthquake in Japan. We can see that emotional changes immediately reflect the occurring of real- world events, thus it is reasonable to use them to perform event detection. Most existing research on microblog event de- tection ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">Weng and Lee, 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Sakaki et al., 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Becker et al., 2010</ref>) only account for the factu- al information (e.g., burstness of topic keyword- s). They usually ignore the importance of emo- tion information for event detection. Although there have recently been a few papers ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Zhao et al., 2012a;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Nguyen et al., 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Akcora et al., 2010)</ref> in this direction, they have a number of disad- vantages. Firstly, they can not detect community- related events. Since they all aggregate emotion at global level, they can only discover national at- tention events, such as public holidays ( "Christ- mas" and "Spring Festival") or natural disasters. In many applications, discovering events related to a certain group of users or a certain topic is more meaningful. Consider the following ques- tions: "what happened in the football communi- ty last week?" and "what are the most significant events in the lawyer community last month?" Sec- ondly, they assign equal weight to each microblog message or user when aggregating them to a glob- al emotion score. Such approaches may lead to incorrect results when a user posts emotion spam in the community. Thirdly, there is a lack of quan- titative evaluation using real-world events in exist- ing work. For example, there is only case study in ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Zhao et al., 2012a)</ref> and <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Akcora et al., 2010)</ref>.</p><p>In this study, we focus on a new task of de- tecting community-related events via community emotion. Our intuition is inspired from the so- cial psychology theory of group emotion. In social psychology, group emotion refers to the moods, emotions and dispositional affects of a group of people 3 . It can arise as a result of group-relevant events ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">Smith et al., 2007)</ref>. For example, people will feel happy when their favorite football team wins a game and feel sad when their team loses a game. Thus we can use the community emo- tion as signals to detect community-related events. To achieve good performance of this new task, the following two factors must be considered: 1) how to measure the community emotion based on mi- croblog message or user emotion and 2) how to perform event detection based on the sequence of community emotion.</p><p>To measure community emotion, we argue that in a given community, different users have differ- ent emotional authorities. The emotion of highly influential people in the community may be more important in determining the community emotion <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Barsäde and Gibson, 1998)</ref>. We propose to use the user's emotion authority computed by the so- cial network of the community to weight the us- er when aggregating community emotion. Since spam user is unlikely to have high emotion au- thority in the community, our method can reduce the effect of emotion spam. Based on the com- munity emotion, we present an emotion burst de- tection algorithm for the community emotion dis- tribution sequence. We identify two emotional s- tates of the community: "emotion stable" state and "emotion burst" state. We use the Dirichlet dis- tribution to model the generation process of the community emotion distribution. An efficient e- motion burst detection algorithm is presented to detect community-related events.</p><p>We evaluate our approach on large-scale mi- croblog data sets by using real-world event list for each community. Experimental results demon- strate that the community emotion is an effective signal for community-related event detection. In comparison with several baseline methods, our e- motion burst detection algorithm also improves</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Related Work</head><p>In this section, we review the related work on sen- timent analysis and event detection in microblog, respectively.</p><p>Sentiment Analysis in Microblog: Sentiment analysis ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">Pang and Lee, 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Liu, 2012</ref>) is main- ly about analyzing people's opinions, sentiments and emotions towards a given event, topic, produc- t, etc. Microblog platforms like Twitter and Wei- bo, provide people a convenient way to post their emotional reactions towards social events in al- most real time. This leads to increasing number of interests on sentiment analysis in microblog da- ta ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Davidov et al., 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Go et al., 2009;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Agarwal et al., 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Pak and Paroubek, 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Jiang et al., 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Speriosu et al., 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Bermingham and Smeaton, 2010)</ref>. The training data for microblog sentiment analysis are usual- ly obtained in an automatic manner by utilizing emoticons, hashtags and smileys. <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Davidov et al. (2010)</ref> propose an approach to automatically ob- tain labeled training examples by exploiting hash- tags and smileys.  proposed an e- moticon smoothed method to integrate both manu- ally labeled data and noisy labeled data for Twitter sentiment classification.</p><p>Different from existing microblog sentimen- t analysis work, which aims at discovering senti- ments and emotions for an event or topic given in advance, we are interested in utilizing the emotion information in microblog messages for real-world event detection. Our work use sentiment analysis as a tool to perform microblog emotion classifi- cation. Then we propose an event detection algo- rithm based on the sequence of community level emotion distribution.</p><p>Event Detection in Microblog: Event detec- tion from microblog data has attracted increas- ing attention recently. We divide existing work into the following two categories: non-emotion- based methods and emotion-based methods. Non- emotion-based methods try to exploit keyword or activity patterns to discover events ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">Weng and Lee, 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Sakaki et al., 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Becker et al., 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Mathioudakis and Koudas, 2010)</ref>. <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Mathioudakis and Koudas (2010)</ref> first identify "bursty" key- words and then discover events by grouping bursty keywords together. <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">Zhao et al. (2012b)</ref> focuses on identifying event-related burst from social media based on multiple activities. They propose a uni- fied optimization model to integrate multiple cor- related activity streams based on the state machine in <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(Kleinberg, 2003)</ref>.</p><p>Emotion-based methods try to exploit the emo- tional reactions to discover events ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Zhao et al., 2012a;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Akcora et al., 2010)</ref>. <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Akcora et al. (2010)</ref> model public emotion as an emotion vector com- puted by counting emotion words and then use a rule-based method to identify public breakpoints. <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Zhao et al. (2012a)</ref> use a simple top-k method to detect abnormal events based on sequence of sen- timent variance.</p><p>Our method is also an emotion-based method. However, our approach is different from existing emotion-based methods in the following aspect- s. Firstly, while existing work aggregates emotion for all users, we focus on emotion for a certain community to discover community-related events. Secondly, existing methods assume that the emo- tions of different users are of equal importance. We distinguish user's emotional authority based on the community structure of users.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Preliminary Definitions</head><p>In this section, we first give some basic concepts before formally defining our problem.</p><p>Topical Community: A group of connected users that are interested in a specific topic. A topi- cal community can be denoted as C = {V, E, M }, where V is the set of community users, E is the set of relationships of between users. M = {M 1 , M 2 , ..., M T } is the microblog message col- lection in the community, which is segmented ac- cording to time. M t is the microblog message col- lection in time interval t.</p><p>Emotion Distribution: An emotion distribu- tion e t is a real-value N -dimension vector sampled from the emotion space, satisfying the constraint ∑ N i=1 e ti = 1. It indicates the emotional state of a microblog message, a user or a community at time t. At a given time interval t, a user emotion distri- bution e t (u) is computed by an aggregation func- tion over the emotion distribution of the microblog messages posted by u in time interval t. Commu- nity emotion distribution e t (c) is computed by an aggregation function over the emotion distribution of the community users in c at time interval t.</p><p>Community Emotion Burst: Given an emo- tion distribution sequence e t for community c, an emotion burst is defined as period [t s , t e ] in which some event relevant to c takes places. During the time period, the emotion distribution of c is :1) sig- nificantly different from its average emotion distri- bution, or 2) extremely uneven distributed.</p><p>Given the above definitions, our object is then to detect community-related events from the emotion distribution sequence of the community.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">The Proposed Framework</head><p>In this section, we describe our microblog event detection framework. The framework aims to de- tect community-related events based on the com- munity emotion. The overview of our framework is shown in <ref type="figure">Figure 2</ref>. In particular, we define the following four main components: 1) Microblog emotion classification: We train emotion classification model by automatically ac- quiring training data using the emoticons.</p><p>2) Community emotion aggregation: We as- sume that in a given community, different users have different weights when aggregating commu- nity emotion. Thus we propose a novel weighting approach based on the user's authority.</p><p>3) Community emotion burst detection: Giv- en the community emotion, we propose an emo- tion burst detection algorithm to detect community emotion bursts. 4) Event extraction: The function of this com- ponent is to extract event keywords for each com- munity emotion burst. We count the document frequency (DF) of each term contained in the mi- croblog messages in the burst period. Then the top-5 DF terms are used to describe the event oc- curring during the burst period, although there ex- ist alternative techniques ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">Ritter et al., 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Li et al., 2010)</ref>.</p><p>Since the last component is not the main focus of this work, we only introduce the first three com- ponents in detail in the following subsections.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">Microblog Emotion Classification</head><p>We build an emotion classifier using the multino- mial Na¨ıveNa¨ıve Bayes classifier for each community to classify microblog messages into different emo- tion classes. Here we are interested in the setting where the microblog messages arrive as stream, thus it is not appropriate to use a constant set of manually labeled messages. To avoid manual an- notation cost, we adopt a distant supervision ap- proach ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Go et al., 2009;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Davidov et al., 2010</ref>; Hu</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Microblog Emotion Classification</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Community Emotion Aggregation</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Community Emotion Burst Detection</head><p>Community Network</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Microblog</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Streams Event Extraction</head><p>Figure 2: Overview of our community-related event detection framework et al., 2013) to acquire labeled microblog mes- sages automatically by using the emoticons. We first select a set of emoticons which are most fre- quently used to express emotion in microblog.</p><p>Then we manually map each emoticon into four emotion classes (26 for happy, 19 for anger, 13 for sad and 11 for fear). We only show the top five emoticons for each emotion type in <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table 1.</ref> The labeled emoticons can then be used to acquire training data to train an emotion classifier for a community in any time period. We combine the features which have been proven effective by previous work, such as punc- tuation and emotion lexicons. Specifically, we use the following features : 1) Words appearing in the microblog message serve as word features, 2) Number of "!" characters and "?" in the microblog message, and 3) Each term in a general emotion lexicon serves as an emotion lexicon feature.</p><p>The emotion distribution e(m) of a microblog message m is represented by a N -dimension dis- tribution vector. For example, if a microblog mes- sage m is classified as happy, then its emotion dis- tribution e(m) is [1, 0, 0, 0]. The emotion distribu- tion of e(u) of user u at time t is average emotion distribution of the microblog messages posted by him during time t.</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">e t (u) = 1 N ut Nut ∑ m=1 e(m)<label>(1)</label></formula><p>where N ut is the number of microblog messages posted by user u at time t.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">Community-level Emotion Aggregation</head><p>A common strategy to measure community emo- tion is to compute the average emotion of the com- munity users. It is based on the assumption that the emotion of different community users are with e- qual importance. This is implemented by employ- ing an average aggregation function on the indi- vidual emotion distribution e t (u):</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">e t (c) = 1 N c ∑ u∈c e t (u)<label>(2)</label></formula><p>where N c is the number of users in community c.</p><p>Intuitively, the emotion of user with higher au- thority in community should be more important in determining community emotion. Thus we esti- mate community emotion by taking into account user's emotional authority, which is based on the assumption that different users in a community have different emotional authorities.</p><p>We employ HITS algorithm <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Kleinberg, 1999</ref>) to compute the user authority auth(u) based on the user network {V, E} of the community. Then auth(u) is used to represent the emotional author- ity of user u. This authority-based community e- motion aggregation approach can also reduce the effect of spam users, since they usually have low authorities in the community network. For sim- plicity and computation efficiency, we assume that auth(u) is time independent, which means that we only need to run the HITS algorithm once for each community. Given the user emotion distribution- s and the user emotional authorities, the emotion distribution for a community c in time interval t can be measured as:</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">e t (c) = 1 A ct ∑ u∈c auth(u)e t (u)<label>(3)</label></formula><p>where A ct = ∑ u∈ct auth(u) is the normalization term.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3">Community Emotion Burst Detection</head><p>We formulate our problem into the binary state model framework <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(Kleinberg, 2003)</ref>. For a giv- en community c, there are T time intervals in total, with community emotion distribution se- quence e = (e 1 , e 2 , ..., e T ) and state sequence q = (q 1 , q 2 , ..., q T ). Each q t can be one of the fol- lowing two states: q t = 0 ("emotion stable" state) and q t = 1 ("emotion burst" state). Our objective (a) "emotion stable" state (b) "emotion burst" state <ref type="figure">Figure 3</ref>: Emotion probability density for "emo- tion stable" state and "emotion burst" state is to find an optimal state sequence q * given the emotion distribution sequence e.</p><p>Since each e t is a distribution rather than pos- itive integer, the emotion generation process can no longer be modeled by a Poisson distribution. We choose to model the emotion generation pro- cess by the Dirichlet distribution. This process is analogous to the document-level topic generation in the LDA topic model ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Blei et al., 2003)</ref>.</p><p>If community c is in an "emotion stable" state in time interval t, its emotion distribution e t should be close to the average emotion distribution e a . The density function is defined as f (e t , e a , s t = 0) = Dirichlet(α 0 e a ), where s t = 0 indicates that the community is in an "emotion stable" s- tate and α 0 is a positive parameter. To ensure that e t closer to e a will get higher probability, α 0 should satisfy the constraint α 0 · min e a &gt; 1. An example of the probability density function of f (e t , e a , s t = 0) in a three dimension emotion s- pace is shown in <ref type="figure">Figure 3(a)</ref>.</p><p>If community c is in an "emotion burst" s- tate in time interval t, the emotion distribution of c is : 1) significantly different from its av- erage emotion distribution, or 2) extremely un- even distributed. For example, assume e a = [0.25, 0.25, 0.25, 0.25], if community is in burst in time interval t, its emotion distribution is more likely to be [0.1, 0.4, 0.1, 0.4] (significantly dif- ferent from e a ) or [0.1, 0.7, 0.1, 0.1] (extremely anger). The density function is then defined as f (e t , e a , s t = 1) = Dirichlet(α 1 e a ). s t = 1 indicates that the community is in an "emotion burst" state and α 1 should satisfy the constraint: α 1 · max e a &lt; 1. An example of the probabili- ty density function of f (e t , e a , s t = 1) in a three dimension emotion space is shown in <ref type="figure">Figure 3(b)</ref>.</p><p>Based on above discussion, the cost function for an emotion state sequence q can be defined as:</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">cost(q|e) = T ∑ t=1 − ln(f t (e t , e a , q t )) + b ln( 1 − π π )<label>(4)</label></formula><p>where π is the probability the community will change the emotion state in two consecutive time intervals t and t + 1. b denotes the number of e- motion state changes in the whole time intervals <ref type="bibr">[1, T ]</ref>.</p><p>Equation 4 is exactly the objective function we need to optimize. This optimization problem can be efficiently solved by using a dynamic program- ming procedure, as summarized in Algorithm 1. Algorithm 1 mainly consists of two phases: a forward phase (line 5 -line 10) which calculates the minimal cost for emotion distribution sub- sequence and a backward phase to construct the optimal emotion state sequence (line 11 -line 14).</p><p>For convenience, we use f t (s) to denote</p><formula xml:id="formula_4">f t (e t , e a , s). π s ′ s = π if s ′ ̸ = s, otherwise π s ′ s = (1 − π)</formula><p>. c t (s) denotes the minimal cost of generating the emotion distribution sub-sequence {e 1 , ..., e t } with q t = s. q ′ t (s) stores the state of time interval t − 1 for the most likely state sub- sequence so far with q t = s.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Algorithm 1 Emotion Burst Extraction</head><p>Input: The emotion distribution sequence e = (e 1 , e 2 , ..., e T ), the state transition cost π and the parameters α 0 and α 1 1: for each s ∈ {0, 1} do for each s ∈ {0, 1} do </p><formula xml:id="formula_5">c t (s) = min s ′ (c t−1 (s ′ ) − ln f t (s) − ln π s ′ s ) 8: q ′ t (s) = arg min s (c t−1 (s ′ ) − ln π s ′ s ) 9:</formula><p>end for 10: end for 11: q * (T ) = arg min s c T (s) <ref type="bibr">12:</ref> for each t = T − 1, · · · , 2 do q * (t) = q ′ t+1 (q * (t + 1)) 14: end for Output: The optimal emotion state sequence q * <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table 2: Basic statistics of data sets   Community #User  #Link  #Microblog #Event  legal cases  4937  97639  269871  31  football  9928  105483  416631  75  economy  2657  65403  179584  46  singer  3759  79458  478265  53</ref> 5 Experimental Setup</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.1">Data Set</head><p>We use a large microblog data set crawled from Sina Weibo, which is the most popular mi- croblog service in China. This data set contains 212,859,466 Chinese microblog messages posted by 916,126 users in a period of about 8 month- s (1/12/2010∼ 20/7/2011). We also crawled the following network, which resulted in 15,681,296 following relationships for the 916,126 users. We choose four communities: "legal cases", "football", "economy" and "singer". To obtain the members for each topical community, we manu- ally selected several keywords and input them as queries to the user search page <ref type="bibr">4</ref> . After filtering out the users whose microblog messages are not col- lected in our corpora, we extract the sub-network of the users from the whole following network.</p><p>We use a simple but efficient method to extract microblog messages for each topical community: 1) If a microblog message is posted by the com- munity members and also contains keywords of the community, it belongs to the community; 2) If a microblog message is posted by community member u and it is reposting, commenting on or replying to another microblog posted by commu- nity member v, then it belongs to the community. The basic statistics of our data sets are shown in <ref type="table">Table 2</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.2">Ground Truth Generation</head><p>Algorithm 1 generates a list of emotion bursts for each community. Since our goal is to identi- fy community-related events, we need to evaluate how well the generated emotion bursts correspond to the ground truth real-world events. To gener- ate the ground truth for evaluation, we utilize the news website Sina News <ref type="bibr">5</ref> . Two PhD students are invited to manually generate a list of real events for each community by referring to the annual top-ic summary page 6 of Sina News. The annotation agreement is higher than 90%. Each event is al- so associated with its occurred date. The number of events for each community is shown in the last column of <ref type="table">Table 2</ref>. For each community, the even- t list is then used to evaluate the performance of different event detection models.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.3">Evaluation Metric</head><p>We use precision, recall and F-measure as evalu- ation metric. For each community, we compare the event list E c and the generated burst list B c to compute the above metric. Specifically, the preci- sion, recall and F-measure for a community c are defined as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_6">P = ∑ |E c | j=1 ∑ |B c | k=1 I(E c j ∈ B c k ) |B c | (5) R = ∑ |E c | j=1 ∑ |B c | k=1 I(E c j ∈ B c k ) |E c | (6) F = 2 × P × R P + R<label>(7)</label></formula><p>where E c j is the occurring time of the j-th event in community c, B c k is the k-th identified burst for community c. I(.) is the indicator function (which equals 1 if its argument is true and 0 otherwise).</p><p>The final precision, recall and F-measure are av- eraged over different communities.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.4">Compared Methods</head><p>We now introduce four methods used for compar- ison as follows:</p><p>EmoPeakFind: The method proposed in <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Akcora et al., 2010)</ref>, which aims at discovering breakpoints from public emotion. They use the following simple rule to find breakpoints from e- motion sequences:</p><formula xml:id="formula_7">Sim(e t−1 , e t ) &lt; Sim(e t−2 , e t−1 )<label>(8)</label></formula><p>Sim(e t−1 , e t ) &lt; Sim(e t , e t+1 )</p><p>where Sim is a similarity function. We use the cosine similarity function in our evaluation. TopKEmoVar: The method used in (Zhao et al., 2012a). They first derive a sequence of relative variation V n for each single emotion sequence e n . Then they define a sequence of emotion variation as ( ∑ 4 n=1 |V n t |). This sequence is sorted in de- scending order and the top-k t is selected as burst state points, where k is set to be the size of the event list for each community. KLB: The method proposed in <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(Kleinberg, 2003)</ref>. Note that KLB can only deal with a single sequence e n = (e n 1 , ..., e n t , ...e n T ) for emotion type n. We first apply KLB to find the optimal state se- quences for each emotion type. Then we perform an OR function to merge the N state sequences to a global emotion state sequence.</p><p>MBurst: The method proposed in ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">Zhao et al., 2012b</ref>) for multi-stream burst detection. MBurst is evaluated on three activity streams in ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">Zhao et al., 2012b</ref>). Here we apply MBurst to the N emo- tion streams. Then we perform an OR function to merge the N state sequences to a global emotion state sequence.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Experimental Results</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.1">Performance Comparison Results</head><p>In this experiment, we compare our method with different baseline methods as introduced in Sec- tion 5.4. We use Equation (3) to aggregate com- munity emotion for all the compared methods. The parameter α 0 and α 1 are empirically set to be 5 minn e n a and 0.5 maxn e n a , respectively. The experimen- tal results are shown in <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Table 3</ref>. <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Table 3</ref> shows that EmoPeakFind and TopKE- moVari are less effective than other methods. The simple rule used in EmoPeakFind produced many noisy bursts, leading to low precision. TopKE- moVari only considers the relative variation of t- wo consecutive time intervals. The choose of k is also nontrivial since it is hard to know the number of events before the events are identi- fied. Note that EmoPeakFind and TopKEmoVari are both rule-based methods, while KLB, MBurst and Our Method are state machine based method- s. This demonstrates that for community-related emotion burst detection, it is more appropriate to use a state machine based model. It looks surprising that MBurst performs worse than KLB, since MBurst is specifically designed for multiple streams. However, MBurst is based on the assumption that the states of multiple streams in the same time interval tend to be the same (i.e., there is positive correlation between t- wo different streams). This assumption no longer holds in the context of different emotion stream- s. For example, if a negative event occurs in the community, while sad emotion is likely to be in a burst state, happy emotion is not likely to be in a burst state. We can see from <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Table 3</ref> that our method out- performs the four baselines. The main reason is that our burst detection method is based on the se- quence of community emotion distribution. Mod- eling community emotion as a distribution is more suitable than modeling several different emotion types.</p><p>We further show some example events detected by our model in <ref type="table">Table 4</ref>. Since the event keyword- s are manually translated from Chinese, one key- word may include more than one English word- s. We can see that community emotion can help to detect emotionally significant events for differ- ent communities. For example, the "legal cases" community is in a strong anger emotional state on December 25, 2010, which indicates an important event "Qian Yunhui's case".</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.2">Effect of Emotion Aggregation Functions</head><p>In this experiment, we show the importance of cor- rectly aggregation community level emotion for community-related event detection. We compare the two aggregation approaches introduced in sec- tion 4.2. The first approach assigns equal weight to each community users, while the second approach assigns weights to users based on their authorities in the community.</p><p>The performance in terms of F-measure is shown in <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">Table 5</ref>. It is obvious that, for all commu- <ref type="table">Table 4</ref>: Examples of events and the corresponding community emotions for two communities. The four emotion types (happy, anger, sad and fear) are mapped to green, red, blue and yellow color, respectively. We further perform an empirically analysis of the events that successfully identified by HITS- based approach but failed by equal weighting ap- proach. By manually analyzing the microblog messages of the corresponding time intervals, we found that most of the errors of equal weighting approach were caused by emotion spam. Users of low authority post many microblog messages with extreme emotion to claim the attention of the com- munity. Since there is no significant community- related events at that time interval, we do not ob- serve emotional changes of the high authority us- es. In the equal weighting method, the existence of emotion spam lead to wrong result of com- munity emotion. Since the weights of users who post emotion spam are small in the HITS-based approach, they have little effect on the communi- ty emotion. This is the main reason why HITS- based weighting method is more effective than e- qual weighting method.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Community</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.3">Parameter Sensitivity</head><p>In this experiment, we test the sensitivity of our model by different choices of the param- eters α 0 and α 1 . α 0 min n e n a is set to be <ref type="bibr">[2,</ref><ref type="bibr">3,</ref><ref type="bibr">4,</ref><ref type="bibr">5,</ref><ref type="bibr">6,</ref><ref type="bibr">7,</ref><ref type="bibr">8]</ref> and α 1 max n e n a is set to be [0.2, 0.3, 0.4, 0.5, 0.6, 0.7, 0.8]. The event detec- tion results of different parameter settings are shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">Figure 4</ref>.</p><p>It can be seen from <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">Figure 4</ref> that: 1) The per- formance is relatively good in a particular range of the parameters. When In general, the performance is more sensitive to α 1 than to α 0 . Note that α 1 controls the generation process of the emotion distribution when the community is in the "emotion burst" state, thus it is relatively more important to tune α 1 than α 0 . The experimental results demonstrates that when 0.3 maxn e n a ≤ α 1 ≤ 0.7 maxn e n a , the performance can be relatively good.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7">Conclusion</head><p>Microblog has become a popular and convenien- t platform for people to share information about social events in real time. In this paper, we focus on the problem of community-related event detec- tion by community emotions. We propose a novel method to compute community-level emotion by considering the user authority in the community network. Then we present an effective emotion burst detection algorithm for the community emo- tion distribution sequence.</p><p>We evaluate our approach on real microblog data sets. Experimental results demonstrate that it is important to take into account the user au- thority when aggregating community emotion for community-related event detection. Our emotion burst detection algorithm also achieves better per- formance than several baseline methods.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 1 shows 1 http://weibo.com/ 2 An icon to indicate user's emotion, as shown in Table 1.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: The global emotion dynamics</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>2: Initialize c 1 (s) = − ln f 1 (s) 3: Initialize q ′ 1 (s) = 0 4: end for 5: for each t = 2, · · · , T do 6:</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><head>Figure 4 :</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Figure 4: F-measure of our method for event detection in different parameter settings</figDesc><graphic url="image-31.png" coords="8,346.95,256.43,149.25,97.30" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" validated="true"><head>Table 1 : List of emoticons</head><label>1</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Happy(26) 
good 
laugh 
love 
smile 
cute 

Anger (19) 
anger 
hate 
curse 
despise 
crazy 

Sad(13) 
sad 
disappoint 
cry 
unhappy 
unwell 

Fear(11) 
fear 
surprise 
shame 
doubt 
fright 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" validated="true"><head>Table 3 : Event detection performance of different methods</head><label>3</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Method 
Precision Recall F-measure 
EmoPeakFind 
0.313 
0.625 
0.417 
TopKEmoVari 
0.423 
0.423 
0.423 
KLB 
0.575 
0.702 
0.632 
MBurst 
0.534 
0.497 
0.515 
Our Method 
0.654 
0.715 
0.683 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" validated="true"><head>Table 5 : Performance of different weighting schemes in terms of F-measure</head><label>5</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Community 
Weighting schema 
equal HITS-based 
legal cases 0.517 
0.590 
football 
0.674 
0.765 
economy 
0.642 
0.712 
singer 
0.589 
0.665 
avg 
0.605 
0.683 

</table></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="3"> http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Group emotion the event detection performance in terms of precision, recall and F-measure.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="4"> http://s.weibo.com/user/&amp;tag=keyword 5 http://news.sina.com.cn</note>

			<note place="foot" n="6"> http://news.sina.com.cn/zt/</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>The authors would like to thank the anony-mous reviewers for their insightful comments and suggestions.</p><p>This </p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Sentiment analysis of twitter data</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Apoorv</forename><surname>Agarwal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Boyi</forename><surname>Xie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ilia</forename><surname>Vovsha</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Owen</forename><surname>Rambow</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rebecca</forename><surname>Passonneau</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Workshop on Languages in Social Media</title>
		<meeting>the Workshop on Languages in Social Media</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="30" to="38" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Identifying breakpoints in public opinion</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Cuneyt Gurcan Akcora</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ali</forename><surname>Murat</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Murat</forename><surname>Bayir</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hakan</forename><surname>Demirbas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Ferhatosmanoglu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the First Workshop on Social Media Analytics</title>
		<meeting>the First Workshop on Social Media Analytics</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="62" to="66" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Sigal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Donald</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Barsäde</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Gibson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Group emotion: A view from top and bottom. Research on Managing Groups and Teams</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="81" to="102" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Learning similarity metrics for event identification in social media</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hila</forename><surname>Becker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mor</forename><surname>Naaman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Luis</forename><surname>Gravano</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the third ACM international conference on Web search and data mining</title>
		<meeting>the third ACM international conference on Web search and data mining</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="291" to="300" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Classifying sentiment in microblogs: is brevity an advantage?</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Adam</forename><surname>Bermingham</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alan</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Smeaton</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">CIKM</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1833" to="1836" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Latent dirichlet allocation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Blei</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Andrew</forename><forename type="middle">Y</forename><surname>Ng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michael</forename><forename type="middle">I</forename><surname>Jordan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Machine Learning Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="993" to="1022" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Enhanced sentiment learning using twitter hashtags and smileys</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dmitry</forename><surname>Davidov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Oren</forename><surname>Tsur</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ari</forename><surname>Rappoport</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">COLING (Posters)</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="241" to="249" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Twitter sentiment classification using distant supervision</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alec</forename><surname>Go</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Richa</forename><surname>Bhayani</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lei</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="12" />
			<pubPlace>Stanford</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
<note type="report_type">CS224N Project Report</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Unsupervised sentiment analysis with emotional signals</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xia</forename><surname>Hu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jiliang</forename><surname>Tang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Huiji</forename><surname>Gao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Huan</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">WWW</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="607" to="618" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Target-dependent twitter sentiment classification</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Long</forename><surname>Jiang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mo</forename><surname>Yu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ming</forename><surname>Zhou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xiaohua</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tiejun</forename><surname>Zhao</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ACL</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="151" to="160" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Authoritative sources in a hyperlinked environment</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Jon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Kleinberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of the ACM (JACM)</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">46</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="604" to="632" />
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Bursty and hierarchical structure in streams</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jon</forename><surname>Kleinberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Data Mining and Knowledge Discovery</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="373" to="397" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Keyword extraction for social snippets</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Zhenhui</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ding</forename><surname>Zhou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yun-Fang</forename><surname>Juan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jiawei</forename><surname>Han</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 19th international conference on World wide web</title>
		<meeting>the 19th international conference on World wide web</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1143" to="1144" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Emoticon smoothed language models for twitter sentiment analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Kun-Lin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wu-Jun</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Minyi</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Guo</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">AAAI</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Sentiment analysis and opinion mining</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bing</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Synthesis Lectures on Human Language Technologies</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="167" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Twittermonitor: trend detection over the twitter stream</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Mathioudakis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nick</forename><surname>Koudas</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2010 ACM SIGMOD International Conference on Management of data</title>
		<meeting>the 2010 ACM SIGMOD International Conference on Management of data</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1155" to="1158" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Event extraction using behaviors of sentiment signals and burst structure in social media</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Thin</forename><surname>Nguyen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dinh</forename><forename type="middle">Q</forename><surname>Phung</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Brett</forename><surname>Adams</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Svetha</forename><surname>Venkatesh</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Knowl. Inf. Syst</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">37</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="279" to="304" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Twitter as a corpus for sentiment analysis and opinion mining</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alexander</forename><surname>Pak</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Patrick</forename><surname>Paroubek</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">LREC</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Opinion mining and sentiment analysis. Foundations and trends in information retrieval</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bo</forename><surname>Pang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lillian</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="135" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Open domain event extraction from twitter</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alan</forename><surname>Ritter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Oren</forename><surname>Etzioni</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sam</forename><surname>Clark</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 18th ACM SIGKDD international conference on Knowledge discovery and data mining</title>
		<meeting>the 18th ACM SIGKDD international conference on Knowledge discovery and data mining</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1104" to="1112" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Earthquake shakes twitter users: real-time event detection by social sensors</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Takeshi</forename><surname>Sakaki</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Makoto</forename><surname>Okazaki</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yutaka</forename><surname>Matsuo</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">WWW</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="851" to="860" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Can emotions be truly group level? evidence regarding four conceptual criteria</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Eliot</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Charles</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Smith</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Diane</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Seger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Mackie</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of personality and social psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">93</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">431</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Twitter polarity classification with label propagation over lexical links and the follower graph</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Speriosu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nikita</forename><surname>Sudan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sid</forename><surname>Upadhyay</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jason</forename><surname>Baldridge</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">EMNLP</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="53" to="63" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Event detection in twitter</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jianshu</forename><surname>Weng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bu-Sung</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ICWSM</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Moodlens: an emoticon-based sentiment analysis system for chinese tweets</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jichang</forename><surname>Zhao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Li</forename><surname>Dong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Junjie</forename><surname>Wu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ke</forename><surname>Xu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">KDD</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1528" to="1531" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Identifying event-related bursts via social media activities</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Baihan</forename><surname>Wayne Xin Zhao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jing</forename><surname>Shu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yang</forename><surname>Jiang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hongfei</forename><surname>Song</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xiaoming</forename><surname>Yan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2012 Joint Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing and Computational Natural Language Learning</title>
		<meeting>the 2012 Joint Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing and Computational Natural Language Learning</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1466" to="1477" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Association for Computational Linguistics</note>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
