<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T11:36+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">A Rule-Based System for Unrestricted Bridging Resolution: Recognizing Bridging Anaphora and Finding Links to Antecedents</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
				<availability status="unknown"><p>Copyright Association for Computational Linguistics</p>
				</availability>
				<date>October 25-29, 2014. 2014</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yufang</forename><surname>Hou</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Heidelberg Institute for Theoretical Studies gGmbH</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Heidelberg</settlement>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Katja</forename><surname>Markert</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">School of Computing</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Leeds</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="GB">UK</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Strube</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Heidelberg Institute for Theoretical Studies gGmbH</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Heidelberg</settlement>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">A Rule-Based System for Unrestricted Bridging Resolution: Recognizing Bridging Anaphora and Finding Links to Antecedents</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2014 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP)</title>
						<meeting>the 2014 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP) <address><addrLine>Doha, Qatar. c</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="2082" to="2093"/>
							<date type="published">October 25-29, 2014. 2014</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Bridging resolution plays an important role in establishing (local) entity coherence. This paper proposes a rule-based approach for the challenging task of unrestricted bridging resolution, where bridging anaphors are not limited to definite NPs and semantic relations between anaphors and their antecedents are not restricted to meronymic relations. The system consists of eight rules which target different relations based on linguistic insights. Our rule-based system significantly outperforms a reimplementation of a previous rule-based system (Vieira and Poe-sio, 2000). Furthermore, it performs better than a learning-based approach which has access to the same knowledge resources as the rule-based system. Additionally, incorporating the rules and more features into the learning-based system yields a minor improvement over the rule-based system .</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Bridging resolution recovers the various non- identity relations between anaphora and an- tecedents. It plays an important role in establish- ing entity coherence in a text. In Example 1, the links between the bridging anaphors (The five as- tronauts and touchdown) and the antecedent (The space shuttle Atlantis) establish (local) entity co- herence. <ref type="bibr">1</ref> (1) The space shuttle Atlantis landed at a desert air strip at Edwards Air Force Base, Calif., ending a five-day mission that dispatched the Jupiter-bound Galileo space probe. The five astronauts returned to Earth about three hours early because high winds had been pre- dicted at the landing site. Fog shrouded the base before touchdown.</p><p>Bridging or associative anaphora has been widely discussed in the linguistic literature <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Clark, 1975;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b23">Prince, 1981;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Gundel et al., 1993;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Löbner, 1998)</ref>. <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Poesio and Vieira (1998)</ref> and <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Bunescu (2003)</ref> include cases where antecedent and anaphor are coreferent but do not share the same head noun (different-head coreference). We follow our previous work ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Hou et al., 2013b</ref>) and restrict bridging to non-coreferential cases. We also exclude comparative anaphora ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Modjeska et al., 2003)</ref>.</p><p>Bridging resolution includes two subtasks: (1) recognizing bridging anaphors and (2) finding the correct antecedent among candidates. In recent empirical work, these two subtasks have been tackled separately: <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">(Markert et al., 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Cahill and Riester, 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b25">Rahman and Ng, 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Hou et al., 2013a</ref>) handle bridging recognition as part of information status (IS) classification, while <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">(Poesio et al., 1997;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Poesio et al., 2004;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Lassalle and Denis, 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Hou et al., 2013b</ref>) concentrate on antecedent selection only, assuming that bridging recognition has already been performed. One exception is Vieira and Poe- sio <ref type="bibr">(2000)</ref>. They propose a rule-based system for processing definite NPs. However, they include different-head coreference into bridging. They re- port results for the whole anaphora resolution but do not report results for bridging resolution only. Another exception is <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">Rösiger and Teufel (2014)</ref>. They apply a coreference resolution system with several additional semantic features to find bridg- ing links in scientific text where bridging anaphors are limited to definite NPs. They report prelim- inary results using the CoNLL scorer. However, we think the coreference resolution system and the evaluation metric for coreference resolution are not suitable for bridging resolution since bridging is not a set problem.</p><p>Another vein of research for bridging resolu- tion focuses on formal semantics. <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Asher and Lascarides (1998)</ref> and <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Cimiano (2006)</ref> model bridg- ing by integrating discourse structure and seman- tics from a formal semantics viewpoint. However, the implementation of such a theoretical frame- work is beyond the current capabilities of NLP since it depends heavily on commonsense entail- ment.</p><p>In this paper, we propose a rule-based system for unrestricted bridging resolution. The system consists of eight rules which we carefully design based on linguistic intuitions, i.e., how the nature of bridging is reflected by various lexical, syntac- tic and semantic features. We evaluate our rule- based system on a corpus where bridging is reli- ably annotated. We find that our rule-based sys- tem significantly outperforms a reimplementation of a previous rule-based system <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">(Vieira and Poesio, 2000</ref>). We further notice that our rule-based system performs better than a learning-based ap- proach which has access to the same knowledge resources as the rule-based system. Surprisingly, incorporating the rules and more features into the learning-based approach only yields a minor im- provement over the rule-based system. We ob- serve that diverse bridging relations and relatively small-scale data for each type of relations make generalization difficult for the learning-based ap- proach. This work is -to the best of our knowledge -the first system recognizing bridging anaphora and finding links to antecedents for unre- stricted phenomenon where bridging anaphors are not limited to definite NPs and semantic relations between anaphors and their antecedents are not re- stricted to meronymic relations.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Data</head><p>All the data used throughout the paper come from the ISNotes corpus 2 released by <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Hou et al. (2013b)</ref>. This corpus contains around 11,000 NPs annotated for information status including 663 bridging NPs and their antecedents in 50 texts taken from the WSJ portion of the OntoNotes cor- pus <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">(Weischedel et al., 2011</ref>). ISNotes is reli- ably annotated for bridging: for bridging anaphor recognition, κ is over 60 for all three possible an-notator pairings (κ is over 70 for two expert anno- tators); for selecting bridging antecedents, agree- ment is around 80% for all annotator pairings.</p><p>It is notable that bridging anaphors in ISNotes are not limited to definite NPs as in previous work ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">Poesio et al., 1997;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Poesio et al., 2004;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Lassalle and Denis, 2011</ref> anaphora distribution with regard to determiners in ISNotes: only around 38% of bridging anaphors are definite NPs (NPs modified by the); 15.4% of bridging anaphors are modified by determiners such as a, an or one which normally indicate in- definite NPs. Most bridging anaphors (43%) are not modified by any determiners, such as touch- down in Example 1. A small fraction of bridging anaphors (1.2%) are modified by other determin- ers, such as demonstratives.</p><p>The semantic relations between anaphor and antecedent in the corpus are extremely diverse: only 14% of anaphors have a part-of/attribute- of relation with the antecedent (see Example 2) and only 7% of anaphors stand in a set relation- ship to the antecedent (see Example 3). 79% of anaphors have "other" relations with their an- tecedents (without further distinction), including encyclopedic relations such as The space shut- tle Atlantis-The five astronauts (see Example 1) as well as context-specific relations such as The space shuttle Atlantis-touchdown (Example 1).</p><p>(2) At age eight, Josephine Baker was sent by her mother to a white women's house to do chores in exchange for meals and a place to sleep -a place in the basement with coal.</p><p>(3) This creates several problems. One is that there are not enough police to satisfy small businesses.</p><p>In ISNotes, bridging anaphora with distant an- tecedents are common when the antecedent is the global focus of a document. 29% of the anaphors in the corpus have antecedents that are three or more sentences away.</p><p>Bridging resolution is an extremely challeng- ing task in ISNotes. In contrast with surface clues for coreference resolution, there are no clear sur- face clues for bridging resolution. In Example 4, the bridging anaphor low-interest disaster loans associates to the antecedent the Carolinas and Caribbean, whereas in Example 5 the NP loans is a generic use. In Example 6, the bridging anaphor The opening show associates to the antecedent Mancuso FBI, whereas the NP the show is coref- erent with its antecedent Mancuso FBI.</p><p>(4) The $2.85 billion measure comes on top of $1.1 billion appropriated after Hugo stuck the Carolinas and Caribbean last month, and these totals don't reflect the additional benefit of low-interest disaster loans.</p><p>(5) Many states already have Enterprise Zones and legislation that combines tax incentives, loans, and grants to encourage investment in depressed areas.</p><p>(6) Over the first few weeks, Mancuso FBI has sprung straight from the headlines. The opening show featured a secretary of defense designate accused of womanizing (a la John Tower).</p><p>. . . Most of all though, the show is redeemed by the character of Mancuso.</p><p>Our previous work on bridging resolution on this corpus only focuses on its subtasks. In <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Hou et al. (2013a)</ref> we model bridging anaphora recognition as a subtask of learning fine-grained information status. We report an F-measure of 0.42 for bridging anaphora recognition. In <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Hou et al. (2013b)</ref> we propose a joint inference framework for antecedent selection by exploring Markov logic networks. We report an accuracy of 0.41 for antecedent selection given gold bridg- ing anaphora. In this paper, we aim to solve these two substasks together, i.e., recognizing bridging anaphora and finding links to antecedents.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Method</head><p>In this section, we describe our rule-based system for unrestricted bridging resolution. We choose ten documents randomly from the corpus as the development set. Then we carefully design rules for finding "bridging links" among all NPs in a document based on the generalizations of bridg- ing in the linguistic literature as well as our in- spections of bridging annotations in the develop- ment set. The system consists of two components: bridging link prediction and post processing.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Bridging Link Prediction</head><p>The bridging link prediction component consists of eight rules. <ref type="bibr">Löbner (1985; 1998)</ref> interprets bridging anaphora as a particular kind of func- tional concept, which in a given situation assign a necessarily unique correlate to a (implicit) pos- sessor argument. He distinguishes between rela- tional nouns (e.g. parts terms, kinship terms, role terms) and sortal nouns and points out that rela- tional nouns are more frequently used as bridg- ing anaphora than sortal nouns. Rule1 to Rule4 in our system aim to resolve such relational nouns. We design Rule5 and Rule6 to capture set bridg- ing. Finally, Rule7 and Rule8 are motivated by previous work on implicit semantic role labeling <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Laparra and Rigau, 2013)</ref> which focuses on few predicates.</p><p>For all NPs in a document, each rule r is applied separately to predict a set of potential bridging links. Every rule has its own constraints on bridg- ing anaphora and antecedents respectively. Bridg- ing anaphors are diverse with regard to syntactic form and function: they can be modified by def- inite or indefinite determiners <ref type="table">(Table 1)</ref>, further- more they can take the subject (e.g. Example 3 and Example 6) or other positions (e.g. Example 2 and Example 4) in sentences. The only fre- quent syntactic property shared is that bridging anaphors most often have a simple internal struc- ture concerning modification. Therefore we first create an initial list of potential bridging anaphora A which excludes NPs which have a complex syn- tactic structure. An NP is added to A if it does not contain any other NPs and do not have modifi- cations strongly indicating comparative NPs (such as other symptoms) <ref type="bibr">3</ref> . Since head match is a strong indicator of coreference anaphora for definite NPs <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">(Vieira and Poesio, 2000;</ref><ref type="bibr">Soon et al., 2001</ref>), we further exclude definite NPs from A if they have the same head as a previous NP. Then a set of potential bridging anaphors A r is chosen from A based on r's constraints on bridging anaphora. Fi- nally, for each potential bridging anaphor ana ∈ A r , a single best antecedent ante from a list of candidate NPs (C ana ) is chosen if the rule's con- straint on antecedents is applied successfully.</p><p>Every rule has its own scope to form the antecedent candidate set C ana . Instead of using a static sentence window to construct the list of antecedent candidates like most previous work for resolving bridging anaphora ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">Poesio et al., 1997;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Poesio et al., 2004;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Lassalle and Denis, 2011</ref>), we use the development set to estimate the proper scope for each rule. The scope is influenced by the following factors: (1) the nature of the target bridging link (e.g., set bridging is a local coherence phenomenon where the antecedent often occurs in the same or up to two sentences prior to the anaphor); and (2) the strength of the rule's constraint to select the correct antecedent (e.g., in Rule8, the ability to select the correct antecedent decreases with increasing the scope to contain more antecedent candidates). In the following, we describe the mo- tivation for each rule and their constraints in detail.</p><p>Rule1: building part NPs. To capture typical part-of bridging (see Example 2), we extract a list of 45 nouns which specify building parts (e.g. room or roof ) from the General Inquirer lexicon ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">Stone et al., 1966)</ref>. A common noun phrase from A is added to A r1 if: (1) its head appears in the building part list; and (2) it does not contain any nominal pre-modifications. Then for each poten- tial bridging anaphor ana ∈ A r1 , the NP with the strongest semantic connectivity to the potential anaphor ana among all NPs preceding ana from the same sentence as well as from the previous two sentences is predicted to be the antecedent.</p><p>The semantic connectivity of an NP to a po- tential anaphor is measured via the hit counts of the preposition pattern query (anaphor preposi- tion NP) in big corpora <ref type="bibr">4</ref> . An initial effort to ex- tract partOf relations using WordNet yields low recall on the development set. Therefore we use semantic connectivity expressed by prepositional patterns (e.g. the basement of the house) to cap- ture underlying semantic relations. Such syntactic patterns are also explored in <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Poesio et al. (2004)</ref> to resolve meronymy bridging.</p><p>Rule2: relative person NPs. This rule is used to capture the bridging relation between a relative (e.g. The husband) and its antecedent (e.g. She). A list of 110 such relative nouns is extracted from WordNet. However, some relative nouns are fre- quently used generically instead of being bridging, such as children. To exclude such cases, we com- pute the argument taking ratio α for an NP using NomBank ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Meyers et al., 2004</ref>). For each NP, α is calculated via its head frequency in the NomBank annotation divided by the head's total frequency in the WSJ corpus in which the NomBank anno- tation is conducted. The value of α reflects how likely an NP is to take arguments. For instance, the value of α is 0.90 for husband but 0.31 for children. To predict bridging anaphora more ac- curately, a conservative constraint is used. An NP from A is added to A r2 if: (1) its head appears in the relative person list; (2) its argument taking ra- tio α is bigger than 0.5; and (3) it does not contain any nominal or adjective pre-modifications. Then for each potential bridging anaphor ana ∈ A r2 , the closest non-relative person NP among all NPs preceding ana from the same sentence as well as from the previous two sentences is chosen as its antecedent.</p><p>Rule3: GPE job title NPs. In news articles, it is common that a globally salient geo-political entity (hence GPE, e.g. Japan or U.S.) is introduced in the beginning, then later a related job title NP (e.g. officials or the prime minister) is used directly without referring to this GPE explicitly. To resolve such bridging cases accurately, we compile a list of twelve job titles which are related to GPEs (e.g. mayor or official). An NP from A is added to A r3 if its head appears in this list and does not have a country pre-modification (e.g. the Egyptian pres- ident). Then for each potential bridging anaphor ana ∈ A r3 , the most salient GPE NP among all NPs preceding ana is predicted as its antecedent. We use the NP's frequency in the whole document to measure its salience throughout the paper. In case of a tie, the closest one is chosen to be the predicted antecedent.</p><p>Rule4: role NPs. Compared to Rule3, Rule4 is designed to resolve more general role NPs to their implicit possessor arguments. We extract a list containing around 100 nouns which specify professional roles from WordNet (e.g. chairman, president or professor). An NP from A is added to A r4 if its head appears in this list. Then for each potential bridging anaphor ana ∈ A r4 , the most salient proper name NP which stands for an orga- nization among all NPs preceding ana from the same sentence as well as from the previous four sentences is chosen as its antecedent (if such an NP exists). Recency is again used to break ties.</p><p>Rule5: percentage NPs. In set bridging as shown in Example 7, the anaphor (Seventeen per- cent) is indicated by a percentage expression from A, which is often in the subject position. The an- tecedent (the firms) is predicted to be the closest NP which modifies another percentage NP via the preposition "of" among all NPs occurring in the same or up to two sentences prior to the potential anaphor.</p><p>(7) 22% of the firms said employees or owners had been robbed on their way to or from work. Seventeen percent reported their cus- tomers being robbed.</p><p>Rule6: other set member NPs. In set bridg- ing, apart from percentage expressions, numbers or indefinite pronouns are also good indicators for bridging anaphora. For such cases, the anaphor is predicted if it is: (1) a number expression (e.g. One in Example 3) or an indefinite pronoun(e.g. some, as shown in Example 8) from A; and (2) a subject NP. The antecedent is predicted to be the closest NP among all plural, subject NPs preced- ing the potential anaphor from the same sentence as well as from the previous two sentences (e.g. Reds and yellows in Example 8). If such an NP does not exist, the closest NP among all plural, ob- ject NPs preceding the potential anaphor from the same sentence as well as from the previous two sentences is chosen to be the predicted antecedent (e.g. several problems in Example 3).</p><p>(8) Reds and yellows went about their business with a kind of measured grimness. Some frantically dumped belongings into pillow- cases.</p><p>Rule7: argument-taking NPs I. Laparra and <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Rigau (2013)</ref> found that different instances of the same predicate in a document likely maintain the same argument fillers. Here we follow this as- sumption but apply it to nouns and their nomi- nal modifiers only: different instances of the same noun predicate likely maintain the same argument fillers indicated by nominal modifiers. First, a common noun phrase from A is added to A r7 if:</p><p>(1) its argument taking ratio α is bigger than 0.5; (2) it does not contain any nominal or adjective pre-modifications; and (3) it is not modified by in- definite determiners <ref type="bibr">5</ref> which usually introduce new discourse referents <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Hawkins, 1978)</ref>. Then for each potential bridging anaphor ana ∈ A r7 , we choose the antecedent by performing the follow- ing steps:</p><p>1. We take ana's head lemma form ana h and collect all its syntactic modifications in the document. We consider nominal pre- modification, possessive modification as well as prepositional post-modification. All real- izations of these modifications which precede ana form the antecedent candidates set C ana .</p><p>2. We choose the most recent NP from C ana as the predicted antecedent for the potential bridging anaphor ana.</p><p>In Example 9, we first predict the two occur- rences of residents as bridging anaphors. Since in the text, other occurrences of the lemma "res- ident" are modified by "Marina" (supported by Marina residents) and "buildings" (supported by some residents of badly damaged buildings), we collect all NPs whose syntactic head is "Ma- rina" or "buildings" in C ana (i.e. Marina, badly damaged buildings and buildings with substan- tial damage). Then among all NPs in C ana , the most recent NP is chosen to be the antecedent (i.e. buildings with substantial damage).</p><p>(9) She finds the response of Marina residents to the devastation of their homes "incredible". . . . Out on the streets, some residents of badly damaged buildings were allowed a 15 minute scavenger hunt through their possessions. . . . After being inspected, buildings with sub- stantial damage were color -coded. Green allowed residents to re-enter; red allowed residents one last entry to gather everything they could within 15 minutes.</p><p>Rule8: argument-taking NPs II. <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Prince (1992)</ref> found that discourse-old entities are more likely to be represented by NPs in subject position. Although she could not draw a similar conclu- sion when collapsing Inferrable (= bridging) with Discourse-old Nonpronominal, we find that in the development set, an argument-taking NP in the subject position is a good indicator for bridging anaphora (e.g. participants in Example 10). A common noun phrase from A is collected in A r8 if: (1) its argument taking ratio α is bigger than 0.5; (2) it does not contain any nominal or adjec- tive pre-modifications; and <ref type="formula">(3)</ref> it is in the subject position. Semantic connectivity again is used as the criteria to choose the antecedent: for each po- tential bridging anaphor ana ∈ A r8 , the NP with the strongest semantic connectivity to ana among all NPs preceding ana from the same sentence as well as from the previous two sentences is pre- dicted to be the antecedent.</p><p>(10) Initial steps were taken at Poland's first in- ternational environmental conference, which I attended last month. . . . While Polish data have been freely available since 1980, it was no accident that participants urged the free flow of information.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Post-processing</head><p>In the bridging link prediction component, each rule is applied separately. To resolve the conflicts between different rules (e.g., two rules predict dif- ferent antecedents for the same potential anaphor), a post processing step is applied. We first order the rules according to their precision for predicting bridging pairs (i.e., recognizing bridging anaphors and finding links to antecedents) in the develop- ment set. When a conflict happens, the rule with the highest order has the priority to decide the an- tecedent. <ref type="table">Table 2</ref> summarizes the rules described in Section 3.1, the numbers in square brackets in the first column indicate the order of the rules. <ref type="table">Ta- ble 3</ref> shows the precisions of bridging anaphora recognition and bridging pairs prediction for each rule in the development set. Firing rate is the proportion of bridging links predicted by rule r among all predicted links.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Experiments and Results</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">Experimental Setup</head><p>We conduct all experiments on the ISNotes cor- pus. We use the OntoNotes named entity and syn- tactic annotations to extract features. Ten doc- uments containing 113 bridging anaphors from the ISNotes corpus are set as the development set to estimate parameters for the rule-based system. The remaining 40 documents are used as the test set. In order to compare the results of different systems directly, we evaluate all systems on the test set.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">Evaluation Metric</head><p>In ISNotes, bridging is annotated mostly between an NP (anaphor) and an entity (antecedent) 6 , so that a bridging anaphor could have multiple links to different instantiations of the same entity (entity information is based on the Ontonotes coreference annotation). For bridging resolution, we use an evaluation metric based on bridging anaphors in- stead of all links between bridging anaphors and their antecedent instantiations. A link predicted by the system is counted as correct if it recognizes the bridging anaphor correctly and links the anaphor to any instantiation of the right antecedent entity preceding the anaphor.</p><p>In the evaluation metric, recall is calculated via the number of the correct links predicted by the system (one unique link per each predicted anaphor) divided by the total number of the gold bridging anaphors, precision is calculated via the number of the correct links predicted by the sys- tem divided by the total links predicted by the sys- tem.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3">A Learning-based Approach</head><p>To compare our rule-based system (hence ruleSys- tem, described in Section 3) with other ap- proaches, we implement a learning-based system for unrestricted bridging resolution. We adapt the pairwise model which is widely used in corefer- ence resolution ( <ref type="bibr">Soon et al., 2001</ref>). Similar to the rule-based system, we first create an initial list of possible bridging anaphora A ml with one more constraint. The purpose is to exclude as many ob- vious non-bridging anaphoric NPs from the list as possible. An NP is added to A ml if: (1) it does not contain any other NPs; (2) it is not mod- ified by pre-modifications which strongly indicate comparative NPs; and (3) it is not a pronoun or a proper name. Then for each NP a ∈ A ml , a list of antecedent candidates C a is created by includ- ing all NPs preceding a from the same sentence antecedent rule anaphor antecedent candidates scope rule1 <ref type="bibr">[2]</ref> building part NPs the NP with the strongest semantic connectivity to the two potential anaphor rule2 <ref type="bibr">[5]</ref> relative person NPs the closest person NP which is not a relative NP two rule3 <ref type="bibr">[6]</ref> GPE job title NPs the most salient GPE NP all rule4 <ref type="bibr">[7]</ref> role NPs the most salient organization NP four rule5 <ref type="bibr">[1]</ref> percentage NPs the closest NP which modifies another percentage NP two via the preposition "of" rule6 <ref type="bibr">[3]</ref> other set member NPs the closest subject, plural NP; two otherwise the closest object, plural NP rule7 <ref type="bibr">[4]</ref> argument-taking NPs I the closest NP whose head is an unfilled role of the potential all anaphor (such a role is predicted via syntactic modifications of NPs which have the same head as the potential anaphor) rule8 <ref type="bibr">[8]</ref> argument-taking NPs II the NP with the strongest semantic connectivity to the two potential anaphor <ref type="table">Table 2</ref>: Rules for unrestricted bridging resolution. Antecedent candidates scope are verified in the development set: "all" represents all NPs preceding the potential anaphor from the whole document, "four" NPs occurring in the same or up to four sentences prior to the potential anaphor, "two" NPs occurring in the same or up to two sentences prior to the potential anaphor.  <ref type="table">Table 3</ref>: Precision of bridging anaphora recognition and bridging pairs prediction for each rule in the development set. The numbers in square brackets in the first column indicate the order of the rules.</p><p>as well as from the previous two sentences <ref type="bibr">7</ref> . We create a pairwise instance (a, c) for every c ∈ C a . We also add extra pairwise instances from the pre- diction of ruleSystem to the learning-based sys- tem. In the decoding stage, the best first strat- egy ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">Ng and Cardie, 2002</ref>) is used to predict the bridging links. Specifically, for each a ∈ A ml , we predict the bridging link to be the most confident pair (a, c ante ) among all instances with the posi- tive prediction. We use SVM light to conduct the experiments <ref type="bibr">8</ref> . All experiments are conducted via 10-fold cross-validation on the whole corpus 9 .</p><p>7 In ISNotes, 71% of NP antecedents occur in the same or up to two sentences prior to the anaphor. Initial experi- ments show that increasing the window size more than two sentences decreases the performance.</p><p>8 To deal with data imbalance, the SVM light parameter is set according to the ratio between positive and negative instances in the training set. <ref type="bibr">9</ref> To compare the learning-based approach to the rule- based system described in Section 3 directly, we report the mlSystem ruleFeats We provide mlSys- tem ruleFeats with the same knowledge resources as the rule-based system. All rules from the rule-based system are incorporated into mlSys- tem ruleFeats as the features. mlSystem ruleFeats + atomFeats We augment mlSystem ruleFeats with more features from our previous work <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">(Markert et al., 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Hou et al., 2013a;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Hou et al., 2013b</ref>) on bridging anaphora recognition and antecedent selection. Some of these features overlap with the atomic features used in the rule-based system. <ref type="table">Table 4</ref> shows all the features we use for rec- ognizing bridging anaphora. " * " indicates the re- sources are used in the rule-based system. We ap- ply them to the first element a of a pairwise in- stance (a, c). <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Markert et al. (2012)</ref> and Hou et Feature Value for anaphor candidate a f 1 preModByNominal whether a contains any nominal pre-modifications f 2 preModByAdj whether a contains any adjective modifications f 3 isGPEJobTitle whether a is a job title about GPE (e.g. mayor or official) f 4 isArgumentTakingNP whether the argument taking ratio of a is bigger than 0.5 for antecedent candidate c f 5 fullMentionTime the normalized value of the frequency of c in the whole document for pairwise instance (a, c) f 6 word distance the token distance between a and c <ref type="table">Table 6</ref>: Additional atomic features from the rule-based system.</p><p>f 14 and f 16). <ref type="table">Table 5</ref> shows all features we use for selecting antecedents for bridging anaphora. " * " indicates the resources that are used in the rule-based sys- tem. These features are from <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Hou et al. (2013b)</ref>'s local pairwise model. They try to model: (1) the semantic relations between bridging anaphors and their antecedents (f 1 to f 4); (2) the salience of an antecedent from different perspectives (f 5 to f 8); and (3) the syntactic and lexical constraints between anaphor and antecedent (f 9 to f 12).</p><p>Apart from the features shown in <ref type="table">Table  4</ref> and <ref type="table">Table 5</ref>, we further enrich mlSys- tem ruleFeats+atomFeats with additional atomic features used in the rule-based system <ref type="table">(Table 6</ref>).</p><p>mlSystem atomFeats Based on mlSys- tem ruleFeats+atomFeats, the rule features from the rule-based system are removed.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.4">Baseline</head><p>We also reimplement the rule-based system from Vieira and Poesio (2000) as a baseline. The origi- nal algorithm focuses on processing definite NPs. It classifies four categories for the definite NPs: discourse new, direct anaphora (same-head coref- erent anaphora), lenient bridging and Unknown. This algorithm also finds antecedents for NPs which belong to direct anaphora or lenient bridg- ing.</p><p>Since Vieira and Poesio (2000) include different-head coreference into their lenient bridging category, we further divide their le- nient bridging category into two subcategories: different-head coreference and bridging. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure  1</ref> shows the details of the division after failing to classify an NP as discourse new or direct anaphora. For more details about the whole system, see <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">Vieira and Poesio (2000)</ref>. We then apply this slightly revised algorithm to process all NPs in the initial list of potential bridging anaphora A from ruleSystem (described in Section 3.1). <ref type="table">Table 7</ref> shows the results on the same test set of different approaches for unrestricted bridging res- olution. The results reveal the difficulty of the task, when evaluating on a realistic scenario with- out constraints on types of bridging anaphora and bridging relations.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.5">Results and Discussion</head><p>Both our rule-based system and all learning- based approaches significantly outperform the baseline at p &lt; 0.01 (randomization test). The low recall in baseline is predictable, since it only considers meronymy bridging and compound noun anaphors whose head is prenominally mod- ified by the antecedent head. (e.g. the state- state gasoline taxes). Under the same features, the learning-based approach (mlSystem ruleFeats) performs slightly worse than the rule-based sys- tem (ruleSystem) with regard to the F-score. R P F baseline 2.9 13.3 4.8 ruleSystem 11.9 42.9 18.6 mlSystem ruleFeats 12.1 35.0 18.0 mlSystem ruleFeats+atomFeats 16.7 21.2 18.7 mlSystem atomFeats 20.5 10.1 13.5 <ref type="table">Table 7</ref>: Experimental results for the baseline, the rule-based system and the learning-based systems.</p><p>Surprisingly, incorporating rich features into the learning-based approach (mlSys- tem ruleFeats+atomFeats) does not yield much improvement over the rule-based system (with an F-score of 18.7 in mlSystem ruleFeats+atomFeats compared to 18.6 in ruleSystem). We suppose that the learning-based system generalizes poorly with only atomic features in <ref type="table">Table 4</ref>, <ref type="table">Table 5 and Table  6</ref>. Results on mlSystem atomFeats support our assumption: the F-score drops considerably after removing the rule features. Although ISNotes is a reasonably sized corpus for bridging compared to previous work, diverse bridging relations, especially lots of context specific relations such as pachinko-devotees or palms-the thieves, lead to relatively small-scale training data for each type of relation. Therefore it is difficult for the learning-based approach to learn effective rules to predict bridging links.</p><p>However, all learning-based systems tend to have higher recall but lower precision compared to the rule-based system. This suggests that the learning-based systems are "greedy" to predict bridging links. A close look at these links in mlSystem atomFeats indicates that the learning- based system predicts more correct bridging anaphors but fails to find the correct antecedents. In fact, lots of those "half" correct links sound reasonable without the specific context, such as the story-readers (gold bridging link: this novel- readers) or the executive director's office-the desks (gold bridging link: the fund's building-the desks).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Conclusions</head><p>We proposed a rule-based approach for un- restricted bridging resolution where bridging anaphora are not limited to definite NPs and the relations between anaphor and antecedent are not restricted to meronymic relations. We designed eight rules to resolve bridging based on linguis- tic intuition. Our rule-based system performs bet- ter than a learning-based approach which has ac- cess to the same knowledge resources as the rule- based system. Particularly, the learning-based sys- tem enriched with more features does not yield much improvement over the rule-based system. We speculate that the learning-based system could benefit from more training data. Furthermore, bet- ter methods to model the semantics of the specific context need to be explored in the future.</p><p>This work is -to our knowledge -the first bridging resolution system that handles the unre- stricted phenomenon in a realistic setting.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: Vieria &amp; Poesio's (2000) original algorithm for processing definite NPs. We further divide their lenient bridging category into two subcategories: 2.1 Different-head coreference and 2.2 Bridging.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" validated="false"><head>) . Table 1 shows the bridging</head><label>.1</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Bridging Anaphors 663 
Non-determiner 
44.9% 
Definite 
38.5% 
Indefinite 
15.4% 
Other-determiner 
1.2% 

Table 1: Bridging anaphora distribution w.r.t. de-
terminers in ISNotes. 

</table></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> Examples are from OntoNotes (Weischedel et al., 2011). Bridging anaphora are typed in boldface; antecedents in italics.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="2"> http://www.h-its.org/english/research/nlp/download/ isnotes.php</note>

			<note place="foot" n="3"> A small list of 10 markers such as such, another. .. and the presence of adjectives or adverbs in the comparative form are used to predict comparative NPs.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="4"> We use Gigaword (Parker et al., 2011) with automatic POS tag and NP chunk information.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="5"> We compile a list of 17 such determiners, such as a, an or one.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="6"> There are a few cases where bridging is annotated between an NP and a non-NP antecedent (e.g. verbs or clauses).</note>

			<note place="foot">results of learning-based approaches on the same test set as the rule-based system.</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgements</head><p>We thank Renata Vieira for excavating part of her source code for us. We also thank the reviewers for their helpful comments. Yufang Hou is funded by a PhD scholarship from the Research Training Group Coherence in Language Processing at Hei-delberg University. This work has been partially funded by the Klaus Tschira Foundation.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Markert et al. local feature set f 1 FullPrevMention (b) * f 2 FullPreMentionTime (n) f 3 PartialPreMention (b) f 4 ContentWordPreMention (b)</head><p>f 5 Determiner (n) * f 6 NPtype (n) * f 7 NPlength (int) f 8 GrammaticalRole (n) * f 9 NPNumber (n) * f 10 PreModByCompMarker (b) * Hou et al. local feature set features to identify bridging anaphora</p><p>f 18 HasChildNP (b) * features to identify function and worldKnowledge NPs f 20 DependOnChangeVerb (b) f 21 IsFrequentProperName (b) "b" indicates binary, "n" nominal, "l" lexical features, " * " resources used in the rule-based system.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Group</head><p>Feature Value semantic f 1 preposition pattern * the normalized hit counts of the preposition pattern query a prep. c (e.g. participants of the conference) in big corpora f 2 verb pattern the normalized hit counts of the verb pattern query c verb a or verb a c in big corpora (for set bridging in Example 7, the pattern query is the firms reported) f 3 WordNet partOf whether a partOf relation holds between a and c in WordNet f 4 semantic class * 16 classes, e.g. location, organization, GPE, rolePerson, relativePerson, product, date, money, percent salience f 5 document span the normalized value of the span of text in which c is mentioned f 6 utterance distance the sentence distance between a and c f 7 local first mention whether c is the first mention within the previous five sentences f 8 global first mention whether c is the first mention in the whole document syntactic f 9 isSameHead whether a and c share the same head &amp; (exclude coreferent antecedent candidates) lexical f 10 isWordOverlap whether a is prenominally modified by the head of c (for bridging where the anaphor is a compound noun, such as the mine-mine security) f 11 isCoArgument whether subject c and object a are dependent on the same verb (the subject can not be the bridging antecedent of the object in the same clause) f 12 WordNet distance the inverse value of the shortest path length between a and c in WordNet identify old, new and several mediated categories but fail to recognize most bridging anaphora. <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Hou et al. (2013a)</ref> remedy this by adding discourse structure features (f 1-f 3), semantic features (f 4- f 10) and features to detect generic nouns (f 11-</p></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nicholas</forename><surname>Asher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alex</forename><surname>Lascarides</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Bridging. Journal of Semantics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="83" to="113" />
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Associative anaphora resolution: A Web-based approach</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Razvan</forename><surname>Bunescu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the EACL 2003 Workshop on The Computational Treatment of Anaphora</title>
		<meeting>the EACL 2003 Workshop on The Computational Treatment of Anaphora<address><addrLine>Budapest, Hungary</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003-04-14" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="47" to="52" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Automatically acquiring fine-grained information status distinctions in German</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Aoife</forename><surname>Cahill</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Arndt</forename><surname>Riester</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the SIGdial 2012 Conference: The 13th Annual Meeting of the Special Interest Group on Discourse and Dialogue</title>
		<meeting>the SIGdial 2012 Conference: The 13th Annual Meeting of the Special Interest Group on Discourse and Dialogue<address><addrLine>Seoul, Korea</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012-07" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="232" to="236" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Ingredients of a first-order account of bridging</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Philipp</forename><surname>Cimiano</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 5th International Workshop on Inference in Computational Semantics</title>
		<meeting>the 5th International Workshop on Inference in Computational Semantics<address><addrLine>Buxton, U.K.</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006-04" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="139" to="144" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Bridging</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Herbert</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Clark</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Conference on Theoretical Issues in Natural Language Processing</title>
		<meeting>the Conference on Theoretical Issues in Natural Language Processing<address><addrLine>Cambridge, Mass</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1975-06" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="169" to="174" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Cognitive status and the form of referring expressions in discourse</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jeanette</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Gundel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nancy</forename><surname>Hedberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ron</forename><surname>Zacharski</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Language</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">69</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="274" to="307" />
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Definiteness and indefiniteness: A study in reference and grammaticality prediction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">John</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Hawkins</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1978" />
			<publisher>Humanities Press</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Atlantic Highlands, N.J.</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Cascading collective classification for bridging anaphora recognition using a rich linguistic feature set</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yufang</forename><surname>Hou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Katja</forename><surname>Markert</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Strube</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2013 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</title>
		<meeting>the 2013 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing<address><addrLine>Seattle, Wash.</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013-10" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="814" to="820" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Global inference for bridging anaphora resolution</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yufang</forename><surname>Hou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Katja</forename><surname>Markert</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Strube</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2013 Conference of the North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics: Human Language Technologies</title>
		<meeting>the 2013 Conference of the North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics: Human Language Technologies<address><addrLine>Atlanta, Georgia</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013-06" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="907" to="917" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">ImpAr: A deterministic algorithm for implicit semantic role labelling</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Egoitz</forename><surname>Laparra</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">German</forename><surname>Rigau</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 51st Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the 51st Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics<address><addrLine>Sofia, Bulgaria</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013-08" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1180" to="1189" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Leveraging different meronym discovery methods for bridging resolution in French</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Emmanuel</forename><surname>Lassalle</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Pascal</forename><surname>Denis</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 8th</title>
		<meeting>the 8th</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Discourse Anaphora and Anaphor Resolution Colloquium</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011-10-67" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="35" to="46" />
			<pubPlace>Faro, Algarve, Portugal</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sebastian</forename><surname>Löbner</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Definites. Journal of Semantics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="279" to="326" />
			<date type="published" when="1985" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Definite associative anaphora. Unpublished Manuscript</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sebastian</forename><surname>Löbner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>HeinrichHeine-Universität Düsseldorf</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Using the web for nominal anaphora resolution</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Katja</forename><surname>Markert</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Malvina</forename><surname>Nissim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Natalia</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the EACL Workshop on the Computational Treatment of Anaphora</title>
		<meeting>the EACL Workshop on the Computational Treatment of Anaphora<address><addrLine>Hungary</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003-04-14" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="39" to="46" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
<note type="report_type">Budapest</note>
	<note>Modjeska</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Collective classification for fine-grained information status</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Katja</forename><surname>Markert</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yufang</forename><surname>Hou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Strube</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 50th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the 50th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics<address><addrLine>Jeju Island, Korea</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012-07" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="795" to="804" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Annotating noun argument structure for NomBank</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Adam</forename><surname>Meyers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ruth</forename><surname>Reeves</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Catherine</forename><surname>Macleod</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rachel</forename><surname>Szekely</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Veronika</forename><surname>Zielinska</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Brian</forename><surname>Young</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ralph</forename><surname>Grishaman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 4th International Conference on Language Resources and Evaluation</title>
		<meeting>the 4th International Conference on Language Resources and Evaluation<address><addrLine>Lisbon, Portugal</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004-05" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="803" to="806" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Using the web in machine learning for other-anaphora resolution</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Natalia</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Modjeska</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Katja</forename><surname>Markert</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Malvina</forename><surname>Nissim</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2003 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</title>
		<meeting>the 2003 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing<address><addrLine>Sapporo, Japan</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003-07" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="176" to="183" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Improving machine learning approaches to coreference resolution</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Vincent</forename><surname>Ng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Claire</forename><surname>Cardie</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 40th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics, Philadelphia</title>
		<meeting>the 40th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics, Philadelphia<address><addrLine>Penn</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2002-07" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="104" to="111" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">English Gigaword Fifth Edition</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Robert</forename><surname>Parker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Graff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Junbo</forename><surname>Kong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ke</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kazuaki</forename><surname>Maeda</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A corpusbased investigation of definite description use</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Massimo</forename><surname>Poesio</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Renata</forename><surname>Vieira</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Computational Linguistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="183" to="216" />
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Resolving bridging references in unrestricted text</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Massimo</forename><surname>Poesio</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Renata</forename><surname>Vieira</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Simone</forename><surname>Teufel</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the ACL Workshop on Operational Factors in Practical, Robust Anaphora Resolution for Unrestricted Text</title>
		<meeting>the ACL Workshop on Operational Factors in Practical, Robust Anaphora Resolution for Unrestricted Text<address><addrLine>Madrid, Spain</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1997-07" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="6" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Learning to resolve bridging references</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Massimo</forename><surname>Poesio</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rahul</forename><surname>Mehta</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Axel</forename><surname>Maroudas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Janet</forename><surname>Hitzeman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 42nd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the 42nd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics<address><addrLine>Barcelona, Spain</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004-07" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="143" to="150" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Towards a taxonomy of givennew information</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Ellen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Prince</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Radical Pragmatics</title>
		<editor>P. Cole</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>New York, N.Y.</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Academic Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1981" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="223" to="255" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The ZPG letter: Subjects, definiteness, and information-status</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Ellen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Prince</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Discourse Description. Diverse Linguistic Analyses of a Fund-Raising Text</title>
		<editor>W.C. Mann and S.A. Thompson</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Amsterdam</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>John Benjamins</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1992" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="295" to="325" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Learning the fine-grained information status of discourse entities</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Altaf</forename><surname>Rahman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Vincent</forename><surname>Ng</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 13th Conference of the European Chapter</title>
		<meeting>the 13th Conference of the European Chapter<address><addrLine>Avignon, France</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2012-04" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="798" to="807" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Resolving coreference and associative noun phrases in scientific text</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ina</forename><surname>Rösiger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Simone</forename><surname>Teufel</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Student Research Workshop at the 14th Conference of the European Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the Student Research Workshop at the 14th Conference of the European Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics<address><addrLine>Gothenburg, Sweden</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014-04-30" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="44" to="55" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A machine learning approach to coreference resolution of noun phrases</title>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Computational Linguistics</title>
		<editor>Wee Meng Soon, Hwee Tou Ng, and Daniel Chung Yong Lim</editor>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">27</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="521" to="544" />
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">General Inquirer: A Computer Approach to Content Analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Philip</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Stone</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dexter</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Dunphy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marshall</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Smith</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Daniel</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Ogilvie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Cambridge Computer</forename><surname>Associates</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1966" />
			<publisher>MIT Press</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Cambridge, Mass</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">An empirically-based system for processing definite descriptions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Renata</forename><surname>Vieira</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Massimo</forename><surname>Poesio</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Computational Linguistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="539" to="593" />
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ralph</forename><surname>Weischedel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Martha</forename><surname>Palmer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mitchell</forename><surname>Marcus</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Eduard</forename><surname>Hovy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sameer</forename><surname>Pradhan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lance</forename><surname>Ramshaw</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nianwen</forename><surname>Xue</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ann</forename><surname>Taylor</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jeff</forename><surname>Kaufman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<editor>Michelle Franchini, Mohammed El-Bachouti, Robert Belvin, and Ann Houston</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<publisher>Linguistic Data Consortium</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Philadelphia, Penn</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>OntoNotes release 4.0. LDC2011T03</note>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
