<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T12:11+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Combining Punctuation and Disfluency Prediction: An Empirical Study</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date>October 25-29, 2014</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xuancong</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
							<email>xuancong84@gmail.com, {simkc, nght}@comp.nus.edu.sg</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">NUS Graduate School for Integrative Sciences and Engineering</orgName>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">National University of Singapore</orgName>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Human Language Technology</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Institute for Infocomm Research</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="SG">Singapore</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Khe</forename><surname>Chai</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">National University of Singapore</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sim</forename></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hwee</forename><forename type="middle">Tou</forename><surname>Ng</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">NUS Graduate School for Integrative Sciences and Engineering</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Combining Punctuation and Disfluency Prediction: An Empirical Study</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2014 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP)</title>
						<meeting>the 2014 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP) <address><addrLine>Doha, Qatar. c</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="121" to="130"/>
							<date type="published">October 25-29, 2014</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Punctuation prediction and disfluency prediction can improve downstream natural language processing tasks such as machine translation and information extraction. Combining the two tasks can potentially improve the efficiency of the overall pipeline system and reduce error propagation. In this work 1 , we compare various methods for combining punctuation prediction (PU) and disfluency prediction (DF) on the Switchboard corpus. We compare an isolated prediction approach with a cascade approach, a rescoring approach, and three joint model approaches. For the cascade approach, we show that the soft cascade method is better than the hard cascade method. We also use the cascade models to generate an n-best list, use the bi-directional cascade models to perform rescoring, and compare that with the results of the cascade models. For the joint model approach, we compare mixed-label Linear-chain Conditional Random Field (LCRF), cross-product LCRF and 2-layer Factorial Conditional Random Field (FCRF) with soft-cascade LCRF. Our results show that the various methods linking the two tasks are not significantly different from one another, although they perform better than the isolated prediction method by 0.5-1.5% in the F1 score. Moreover, the clique order of features also shows a marked difference.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>The raw output from automatic speech recogni- tion (ASR) systems does not have sentence bound-aries or punctuation symbols. Spontaneous speech also contains a significant proportion of disflu- ency. Researchers have shown that splitting input sequences into sentences and adding in punctua- tion symbols improve machine translation <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Favre et al., 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Lu and Ng, 2010)</ref>. Moreover, dis- fluencies in speech also introduce noise in down- stream tasks like machine translation and informa- tion extraction ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Wang et al., 2010</ref>). Thus, punc- tuation prediction (PU) and disfluency prediction (DF) are two important post-processing tasks for automatic speech recognition because they im- prove not only the readability of ASR output, but also the performance of downstream Natural Lan- guage Processing (NLP) tasks.</p><p>The task of punctuation prediction is to insert punctuation symbols into conversational speech texts. Punctuation prediction on long, unseg- mented texts also achieves the purpose of sentence boundary prediction, because sentence boundaries are identified by sentence-end punctuation sym- bols: periods, question marks, and exclamation marks. Consider the following example, How do you feel about the Viet Nam War ? Yeah , I saw that as well .</p><p>The question mark splits the sequence into two sentences. This paper deals with this task which is more challenging than that on text that has already been split into sentences.</p><p>The task of disfluency prediction is to identify word tokens that are spoken incorrectly due to speech disfluency. There are two main types of disfluencies: filler words and edit words. Filler words mainly include filled pauses (e.g., 'uh', 'um') and discourse markers (e.g., "I mean", "you know"). As they are insertions in spontaneous speech to indicate pauses or mark boundaries in discourse, they do not convey useful content in- formation. Edit words are words that are spoken wrongly and then corrected by the speaker. For example, consider the following utterance:</p><p>I want a flight <ref type="bibr">Edit</ref> </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>to Boston</head><p>Filler uh I mean <ref type="bibr">Repair</ref> </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>to Denver</head><p>The phrase "to Boston" forms the edit region to be replaced by "to Denver". The words "uh I mean" are filler words that serve to cue the listener about the error and subsequent corrections.</p><p>The motivation of combining the two tasks can be illustrated by the following two utterances:</p><p>I am uh I am not going with you . I am sorry . I am not going with you .</p><p>Notice that the bi-gram "I am" is repeated in both sentences. For the first utterance, if punctu- ation prediction is performed first, it might break the utterance both before and after "uh" so that the second-stage disfluency prediction will treat the whole utterance as three sentences, and thus may not be able to detect any disfluency because each one of the three sentences is legitimate on its own. On the other hand, for the second utterance, if dis- fluency prediction is performed first, it might mark "I am sorry" as disfluent in the first place and re- move it before passing into the second-stage punc- tuation prediction. Therefore, no matter which task is performed first, certain utterances can al- ways cause confusion.</p><p>There are many ways to combine the two tasks. For example, we can perform one task first fol- lowed by another, which is called the cascade ap- proach. We can also mix the labels, or take the cross-product of the labels, or use joint prediction models. In this paper, we study the mutual influ- ence between the two tasks and compare a variety of common state-of-the-art joint prediction tech- niques on this joint task.</p><p>In Section 2, we briefly introduce previous work on the two tasks. In Section 3, we describe our baseline system which performs punctuation and disfluency prediction separately (i.e., in isolation). In Section 4, we compare the soft cascade ap- proach with the hard cascade approach. We also examine the effect of task order, i.e., performing which task first benefits more. In Section 5, we compare the cascade approach with bi-directional n-best rescoring. In Section 6, we compare the 2- layer Factorial CRF ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Sutton et al., 2007</ref>) with the cross-product LCRF ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Ng and Low, 2004</ref>), mixed- label LCRF ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">Stolcke et al., 1998</ref>), the cascade ap- proach, and the baseline isolated prediction. Sec- tion 7 gives a summary of our overall findings. Section 8 gives the conclusion.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Previous Work</head><p>There were many works on punctuation prediction or disfluency prediction as an isolated task. For punctuation prediction, <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Huang and Zweig (2002)</ref> used maximum entropy model; <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Christensen et al. (2001)</ref> used finite state and multi-layer perceptron method; <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Liu et al. (2005)</ref> used conditional ran- dom fields; <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Lu and Ng (2010)</ref> proposed using dy- namic conditional random fields for joint sentence boundary type and punctuation prediction; <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">Wang et al. (2012)</ref> has added prosodic features for the dynamic conditional random field approach and <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">Zhang et al. (2013)</ref> used transition-based parsing.</p><p>For disfluency prediction, <ref type="bibr">Shriberg et al. (1997)</ref> uses purely prosodic features to perform the task. <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Johnson and Charniak (2004)</ref> proposed a TAG- based (Tree-Adjoining Grammar) noisy channel model. <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Maskey et al. (2006)</ref> proposed a phrase- level machine translation approach for this task. <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Georgila (2009)</ref> used integer linear programming (ILP) which can incorporate local and global con- straints. <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">Zwarts and Johnson (2011)</ref> has inves- tigated the effect of using extra language mod- els as features in the reranking stage. <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Qian and Liu (2013)</ref> proposed using weighted Max-margin Markov Networks (M3N) to balance precision and recall to further improve the F1-score. <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Wang et al. (2014)</ref> proposed a beam-search decoder which in- tegrates M3N and achieved further improvements.</p><p>There were also some works that addressed both tasks. <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Liu et al. (2006)</ref> and <ref type="bibr">Baron et al. (1998)</ref> carried out sentence unit (SU) and disfluency pre- diction as separate tasks. The difference between SU prediction and punctuation prediction is only in the non-sentence-end punctuation symbols such as commas. <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">Stolcke et al. (1998)</ref> mixed sen- tence boundary labels with disfluency labels so that they do not predict punctuation on disfluent tokens. <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Kim (2004)</ref> performed joint SU and In- terruption Point (IP) prediction, deriving edit and filler word regions from predicted IPs using a rule- based system as a separate step.</p><p>In this paper, we treat punctuation prediction and disfluency prediction as a joint prediction task, and compare various state-of-the-art joint predic- tion methods on this task.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">The Baseline System</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Experimental Setup</head><p>We use the Switchboard corpus (LDC99T42) in our experiment with the same train/develop/test split as <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(Qian and Liu, 2013)</ref> and <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Johnson and Charniak, 2004</ref>). The corpus statistics are shown in <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>. Since the proportion of exclamation marks and incomplete SU boundaries is too small, we convert all exclamation marks to periods and remove all incomplete SU boundaries (treat as no punctuation). In the Switchboard corpus, the ut- terances of each speaker have already been seg- mented into short sentences when used in (Qian and <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Liu, 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Johnson and Charniak, 2004</ref>). In our work, we concatenate the utterances of each speaker to form one long sequence of words for use as the input to punctuation prediction and dis- fluency prediction. This form of input where, utterances are not pre-segmented into short sen- tences, better reflects the real-world scenarios and provides a more realistic test setting for punctu- ation and disfluency prediction. Punctuation pre- diction also gives rise to sentence segmentation in this setting. *: each conversation produces two long/sentence- joined sequences, one from each speaker.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Data</head><p>Our baseline system uses M3N ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">Taskar et al., 2004</ref>), one M3N for punctuation prediction and the other for disfluency prediction. We use the same set of punctuation and disfluency labels (as shown in <ref type="table">Table 2</ref>) throughout this paper. To com- pare the various isolated, cascade, and joint pre- diction models, we use the same feature templates for both tasks as listed in <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">Table 3</ref>. Since some of the feature templates require predicted filler labels and part-of-speech (POS) tags, we have trained a POS tagger and a filler predictor both using CRF (i.e., using the same approach as that in Qian and Liu <ref type="bibr">(2013)</ref>). The same predicted POS tags and fillers are used for feature extraction in all the experiments in this paper for a fair comparison. The degradation on disfluency prediction due to the concatenation of utterances of each speaker is shown in <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">Table 4</ref>. The pause duration fea- tures are extracted by running forced alignment on the corresponding Switchboard speech corpus (LDC97S62).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Task Label Meaning</head><p>Disfluency prediction <ref type="table">Table 2</ref>: Labels for punctuation prediction and dis- fluency prediction.</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">E edit word F filler word O otherwise / fluent Punctuation prediction Comma comma Period full-stop QMark question mark None no punctuation</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Features</head><p>We use the standard NLP features such as F (w −1 w 0 ='so that'), i.e., the word tokens at the previous and current node position are 'so' and 'that' respectively. Each feature is associated with a clique order. For example, since the clique order of this feature template is 2 (see <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">Table 3</ref>), its feature functions can be</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">f (w −1 w 0 ='so that', y 0 ='F', y −1 ='O', t).</formula><p>The example has a value of 1 only when the words at node t − 1 and t are 'so that', and the labels at node t and t − 1 are 'F' and 'O' respectively. The maximum length of the y history is called the clique order of the feature (in this feature func- tion, it is 2 since only y 0 and y −1 are covered). The feature templates are listed in <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">Table 3</ref>. w i refers to the word at the i th position relative to the current node; window size is the maximum span of words centered at the current word that the template covers, e.g., w −1 w 0 with a window size of 9 means w −4 w −3 , w −3 w −2 , ..., w 3 w 4 ; p i refers to the POS tag at the i th position relative to the current node; w i∼j refers to any word from the i th position to the j th position relative to the current node, this template can capture word pairs which can potentially indicate a repair, e.g., "was ... is ...", the speaker may have spoken any word(s) in between and it is very difficult for the standard n-gram features to capture all possible variations; w i, =F refers to the i th non-filler word with respect to the current position, this template can extract n-gram features skipping filler words; the multi-pair comparison function I(a, b, c, ...) indicates whether each pair (a and b, b and c, and so on) is identical, for example, if a = b = c = d, it will output "101" ('1' for being equal, '0' for being unequal), this feature template can capture consecutive word/POS repetitions which can further improve upon the standard repetition features; and ngram-score features are the nat- ural logarithm of the following 8 probabilities:</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">P (w −3 , w −2 , w −1 , w 0 ), P (w 0 |w −3 , w −2 , w −1 ), P (w −3 , w −2 , w −1 ), P (/s|w −3 , w −2 , w −1 ), P (w −3 ), P (w −2 )</formula><p>, P (w −1 ) and P (w 0 ) (where "/s" denotes sentence-end).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Feature Template Window</head><p>Size Clique Order w 0  The performance of the system can be fur- ther improved by adding additional prosodic fea- tures ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Savova and Bachenko, 2003;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b18">Shriberg et al., 1998;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Christensen et al., 2001</ref>) apart from pause durations. However, since in this work we focus on model-level comparison, we do not use other prosodic features for simplicity.  We use the standard F1 score as our evaluation metric and this is similar to that in Qian and Liu <ref type="bibr">(2013)</ref>. For training, we set the frequency prun- ing threshold to 5 to control the number of pa- rameters. The regularization parameter is tuned on the development set. Since the toolkits used to run different experiments have slightly differ- ent limitations, in order to make fair comparisons across different toolkits, we do not use weighting to balance precision and recall when training M3N and we have reduced the clique order of transi- tion features to two and all the other features to one in some of our experiments. Since the per- formance of filler word prediction on this dataset is already very high, (&gt;97%), we only focus on the F1 score of edit word prediction in this pa- per when reporting the performance of disfluency prediction. <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">Table 4</ref> shows our baseline results. Our preliminary study shows the following gen-eral trends: (i) for disfluency prediction: joining utterances into long sentences will cause a 5-6% drop in F1 score; removing precision/recall bal- ance in M3N will cause about 1% drop in F1 score; and reducing the clique order in <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">Table 3</ref> will cause about 1-2% drop in F1 score; and (ii) for punctua- tion prediction: removing precision/recall balance in M3N will cause negligible drop in F1 score; and reducing clique order will cause about 2-3% drop in F1 score. Conventionally, the degradation from reducing the clique orders can be mostly compen- sated by using the BIES (Begin, Inside, End, and Single) labeling scheme. In this work, for con- sistency and comparability across various experi- ments, we will stick to the same set of labels in <ref type="table">Table 2</ref>.</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">9 1 w −1 w 0 9 2 w −2 w −1 w 0 9 2 p 0 9 1 p −1 p 0 9 2 p −2 p −1 p 0 9 2 w 0 w −6∼−1 , w 0 w 1∼6 1 1 I(w i , w j ) 21 2 I(w i , w j , w i+1 , w j+1 ) 21 2 I(w i , w j )(w i if w i =w j ) 21 2 I(p i , p j ) 21 3 I(p i , p j , p i+1 , p j+1 ) 21 3 I(p i , p j )(p i if p i =p j ) 21 3 p −1 w 0 5 2 w −1 p 0 5 2 w −2, =F w −1, =F 1 2 w −3, =F w −2, =F w −1, =F 1 2 p −2, =F p −1, =F 1 2 p −3, =F p −2, =F p −1, =F 1 2 ngram-score</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3">Evaluation and Results</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Experiment</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">The Cascade Approach</head><p>Instead of decomposing the joint prediction of punctuation and disfluency into two independent tasks, the cascade approach considers one task to be conditionally dependent on the other task such that the predictions are performed in sequence, where the results from the first step is used in the second step. In this paper, we compare two types of cascade: hard cascade versus soft cascade.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">Hard Cascade</head><p>For the hard cascade, we use the output from the first step to modify the input sequence before ex- tracting features for the second step. For PU→DF (PUnctuation prediction followed by DisFluency prediction), we split the input sequence into sen- tences according to the sentence-end punctuation symbols predicted by the first step, and then per- form the DF prediction on the short/sentence-split sequences in the second step. For DF→PU, we remove the edit and filler words predicted by the first step, and then predict the punctuations using the cleaned-up input sequence. The hard cascade method may be helpful because the disfluency pre- diction on short/sentence-split sequences is better than on long/sentence-joined sequences (see the second and third rows in <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">Table 4</ref>). On the other hand, the punctuation prediction on fluent text is more accurate than that on non-fluent text based on our preliminary study.</p><p>For this experiment, four models are trained using M3N without balancing precision/recall. For the first step, two models are trained on long/sentence-joined sequences with disfluent to- kens -one for PU prediction and the other for DF prediction. These are simply the isolated base- line systems. For the second step, the DF predic- tion model is trained on the short/sentence-split se- quences with disfluent tokens while the PU predic- tion model is trained on the long/sentence-joined sequences with disfluent tokens removed. Note that in the second step of DF→PU, punctuation la- bels are predicted only for the fluent tokens since the disfluent tokens predicted by the first step has already been removed. Therefore, during evalua- tion, if the first step makes a false positive by pre- dicting a fluent token as an edit or filler, we set its punctuation label to the neutral label, None. All the four models are trained using the same feature templates as shown in <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">Table 3</ref>. The regularization parameter is tuned on the development set.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">Soft Cascade</head><p>For the soft cascade method, we use the labels pre- dicted from the first step as additional features for the second step. For PU→DF, we model the joint probability as:</p><formula xml:id="formula_4">P (DF, PU|x) = P (PU|x) × P (DF|PU, x) (1)</formula><p>Likewise, we model the joint probability for DF→PU as:</p><formula xml:id="formula_5">P (DF, PU|x) = P (DF|x) × P (PU|DF, x) (2)</formula><p>For this experiment, four models are trained us- ing M3N without balancing precision/recall. As with the case of hard cascade, the two models used in the first step are simply the isolated base- line systems. For the second step, in addition to the feature templates in <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">Table 3</ref>, we also pass on the labels (at the previous, current and next posi- tion) predicted by the first step as three third-order- clique features. We also tune the regularization pa- rameter on the development set to obtain the best model. <ref type="table">Table 5</ref> compares the performance of the hard and soft cascade methods with the isolated base- line systems. In addition, we have also included the results of using the true labels in place of the labels predicted by the first step to indicate the upper-bound performance of the cascade ap- proaches. The results show that both the hard and soft cascade methods outperform the baseline sys- tems, with the latter giving a better performance   <ref type="table">Table 5</ref>: Performance comparison between the hard cascade method and the soft cascade method with respect to the baseline isolated prediction. All models are trained using M3N without balanc- ing precision and recall.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3">Experimental Results</head><p>(statistical significance at p=0.01). However, hard cascade has a higher upper-bound than soft cas- cade. This observation can be explained as fol- lows.</p><p>For hard cascade, the input sequence is modi- fied prior to feature extraction. Therefore, many of the features generated by the feature templates given in <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">Table 3</ref> will be affected by these modi- fications. So, provided that the modifications are based on the correct information, the resulting fea- tures will not contain unwanted artefacts caused by the absence of the sentence boundary informa- tion for the presence of disfluencies. For exam- ple, in "do you do you feel that it was worthy", the punctuation prediction system tends to insert a sentence-end punctuation after the first "do you" because the speaker restarts the sentence.</p><p>If the disfluency was correctly predicted in the first step, then the hard cascade method would have removed the first "do you" and eliminated the confusion. Similarly, in "I 'm sorry . I 'm not going with you tomorrow . ", the first "I 'm" is likely to be incorrectly detected as disfluent tokens since consecutive repetitions are a strong indica- tion of disfluency. In the case of hard cascade, PU→DF, the input sequence would have been split into sentences and the repetition feature would not be activated. However, since the hard cascade method has a greater influence on the features for the second step, it is also more sensitive to the pre- diction errors from the first step.</p><p>Another observation from <ref type="table">Table 5</ref> is that the improvement of the soft cascade over the isolate baseline is much larger on DF (1.4% absolute) than that on PU (only 0.5% absolute). The same holds true for the hard cascade, despite the fact that there are more DF labels than PU labels in this corpus (see <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>) and the first step prediction is more accurate on DF than on PU. This suggests that their mutual influence is not symmetrical, in the way that the output from punctuation predic- tion provides more useful information for disflu- ency prediction than the other way round.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">The Rescoring Approach</head><p>In Section 4, we have described that the two tasks can be cascaded in either order, i.e., PU→DF and DF→PU. However, the performance of the sec- ond step greatly depends on that of the first step. In order to reduce sensitivity to the errors made in the first step, one simple approach is to prop- agate multiple hypotheses from the first step to the second step to obtain a list of joint hypothe- ses (with both the DF and PU labels). We then rerank these hypotheses based on the joint proba- bility and pick the best. We call this the rescoring approach. From <ref type="formula">(1)</ref> and <ref type="formula">(2)</ref>, the joint probabilities can be expressed in terms of the probabilities gen- erated by four models: P (PU|x), P (DF|PU, x), P (DF|x), and P (PU|DF, x). We can combine the four models to form the following joint probability function for rescoring:</p><formula xml:id="formula_6">P (DF, PU|x) = P (DF|x) α 1 × P (PU|DF, x) α 2 × P (PU|x) β 1 × P (DF|PU, x) β 2</formula><p>where α 1 , α 2 , β 1 , and β 2 are used to weight the relative importance between (1) and <ref type="formula">(2)</ref>; and between the first and second steps. In practice, the probabilities are computed in the log domain where the above expression becomes a weighted sum of the log probabilities. A similar rescoring approach using two models is described in <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Shi and Wang (2007)</ref>.</p><p>The experimental framework is shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Fig- ure 1</ref>. For PU→DF, we first use P (PU|x) to gen- erate an n-best list. Then, for each hypothesis in the n-best list, we use P (DF|PU, x) to obtain an- other n-best list. So we have n 2 -best joint hy- potheses. We do the same for DF→PU to ob- tain another n 2 -best joint hypotheses. We rescore the 2n 2 -best list using the four models. The four weights α 1 , α 2 , β 1 , and β 2 are tuned to opti- mize the overall F1 score on the development set. We used the MERT (minimum-error-rate training, <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Och, 2003)</ref>) algorithm to tune the weights. We also vary the size of n.</p><formula xml:id="formula_7">P(PU|x) P(DF|PU,x) Input Sequence P(PU|DF,x) P(DF|x) PU-hypo-1 PU-hypo-n … DF-hypo-1 DF-hypo-n … 2 n-best joint-hypo-1 … … joint-hypo-1 2 n 2 -best joint-hypo-2 joint-hypo-2 … …</formula><p>Rescore using: The results shown in <ref type="table" target="#tab_7">Table 6</ref> suggest that the rescoring method does not improve over the soft- cascade baseline. This can be due to the fact that we are using the same four models for the soft- cascade and the rescoring methods. It may be possible that the information contained in the two models for the soft-cascade PU→DF mostly over- laps with the information contained in the other two models for the soft-cascade DF→PU since all the four models are trained using the same fea- tures. Thus, no additional information is gained by combining the four models.</p><formula xml:id="formula_8">í</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">The Joint Approach</head><p>In this section, we compare 2-layer FCRF ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Lu and Ng, 2010</ref>) with mixed-label LCRF ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">Stolcke et al., 1998</ref>) and cross-product LCRF on the joint predic- tion task. For the 2-layer FCRF, we use punctua- tion labels for the first layer and disfluency labels for the second layer (see <ref type="table">Table 2</ref>). For the mixed- label LCRF, we split the neutral label {O} into {Comma, Period, QMark, None} so that we have six labels in total, {E, F, Comma, Period, QMark, None}. In this approach, disfluent tokens do not have punctuation labels because in real applica- tions, if we just want to get the cleaned-up/fluent text with punctuations, we do not need to predict punctuations on disfluent tokens as they will be removed during the clean-up process. Since this approach does not predict punctuation labels on disfluent tokens, its punctuation F1 score is only evaluated on those fluent tokens. For the cross- product LCRF, we compose each of the three dis- fluency labels with the four punctuation labels to get 12 PU-DF-joint labels ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Ng and Low, 2004</ref>). <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Figure 2</ref> shows a comparison of these three models in the joint prediction of punctuation and disflu- ency. All the LCRF and FCRF models are trained using the GRMM toolkit <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">(Sutton, 2006</ref>). We use the same feature templates <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">(Table 3)</ref> to generate all the features for the toolkit. However, to reduce the training time, we have set clique order to 2 for the transitions and 1 for all other features. We tune the Gaussian prior variance on the development set for all the experiments to obtain the best model for testing. <ref type="table">Table 7</ref> shows the comparison of results. On DF alone, the improvement of the cross-product LCRF over the mixed-label LCRF, and the im- provement of the mixed-label LCRF over the isolated baseline are not statistically significant. However, if we test the statistical significance on the overall performance of both PU and DF, both the 2-layer FCRF and the cross-product LCRF perform better than the mixed-label LCRF. And we also obtain the same conclusion as <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">Stolcke et al. (1998)</ref> that mixed-label LCRF performs better than isolated prediction. However, for the comparison between the 2-layer FCRF and the cross-product LCRF, although the 2-layer FCRF performs better than the cross-product LCRF on disfluency prediction, it does worse on punctua- tion prediction. Overall, the two methods perform about the same, their difference is not statistically significant. In addition, both the 2-layer FCRF and the cross-product LCRF slightly outperform the soft cascade method (statistical significance at p=0.04).   </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7">Discussion</head><p>In this section, we will summarise our observa- tions based on the empirical studies that we have conducted in this paper. Firstly, punctuation prediction and disfluency prediction do influence each other. The output from one task does provide useful information that can improve the other task. All the approaches studied in this work, which link the two tasks together, perform better than their corresponding  <ref type="table">Table 7</ref>: Performance comparison among 2- layer FCRF, mixed-label LCRF and cross-product LCRF, with respect to the soft-cascade and the iso- lated prediction baseline. All models are trained using GRMM <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">(Sutton, 2006</ref>), with reduced clique orders. Ref: it was n't , you know , it was never announced .</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Token:</head><p>it was n't you know it was never announced</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>PU:</head><p>None None Comma None Comma None None None Period DF:  isolated prediction baseline. Secondly, as compared to the soft cascade, the hard cascade passes more information from the first step into the second step, and thus is much more sensitive to errors in the first step. In prac- tice, unless the first step has very high accuracy, soft cascade is expected to do better than hard cas- cade.</p><formula xml:id="formula_9">E E E F F O O O O (a) Mixed- label</formula><p>Thirdly, if we train a model using a fine-grained label set but test it on the same coarse-grained la- bel set, we are very likely to get improvement. For example:</p><p>• The edit word F1 for mixed edit and filler pre- diction using {E, F, O} is better than that for edit prediction using {E, O} (see the second and third rows in <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">Table 4</ref>). This is because the former actually splits the O in the latter into F and O. Thus, it has a finer label granularity.</p><p>• Disfluency prediction using mixed-label LCRF (using label set {E, F, Comma, Pe- riod, Question, None}) performs better than that using isolated LCRF (using label set {E, F, O}) (see the second and fourth rows in <ref type="table">Table 7</ref>). This is because the former dis-tinguishes between different punctuations for fluent tokens and thus has a finer label granu- larity.</p><p>• Both the cross-product LCRF and 2-layer FCRF perform better than mixed-label LCRF because the former two distinguish between different punctuations for edit, filler and flu- ent tokens while the latter distinguishes be- tween different punctuations only for fluent tokens. Thus, the former has a much finer la- bel granularity.</p><p>From the above comparisons, we can see that increasing the label granularity can greatly im- prove the accuracy of a model. However, this may also increase the model complexity dramat- ically, especially when higher clique order is used. Although the joint approach (2-layer FCRF and cross-product LCRF) are better than the soft- cascade approach, they cannot be easily scaled up to using higher order cliques, which greatly limits their potential. In practice, the soft cascade ap- proach offers a simpler and more efficient way to achieve a joint prediction of punctuations and dis- fluencies.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="8">Conclusion</head><p>In general, punctuation prediction and disfluency prediction can improve downstream NLP tasks. Combining the two tasks can potentially improve the efficiency of the overall framework and mini- mize error propagation. In this work, we have car- ried out an empirical study on the various methods for combining the two tasks. Our results show that the various methods linking the two tasks perform better than the isolated prediction. This means that punctuation prediction and disfluency predic- tion do influence each other, and the prediction outcome in one task can provide useful informa- tion that helps to improve the other task. Specifi- cally, we compare the cascade models and the joint prediction models. For the cascade approach, we show that soft cascade is less sensitive to predic- tion errors in the first step, and thus performs bet- ter than hard cascade. For joint model approach, we show that, when clique order of one is used, all the three joint model approaches perform signifi- cantly better than the isolated prediction baseline. Moreover, the 2-layer FCRF and the cross-product LCRF perform slightly better than the mix-label LCRF and the soft-cascade approach, suggesting that modelling at a finer label granularity is po- tentially beneficial. However, the soft cascade ap- proach is more efficient than the joint approach when a higher clique order is used.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>F1</head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: Illustration of the rescoring pipeline framework using the four M3N models used in the softcascade method: P (PU|x), P (DF|PU, x), P (DF|x) and P (PU|DF, x)</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Experiment</head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>E</head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head>Figure 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2: Illustration using (a) mixed-label LCRF; (b) cross-product LCRF; and (c) 2-layer FCRF, for joint punctuation (PU) and disfluency (DF) prediction. Shaded nodes are observations and unshaded nodes are variables to be predicted.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" validated="false"><head>Table 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Feature templates for disfluency predic-
tion, or punctuation prediction, or joint prediction 
for all the experiments in this paper. 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4" validated="false"><head>Table 4 :</head><label>4</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Baseline results showing the degradation 
by joining utterances into long sentences, remov-
ing precision/recall balancing, and reducing the 
clique order of features. All models are trained 
using M3N. 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_7" validated="false"><head>Table 6 :</head><label>6</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Performance comparison between the 
rescoring method and the soft-cascade method 
with respect to the baseline isolated prediction. 
The rescoring is done on 2n 2 hypotheses. All 
models are trained using M3N without balancing 
precision and recall. Figures in the bracket are the 
oracle F1 scores of the 2n 2 hypotheses. *:on the 
development set, the best overall result is obtained 
at n = 10. 

</table></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> The research reported in this paper was carried out as part of the PhD thesis research of Xuancong Wang at the NUS Graduate School for Integrated Sciences and Engineering.</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>This research is supported by the Singapore Na-tional Research Foundation under its International Research Centre @ Singapore Funding Initiative and administered by the IDM Programme Office.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Automatic punctuation and disfluency detection in multi-party meetings using prosodic and lexical cues</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Don</forename><surname>Baron</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Elizabeth</forename><surname>Shriberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Andreas</forename><surname>Stolcke</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of ICSLP</title>
		<meeting>of ICSLP</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Punctuation annotation using statistical prosody models</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Heidi</forename><surname>Christensen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yoshihiko</forename><surname>Gotoh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Steve</forename><surname>Renals</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ISCA Tutorial and Research Workshop (ITRW) on Prosody in Speech Recognition and Understanding</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Punctuating speech for information extraction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ralph</forename><surname>Benoit Favre</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dustin</forename><surname>Grishman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Heng</forename><surname>Hillard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dilek</forename><surname>Ji</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mari</forename><surname>Hakkani-Tur</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Ostendorf</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of ICASSP</title>
		<meeting>of ICASSP</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Using integer linear programming for detecting speech disfluencies</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kallirroi</forename><surname>Georgila</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of NAACL</title>
		<meeting>of NAACL</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Maximum entropy model for punctuation annotation from speech</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jing</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Geoffrey</forename><surname>Zweig</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of INTERSPEECH</title>
		<meeting>of INTERSPEECH</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A TAGbased noisy-channel model of speech repairs</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mark</forename><surname>Johnson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Eugene</forename><surname>Charniak</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of ACL</title>
		<meeting>of ACL</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Automatic detection of sentence boundaries, disfluencies, and conversational fillers in spontaneous speech</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Joungbum</forename><surname>Kim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>Master dissertation of University of Washington</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Using conditional random fields for sentence boundary detection in speech</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yang</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Andreas</forename><surname>Stolcke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Elizabeth</forename><surname>Shriberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mary</forename><surname>Harper</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of ACL</title>
		<meeting>of ACL</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Enriching speech recognition with automatic detection of sentence boundaries and disfluencies</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yang</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Elizabeth</forename><surname>Shriberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Andreas</forename><surname>Stolcke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dustin</forename><surname>Hillard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mari</forename><surname>Ostendorf</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mary</forename><surname>Harper</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE Transactions on Audio, Speech, and Language Processing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1526" to="1540" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Better punctuation prediction with dynamic conditional random fields</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wei</forename><surname>Lu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hwee Tou</forename><surname>Ng</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of EMNLP</title>
		<meeting>of EMNLP</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A phrase-level machine translation approach for disfluency detection using weighted finite state transducers</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sameer</forename><surname>Maskey</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bowen</forename><surname>Zhou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yuqing</forename><surname>Gao</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of INTERSPEECH</title>
		<meeting>of INTERSPEECH</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Chinese part-of-speech tagging: One-at-a-time or all-atonce? Word-based or character-based?</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tou</forename><surname>Hwee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jin</forename><forename type="middle">Kiat</forename><surname>Ng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Low</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of EMNLP</title>
		<meeting>of EMNLP</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Minimum error rate training in statistical machine translation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Franz Josef</forename><surname>Och</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of ACL</title>
		<meeting>of ACL</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Disfluency detection using multi-step stacked learning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xian</forename><surname>Qian</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yang</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of NAACL</title>
		<meeting>of NAACL</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Prosodic features of four types of disfluencies</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Guergana</forename><surname>Savova</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Joan</forename><surname>Bachenko</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ISCA Tutorial and Research Workshop on Disfluency in Spontaneous Speech</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A dual-layer CRFs based joint decoding method for cascaded segmentation and labeling tasks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yanxin</forename><surname>Shi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mengqiu</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of IJCAI</title>
		<meeting>of IJCAI</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Rebecca Bates and Andreas Stolcke. 1997. A prosody-only decision-tree model for disfluency detection</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Elizabeth</forename><surname>Shriberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of Eurospeech</title>
		<meeting>of Eurospeech</meeting>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Klaus Ries, Rachel Martin, and Carol Van Ess-Dykema. 1998. Can prosody aid the automatic classification of dialog acts in conversational speech?</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Elizabeth</forename><surname>Shriberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Andreas</forename><surname>Stolcke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Daniel</forename><surname>Jurafsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Noah</forename><surname>Coccaro</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marie</forename><surname>Meteer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rebecca</forename><surname>Bates</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Paul</forename><surname>Taylor</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Language and speech</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">41</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="443" to="492" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Automatic detection of sentence boundaries and disfluencies based on recognized words</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Andreas</forename><surname>Stolcke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Elizabeth</forename><surname>Shriberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rebecca</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Bates</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mari</forename><surname>Ostendorf</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dilek</forename><surname>Hakkani</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Madelaine</forename><surname>Plauche</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gokhan</forename><surname>Tur</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yu</forename><surname>Lu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of ICSLP</title>
		<meeting>of ICSLP</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Charles</forename><surname>Sutton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://mallet.cs.umass.edu/grmm/" />
		<title level="m">GRMM: GRaphical Models in Mallet</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dynamic conditional random fields: factorized probabilistic models for labeling and segmenting sequence data</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Charles</forename><surname>Sutton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Andrew</forename><surname>Mccallum</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Khashayar</forename><surname>Rohanimanesh</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">In Journal of Machine Learning Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="693" to="723" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Max-margin Markov networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ben</forename><surname>Taskar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Carlos</forename><surname>Guestrin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Daphne</forename><surname>Koller</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of NIPS</title>
		<meeting>of NIPS</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Automatic disfluency removal for improving spoken language translation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wen</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gokhan</forename><surname>Tur</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of ICASSP</title>
		<meeting>of ICASSP</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Jing Zheng, and Necip Fazil Ayan</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dynamic conditional random fields for joint sentence boundary and punctuation prediction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xuancong</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hwee</forename><forename type="middle">Tou</forename><surname>Ng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Khe Chai</forename><surname>Sim</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of Interspeech</title>
		<meeting>of Interspeech</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A beam-search decoder for disfluency detection</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xuancong</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hwee</forename><forename type="middle">Tou</forename><surname>Ng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Khe Chai</forename><surname>Sim</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of COLING</title>
		<meeting>of COLING</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Punctuation prediction with transitionbased parsing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dongdong</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Shuangzhi</forename><surname>Wu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nan</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mu</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of ACL</title>
		<meeting>of ACL</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The impact of language models and loss functions on repair disfluency detection</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Simon</forename><surname>Zwarts</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mark</forename><surname>Johnson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of ACL</title>
		<meeting>of ACL</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
