<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T10:36+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Reordering Model for Forest-to-String Machine Translation</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
				<availability status="unknown"><p>Copyright Association for Computational Linguistics</p>
				</availability>
				<date>October 25-29, 2014. 2014</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Martiň</forename><surname>Cmejrek</surname></persName>
							<email>martin.cmejrek@us.ibm.com</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory">IBM Watson Group Prague</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="CZ">Czech Republic</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Reordering Model for Forest-to-String Machine Translation</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2014 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP)</title>
						<meeting>the 2014 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP) <address><addrLine>Doha, Qatar. c</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="227" to="232"/>
							<date type="published">October 25-29, 2014. 2014</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>In this paper, we present a novel extension of a forest-to-string machine translation system with a reordering model. We predict reordering probabilities for every pair of source words with a model using features observed from the input parse forest. Our approach naturally deals with the ambiguity present in the input parse forest, but, at the same time, takes into account only the parts of the input forest used by the current translation hypothesis. The method provides improvement from 0.6 up to 1.0 point measured by (Ter − Bleu)/2 metric.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Various commonly adopted statistical machine translation (SMT) approaches differ in the amount of linguistic knowledge present in the rules they employ.</p><p>Phrase-based ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Koehn et al., 2003</ref>) models are strong in lexical coverage in local contexts, and use external models to score reordering op- tions <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">(Tillman, 2004;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Koehn et al., 2005</ref>).</p><p>Hierarchical models <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Chiang, 2005</ref>) use lexi- calized synchronous context-free grammar rules to produce local reorderings. The grammatical- ity of their output can be improved by addi- tional reordering models scoring permutations of the source words. Reordering model can be either used for source pre-ordering ( <ref type="bibr">Tromble and Eisner, )</ref>, integrated into decoding via translation rules ex- tension ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Hayashi et al., 2010)</ref>, additional lexical features ( <ref type="bibr">He et al., )</ref>, or using external sources of information, such as source syntactic features ob- served from a parse tree ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Huang et al., 2013)</ref>.</p><p>Tree-to-string (T2S) models ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Liu et al., 2006</ref>; <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Galley et al., 2006</ref>) use rules with syntactic struc- tures, aiming at even more grammatically appro- priate reorderings.</p><p>Forest-to-string (F2S) systems ( ) use source syntactic forest as the input to overcome parsing errors, and to al- leviate sparseness of translation rules.</p><p>The parse forest may often represent several meanings for an ambiguous input that may need to be transtated differently using different word or- derings. The following example of an ambiguous Chinese sentence with ambiguous part-of-speech labeling motivates our interest in the reordering model for the F2S translation.</p><p>S. tˇaoì un (0) SSS. h` ui (1) SSS zěnmeyàng (2) discussion/NN SS meeting/NN how/VV discuss/VV SSSSSwill/VV There are several possible meanings based on the different POS tagging sequences. We present translations for two of them, together with the in- dices to their original source words:</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">(a) NN NN VV:</formula><p>How 2 was 2 the 0 discussion 0 meeting 1 ?</p><p>(b) VV VV VV: Discuss 0 what 2 will 1 happen 1 .</p><p>A T2S system starts from a single parse corre- sponding to one of the possible POS sequences, the same tree can be used to predict word reorder- ings. On the other hand, a F2S system deals with the ambiguity through exploring translation hy- potheses for all competing parses representing the different meanings. As our example suggests, dif- ferent meanings also tend to reorder differently id rule r 1 NP(tˇaoì un/NN) → discussion r 2 NP(h` ui/NN) → meeting r 3 NP(x 1 :NP x 2 :NP) → the x 1 x 2 r 4 IP(x 1 :NP zěnmeyàng/VV) → how was x 1 r 5 IP(h` ui/VV zěnmeyàng/VV) → what will happen r 6 IP(tˇaoì un/VV x 1 :IP) → discuss x 1 <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>: Tree-to-string translation rules (without internal structures).</p><p>during translation. First, the reordering model suit- able for F2S translation should allow for trans- lation of all meanings present in the input. Sec- ond, as the process of deriving a partial transla- tion hypothesis rules out some of the meanings, the reordering model should restrict itself to fea- tures originating in the relevant parts of the input forest. Our work presents a novel technique satis- fying both these requirements, while leaving the disambuiguation decision up to the model using global features. The paper is organized as follows: We briefly overview the F2S and Hiero translation models in Section 2, present the proposed forest reordering model in Section 3, describe our experiment and present results in Section 4.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Translation Models</head><p>Forest-to-string translation ( ) is an extension of the tree-to-string model ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Liu et al., 2006;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Huang et al., 2006</ref>) allowing it to use a packed parse forest as the input instead of a sin- gle parse tree. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref> shows a tree-to-string translation rule ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Huang et al., 2006</ref>), which is a tuple lhs(r), rhs(r), ψ(r), where lhs(r) is the source- side tree fragment, whose internal nodes are la- beled by nonterminal symbols (like NP), and whose frontier nodes are labeled by source- language words (like "zěnmeyàng") or variables from a finite set X = {x 1 , x 2 , . . .}; rhs(r) is the target-side string expressed in target-language words (like "how was") and variables; and ψ(r) is a mapping from X to nonterminals. Each variable x i ∈ X occurs exactly once in lhs(r) and exactly once in rhs(r).</p><p>The <ref type="table">Table 1</ref> lists all rules necessary to derive translations (a) and (b), with their internal struc- ture removed for simplicity.</p><p>Typically, an F2S system translates in two steps (shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 2</ref>): parsing and decoding. In the parsing step, the source language input is con- verted into a parse forest (A). In the decoding step, we first convert the parse forest into a translation forest F t in (B) by using the fast pattern-matching technique ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Zhang et al., 2009)</ref>. Then the decoder uses dynamic programing with beam search and cube pruning to find the approximation to the best scoring derivation in the translation forest, and outputs the target string.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Forest Reordering Model</head><p>In this section, we describe the process of ap- plying the reordering model scores. We score pairwise translation reorderings for every pair of source words similarly as described by <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Huang et al. (2013)</ref>. In their approach, an external model of ordering distributions of sibling constituent pairs predicts the reordering of word pairs. Our ap- proach deals with parse forests rather than with single trees, thus we have to model the scores dif- ferently. We model ordering distributions for ev- ery pair of close relatives-nodes in the parse forest that may occur together as frontier nodes of a sin- gle matching rule. We further condition the distri- bution on a third node-a common ancestor of the node pair that corresponds to the root node of the matching rule. This way our external model takes into acount the syntactic context of the hypothe- sis. For example, nodes NP 0, 1 and NP 1, 2 are close relatives, NP 0, 2 and IP 0, 3 are their common ances- tors; NP 0, 1 and VV 2, 3 are close relatives, IP 0, 3 is their common ancestor; NP 0, 1 and VV 1, 2 are not close relatives. More formally, let us have an input sentence (w 0 , ..., w n ) and its translation hypothesis h. For every i and j such that 0 ≤ i &lt; j ≤ n we as- sume that the translations of w i and w j are in the hypothesis h either in the same or inverted order- ing o i j ∈ {Inorder, Reorder}, with a probability P order (o i j |h). Conditioning on h signifies that the probabilistic model takes the current hypothesis as a parameter. The reordering score of the entire hy-   The corresponding translation forest F t after applying the tree-to-string translation rule set R t . Each translation hyperedge (e.g. e 4 ) has the same index as the corresponding rule (r 4 ). The forest-to- string system can produce the example translation (a) (solid derivation: r 1 , r 2 , r 3 , and r 4 ) and (b) (dashed derivation: r 5 , r 6 ).</p><p>pothesis f order (h) is then computed as</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">f order = 0≤i&lt; j≤n − log P order (o i j = o h i j | h),<label>(1)</label></formula><p>where o h i j denotes the actual ordering used in h. The score f order can be computed recursively by dynamic programing during the decoding. As an example, we show in <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">Table 2</ref> reordering probabil- ities retrieved in decoding of our sample sentence.</p><p>(a) If h is a hypothesis formed by a single trans- lation rule r with no frontier nonterminals, we evaluate all word pairs w i and w j covered by h such that i &lt; j. For each such pair we find the frontier nodes x and y matched by r such that x spans exactly w i and y spans exactly w j . (In this case, x and y match preterminal nodes, each spanning one position). We also find the node z matching the root of r. Then we directly use the Equation 1 to compute the score using an exter- nal model P order (o i j |xyz) to estimate the probabil- ity of reordering the relative nodes. For example, when applying rule r 5 , we use the ordering dis- tribution P order (o 1,2 |VV 1, 2 , VV 2, 3 , IP 1, 3 ) to score reorderings of h` ui and zěnmeyàng.</p><p>(b) If h is a hypothesis formed by a T2S rule with one or more frontier nonterminals, we eval- uate all word pairs as follows: If both w i and w j are spanned by the same frontier nonterminal (e.g., tˇaoì un and h` ui when applying the rule r 4 ), the score f order had been already computed for the un- derlying subhypothesis, and therefore was already included in the total score. Otherwise, we compute the word pair ordering cost. We find the close rel- atives x and y representing each w i and w j . If w i is matched by a terminal in r, we select x as the node matching r and spanning exactly w i . If w i is spanned by a frontier nonterminal in r (meaning that it was translated in a subhypothesis), we select x as the node matching that nonterminal. We pro- ceed identically for w j and y. For example, when applying the rule r 4 , the word zěnmeyàng will be represented by the node VV 2, 3 , while tˇaoì un and h` ui will be represented by the node NP 0, 2 .</p><p>Note that the ordering o h i j cannot be determined in some cases, sometimes a source word does not produce any translation, or the translation of one word is entirely surrounded by the translations of another word. A weight corresponding to the bi- nary discount feature f o unknown is added to the score for each such case.</p><p>The external model P order (o i j |xyz) is imple- mented as a maximum entropy model. Features of the model are observed from paths connecting node z with nodes x and y as follows: First, we pick paths z → x and z → y. Let z ′ be the last node shared by both paths (the closest common ances- tor of x and y). Then we distinguish three types of path: (1) The common prefix z → z ′ (it may have zero length), the left path z → x, and the right path z → y. We observe the following features on each path: the syntactic labels of the nodes, the produc- tion rules, the spans of nodes, a list of stop words immediately preceding and following the span of the node. We merge the features observed from different paths z → x and z → y. This approach 229 rule word pair order probability a) how 2 was 2 the discussion <ref type="bibr">0</ref>   ignores the internal structure of each rule 1 , relying on frontier node annotation. On the other hand it is still feasible to precompute the reordering prob- abilities for all combinations of xyz.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Experiment</head><p>In this section we describe the setup of the exper- iment, and present results. Finally, we propose fu- ture directions of research.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">Setup</head><p>Our baseline is a strong F2S system ( ˇ Cmejrek et al., 2013) built on large data with the full set of model features including rule translation prob- abilities, general lexical and provenance transla- tion probabilities, language model, and a vari- ety of sparse features. We build it as follows.</p><p>The training corpus consists of 16 million sen- tence pairs available within the DARPA BOLT Chinese-English task. The corpus includes a mix of newswire, broadcast news, webblog data com- ing from various sources such as LDC, HK Law, HK Hansard and UN data. The Chinese text is seg- mented with a segmenter trained on CTB data us- ing conditional random fields (CRF).</p><p>Bilingual word alignments are trained and com- bined from two sources: GIZA <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">(Och, 2003)</ref> and maximum entropy word aligner <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Ittycheriah and Roukos, 2005</ref>).</p><p>Language models are trained on the English side of the parallel corpus, and on monolingual corpora, such as Gigaword (LDC2011T07) and Google News, altogether comprising around 10 billion words.</p><p>We parse the Chinese part of the training data with a modified version of the Berkeley parser 1 Only to some extent, the rule still has to match the input forest, but the reordering model decides based on the sum of paths observed between the root and frontier nodes.</p><p>( <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Petrov and Klein, 2007)</ref>, then prune the ob- tained parse forests for each training sentence with the marginal probability-based inside-outside al- gorithm to contain only 3n CFG nodes, where n is the sentence length.</p><p>We extract tree-to-string translation rules from forest-string sentence pairs using the forest-based GHKM algorithm <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Galley et al., 2004</ref>).</p><p>In the decoding step, we use larger input parse forests than in training, we prune them to contain 10n nodes. Then we use fast pattern- matching ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Zhang et al., 2009</ref>) to convert the parse forest into the translation forest.</p><p>The proposed reordering model is trained on 100, 000 automatically aligned forest-string sen- tence pairs from the parallel training data. These sentences provide 110M reordering events that are used by megam <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Daumé III, 2004</ref>) to train the max- imum entropy model. The current implementation of the reordering model requires offline preprocessing of the input hypergraphs to precompute reordering probabili- ties for applicable triples of nodes (x, y, z). Since the number of levels in the syntactic trees in T2S rules is limited to 4, we only need to consider such triples, where z is up to 4 levels above x or y.</p><p>We tune on 1275 sentences, each with 4 refer- ences, from the LDC2010E30 corpus, initially re- leased under the DARPA GALE program.</p><p>We combine two evaluation metrics for tun- ing and testing: Bleu ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Papineni et al., 2002</ref>) and Ter ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">Snover et al., 2006</ref>  portion (691 sentences, 4 references), and NIST MT08 Web portion (666 sentences, 4 references). <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">Table 3</ref> shows all results of the baseline and the system extended with the forest reordering model. The (Ter − Bleu)/2 score of the baseline system is 12.0 on MT08 Newswire, showing that it is a strong baseline. The system with the proposed re- ordering model significantly improves the base- line by 0.6, 0.8, and 1.0 (Ter − Bleu)/2 points on GALE Web, MT08 Newswire, and MT08 Web. The current approach relies on frontier node annotations, ignoring to some extent the internal structure of the T2S rules. As part of future re- search, we would like to compare this approach with the one that takes into accout the internal structure as well.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">Results</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Conclusion</head><p>We have presented a novel reordering model for the forest-to-string MT system. The model deals with the ambiguity of the input forests, but also predicts specifically to the current parse followed by the translation hypothesis. The reordering prob- abilities can be precomputed by an offline pro- cess, allowing for efficient scoring in runtime. The method provides improvement from 0.6 up to 1.0 point measured by (Ter − Bleu)/2 metrics.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: Tree-to-string rule r 4 .</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>(</head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2: Parse and translation hypergraphs. (A) The parse forest of the example sentence. Solid hyperedges denote the best parse, dashed hyperedges denote the second best parse. Unary edges were collapsed. (B) The corresponding translation forest F t after applying the tree-to-string translation rule set R t. Each translation hyperedge (e.g. e 4 ) has the same index as the corresponding rule (r 4 ). The forest-tostring system can produce the example translation (a) (solid derivation: r 1 , r 2 , r 3 , and r 4 ) and (b) (dashed derivation: r 5 , r 6 ).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" validated="false"><head>Table 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Example of reordering scores computed for derivations (a) and (b). 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4" validated="false"><head>Table 3 : Results.</head><label>3</label><figDesc></figDesc><table></table></figure>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>We thank Jiří Havelka for proofreading and help-ful suggestions. We would like to acknowledge the support of DARPA under Grant HR0011-12-C-0015 for funding part of this work. The views, opinions, and/or findings contained in this article are those of the author and should not be inter-preted as representing the official views or poli-cies, either expressed or implied, of the DARPA.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A hierarchical phrase-based model for statistical machine translation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Chiang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the ACL</title>
		<meeting>the ACL</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Online passive-aggressive algorithms</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Koby</forename><surname>Crammer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ofer</forename><surname>Dekel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Joseph</forename><surname>Keshet</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Shai</forename><surname>Shalev-Shwartz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yoram</forename><surname>Singer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Machine Learning Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Notes on CG and LM-BFGS optimization of logistic regression</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hal</forename><surname>Daumé</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Iii</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://pub.hal3.name#daume04cg-bfgs,im-plementationavailableathttp://hal3.name/megam/" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">What&apos;s in a translation rule</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michel</forename><surname>Galley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mark</forename><surname>Hopkins</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kevin</forename><surname>Knight</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Daniel</forename><surname>Marcu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the HLT-NAACL</title>
		<meeting>the HLT-NAACL</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Scalable inference and training of context-rich syntactic translation models</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michel</forename><surname>Galley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jonathan</forename><surname>Graehl</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kevin</forename><surname>Knight</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Daniel</forename><surname>Marcu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Steve</forename><surname>Deneefe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wei</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ignacio</forename><surname>Thayer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the COLING-ACL</title>
		<meeting>the COLING-ACL</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Hierarchical Phrase-based Machine Translation with Word-based Reordering Model</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Katsuhiko</forename><surname>Hayashi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hajime</forename><surname>Tsukada</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Katsuhito</forename><surname>Sudoh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kevin</forename><surname>Duh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Seiichi</forename><surname>Yamamoto</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the COLING</title>
		<meeting>the COLING</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Maximum entropy based phrase reordering for hierarchical phrase-based translation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Zhongjun</forename><surname>He</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yao</forename><surname>Meng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hao</forename><surname>Yu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the EMNLP</title>
		<meeting>the EMNLP</meeting>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Statistical syntax-directed translation with extended domain of locality</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Liang</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kevin</forename><surname>Knight</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Aravind</forename><surname>Joshi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the AMTA</title>
		<meeting>the AMTA</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Factored soft source syntactic constraints for hierarchical machine translation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Zhongqiang</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jacob</forename><surname>Devlin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rabih</forename><surname>Zbib</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceeedings of the EMNLP</title>
		<meeting>eeedings of the EMNLP</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A maximum entropy word aligner for arabic-english machine translation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Abraham</forename><surname>Ittycheriah</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Salim</forename><surname>Roukos</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the HLT and EMNLP</title>
		<meeting>the HLT and EMNLP</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Statistical phrase-based translation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Philipp</forename><surname>Koehn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Franz</forename><forename type="middle">Joseph</forename><surname>Och</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Daniel</forename><surname>Marcu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of NAACL</title>
		<meeting>NAACL</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Edinburgh system description for the 2005 iwslt speech translation evaluation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Philipp</forename><surname>Koehn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Amittai</forename><surname>Axelrod</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alexandra</forename><forename type="middle">Birch</forename><surname>Mayne</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chris</forename><surname>Callison-Burch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Miles</forename><surname>Osborne</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Talbot</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the IWSLT</title>
		<meeting>the IWSLT</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Treeto-string alignment template for statistical machine translation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yang</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Qun</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Shouxun</forename><surname>Lin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of COLING-ACL</title>
		<meeting>COLING-ACL</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Forest-based translation rule extraction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Haitao</forename><surname>Mi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Liang</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of EMNLP</title>
		<meeting>EMNLP</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Forestbased translation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Haitao</forename><surname>Mi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Liang</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Qun</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of ACL: HLT</title>
		<meeting>ACL: HLT</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Minimum error rate training in statistical machine translation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Franz Joseph</forename><surname>Och</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of ACL</title>
		<meeting>ACL</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Bleu: a method for automatic evaluation of machine translation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kishore</forename><surname>Papineni</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Salim</forename><surname>Roukos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Todd</forename><surname>Ward</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Weijing</forename><surname>Zhu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of ACL</title>
		<meeting>ACL</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Improved inference for unlexicalized parsing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Slav</forename><surname>Petrov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dan</forename><surname>Klein</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of HLTNAACL</title>
		<meeting>HLTNAACL</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A study of translation edit rate with targeted human annotation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Matthew</forename><surname>Snover</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bonnie</forename><surname>Dorr</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Richard</forename><surname>Schwartz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Linnea</forename><surname>Micciulla</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">John</forename><surname>Makhoul</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the AMTA</title>
		<meeting>the AMTA</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A unigram orientation model for statistical machine translation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christoph</forename><surname>Tillman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the HLT-NAACL</title>
		<meeting>the HLT-NAACL</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Learning linear ordering problems for better translation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Roy</forename><surname>Tromble</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jason</forename><surname>Eisner</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the EMNLP</title>
		<meeting>the EMNLP</meeting>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Flexible and efficient hypergraph interactions for joint hierarchical and forest-to-string decoding</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Martiň</forename><surname>Cmejrek</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Haitao</forename><surname>Mi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bowen</forename><surname>Zhou</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the EMNLP</title>
		<meeting>the EMNLP</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Fast translation rule matching for syntax-based statistical machine translation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hui</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Min</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Haizhou</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chew Lim</forename><surname>Tan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of EMNLP</title>
		<meeting>EMNLP<address><addrLine>Singapore</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009-08" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1037" to="1045" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
