<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T13:13+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Revisiting Embedding Features for Simple Semi-supervised Learning</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
				<availability status="unknown"><p>Copyright Association for Computational Linguistics</p>
				</availability>
				<date>October 25-29, 2014. 2014</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jiang</forename><surname>Guo</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wanxiang</forename><surname>Che</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Haifeng</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">Baidu Inc</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Beijing</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ting</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Research Center for Social Computing and Information Retrieval</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Harbin Institute of Technology</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Revisiting Embedding Features for Simple Semi-supervised Learning</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2014 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP)</title>
						<meeting>the 2014 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP) <address><addrLine>Doha, Qatar. c</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="110" to="120"/>
							<date type="published">October 25-29, 2014. 2014</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Recent work has shown success in using continuous word embeddings learned from unlabeled data as features to improve supervised NLP systems, which is regarded as a simple semi-supervised learning mechanism. However, fundamental problems on effectively incorporating the word embedding features within the framework of linear models remain. In this study, we investigate and analyze three different approaches, including a new proposed distributional prototype approach, for utilizing the embedding features. The presented approaches can be integrated into most of the classical linear models in NLP. Experiments on the task of named entity recognition show that each of the proposed approaches can better utilize the word embedding features, among which the distributional prototype approach performs the best. Moreover, the combination of the approaches provides additive improvements , outperforming the dense and continuous embedding features by nearly 2 points of F1 score.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Learning generalized representation of words is an effective way of handling data sparsity caused by high-dimensional lexical features in NLP sys- tems, such as named entity recognition (NER) and dependency parsing. As a typical low- dimensional and generalized word representa- tion, Brown clustering of words has been stud- ied for a long time. For example, <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Liang (2005)</ref> and <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Koo et al. (2008)</ref> used the Brown cluster features for semi-supervised learning of various NLP tasks and achieved significant improvements. * Email correspondence.</p><p>Recent research has focused on a special fam- ily of word representations, named "word embed- dings". Word embeddings are conventionally de- fined as dense, continuous, and low-dimensional vector representations of words. Word embed- dings can be learned from large-scale unlabeled texts through context-predicting models (e.g., neu- ral network language models) or spectral methods (e.g., canonical correlation analysis) in an unsu- pervised setting.</p><p>Compared with the so-called one-hot represen- tation where each word is represented as a sparse vector of the same size of the vocabulary and only one dimension is on, word embedding preserves rich linguistic regularities of words with each di- mension hopefully representing a latent feature. Similar words are expected to be distributed close to one another in the embedding space. Conse- quently, word embeddings can be beneficial for a variety of NLP applications in different ways, among which the most simple and general way is to be fed as features to enhance existing supervised NLP systems.</p><p>Previous work has demonstrated effectiveness of the continuous word embedding features in sev- eral tasks such as chunking and NER using gener- alized linear models ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Turian et al., 2010)</ref>. <ref type="bibr">1</ref> How- ever, there still remain two fundamental problems that should be addressed:</p><p>• Are the continuous embedding features fit for the generalized linear models that are most widely adopted in NLP?</p><p>• How can the generalized linear models better utilize the embedding features?</p><p>According to the results provided by <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Turian et al. (2010)</ref>, the embedding features brought signif- icantly less improvement than Brown clustering features. This result is actually not reasonable be- cause the expressing power of word embeddings is theoretically stronger than clustering-based rep- resentations which can be regarded as a kind of one-hot representation but over a low-dimensional vocabulary ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Bengio et al., 2013)</ref>. <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">Wang and Manning (2013)</ref> showed that linear architectures perform better in high-dimensional discrete feature space than non-linear ones, whereas non-linear architectures are more effec- tive in low-dimensional and continuous feature space. Hence, the previous method that directly uses the continuous word embeddings as features in linear models (CRF) is inappropriate. Word embeddings may be better utilized in the linear modeling framework by smartly transforming the embeddings to some relatively higher dimensional and discrete representations.</p><p>Driven by this motivation, we present three different approaches: binarization (Section 3.2), clustering (Section 3.3) and a new proposed distri- butional prototype method (Section 3.4) for better incorporating the embeddings features. In the bi- narization approach, we directly binarize the con- tinuous word embeddings by dimension. In the clustering approach, we cluster words based on their embeddings and use the resulting word clus- ter features instead. In the distributional prototype approach, we derive task-specific features from word embeddings by utilizing a set of automati- cally extracted prototypes for each target label.</p><p>We carefully compare and analyze these ap- proaches in the task of NER. Experimental results are promising. With each of the three approaches, we achieve higher performance than directly using the continuous embedding features, among which the distributional prototype approach performs the best. Furthermore, by putting the most effective two of these features together, we finally outper- form the continuous embedding features by nearly 2 points of F1 Score (86.21% vs. 88.11%).</p><p>The major contribution of this paper is twofold.</p><p>(1) We investigate various approaches that can bet- ter utilize word embeddings for semi-supervised learning. (2) We propose a novel distributional prototype approach that shows the great potential of word embedding features. All the presented ap- proaches can be easily integrated into most of the classical linear NLP models.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Semi-supervised Learning with Word Embeddings</head><p>Statistical modeling has achieved great success in most NLP tasks. However, there still remain some major unsolved problems and challenges, among which the most widely concerned is the data sparsity problem. Data sparsity in NLP is mainly caused by two factors, namely, the lack of labeled training data and the Zipf distribution of words. On the one hand, large-scale labeled training data are typically difficult to obtain, espe- cially for structure prediction tasks, such as syn- tactic parsing. Therefore, the supervised mod- els can only see limited examples and thus make biased estimation. On the other hand, the nat- ural language words are Zipf distributed, which means that most of the words appear a few times or are completely absent in our texts. For these low-frequency words, the corresponding parame- ters usually cannot be fully trained.</p><p>More foundationally, the reason for the above factors lies in the high-dimensional and sparse lex- ical feature representation, which completely ig- nores the similarity between features, especially word features. To overcome this weakness, an ef- fective way is to learn more generalized represen- tations of words by exploiting the numerous un- labeled data, in a semi-supervised manner. After which, the generalized word representations can be used as extra features to facilitate the super- vised systems. <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Liang (2005)</ref> learned Brown clusters of words ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Brown et al., 1992</ref>) from unlabeled data and use them as features to promote the supervised NER and Chinese word segmentation. Brown clusters of words can be seen as a generalized word representation distributed in a discrete and low-dimensional vocabulary space. Contextually similar words are grouped in the same cluster. The Brown clustering of words was also adopted in de- pendency parsing ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Koo et al., 2008)</ref> and POS tag- ging for online conversational text ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Owoputi et al., 2013)</ref>, demonstrating significant improvements.</p><p>Recently, another kind of word representation named "word embeddings" has been widely stud- ied ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Bengio et al., 2003;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b19">Mnih and Hinton, 2008)</ref>. Using word embeddings, we can evaluate the sim- ilarity of two words straightforward by comput- ing the dot-product of two numerical vectors in the Hilbert space. Two similar words are expected to be distributed close to each other. <ref type="bibr">2</ref> Word embeddings can be useful as input to an NLP model (mostly non-linear) or as additional features to enhance existing systems. <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Collobert et al. (2011)</ref> used word embeddings as input to a deep neural network for multi-task learning. De- spite of the effectiveness, such non-linear models are hard to build and optimize. Besides, these ar- chitectures are often specialized for a certain task and not scalable to general tasks. A simple and more general way is to feed word embeddings as augmented features to an existing supervised sys- tem, which is similar to the semi-supervised learn- ing with Brown clusters.</p><p>As discussed in Section 1, <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Turian et al. (2010)</ref> is the pioneering work on using word embedding features for semi-supervised learning. However, their approach cannot fully exploit the potential of word embeddings. We revisit this problem in this study and investigate three different ap- proaches for better utilizing word embeddings in semi-supervised learning.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Approaches for Utilizing Embedding Features</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Word Embedding Training</head><p>In this paper, we will consider a context- predicting model, more specifically, the Skip-gram model ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Mikolov et al., 2013a;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Mikolov et al., 2013b</ref>) for learning word embeddings, since it is much more efficient as well as memory-saving than other approaches. Let's denote the embedding matrix to be learned by C d×N , where N is the vocabulary size and d is the dimension of word embeddings. Each column of C represents the embedding of a word. The Skip-gram model takes the current word w as in- put, and predicts the probability distribution of its context words within a fixed window size. Con- cretely, w is first mapped to its embedding v w by selecting the corresponding column vector of C (or multiplying C with the one-hot vector of w). The probability of its context word c is then com- puted using a log-linear function:</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">P (c|w; θ) = exp(v c v w ) c ∈V exp(v c v w ) (1)</formula><p>where V is the vocabulary. The parameters θ are v w i , v c i for w, c ∈ V and i = 1, ..., d. Then, the log-likelihood over the entire training dataset D can be computed as:</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">J(θ) = (w,c)∈D log p(c|w; θ)<label>(2)</label></formula><p>The model can be trained by maximizing J(θ).</p><p>Here, we suppose that the word embeddings have already been trained from large-scale unla- beled texts. We will introduce various approaches for utilizing the word embeddings as features for semi-supervised learning. The main idea, as in- troduced in Section 1, is to transform the continu- ous word embeddings to some relatively higher di- mensional and discrete representations. The direct use of continuous embeddings as features ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Turian et al., 2010</ref>) will serve as our baseline setting.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Binarization of Embeddings</head><p>One fairly natural approach for converting the continuous-valued word embeddings to discrete values is binarization by dimension.</p><p>Formally, we aim to convert the continuous- valued embedding matrix C d×N , to another matrix M d×N which is discrete-valued. There are various conversion functions. Here, we consider a sim- ple one. For the i th dimension of the word em- beddings, we divide the corresponding row vector C i into two halves for positive (C i+ ) and nega- tive (C i− ), respectively. The conversion function is then defined as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">M ij = φ(C ij ) =      U + , if C ij ≥ mean(C i+ ) B − , if C ij ≤ mean(C i− ) 0, otherwise</formula><p>where mean(v) is the mean value of vector v, U + is a string feature which turns on when the value (C ij ) falls into the upper part of the positive list. Similarly, B − refers to the bottom part of the neg- ative list. The insight behind φ is that we only con- sider the features with strong opinions (i.e., posi- tive or negative) on each dimension and omit the values close to zero.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3">Clustering of Embeddings</head><p>Yu et al. (2013) introduced clustering embeddings to overcome the disadvantage that word embed- dings are not suitable for linear models. They sug- gested that the high-dimensional cluster features make samples from different classes better sepa- rated by linear models.</p><p>In this study, we again investigate this ap- proach. Concretely, each word is treated as a sin- gle sample. The batch k-means clustering algo- rithm <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">(Sculley, 2010</ref>) is used, <ref type="bibr">3</ref> and each cluster is represented as the mean of the embeddings of words assigned to it. Similarities between words and clusters are measured by Euclidean distance.</p><p>Moreover, different number of clusters n con- tain information of different granularities. There- fore, we combine the cluster features of different ns to better utilize the embeddings.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.4">Distributional Prototype Features</head><p>We propose a novel kind of embedding features, named distributional prototype features for su- pervised models. This is mainly inspired by prototype-driven learning <ref type="bibr">(Haghighi and Klein, 2006</ref>) which was originally introduced as a pri- marily unsupervised approach for sequence mod- eling. In prototype-driven learning, a few pro- totypical examples are specified for each target label, which can be treated as an injection of prior knowledge. This sparse prototype informa- tion is then propagated across an unlabeled corpus through distributional similarities.</p><p>The basic motivation of the distributional pro- totype features is that similar words are supposed to be tagged with the same label. This hypothesis makes great sense in tasks such as NER and POS tagging. For example, suppose Michael is a pro- totype of the named entity (NE) type PER. Using the distributional similarity, we could link similar words to the same prototypes, so the word David can be linked to Michael because the two words have high similarity (exceeds a threshold). Using this link feature, the model will push David closer to PER.</p><p>To derive the distributional prototype features, first, we need to construct a few canonical exam- ples (prototypes) for each target annotation label. We use the normalized pointwise mutual informa- tion (NPMI) <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Bouma, 2009)</ref> between the label and word, which is a smoothing version of the standard PMI, to decide the prototypes of each label. Given the annotated training corpus, the NPMI between a label and word is computed as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">λ n (label, word) = λ(label, word) − ln p(label, word)<label>(3)</label></formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>NE Type Prototypes B-PER Mark, Michael, David, Paul I-PER Akram, Ahmed, Khan, Younis B-ORG</head><p>Reuters, U.N., Ajax, PSV I-ORG Newsroom, Inc, Corp, Party B-LOC U.S., Germany, Britain, Australia I-LOC States, Republic, Africa, Lanka B-MISC Russian, German, French, British I-MISC Cup, Open, League, OPEN O ., ,, the, to where,</p><formula xml:id="formula_4">λ(label, word) = ln p(label, word) p(label)p(word)<label>(4)</label></formula><p>is the standard PMI.</p><p>For each target label l (e.g., PER, ORG, LOC), we compute the NPMI of l and all words in the vocabulary, and the top m words are chosen as the prototypes of l. We should note that the proto- types are extracted fully automatically, without in- troducing additional human prior knowledge. <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table 1</ref> shows the top four prototypes extracted from the NER training corpus of CoNLL-2003 shared task <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">(Tjong Kim Sang and De Meulder, 2003)</ref>, which contains four NE types, namely, PER, ORG, LOC, and MISC. Non-NEs are denoted by O. We convert the original annotation to the standard BIO-style. Thus, the final corpus con- tains nine labels in total.</p><p>Next, we introduce the prototypes as features to our supervised model. We denote the set of pro- totypes for all target labels by S p . For each proto- type z ∈ S p , we add a predicate proto = z, which becomes active at each w if the distributional sim- ilarity between z and w (DistSim(z, w)) is above some threshold. DistSim(z, w) can be efficiently calculated through the cosine similarity of the em- beddings of z and w. <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref> gives an illustra- tion of the distributional prototype features. Un- like previous embedding features or Brown clus- ters, the distributional prototype features are task- specific because the prototypes of each label are extracted from the training data.</p><p>Moreover, each prototype word is also its own prototype (since a word has maximum similarity to itself). Thus, if the prototype is closely related to a label, all the words that are distributionally</p><formula xml:id="formula_5">i -1 x i x 1  i y i y O B-LOC in /IN Hague /NNP O B-LOC 1 ( , )    i i f y y ( , ) word = Hague pos = NNP proto = Britain B-LOC proto = England ...                     i i f x y</formula><p>Figure 1: An example of distributional prototype features for NER. similar to that prototype are pushed towards that label.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Supervised Evaluation Task</head><p>Various tasks can be considered to compare and analyze the effectiveness of the above three ap- proaches. In this study, we partly follow Turian et al. <ref type="formula" target="#formula_1">(2010)</ref> and , and take NER as the supervised evaluation task. NER identifies and classifies the named entities such as the names of persons, locations, and orga- nizations in text. The state-of-the-art systems typ- ically treat NER as a sequence labeling problem, where each word is tagged either as a BIO-style NE or a non-NE category.</p><p>Here, we use the linear chain CRF model, which is most widely used for sequence modeling in the field of NLP. The CoNLL-2003 shared task dataset from the Reuters, which was used by <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Turian et al. (2010)</ref> and , was chosen as our evaluation dataset. The training set contains 14,987 sentences, the development set contains 3,466 sentences and is used for parameter tuning, and the test set contains 3,684 sentences.</p><p>The baseline features are shown in <ref type="table">Table 2</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">Embedding Feature Templates</head><p>In this section, we introduce the embedding fea- tures to the baseline NER system, turning the su- pervised approach into a semi-supervised one. Dense embedding features. The dense con- tinuous embedding features can be fed directly to the CRF model. These embedding features can be seen as heterogeneous features from the exist- ing baseline features, which are discrete. There is no effective way for dense embedding features to be combined internally or with other discrete fea- tures. So we only use the unigram embedding fea- tures following <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Turian et al. (2010)</ref>. Concretely, the embedding feature template is:</p><p>Baseline NER Feature Templates 00: <ref type="table">Table 2</ref>: Features used in the NER system. t is the POS tag. chk is the chunking tag. Prefix and Suffix are the first and last l characters of a word. Type indicates if the word is all-capitalized, is-capitalized, all-digits, etc.</p><formula xml:id="formula_6">w i+k , −2 ≤ k ≤ 2 01: w i+k • w i+k+1 , −2 ≤ k ≤ 1 02: t i+k , −2 ≤ k ≤ 2 03: t i+k • t i+k+1 , −2 ≤ k ≤ 1 04: chk i+k , −2 ≤ k ≤ 2</formula><note type="other">05: chk i+k • chk i+k+1 , −2 ≤ k ≤ 1 06: Prefix (w i+k , l), −2 ≤ k ≤ 2, 1 ≤ l ≤ 4 07: Suffix (w i+k , l), −2 ≤ k ≤ 2, 1 ≤ l ≤ 4 08: Type(w i+k ), −2 ≤ k ≤ 2 Unigram Features y i • 00 − 08 Bigram Features y i−1 • y i</note><formula xml:id="formula_7">• de i+k [d], −2 ≤ k ≤ 2, d</formula><p>ranges over the dimensions of the dense word embedding de.</p><p>Binarized embedding features. The binarized embedding feature template is similar to the dense one. The only difference is that the feature val- ues are discrete and we omit dimensions with zero value. Therefore, the feature template becomes:</p><formula xml:id="formula_8">• bi i+k [d], −2 ≤ k ≤ 2, where bi i+k [d] = 0,</formula><p>d ranges over the dimensions of the binarized vector bi of word embedding.</p><p>In this way, the dimension of the binarized em- bedding feature space becomes 2 × d compared with the originally d of the dense embeddings.</p><p>Compound cluster features. The advantage of the cluster features is that they can be combined internally or with other features to form compound features, which can be more discriminative. Fur- thermore, the number of resulting clusters n can be tuned, and different ns indicate different granu- larities. Concretely, the compound cluster feature template for each specific n is:</p><formula xml:id="formula_9">• c i+k , −2 ≤ k ≤ 2.</formula><p>• c i+k • c i+k+1 , −2 ≤ k ≤ 1.</p><formula xml:id="formula_10">• c i−1 • c i+1 .</formula><p>Distributional prototype features. The set of prototypes is again denoted by S p , which is de-cided by selecting the top m (NPMI) words as pro- totypes of each label, where m is tuned on the de- velopment set. For each word w i in a sequence, we compute the distributional similarity between w i and each prototype in S p and select the proto- types zs that DistSim(z, w) ≥ δ. We set δ = 0.5 without manual tuning. The distributional proto- type feature template is then:</p><formula xml:id="formula_11">• {proto i+k =z | DistSim(w i+k , z) ≥ δ &amp; z ∈ S p }, −2 ≤ k ≤ 2 .</formula><p>We only use the unigram features, since the number of active distributional prototype features varies for different words (positions). Hence, these features cannot be combined effectively.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">Brown Clustering</head><p>Brown clustering has achieved great success in various NLP applications. At most time, it provides a strong baseline that is difficult to beat <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">(Turian et al., 2010)</ref>. Consequently, in our study, we conduct comparisons among the embed- ding features and the Brown clustering features, along with further investigations of their combina- tion.</p><p>The Brown algorithm is a hierarchical cluster- ing algorithm which optimizes a class-based bi- gram language model defined on the word clus- ters ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Brown et al., 1992)</ref>. The output of the Brown algorithm is a binary tree, where each word is uniquely identified by its path from the root. Thus each word can be represented as a bit-string with a specific length.</p><p>Following the setting of <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Owoputi et al. (2013)</ref>, we will use the prefix features of hierarchical clus- ters to take advantage of the word similarity in dif- ferent granularities. Concretely, the Brown cluster feature template is:</p><formula xml:id="formula_12">• bc i+k , −2 ≤ k ≤ 2.</formula><p>• prefix (bc i+k , p), p ∈ {2,4,6,...,16}, −2 ≤ k ≤ 2. prefix takes the p-length prefix of the Brown cluster coding bc i+k .</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Experiments</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.1">Experimental Setting</head><p>We take the English Wikipedia until August 2012 as our unlabeled data to train the word embed- dings. <ref type="bibr">4</ref> Little pre-processing is conducted for the training of word embeddings. We remove para- graphs that contain non-roman characters and all MediaWiki markups. The resulting text is tok- enized using the Stanford tokenizer, <ref type="bibr">5</ref> and every word is converted to lowercase. The final dataset contains about 30 million sentences and 1.52 bil- lion words. We use a dictionary that contains 212,779 most common words (frequency ≥ 80) in the dataset. An efficient open-source implementa- tion of the Skip-gram model is adopted. <ref type="bibr">6</ref> We ap- ply the negative sampling 7 method for optimiza- tion, and the asynchronous stochastic gradient de- scent algorithm (Asynchronous SGD) for parallel weight updating. In this study, we set the dimen- sion of the word embeddings to 50. Higher di- mension is supposed to bring more improvements in semi-supervised learning, but its comparison is beyond the scope of this paper.</p><p>For the cluster features, we tune the number of clusters n from 500 to 3000 on the develop- ment set, and finally use the combination of n = 500, 1000, 1500, 2000, 3000, which achieves the best results. For the distributional prototype fea- tures, we use a fixed number of prototype words (m) for each target label. m is tuned on the devel- opment set and is finally set to 40.</p><p>We induce 1,000 brown clusters of words, the setting in prior work ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Koo et al., 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Turian et al., 2010)</ref>. The training data of brown clustering is the same with that of training word embeddings. <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">Table 3</ref> shows the performances of NER on the test dataset. Our baseline is slightly lower than that of <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Turian et al. (2010)</ref>, because they use the BILOU encoding of NE types which outper- forms BIO encoding <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">(Ratinov and Roth, 2009</ref>). 8 Nonetheless, our conclusions hold. As we can see, all of the three approaches we investigate in this study achieve better performance than the direct use of the dense continuous embedding features.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.2">Results</head><p>To our surprise, even the binarized embedding features (BinarizedEmb) outperform the continu- ous version (DenseEmb). This provides clear evi- dence that directly using the dense continuous em- beddings as features in CRF indeed cannot fully   <ref type="formula" target="#formula_1">(2005)</ref> 86.86 <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Krishnan and Manning (2006)</ref> 87.24 Ando and <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Zhang (2005)</ref> 89.31 Collobert et al. <ref type="formula" target="#formula_1">(2011)</ref> 88.67 exploit the potential of word embeddings. The compound cluster features (ClusterEmb) also out- perform the DenseEmb. The same result is also shown in ( . Further, the distribu- tional prototype features (DistPrototype) achieve the best performance among the three approaches (1.23% higher than DenseEmb).</p><p>We should note that the feature templates used for BinarizedEmb and DistPrototype are merely unigram features. However, for ClusterEmb, we form more complex features by combining the clusters of the context words. We also consider different number of clusters n, to take advantage of the different granularities. Consequently, the dimension of the cluster features is much higher than that of BinarizedEmb and DistPrototype.</p><p>We further combine the proposed features to see if they are complementary to each other. As shown in <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">Table 3</ref>, the cluster and distributional prototype features are the most complementary, whereas the binarized embedding features seem to have large overlap with the distributional prototype features. By combining the cluster and distributional pro- totype features, we further push the performance to 88.11%, which is nearly two points higher than the performance of the dense embedding features (86.21%). <ref type="bibr">9</ref> We also compare the proposed features with the Brown cluster features. As shown in <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">Table 3</ref>, the distributional prototype features alone achieve comparable performance with the Brown clusters. When the cluster and distributional prototype fea- tures are used together, we outperform the Brown clusters. This result is inspiring because we show that the embedding features indeed have stronger expressing power than the Brown clusters, as de- sired. Finally, by combining the Brown cluster features and the proposed embedding features, the performance can be improved further (88.58%). The binarized embedding features are not included in the final compound features because they are al- most overlapped with the distributional prototype features in performance.</p><p>We also summarize some of the reported benchmarks that utilize unlabeled data (with no gazetteers used), including the Stanford NER tag- ger ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Finkel et al. (2005)</ref> and <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Krishnan and Manning (2006)</ref>) with distributional similarity fea- tures. <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Ando and Zhang (2005)</ref> use unlabeled data for constructing auxiliary problems that are ex- pected to capture a good feature representation of the target problem. <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Collobert et al. (2011)</ref> adjust the feature embeddings according to the specific task in a deep neural network architecture. We can see that both Ando and <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Zhang (2005)</ref> and Col- lobert et al. (2011) learn task-specific lexical fea- tures, which is similar to the proposed distribu- tional prototype method in our study. We suggest this to be the main reason for the superiority of these methods.</p><p>Another advantage of the proposed discrete fea- tures over the dense continuous features is tag- ging efficiency. <ref type="table">Table 4</ref> shows the running time using different kinds of embedding features. We achieve a significant reduction of the tagging time per sentence when using the discrete features. This is mainly due to the dense/sparse battle. Al- though the dense embedding features are low- dimensional, the feature vector for each word is much denser than in the sparse and discrete feature space. Therefore, we actually need much more computation during decoding. Similar results can be observed in the comparison of the DistProto- type and ClusterEmb features, since the density of the DistPrototype features is higher. It is possible  <ref type="table">Table 4</ref>: Running time of different features on a Intel(R) Xeon(R) E5620 2.40GHz machine.</p><p>to accelerate the DistPrototype, by increasing the threshold of DistSim(z, w). However, this is in- deed an issue of trade-off between efficiency and accuracy.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.3">Analysis</head><p>In this section, we conduct analyses to show the reasons for the improvements.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.3.1">Rare words</head><p>As discussed by <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Turian et al. (2010)</ref>, much of the NER F1 is derived from decisions regarding rare words. Therefore, in order to show that the three proposed embedding features have stronger abil- ity for handling rare words, we first conduct anal- ysis for the tagging errors of words with differ- ent frequency in the unlabeled data. We assign the word frequencies to several buckets, and evaluate the per-token errors that occurred in each bucket. Results are shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 2</ref>. In most cases, all three embedding features result in fewer errors on rare words than the direct use of dense continuous embedding features. Interestingly, we find that for words that are extremely rare (0-256), the binarized embedding features incur significantly fewer errors than other approaches. As we know, the embeddings for the rare words are close to their initial value, because they received few updates during training. Hence, these words are not fully trained. In this case, we would like to omit these features because their embeddings are not even trustable. However, all embedding features that we proposed except Bi- narizedEmb are unable to handle this.</p><p>In order to see how much we have utilized the embedding features in BinarizedEmb, we cal- culate the sparsity of the binarized embedding vectors, i.e., the ratio of zero values in each vector (Section 3.2). As demonstrated in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Fig- ure 3</ref>, the sparsity-frequency curve has good prop- erties: higher sparsity for very rare words and very frequent words, while lower sparsity for mid- frequent words. It indicates that for words that are very rare or very frequent, BinarizedEmb just omit most of the features. This is reasonable also for the very frequent words, since they usually have rich and diverse context distributions and their embeddings cannot be well learned by our mod- els ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Huang et al., 2012)</ref>.  As expected, the distributional prototype fea- tures produce fewest errors in most cases. The main reason is that the prototype features are task- specific. The prototypes are extracted from the training data and contained indicative information of the target labels. By contrast, the other em- bedding features are simply derived from general word representations and are not specialized for certain tasks, such as NER.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.3.2">Linear Separability</head><p>Another reason for the superiority of the proposed embedding features is that the high-dimensional discrete features are more linear separable than the low-dimensional continuous embeddings. To verify the hypothesis, we further carry out experi- ments to analyze the linear separability of the pro- posed discrete embedding features against dense continuous embeddings.</p><p>We formalize this problem as a binary classi- fication task, to determine whether a word is an NE or not (NE identification). The linear support vector machine (SVM) is used to build the clas- sifiers, using different embedding features respec-  tively. We use the LIBLINEAR tool <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(Fan et al., 2008)</ref> as our SVM implementation. The penalty parameter C is tuned from 0.1 to 1.0 on the devel- opment dataset. The results are shown in <ref type="table" target="#tab_5">Table 5</ref>.</p><p>As we can see, NEs and non-NEs can be better separated using ClusterEmb or DistPrototype fea- tures. However, the BinarizedEmb features per- form worse than the direct use of word embedding features. The reason might be inferred from the third column of <ref type="table" target="#tab_5">Table 5</ref>. As demonstrated in <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">Wang and Manning (2013)</ref>, linear models are more ef- fective in high-dimensional and discrete feature space. The dimension of the BinarizedEmb fea- tures remains small (500), which is merely twice the DenseEmb. By contrast, feature dimensions are much higher for ClusterEmb and DistProto- type, leading to better linear separability and thus can be better utilized by linear models. We notice that the DistPrototype features per- form significantly worse than ClusterEmb in NE identification. As described in Section 3.4, in previous experiments, we automatically extracted prototypes for each label, and propagated the in- formation via distributional similarities. Intu- itively, the prototypes we used should be more ef- fective in determining fine-grained NE types than identifying whether a word is an NE. To verify this, we extract new prototypes considering only two labels, namely, NE and non-NE, using the same metric in Section 3.4. As shown in the last row of <ref type="table" target="#tab_5">Table 5</ref>, higher performance is achieved.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Related Studies</head><p>Semi-supervised learning with generalized word representations is a simple and general way of im- proving supervised NLP systems. One common approach for inducing generalized word represen- tations is to use clustering (e.g., Brown clustering) ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">Miller et al., 2004;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Liang, 2005;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Koo et al., 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr">Huang and Yates, 2009)</ref>.</p><p>Aside from word clustering, word embeddings have been widely studied. <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Bengio et al. (2003)</ref> propose a feed-forward neural network based lan- guage model (NNLM), which uses an embedding layer to map each word to a dense continuous- valued and low-dimensional vector (parameters), and then use these vectors as the input to predict the probability distribution of the next word. The NNLM can be seen as a joint learning framework for language modeling and word representations.</p><p>Alternative models for learning word embed- dings are mostly inspired by the feed-forward NNLM, including the Hierarchical Log-Bilinear Model <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">(Mnih and Hinton, 2008)</ref>, the recurrent neural network language model <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">(Mikolov, 2012)</ref>, the C&amp;W model <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Collobert et al., 2011</ref>), the log- linear models such as the CBOW and the Skip-gram model <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">(Mikolov et al., 2013a;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Mikolov et al., 2013b)</ref>.</p><p>Aside from the NNLMs, word embeddings can also be induced using spectral methods, such as latent semantic analysis and canonical correlation analysis <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Dhillon et al., 2011</ref>). The spectral meth- ods are generally faster but much more memory- consuming than NNLMs.</p><p>There has been a plenty of work that exploits word embeddings as features for semi-supervised learning, most of which take the continuous fea- tures directly in linear models ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Turian et al., 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Guo et al., 2014</ref>).  propose com- pound k-means cluster features based on word em- beddings. They show that the high-dimensional discrete cluster features can be better utilized by linear models such as CRF. <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">Wu et al. (2013)</ref> fur- ther apply the cluster features to transition-based dependency parsing.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7">Conclusion and Future Work</head><p>This paper revisits the problem of semi-supervised learning with word embeddings. We present three different approaches for a careful comparison and analysis. Using any of the three embedding fea- tures, we obtain higher performance than the di- rect use of continuous embeddings, among which the distributional prototype features perform the best, showing the great potential of word embed- dings. Moreover, the combination of the proposed embedding features provides significant additive improvements.</p><p>We give detailed analysis about the experimen- tal results. Analysis on rare words and linear sep- arability provides convincing explanations for the performance of the embedding features.</p><p>For future work, we are exploring a novel and a theoretically more sounding approach of introduc- ing embedding kernel into the linear models. <ref type="bibr">Aria Haghighi and Dan Klein. 2006</ref>. Prototype-driven learning for sequence models. In Proceedings of the main conference on Human Language Technol- ogy Conference of the North American Chapter of the Association of Computational Linguistics, pages 320-327. Association for Computational Linguis- tics.</p><p>Fei </p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Figure 3: Sparsity (with confidence interval) of the binarized embedding vector w.r.t. word frequency in the unlabeled data.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 2 (</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2(b) further supports our analysis. BinarizedEmb also reduce much of the errors for the highly frequent words (32k-64k). As expected, the distributional prototype features produce fewest errors in most cases. The main reason is that the prototype features are taskspecific. The prototypes are extracted from the training data and contained indicative information of the target labels. By contrast, the other embedding features are simply derived from general word representations and are not specialized for certain tasks, such as NER.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Huang and Alexander Yates. 2009. Distribu- tional representations for handling sparsity in super- vised sequence-labeling. In Proceedings of the Joint Conference of the 47th Annual Meeting of the ACL and the 4th International Joint Conference on Natu- ral Language Processing of the AFNLP: Volume 1- Volume 1, Proceedings of the Joint Conference of the 47th Annual Meeting of the ACL and the 4th Inter- national Joint Conference on Natural Language Pro- cessing of the AFNLP: Volume 1-Volume 1, pages 495-503.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" validated="false"><head>Table 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Prototypes extracted from the CoNLL-
2003 NER training data using NPMI. 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" validated="false"><head>Table 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>The performance of semi-supervised 
NER on the CoNLL-2003 test data, using vari-
ous embedding features.  † DenseEmb refers to the 
method used by Turian et al. (2010), i.e., the direct 
use of the dense and continuous embeddings. 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_5" validated="false"><head>Table 5 :</head><label>5</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Performance of the NE/non-NE classi-
fication on the CoNLL-2003 development dataset 
using different embedding features. 

</table></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> Generalized linear models refer to the models that describe the data as a combination of linear basis functions, either directly in the input variables space or through some transformation of the probability distributions (e.g., loglinear models).</note>

			<note place="foot" n="2"> The term similar should be viewed depending on the specific task.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="3"> code.google.com/p/sofia-ml</note>

			<note place="foot" n="4"> download.wikimedia.org.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="5"> nlp.stanford.edu/software/tokenizer. shtml. 6 code.google.com/p/word2vec/. 7 More details are analyzed in (Goldberg and Levy, 2014). 8 We use BIO encoding here in order to compare with most of the reported benchmarks.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="9"> Statistical significant with p-value &lt; 0.001 by two-tailed t-test.</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>We are grateful to Mo Yu for the fruitful discus-sion on the implementation of the cluster-based embedding features. We also thank Ruiji Fu, Meishan Zhang, Sendong Zhao and the anony-mous reviewers for their insightful comments and suggestions. This work was supported by the National Key Basic Research Program of China via grant 2014CB340503 and the National Natu-ral Science Foundation of China (NSFC) via grant 61133012 and 61370164.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A highperformance semi-supervised learning method for text chunking</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kubota</forename><surname>Rie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tong</forename><surname>Ando</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 43rd annual meeting on association for computational linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the 43rd annual meeting on association for computational linguistics</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="9" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Association for Computational Linguistics</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A neural probabilistic language model</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yoshua</forename><surname>Bengio</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Jean Ducharme</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Pascal</forename><surname>Vincent</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christian</forename><surname>Janvin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The Journal of Machine Learning Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1137" to="1155" />
			<date type="published" when="2003-02" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Representation learning: A review and new perspectives. Pattern Analysis and Machine Intelligence</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yoshua</forename><surname>Bengio</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Aaron</forename><surname>Courville</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Pascal</forename><surname>Vincent</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE Transactions on</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">35</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1798" to="1828" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Normalized (pointwise) mutual information in collocation extraction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gerlof</forename><surname>Bouma</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of GSCL</title>
		<meeting>GSCL</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="31" to="40" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Class-based n-gram models of natural language</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Peter F Brown</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Peter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Robert</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Desouza</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Vincent J Della</forename><surname>Mercer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jenifer C</forename><surname>Pietra</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Lai</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Computational linguistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">18</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="467" to="479" />
			<date type="published" when="1992" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Natural language processing (almost) from scratch</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ronan</forename><surname>Collobert</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jason</forename><surname>Weston</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>On</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Bottou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Koray</forename><surname>Karlen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Pavel</forename><surname>Kavukcuoglu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Kuksa</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The Journal of Machine Learning Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2493" to="2537" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Multi-view learning of word embeddings via cca</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Paramveer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dean</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Dhillon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lyle</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Foster</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Ungar</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">NIPS</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="199" to="207" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Liblinear: A library for large linear classification</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kai-Wei</forename><surname>Rong-En Fan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Cho-Jui</forename><surname>Chang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xiangrui</forename><surname>Hsieh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chih-Jen</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Lin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The Journal of Machine Learning Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1871" to="1874" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Incorporating non-local information into information extraction systems by gibbs sampling</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jenny</forename><forename type="middle">Rose</forename><surname>Finkel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Trond</forename><surname>Grenager</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christopher</forename><surname>Manning</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 43rd Annual Meeting on Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the 43rd Annual Meeting on Association for Computational Linguistics</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="363" to="370" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Association for Computational Linguistics</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">word2vec explained: deriving mikolov et al.&apos;s negative-sampling word-embedding method</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yoav</forename><surname>Goldberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Omer</forename><surname>Levy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>abs/1402.3722</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<publisher>CoRR</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Learning sense-specific word embeddings by exploiting bilingual resources</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jiang</forename><surname>Guo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wanxiang</forename><surname>Che</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Haifeng</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ting</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of COLING 2014, the 25th International Conference on Computational Linguistics: Technical Papers</title>
		<meeting>COLING 2014, the 25th International Conference on Computational Linguistics: Technical Papers<address><addrLine>Dublin, Ireland</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="497" to="507" />
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>August. Dublin City University and Association for Computational Linguistics</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Improving word representations via global context and multiple word prototypes</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Eric</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Richard</forename><surname>Socher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christopher</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Manning</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Andrew</forename><forename type="middle">Y</forename><surname>Ng</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of the Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL), Proc. of the Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL)</title>
		<meeting>of the Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL), . of the Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL)<address><addrLine>Jeju Island, Korea. ACL</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="873" to="882" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Simple semi-supervised dependency parsing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Terry</forename><surname>Koo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xavier</forename><surname>Carreras</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Collins</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of ACL-08: HLT, Proc. of ACL-08: HLT</title>
		<editor>Kathleen McKeown, Johanna D. Moore, Simone Teufel, James Allan, and Sadaoki Furui</editor>
		<meeting>of ACL-08: HLT, . of ACL-08: HLT<address><addrLine>Columbus, Ohio. ACL</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="595" to="603" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">An effective two-stage model for exploiting nonlocal dependencies in named entity recognition</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Vijay</forename><surname>Krishnan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Christopher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Manning</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 21st International Conference on Computational Linguistics and the 44th annual meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the 21st International Conference on Computational Linguistics and the 44th annual meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1121" to="1128" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Association for Computational Linguistics</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Semi-supervised learning for natural language</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Percy</forename><surname>Liang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>Massachusetts Institute of Technology</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
<note type="report_type">Master thesis</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Efficient estimation of word representations in vector space</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tomas</forename><surname>Mikolov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kai</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Greg</forename><surname>Corrado</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jeffrey</forename><surname>Dean</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of Workshop at ICLR, Proc. of Workshop at ICLR</title>
		<meeting>of Workshop at ICLR, . of Workshop at ICLR<address><addrLine>Arizona</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Distributed representations of words and phrases and their compositionality</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tomas</forename><surname>Mikolov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ilya</forename><surname>Sutskever</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kai</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Greg</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Corrado</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jeff</forename><surname>Dean</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of the NIPS, Proc. of the NIPS</title>
		<meeting>of the NIPS, . of the NIPS<address><addrLine>Nevada</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>MIT Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3111" to="3119" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Statistical Language Models Based on Neural Networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tomas</forename><surname>Mikolov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>Brno University of Technology</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
<note type="report_type">Ph. d. thesis</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Name tagging with word clusters and discriminative training</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Scott</forename><surname>Miller</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jethran</forename><surname>Guinness</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alex</forename><surname>Zamanian</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">HLT-NAACL</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="337" to="342" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A scalable hierarchical distributed language model</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Andriy</forename><surname>Mnih</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Geoffrey</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Hinton</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of the NIPS, Proc. of the NIPS</title>
		<meeting>of the NIPS, . of the NIPS<address><addrLine>Vancouver</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>MIT Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1081" to="1088" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Improved part-of-speech tagging for online conversational text with word clusters</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Olutobi</forename><surname>Owoputi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O&amp;apos;</forename><surname>Brendan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chris</forename><surname>Connor</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kevin</forename><surname>Dyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nathan</forename><surname>Gimpel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Noah A</forename><surname>Schneider</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Smith</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of NAACL-HLT</title>
		<meeting>NAACL-HLT</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="380" to="390" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Design challenges and misconceptions in named entity recognition</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lev</forename><surname>Ratinov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dan</forename><surname>Roth</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Thirteenth Conference on Computational Natural Language Learning, CoNLL &apos;09</title>
		<meeting>the Thirteenth Conference on Computational Natural Language Learning, CoNLL &apos;09<address><addrLine>Stroudsburg, PA, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="147" to="155" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Combined regression and ranking</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Sculley</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 16th ACM SIGKDD international conference on Knowledge discovery and data mining</title>
		<meeting>the 16th ACM SIGKDD international conference on Knowledge discovery and data mining</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="979" to="988" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Introduction to the conll-2003 shared task: Language-independent named entity recognition</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Erik F Tjong Kim</forename><surname>Sang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Fien De</forename><surname>Meulder</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the seventh conference on Natural language learning at HLT-NAACL 2003</title>
		<meeting>the seventh conference on Natural language learning at HLT-NAACL 2003</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="142" to="147" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Association for Computational Linguistics</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Word representations: a simple and general method for semi-supervised learning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Joseph</forename><surname>Turian</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lev</forename><surname>Ratinov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yoshua</forename><surname>Bengio</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of the Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL), Proc. of the Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL)</title>
		<editor>Jan Hajic, Sandra Carberry, and Stephen Clark</editor>
		<meeting>of the Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL), . of the Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL)<address><addrLine>Uppsala, Sweden. ACL</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="384" to="394" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Effect of non-linear deep architecture in sequence labeling</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mengqiu</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Christopher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Manning</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of the Sixth International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing, Proc. of the Sixth International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing</title>
		<meeting>of the Sixth International Joint Conference on Natural Language essing, . of the Sixth International Joint Conference on Natural Language essing<address><addrLine>Nagoya, Japan</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1285" to="1291" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Asian Federation of Natural Language Processing</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Generalization of words for chinese dependency parsing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xianchao</forename><surname>Wu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jie</forename><surname>Zhou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yu</forename><surname>Sun</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Zhanyi</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dianhai</forename><surname>Yu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hua</forename><surname>Wu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Haifeng</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page">73</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>IWPT-2013</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Compound embedding features for semi-supervised learning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mo</forename><surname>Yu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tiejun</forename><surname>Zhao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Daxiang</forename><surname>Dong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hao</forename><surname>Tian</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dianhai</forename><surname>Yu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of the NAACLHLT, Proc. of the NAACL-HLT</title>
		<meeting>of the NAACLHLT, . of the NAACL-HLT</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="563" to="568" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Atlanta. NAACL</note>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
