<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T10:56+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Policy Learning for Domain Selection in an Extensible Multi-domain Spoken Dialogue System</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
				<availability status="unknown"><p>Copyright Association for Computational Linguistics</p>
				</availability>
				<date>October 25-29, 2014. 2014</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Zhuoran</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
							<email>zhuoran.wang@hw.ac.uk</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hongliang</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Guanchun</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hao</forename><surname>Tian</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hua</forename><surname>Wu</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Haifeng</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Mathematical &amp; Computer Sciences Heriot-Watt University Edinburgh</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="GB">UK</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">Baidu Inc</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Beijing</settlement>
									<country key="CN">P. R. China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Policy Learning for Domain Selection in an Extensible Multi-domain Spoken Dialogue System</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2014 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP)</title>
						<meeting>the 2014 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP) <address><addrLine>Doha, Qatar. c</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="57" to="67"/>
							<date type="published">October 25-29, 2014. 2014</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>This paper proposes a Markov Decision Process and reinforcement learning based approach for domain selection in a multi-domain Spoken Dialogue System built on a distributed architecture. In the proposed framework, the domain selection problem is treated as sequential planning instead of classification, such that confirmation and clarification interaction mechanisms are supported. In addition, it is shown that by using a model parameter tying trick, the extensibility of the system can be preserved, where dialogue components in new domains can be easily plugged in, without retraining the domain selection policy. The experimental results based on human subjects suggest that the proposed model marginally outperforms a non-trivial baseline.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Due to growing demand for natural human- machine interaction, over the last decade Spo- ken Dialogue Systems (SDS) have been increas- ingly deployed in various commercial applications ranging from traditional call centre automation (e.g. AT&amp;T "Lets Go!" bus information sys- tem ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">Williams et al., 2010)</ref>) to mobile personal assistants and knowledge navigators (e.g. Ap- ple's Siri R , Google Now TM , Microsoft Cortana, etc.) or voice interaction for smart household ap- pliance control (e.g. Samsung Evolution Kit for Smart TVs). Furthermore, latest progress in open- vocabulary Automatic Speech Recognition (ASR) is pushing SDS from traditional single-domain in- formation systems towards more complex multi- domain speech applications, of which typical ex- amples are those voice assistant mobile applica- tions.</p><p>Recent advances in SDS have shown that sta- tistical approaches to dialogue management can result in marginal improvement in both the nat- uralness and the task success rate for domain- specific dialogues ( <ref type="bibr">Lemon and Pietquin, 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b35">Young et al., 2013)</ref>. State-of-the-art statistical SDS treat the dialogue problem as a sequential decision making process, and employ established planning models, such as Markov Decision Pro- cesses (MDPs) ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">Singh et al., 2002</ref>) or Partially Ob- servable Markov Decision Processes (POMDPs) <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">Williams and Young, 2007)</ref>, in conjunction with reinforcement learning techniques <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">(Jurčíček et al., 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b19">Jurčíček et al., 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Gaši´Gaši´c et al., 2013a)</ref> to seek optimal dialogue policies that maximise long-term expected (discounted) rewards and are robust to ASR errors.</p><p>However, to the best of our knowledge, most of the existing multi-domain SDS in public use are rule-based (e.g. ( <ref type="bibr">Gruber et al., 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Mirkovic and Cavedon, 2006)</ref>). The application of statistical models in multi-domain dialogue systems is still preliminary. <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">Komatani et al. (2006)</ref> and <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">Nakano et al. (2011)</ref> utilised a distributed architecture ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">Lin et al., 1999</ref>) to integrate expert dialogue systems in different domains into a unified framework, where a central controller trained as a data-driven clas- sifier selects a domain expert at each turn to ad- dress user's query. Alternatively, <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Hakkani-Tür et al. (2012)</ref> adopted the well-known Information State mechanism <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">(Traum and Larsson, 2003)</ref> to construct a multi-domain SDS and proposed a dis- criminative classification model for more accurate state updates. More recently, Gaši´ <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Gaši´c et al. (2013b)</ref> proposed that by a simple expansion of the kernel function in Gaussian Process (GP) reinforcement learning ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Engel et al., 2005;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Gaši´Gaši´c et al., 2013a</ref>), one can adapt pre-trained dialogue policies to han- dle unseen slots for SDS in extended domains.</p><p>In this paper, we use a voice assistant applica-  tion (similar to Apple's Siri but in Chinese lan- guage) as an example to demonstrate a novel MDP-based approach for central interaction man- agement in a complex multi-domain dialogue sys- tem. The voice assistant employs a distributed ar- chitecture similar to ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">Lin et al., 1999;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b21">Komatani et al., 2006;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b25">Nakano et al., 2011)</ref>, and handles mixed interactions of multi-turn dialogues across differ- ent domains and single-turn queries powered by a collection of information access services (such as web search, Question Answering (QA), etc.). In our system, the dialogues in each domain are managed by an individual domain expert SDS, and the single-turn services are used to handle those so-called out-of-domain requests. We use fea- turised representations to summarise the current dialogue states in each domain (see Section 3 for more details), and let the central controller (the MDP model) choose one of the following system actions at each turn: (1) addressing user's query based on a domain expert, (2) treating it as an out-of-domain request, (3) asking user to confirm whether he/she wants to continue a domain ex- pert's dialogue or to switch to out-of-domain ser- vices, and (4) clarifying user's intention between two domains. The Gaussian Process Temporal Difference (GPTD) algorithm ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Engel et al., 2005;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Gaši´Gaši´c et al., 2013a</ref>) is adopted here for policy op- timisation based on human subjects, where a pa- rameter tying trick is applied to preserve the ex- tensibility of the system, such that new domain experts (dialogue systems) can be flexibly plugged in without the need of re-training the central con- troller.</p><p>Comparing to the previous classification-based methods ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">Komatani et al., 2006;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b25">Nakano et al., 2011</ref>), the proposed approach not only has the advantage of action selection in consideration of long-term rewards, it can also yield more robust policies that allow clarifications and confirmations to mitigate ASR and Spoken Language Under- standing (SLU) errors. Our human evaluation re- sults show that the proposed system with a trained MDP policy achieves significantly better natural- ness in domain switching tasks than a non-trivial baseline with a hand-crafted policy.</p><p>The remainder of this paper is organised as follows. Section 2 defines the terminology used throughout the paper. Section 3 briefly overviews the distributed architecture of our system. The MDP model and the policy optimisation algorithm are introduced in Section 4 and Section 5, respec- tively. After this, experimental settings and eval- uation results are described in Section 6. Finally, we discuss some possible improvements in Sec- tion 7 and conclude ourselves in Section 8.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Terminology</head><p>A voice assistant application provides a unified speech interface to a collection of individual infor- mation access systems. It aims to collect and sat- isfy user requests in an interactive manner, where different types of interactions can be involved. Here we focus ourselves on two interaction scenar- ios, i.e. task-oriented (multi-turn) dialogues and single-turn queries.</p><p>According to user intentions, the dialogue inter- actions in our voice assistant system can further be categorised into different domains, of which each is handled by a separate dialogue manager, namely a domain expert. Example domains include travel information, restaurant search, etc. In addition, some domains in our system can be further de- composed into sub-domains, e.g. the travel in- formation domain consists of three sub-domains: flight ticket booking, train ticket booking and hotel reservation. We use an integrated domain expert to address queries in all its sub-domains, so that rel- evant information can be shared across those sub- domains to allow intelligent induction in the dia- logue flow.</p><p>For convenience of future reference, we call those single-turn information access systems out- of-domain services or simply services for short. The services integrated in our system include web search, semantic search, QA, system command ex- ecution, weather report, chat-bot, and many more.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">System Architecture</head><p>The voice assistant system introduced in this pa- per is built on a distributed architecture ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">Lin et al., 1999</ref>), as shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref>, where the dialogue flow is processed as follows. Firstly, a user's query (either an ASR utterance or directly typed in text) is passed to a user intention identifier, which la- bels the raw query with a list of intention hypothe- ses with confidence scores. Here an intention label could be either a domain name or a service name. After this, the central controller distributes the raw query together with its intention labels and confi- dence scores to all the domain experts and the ser- vice modules, which will attempt to process the query and return their results to the central con- troller.</p><p>The domain experts in the current implementa- tion of our system are all rule-based SDS follow- ing the RavenClaw framework proposed in <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Bohus and Rudnicky, 2009)</ref>. When receiving a query, a domain expert will use its own SLU module to parse the utterance or text input and try to update its dialogue state in consideration of both the SLU output and the intention labels. If the dialogue state in the domain expert can be updated given the query, it will return its output, internal ses- sion record and a confidence score to the central controller, where the output can be either a natu- ral language utterance realised by its Natural Lan- guage Generation (NLG) module or a set of data records obtained from its database (if a database search operation is triggered), or both. If the do- main expert cannot update its state using the cur- rent query, it will just return an empty result with a low confidence score. Similar procedures ap- ply to those out-of-domain services as well, but there are no session records or confidence scores returned. Finally, given all the returned informa- tion, the central controller chooses, according to its policy, the module (either a domain expert or a service) whose results will be provided to the user.</p><p>When the central controller decides to pass a domain expert's output to the user, we regard the domain expert as being activated. Also note here, the updated state of a domain expert in a turn will not be physically stored, unless the domain expert is activated in that turn. This is a necessary mech- anism to prevent an inactive domain expert being misled by ambiguous queries in other domains.</p><p>In addition, we use a well-engineered priority ranker to rank the services based on the num- bers of results they returned as well as some prior knowledge about the quality of their data sources. When the central controller decides to show user the results from an out-of-domain service, it will choose the top one from the ranked list.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">MDP Modelling of the Central Control Process</head><p>The main focus of this paper is to seek a policy for robustly switching the control flow among those domain experts and services (the service ranker in practice) during a dialogue, where the user may have multiple or compound goals (e.g. booking a flight ticket, booking a restaurant in the destina- tion city and checking the weather report of the departure or destination city). In order to make the system robust to ASR er- rors or ambiguous queries, the central controller should also have basic dialogue abilities for confir- mation and clarification purposes. Here we define the confirmation as an action of asking whether a user wants to continue the dialogue in a certain do- main. If the system receives a negative response at this point, it will switch to out-of-domain services. On the other hand, the clarification action is de-fined between domains, in which case, the system will explicitly ask the user to choose between two domain candidates before continuing the dialogue.</p><p>Due to the confirmation and clarification mech- anisms defined above, the central controller be- comes a sequential decision maker that must take the overall smoothness of the dialogue into ac- count. Therefore, we propose an MDP-based ap- proach for learning an optimal central control pol- icy in this section.</p><p>The potential state space of our MDP is huge, which in principle consists of the combinations of all possible situations of the domain experts and the out-of-domain services, therefore function ap- proximation techniques must be employed to en- able tractable computations. However, when de- veloping such a complex application as the voice assistant here, one also needs to take the extensi- bility of the system into account, so that new do- main experts can be easily integrated into the sys- tem without major re-training or re-engineering of the existing components. Essentially, it requires the state featurisation and the central control pol- icy learnt here to be independent of the number of domain experts. In Section 4.3, we show that such a property can be achieved by a parameter tying trick in the definition of the MDP.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">MDP Preliminaries</head><p>Let P X denote the set of probability distributions over a set X. An MDP is defined as a five tuple S, A, T, R, γ, where the components are defined as follows. S and A are the sets of system states and actions, respectively. T : S × A → P S is the transition function, and T (s |s, a) defines the con- ditional probability of the system transiting from state s ∈ S to state s ∈ S after taking action a ∈ A. R : S × A → P R is the reward function with R(s, a) specifying the distribution of the im- mediate rewards for the system taking action a at state s. In addition, 0 ≤ γ ≤ 1 is the discount factor on the summed sequence of rewards.</p><p>A finite-horizon MDP operates as follows. The system occupies a state s and takes an action a, which then will make it transit to a next state s ∼ T (·|s, a) and receive a reward r ∼ R(s, a). This process repeats until a terminal state is reached.</p><p>For a given policy π : S → A, the value function V π is defined to be the expected cumula- tive reward, as V π (s 0 ) = E n t=0 γ t r t | st,π(st) , where s 0 is the starting state and n is the plan- ning horizon. The aim of policy optimisation is to seek an optimal policy π * that maximises the value function. If T and R are given, in conjunc- tion with a Q-function, the optimal value V * can be expressed by recursive equations as Q(s, a) = R(s, a) + γ s ∈S T (s |s, a)V * (s ) and V * (s) = max a∈A Q(s, a) (here we assume R(s, a) is de- terministic), which can be solved by dynamic pro- gramming <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Bellman, 1957</ref>). For problems with unknown T or R, such as dialogue systems, the Q-values are usually estimated via reinforcement learning <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">(Sutton and Barto, 1998</ref>).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">Problem Definition</head><p>Let D denote the set of the domain experts in our voice assistant system, and s d be the current di- alogue state of domain expert d ∈ D at a certain timestamp. We also define s o as an abstract state to describe the current status of those out-of-domain services. Then mathematically we can represent the central control process as an MDP, where its state s is a joint set of the states of all the domain experts and the services, as s = {s d } d∈D ∪ {s o }. Four types of system actions are defined as fol- lows.</p><p>• present(d): presenting the output of do- main expert d to user;</p><p>• present ood(null): presenting the re- sults of the top-ranked out-of-domain service given by the service ranker;</p><p>• confirm(d): confirming whether user wants to continue with domain expert d (or to switch to out-of-domain services);</p><p>• clarify(d,d ): asking user to clarify his/her intention between domains d and d .</p><p>For convenience of notations, we use a(x) to denote a system action of our MDP, where a ∈ {present, present ood, confirm, clarify},</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">x ∈ {d, null, (d, d )} d,d ∈D,d =d , x = null</formula><p>only applies to present ood, and x = (d, d ) only applies to clarify actions.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3">Function Approximation</head><p>Function approximation is a commonly used tech- nique to estimate the Q-values when the state space of the MDP is huge. Concretely, in our case, we assume that:</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">Q(s, a(x)) = f (φ(s, a(x)); θ)<label>(1)</label></formula><p>where φ : S × A → R K is a feature function that maps a state-action pair to an K-dimensional feature vector, and f : R K → R is a function of φ(s, a(x)) parameterised by θ. A frequent choice of f is the linear function, as:</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">Q(s, a(x)) = θ φ(s, a(x))<label>(2)</label></formula><p>After this, the policy optimisation problem be- comes learning the parameter θ to approximate the Q-values based on example dialogue trajectories. However, a crucial problem with the standard formulation in Eq. <ref type="formula" target="#formula_2">(2)</ref> is that the feature function φ is defined over the entire state and action spaces. In this case, when a new domain expert is inte- grated into the system, both the state space and the action space will be changed, therefore one will have to re-define the feature function and conse- quentially re-train the model. In order to achieve an extensible system, we make some simplifica- tion assumptions and decompose the feature func- tion as follows. Firstly, we let:</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">φ(s, a(x)) = φ a (s x )<label>(3)</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_4">=        φ pr (s d ) if a(x) =present(d) φ ood (s o ) if a(x) =present ood() φ cf (s d ) if a(x) =confirm(d) φ cl (s d , s d ) if a(x) =clarify(d,d )</formula><p>where the feature function is reduced to only de- pend on the state of the action's operand, instead of the entire system state. Then, we make those ac- tions a(x) that have a same action type (a) but op- erate different domain experts (x) share the same parameter, i.e.:</p><formula xml:id="formula_5">Q(s, a(x)) = θ a φ a (s x )<label>(4)</label></formula><p>This decomposition and parameter tying trick pre- serves the extensibility of the system, because both θ a and φ a are independent of x, when there is a new domain expert˜dexpert˜ expert˜d, we can directly substitute its state s ˜ d into Eq. <ref type="formula" target="#formula_3">(3)</ref> and <ref type="formula" target="#formula_5">(4)</ref> to compute its cor- responding Q-values.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.4">Features</head><p>Based on the problem formulation in Eq. <ref type="formula" target="#formula_3">(3)</ref>   <ref type="formula" target="#formula_3">(3)</ref> is explained as follows. For φ pr , we choose the first 8 fea- tures plus a bias dimension that is always set to −1. Whilst, feature #9 plus a bias is used to de- fine φ ood . All the features are used in φ cf , as to do a confirmation, one needs to consider the joint situation in and out of the domain. Finally, the feature function for a clarification action between two domains d and d is defined as φ cl (s d , s d ) = exp{−|φ pr (s d ) − φ pr (s d )|}, where we use | · | to denote the element-wise absolute of a vector operand. The intuition here is that the more dis- tinguishable the (featurised) states of two domain experts are, the less we tend to clarify them.</p><p>For those domain experts that have multiple sub-domains with different numbers of required and optional slots, the feature extraction procedure only applies to the latest active sub-domain.</p><p>In addition, note that, the confidence scores pro- vided by the user intention identifier are only used as features for out-of-domain services. This is be- cause in the current version of our system, the con- fidence estimation of the intention identifier for domain-dependent dialogue queries is less reliable due to the lack of context information. In contrast, the confidence scores returned by the domain ex- perts will be more informative at this point.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Policy Learning with GPTD</head><p>In traditional statistical SDS, dialogue policies are usually trained using reinforcement learning based on simulated dialogue trajectories ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">Schatzmann et al., 2007;</ref>. Although the evaluation of the simulators themselves could be an arguable issue, there are various advantages, e.g. hundreds of thousands of data examples can be easily generated for training and initial policy evaluation purposes, and different reinforcement learning models can be compared without incur- ring notable extra costs.</p><p>However, for more complex multi-domain SDS, particularly a voice assistant application like ours that aims at handling very complicated (ideally open-domain) dialogue scenarios, it would be dif- ficult to develop a proper simulator that can rea- sonably mimic real human behaviours. There- fore, in this work, we learn the central control policy directly with human subjects, for which the following properties of the learning algorithm are required. Firstly and most importantly, the learner must be sample-efficient as the data collec- tion procedure is costly. Secondly, the algorithm should support batch reinforcement learning. This is because when using function approximation, the learning process may not strictly converge, and the quality of the sequence of generated policies tends to oscillate after a certain number of improving steps at the beginning ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Bertsekas and Tsitsiklis, 1996)</ref>. If online reinforcement learning is used, we will be unable to evaluate the generated policy after each update, and hence will not know which policy to keep for the final evaluation. Therefore, we do a batch policy update and iterate the learn- ing process for a number of batches, such that the data collection phase in a new iteration yields an evaluation of the policy obtained from the previ- ous iteration at the same time.</p><p>To fulfill the above two requirements, the Gaus- sian Process Temporal Difference (GPTD) algo- rithm ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Engel et al., 2005</ref>) is a proper choice, due to its sample efficiency <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Fard et al., 2011</ref>) and batch learning ability ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Engel et al., 2005</ref>), as well as its previous success in dialogue policy learning with human subjects <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(Gaši´Gaši´c et al., 2013a)</ref>. Note that, GPTD can also admit recursive (online) compu- tations, but here we focus ourselves on the batch version.</p><p>A Gaussian Process (GP) is a generative model of Bayesian inference that can be used for func- tion regression, and has the superiority of obtain- ing good posterior estimates with just a few obser- vations <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">(Rasmussen and Williams, 2006</ref>). GPTD models the Q-function as a zero mean GP which defines correlations in different parts of the fea- turised state and action spaces through a kernel function κ, as:</p><formula xml:id="formula_6">Q(s, a(x)) ∼ GP(0, κ((s x , a), (s x , a))) (5)</formula><p>Given a sequence of t state-action pairs X t = [(s 0 , a 0 (x 0 )), . . . , (s t , a t (x t ))] from a collection of dialogues and their corresponding immedi- ate rewards r t = [r 0 , . . . , r t ], the posterior of Q(s, a(x)) for an arbitrary new state-action pair (s, a(x)) can be computed as:</p><formula xml:id="formula_7">Q(s, a(x))| Xt,rt ∼ N ¯ Q(s, a(x)), cov (s, a(x)) (6) ¯ Q(s, a(x)) = k t (s x , a) H t G −1 t r t (7) cov (s, a(x)) = κ((s x , a), (s x , a)) − k t (s x , a) H t G −1 t H t k t (s x , a) (8) G t = H t K t H t + σ 2 H t H t (9) H t =      1 −γ · · · 0 0 0 1 · · · 0 0 . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . 0 · · · 0 1 −γ      (10)</formula><p>where K t is the Gram matrix with elements</p><formula xml:id="formula_8">K t (i, j) = κ((s i x i , a i ), (s j x j , a j )), k t (s x , a) = [κ((s i x i , a i ), (s x , a))] t i=0</formula><p>is a vector, and σ is a hyperparameter specifying the diagonal covari- ance values of the zero-mean Gaussian noise. In addition, we use cov (s, a(x)) to denote (for short) the self-covariance cov <ref type="figure">(s, a(x), s, a(x)</ref>).</p><p>In our case, as different feature functions φ a are defined for different action types, the kernel func- tion is defined to be:</p><formula xml:id="formula_9">κ((s x , a), (s x , a )) = [[a = a ]]κ a (s x , s x ) (11)</formula><p>where <ref type="bibr">[[·]</ref>] is an indicator function and κ a is the ker- nel function defined corresponding to the feature function φ a . Given a state, a most straightforward policy is to select the action that corresponds to the max- imum mean Q-value estimated by the GP. How- ever, since the objective is to learn the Q-function associated with the optimal policy by interacting directly with users, the policy must exhibit some form of stochastic behaviour in order to explore alternatives during the process of learning. In this work, the strategy employed for the exploration- exploitation trade-off is that, during exploration, actions are chosen according to the variance of the GP estimate for the Q-function, and during exploitation, actions are chosen according to the mean. That is:</p><formula xml:id="formula_10">π(s) = arg max a(x) ¯ Q(s, a(x)) : w.p. 1 − arg max a(x) cov (s, a(x)) : w.p.</formula><p>(12) where 0 &lt; &lt; 1 is a pre-defined exploration rate, and will be exponentially reduced at each batch iteration during our learning process.</p><p>Note that, in practice, not all the actions are valid at every possible state. For example, if a do- main expert d has never been activated during a dialogue and can neither process the user's current query, the actions with an operand d will be re- garded as invalid at this state. When executing the policy, we only consider those valid actions for a given state.  The domain selections are totally correct, and the entire dialogue flow is fluent.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>4</head><p>The domain selections are totally correct, but the dialogue flow is slightly redundant.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>3</head><p>There are accidental domain selections errors, or the dialogue flow is perceptually redundant.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>2</head><p>There are frequent domain selections errors, or the dialogue flow is intolerably redundant.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>1</head><p>Most domain selections are incorrect, or the dialogue is incompletable. <ref type="table">Table 2</ref>: The scoring standard in our experiments.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Experimental Results</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.1">Training</head><p>We use the batch version of GPTD as described in Section 5 to learn the central control policy with human subjects. There are three domain ex- perts available in our current system, but during the training only two domains are used, which are the travel information domain and the restaurant search domain. We reserve a movie search domain for evaluating the generalisation property of the learnt policy (see Section 6.2). The learning pro- cess started from a hand-crafted policy. Then 15 experienced users 2 volunteered to contribute dia- logue examples with multiple or compound goals (see <ref type="figure">Figure 4</ref> for an instance), from whom we collected around 50∼70 dialogues per day for 5 days 3 . After each dialogue, the users were asked to score the system from 5 to 1 according to a scor- ing standard shown in <ref type="table">Table 2</ref>. The scores were taken as the (delayed) rewards to train the GPTD model, where we set the rewards for intermediate turns to 0. The working policy was updated daily based on the data obtained up to that day. The data collected on the first day was used for pre- liminary experiments to choose the hyperparame- ters of the model, such as the kernel function, the kernel parameters (if applicable), and σ and γ in the GPTD model. We initially experimented with linear, polynomial and Gaussian kernels, with dif- ferent configurations of σ and γ values, as well as kernel parameter values. It was found that the linear kernel in combination with σ = 5 and γ = 0.99 works more appropriate than the other settings. This configuration was then fixed for the rest iterations. The learning process was iterated for 4 days af- ter the first one. On each day, we computed the mean and standard deviation of the user scores as an evaluation of the policy learnt on the pre- vious day. The learning curve is illustrated in <ref type="figure">Fig- ure 2</ref>. Note here, as we were actually executing a stochastic policy according to <ref type="bibr">Eq. (12)</ref>, to calcu- late the values in <ref type="figure">Figure 2</ref> we ignored those dia- logues that contain any actions selected due to the exploration. We also manually labelled the cor- rectness of domain selection at every turn of the dialogues. The domain selection accuracies of the obtained policy sequence are shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Figure 3</ref>, where similarly, those exploration actions as well Policy Scenario Baseline GPTD p-value (i) 4.5±0.8 4.2±0.8 0.387 (ii)</p><p>3.4±0.9 4.2±0.8 0.018 (iii) 4.1±1.0 4.3±1.0 0.0821 (iv)</p><p>3.9±1.1 4.5±0.8 0.0440 <ref type="table">Table 3</ref>: Paired comparison experiments between the system with a trained GPTD policy and the rule-based baseline.</p><p>as the clarification and confirmation actions were excluded from the calculations. Although the do- main selection accuracy is not the target that our learning algorithm aims to optimise, it reflects the quality of the learnt policies from a different angle of view. It can be found in <ref type="figure">Figure 2</ref> that the best policy was obtained in the third iteration, and after that the policy quality oscillated. The same finding is indicated in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Figure 3</ref> as well, when we use the do- main selection accuracy as the evaluation metric. Therefore, we kept the policy corresponding to the peak point of the learning curve for the compari- son experiments below.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.2">Comparison Experiments</head><p>We conducted paired comparison experiments in four scenarios to compare between the system with the GPTD-learnt central control policy and a non-trivial baseline. The baseline is a publicly de- ployed version of the voice assistant application. The central control policy of the baseline system is handcrafted, which has a separate list of semantic matching rules for each domain to enable domain switching.</p><p>The first two scenarios aim to test the perfor- mance of the two systems on (i) switching between a domain expert and out-of-domain services, and (ii) switching between two domain experts, where only the two training domains (travel information and restaurant search) were considered. Scenar- ios (iii) and (iv) are similar to scenarios (i) and (ii) respectively, but at this time, the users were re- quired to carry out the tests surrounding the movie search domain (which is addressed by a new do- main expert not used in the training phase). There were 13 users who participated this experiment. In each scenario, every user was required to test the two systems with an identical goal and similar queries. After each test, the users were asked to score the two systems separately according to the scoring standard in <ref type="table">Table 2</ref>.</p><p>The average scores received by the two systems are shown in <ref type="table">Table 3</ref>, where we also compute the statistical significance (the p-values) of the results based on paired t-tests. It can be found that the learnt policy works significantly better than the rule-based policy in scenarios (ii) and (iv), but in scenarios (i) and (iii) the differences between two systems are statistically insignificant. Moreover, the learnt policy preserves the extensibility of the entire system as expected, of which strong evi- dences are given by the results in scenarios (iii) and (iv).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.3">Policy Analysis</head><p>To better understand the policy learnt by the GPTD model, we look into the obtained weight vectors, as shown in <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">Table 4</ref>. It can be found that confidence score (#5) is an informative feature for all the system actions, while the relative turn of a domain being last activated (#7) is an additional strong evidence for a confirmation decision. In addition, the similarity between the dialogue com- pletion status (#1 &amp; #2) of two ambiguous domain experts and the relative turns of them being last confirmed (#8) tend to be extra dominating fea- tures for clarification decisions, besides the close- ness of the confidence scores returned by the two domain experts.</p><p>A less noticeable but important phenomenon is observed for feature #6, i.e. the total number of active turns of a domain expert during a dialogue. Concretely, feature #6 has a small negative effect on presentation actions but a small positive con- tribution to confirmation actions. Such weights could correspond to the discount factor's penalty to long dialogues in the value function. How- ever, it implies an unexpected effect in extreme cases, which we explain in detail as follows. Al- though the absolute weights for feature #6 are tiny for both presentation and confirmation actions, the feature value will grow linearly during a dialogue. Therefore, when a dialogue in a certain domain last rather long, there tend to be very frequent con- firmations. A possible solution to this problem could be either ignoring feature #6 or twisting it to some nonlinear function, such that its value stops increasing at a certain threshold point. In addition, to cover sufficient amount of those "extreme" ex- amples in the training phase could also be an alter-  native solution, as our current training set contains very few examples that exhibit extraordinary long domain persistence.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7">Further Discussions</head><p>The proposed approach is a rather general frame- work to learn extensible central control policies for multi-domain SDS based on distributed archi- tectures. It does not rely on any internal represen- tations of those individual domain experts, as long as a unified featurisation of their dialogue states can be achieved. However, from the entire system point of view, the current implementation is still preliminary. Particularly, the confirmation and clarification mechanisms are isolated, for which the surface re- alisations sometimes may sound stiff. This phe- nomenon explains one of the reasons that make the proposed system slightly less preferred by the users than the baseline in scenario (i), when the interaction flows are relative simple. A possi- ble improvement here could be associating the confirmation and clarification actions in the cen- tral controller to the error handling mechanisms within each domain expert, and letting domain ex- perts generate their own utterances on receiving a confirmation/clarification request from the central controller.</p><p>Online reinforcement learning with real user cases will be another undoubted direction of fur- ther improvement of our system. The key chal- lenge here is to automatically estimate user's satis- factions, which will be transformed to the rewards for the reinforcement learners. Strong feedbacks such as clicks or actual order placements can be collected. But to regress user's true satisfaction, other environment features must also be taken into account. Practical solutions are still an open issue at this stage, and are left to our future work.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="8">Conclusion</head><p>In this paper, we introduce an MDP framework for learning domain selection policies in a com- plex multi-domain SDS. Standard problem for- mulation is modified with tied model parameters, so that the entire system is extensible and new domain experts can be easily integrated without re-training the policy. This expectation is con- firmed by empirical experiments with human sub- jects, where the proposed system marginally beats a non-trivial baseline and demonstrates proper ex- tensibility. Several possible improvements are dis- cussed, which will be the central arc of our future research.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: The distributed architecture of the voice assistant system (a simplified illustration).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>5</head><label>5</label><figDesc></figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>Figure 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Figure 2: Average scores and standard deviations during policy iteration.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3" validated="false"><head>Table 4 :</head><label>4</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Feature weights learnt by GPTD. See Ta-
ble 1 for the meanings of the features. 

</table></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> This is a rather general assumption. Informally speaking, for most task-oriented SDS, one can extract a slot-value representation from their dialogue models, of which examples include the RavenClaw architecture (Bohus and Rudnicky, 2009), the Information State dialogue engine (Traum and Larsson, 2003), MDP-SDS (Singh et al., 2002) or POMDP-SDS (Thomson and Young, 2010; Young et al., 2010; Williams and Young, 2007).</note>

			<note place="foot" n="2"> Overall user satisfactions may rely on various aspects of the entire system, e.g. the data source quality of the services, the performance of each domain expert, etc. It will be difficult to make non-experienced users to score the central controller isolatedly. 3 Not all the users participated the experiments everyday. There were 311 valid dialogues received in total, with an average length of 9 turns.</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgements</head><p>The research in this paper is supported by China's 973 Programme no. 2014CB340505. The first au-thor is partially funded by the EC FP7 programme under grant agreement no. 287615 (PARLANCE) and a SICSA PECE grant. The authors would also like to thank Qiaoqiao She, Duo Cai and the HCI-APP group at Baidu for volunteering to participate in the human subject experiments.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Dynamic Programming</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Richard</forename><forename type="middle">Ernest</forename><surname>Bellman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1957" />
			<publisher>Princeton University Press</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Princeton, NJ</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Neuro-Dynamic Programming</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dimitri</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Bertsekas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">John</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Tsitsiklis</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Athena Scientific</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The RavenClaw dialog management framework: Architecture and systems</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dan</forename><surname>Bohus</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alexander</forename><forename type="middle">I</forename><surname>Rudnicky</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Computer Speech and Language</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">23</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="332" to="361" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Reinforcement learning with Gaussian processes</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yaakov</forename><surname>Engel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Shie</forename><surname>Mannor</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ron</forename><surname>Meir</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 22nd International Conference on Machine Learning (ICML)</title>
		<meeting>the 22nd International Conference on Machine Learning (ICML)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="201" to="208" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">PAC-Bayesian policy evaluation for reinforcement learning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Joelle</forename><surname>Mahdi Milani Fard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Csaba</forename><surname>Pineau</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Szepesvári</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 27th Conference on Uncertainty in Artificial Intelligence (UAI)</title>
		<meeting>the 27th Conference on Uncertainty in Artificial Intelligence (UAI)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="195" to="202" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<monogr>
				<title level="m">USER/ASR: 去青岛的机票 (Flight ticket to Qingdao.) SYSTEM: 好的，到青岛的飞机票。请问您什么时候离开？ 自哪儿出发啊？ (Okay, flight ticket to Qingdao. When are you departing, and where are you departing from?)</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
	<note>Travel Info. Domain Expert</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<monogr>
				<title level="m">USER/ASR: 明天出发 (I&apos;m leaving tomorrow.) SYSTEM: 好的，明天到青岛的飞机票。您预计由哪儿出发啊？ (Okay</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
	<note>flight ticket to Qingdao, leaving tomorrow. Where are you departing from?) [Travel Info. Domain Expert</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<monogr>
				<title level="m">USER/ASR: 北京 (Beijing) SYSTEM: [Results Displayed-Travel Info. Domain Expert] USER: 青岛有好吃的四川菜吗 (Are there any good Sichuan cuisines in Qingdao?) ASR: 听到有好吃的酸的川菜吗 (ungrammatical utterance</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
	<note>partially with &quot;delicious&quot; and &quot;Sichuan food&quot;.</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<monogr>
				<title level="m">SYSTEM: 您要继续订机票吗？ (Do you want to continue with flight ticket booking?) [Confirmation-Central Controller] USER: 不是 (No) SYSTEM</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
	<note>Web Search Service: &quot;听到有好吃的酸的川菜吗&quot;</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<monogr>
				<title level="m">USER/ASR: 明天去青岛 (I&apos;m going to Qingdao tomorrow.) SYSTEM</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
	<note>Results Displayed-Travel Info. Domain Expert</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<monogr>
				<title level="m">USER/ASR: 青岛机场附近的餐厅 (Restaurants near Qingdao Airport) SYSTEM: 为您找到以下餐厅 (I found the following restaurants for you</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
	<note>Results Displayed-Restaurant Search Domain Expert</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The temperature is 16 to 20 degree centigrade with moderate east wind</title>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">USER/ASR: 青岛明天会下雨吗? (Will it rain in Qingdao tomorrow?) SYSTEM: 青岛明天阵雨，温度16℃至20℃，东风5-6级 (Qingdao is rainy tomorrow</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
	<note>Results Displayed-Weather Report Service</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Figure 4: An example dialogue containing multiple user goals. The icons stand for graphical user interface based nonverbal outputs</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Online policy optimisation of Bayesian spoken dialogue systems via human interaction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Milica</forename><surname>Gaši´gaši´c</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Catherine</forename><surname>Breslin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Matthew</forename><surname>Henderson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dongho</forename><surname>Kim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Martin</forename><surname>Szummer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Blaise</forename><surname>Thomson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Pirros</forename><surname>Tsiakoulis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Steve</forename><surname>Young</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the IEEE International Conference on Acoustics, Speech and Signal Processing (ICASSP)</title>
		<meeting>the IEEE International Conference on Acoustics, Speech and Signal Processing (ICASSP)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="8367" to="8371" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">POMDP-based dialogue manager adaptation to extended domains</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Milica</forename><surname>Gaši´gaši´c</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Catherine</forename><surname>Breslin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Matthew</forename><surname>Henderson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dongho</forename><surname>Kim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Martin</forename><surname>Szummer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 14th annual SIGdial Meeting on Discourse and Dialogue</title>
		<meeting>the 14th annual SIGdial Meeting on Discourse and Dialogue</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="214" to="222" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Blaise Thomson, Pirros Tsiakoulis, and Steve Young</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Thomas</forename><forename type="middle">Robert</forename><surname>Gruber</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Adam</forename><forename type="middle">John</forename><surname>Cheyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page">66</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Intelligent automated assistant. United States Patent No</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Didier</forename><forename type="middle">Rene</forename><surname>Kittlaus</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christopher</forename><forename type="middle">Dean</forename><surname>Guzzoni</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Richard</forename><forename type="middle">Donald</forename><surname>Brigham</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marcello</forename><surname>Giuli</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Harry Joseph</forename><surname>Basteaforte</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Saddler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<pubPlace>US</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A discriminative classification-based approach to information state updates for a multi-domain dialog system</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Dilek</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gokhan</forename><surname>Hakkani-Tür</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Larry</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Tür</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ashley</forename><surname>Heck</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Asli C ¸</forename><surname>Fidler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Elikyilmaz</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 13th Annual Conference of the International Speech Communication Association (INTERSPEECH)</title>
		<meeting>the 13th Annual Conference of the International Speech Communication Association (INTERSPEECH)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Natural actor and belief critic: Reinforcement algorithm for learning parameters of dialogue systems modelled as POMDPs</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Filip</forename><surname>Jurčíček</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Blaise</forename><surname>Thomson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Steve</forename><surname>Young</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">ACM Transactions on Speech and Language Processing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">25</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Reinforcement learning for parameter estimation in statistical spoken dialogue systems</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Filip</forename><surname>Jurčíček</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Blaise</forename><surname>Thomson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Steve</forename><surname>Young</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Computer Speech &amp; Language</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="168" to="192" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Parameter estimation for agendabased user simulation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Simon</forename><surname>Keizer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Milica</forename><surname>Gaši´gaši´c</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Filip</forename><surname>Jurčíček</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">François</forename><surname>Mairesse</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Blaise</forename><surname>Thomson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kai</forename><surname>Yu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Steve</forename><forename type="middle">Young</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 11th annual SIGdial Meeting on Discourse and Dialogue</title>
		<meeting>the 11th annual SIGdial Meeting on Discourse and Dialogue</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="116" to="123" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Multi-domain spoken dialogue system with extensibility and robustness against speech recognition errors</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kazunori</forename><surname>Komatani</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Naoyuki</forename><surname>Kanda</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mikio</forename><surname>Nakano</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kazuhiro</forename><surname>Nakadai</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hiroshi</forename><surname>Tsujino</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tetsuya</forename><surname>Ogata</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hiroshi</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Okuno</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 7th SIGdial Workshop on Discourse and Dialogue</title>
		<meeting>the 7th SIGdial Workshop on Discourse and Dialogue</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="9" to="17" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Data-Driven Methods for Adaptive Spoken Dialogue Systems: Computational Learning for Conversational Interfaces</title>
		<editor>Oliver Lemon and Olivier Pietquin</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A distributed architecture for cooperative spoken dialogue agents with coherent dialogue state and history</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hsin-Min</forename><surname>Bor-Shen Lin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lin-Shan</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the IEEE Automatic Speech Recognition and Understanding Workshop (ASRU)</title>
		<meeting>the IEEE Automatic Speech Recognition and Understanding Workshop (ASRU)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Dialogue management using scripts. United States Patent No</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Danilo</forename><surname>Mirkovic</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lawrence</forename><surname>Cavedon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
			<pubPlace>US</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A two-stage domain selection framework for extensible multi-domain spoken dialogue systems</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mikio</forename><surname>Nakano</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Shun</forename><surname>Sato</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kazunori</forename><surname>Komatani</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kyoko</forename><surname>Matsuyama</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kotaro</forename><surname>Funakoshi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hiroshi</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Okuno</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 12th annual SIGdial Meeting on Discourse and Dialogue</title>
		<meeting>the 12th annual SIGdial Meeting on Discourse and Dialogue</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="18" to="29" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Gaussian Processes for Machine Learning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Carl</forename><forename type="middle">Edward</forename><surname>Rasmussen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christopher</forename><forename type="middle">K I</forename><surname>Williams</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
			<publisher>MIT Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Agenda-based user simulation for bootstrapping a POMDP dialogue system</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jost</forename><surname>Schatzmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Blaise</forename><surname>Thomson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Karl</forename><surname>Weilhammer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hui</forename><surname>Ye</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Steve</forename><surname>Young</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of Human Language Technologies 2007: The Conference of the North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics; Companion Volume</title>
		<meeting>Human Language Technologies 2007: The Conference of the North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics; Companion Volume<address><addrLine>Short Papers</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="149" to="152" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Optimizing dialogue management with reinforcement learning: Experiments with the NJFun system</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Satinder</forename><surname>Singh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Diane</forename><surname>Litman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Kearns</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marilyn</forename><surname>Walker</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Artificial Intelligence Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">16</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="105" to="133" />
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Reinforcement Learning: An Introduction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Richard</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Sutton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Andrew</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Barto</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
			<publisher>MIT Press</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Cambridge, MA</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Bayesian update of dialogue state: A POMDP framework for spoken dialogue systems</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Blaise</forename><surname>Thomson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Steve</forename><surname>Young</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Computer Speech and Language</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="562" to="588" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Information State approach to dialogue management</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>David</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Staffan</forename><surname>Traum</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Larsson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Current and New Directions in Discourse and Dialogue</title>
		<editor>Jan van Kuppevelt and Ronnie W. Smith</editor>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="325" to="353" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Partially observable Markov decision processes for spoken dialog systems</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jason</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Williams</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Steve</forename><surname>Young</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Computer Speech and Language</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">21</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="393" to="422" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Demonstration of AT&amp;T &quot;Let&apos;s Go&quot;: A production-grade statistical spoken dialog system</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jason</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Williams</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Iker</forename><surname>Arizmendi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alistair</forename><surname>Conkie</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 3rd IEEE Workshop on Spoken Language Technology (SLT)</title>
		<meeting>the 3rd IEEE Workshop on Spoken Language Technology (SLT)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Hidden Information State model: a practical framework for POMDP-based spoken dialogue management</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Steve</forename><surname>Young</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Milica</forename><surname>Gaši´gaši´c</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Simon</forename><surname>Keizer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">François</forename><surname>Mairesse</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jost</forename><surname>Schatzmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Blaise</forename><surname>Thomson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kai</forename><surname>Yu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Computer Speech and Language</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="150" to="174" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">POMDP-based statistical spoken dialogue systems: a review</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Steve</forename><surname>Young</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Milica</forename><surname>Gaši´gaši´c</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Blaise</forename><surname>Thomson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jason</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Williams</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proceedings of the IEEE</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="issue">99</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="20" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
