<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T13:02+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">An Etymological Approach to Cross-Language Orthographic Similarity. Application on Romanian</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
				<availability status="unknown"><p>Copyright Association for Computational Linguistics</p>
				</availability>
				<date>October 25-29, 2014. 2014</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alina</forename><forename type="middle">Maria</forename><surname>Ciobanu</surname></persName>
							<email>alina.ciobanu@my.fmi.unibuc.ro,ldinu@fmi.unibuc.ro</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Faculty of Mathematics and Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Center for Computational Linguistics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">University of Bucharest</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">University of Bucharest</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Liviu</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Dinu</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Faculty of Mathematics and Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Center for Computational Linguistics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">University of Bucharest</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">University of Bucharest</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">An Etymological Approach to Cross-Language Orthographic Similarity. Application on Romanian</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2014 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP)</title>
						<meeting>the 2014 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP) <address><addrLine>Doha, Qatar. c</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="1047" to="1058"/>
							<date type="published">October 25-29, 2014. 2014</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>In this paper we propose a computational method for determining the orthographic similarity between Romanian and related languages. We account for etymons and cognates and we investigate not only the number of related words, but also their forms, quantifying orthographic similarities. The method we propose is adaptable to any language, as far as resources are available.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Language relatedness and language change across space and time are two of the main questions of the historical and comparative linguistics <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">(Rama and Borin, 2014</ref>). Many comparative methods have been used to establish relationships between lan- guages, to determine language families and to re- construct their proto-languages ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Durie and Ross, 1996)</ref>. If grouping of languages in linguistic fam- ilies is generally accepted, the relationships be- tween languages belonging to the same family are periodically investigated. In spite of the fact that linguistic literature abounds in claims of classifi- cation of natural languages, the degrees of similar- ity between languages are far from being certain. In many situations, the similarity of natural lan- guages is a fairly vague notion, both linguists and non-linguists having intuitions about which lan- guages are more similar to which others. McMa- hon and <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">McMahon (2003)</ref> and <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">Rama and Borin (2014)</ref> note that the computational historical lin- guistics did not receive much attention until the beginning of the 1990s, and argue for the necessity of development of quantitative and computational methods in this field.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.1">Related Work</head><p>According to <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Campbell (2003)</ref>, the methods based on comparisons of cognate lists and sound corre- spondences are the most popular approaches em- ployed for establishing relationships between lan- guages. <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Barbançon et al. (2013)</ref> emphasize the va- riety of computational methods used in this field, and state that the differences in datasets and ap- proaches cause difficulties in the evaluation of the results regarding the reconstruction of the phylo- genetic tree of languages. Linguistic phylogeny reconstruction proves especially useful in histor- ical and comparative linguistics, as it enables the analysis of language evolution. <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">Ringe et al. (2002)</ref> propose a computational method for evolutionary tree reconstruction based on a "perfect phylogeny" algorithm; using a Bayesian phylogeographic ap- proach, <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Alekseyenko et al. (2012)</ref>, continuing the work of <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Atkinson et al. (2005)</ref>, model the expan- sion of the Indo-European language family and find support for the hypothesis which places its homeland in Anatolia; <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Atkinson and Gray (2006)</ref> analyze language divergence dates and argue for the usage of computational phylogenetic meth- ods in the question of Indo-European age and ori- gins. Using modified versions of Swadesh's lists 1 , <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Dyen et al. (1992)</ref> investigate the classification of Indo-European languages by applying a lexicosta- tistical method.</p><p>The similarity of languages is interesting not only for historical and comparative linguistics, but for machine translation and language acqui- sition as well. <ref type="bibr" target="#b35">Scannell (2006)</ref> and <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">Hajič et al. (2000)</ref> argue for the possibility of obtaining a bet- ter translation quality using simple methods for very closely related languages. <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">Koppel and Ordan (2011)</ref> study the impact of the distance between languages on the translation product and conclude that it is directly correlated with the ability to dis- tinguish translations from a given source language from non-translated text. Some genetically re- lated languages are so similar to each other, that speakers of such languages are able to communi- cate without prior instruction <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">(Gooskens, 2007)</ref>. <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">Gooskens et al. (2008)</ref> analyze several phonetic and lexical predictors and their conclusion is that lexical similarity can be seen as a predictor of lan- guage intelligibility. The impact of language sim- ilarities in the process of second language acquisi- tion is argued by the contrastive analysis hypoth- esis, which claims that where similarities between the first and the second language occur, the acqui- sition would be easier compared with the situation in which there were differences between the two languages ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Benati and VanPatten, 2011</ref>).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.2">Our Approach</head><p>Although there are multiple aspects that are rele- vant in the study of language relatedness, such as the orthographic, phonetic, syntactic and semantic differences, in this paper we focus only on the or- thographic similarity. The orthographic approach relies on the idea that sound changes leave traces in the orthography, and alphabetic character cor- respondences represent, to a fairly large extent, sound correspondences <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Delmestri and Cristianini, 2010)</ref>.</p><p>In this paper we propose an orthographic simi- larity method focused on etymons (direct sources of the words in a foreign language) and cognates (words in different languages having the same ety- mology and a common ancestor). In a broadly ac- cepted sense, the higher the similarity degree be- tween two languages, the closer they are.</p><p>One of our motivations is that when people en- counter a language for the first time in written form, it is most likely that they can distinguish and individualize words which resemble words from their native language. These words are proba- bly either inherited from their mother tongue (ety- mons), or have a common ancestor with the words in their language (cognates).</p><p>Our first goal is, given a corpus C, to automat- ically detect etymons and cognates. In Section 2 we propose a dictionary-based approach to auto- matically extract related words, and a method for computing the orthographic similarity of natural languages. Most of the traditional approaches in this field focus either on etymology detection or on cognate identification, most of them reporting results only on small sets of cognate pairs (usually manually determined lists of about 200 cognates, for which the cognate judgments are made by hu- man experts <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">(Rama and Borin, 2014)</ref>). Our ap- proach implies a detailed investigation which ac- counts not only for the number of related words, as it is usually done in lexicostatistics (where the relationships between languages are determined based on the percentage of related words), but also for their forms, quantifying orthographic similari- ties. We employ three string similarity metrics for a finer-grained analysis, as related words in dif- ferent languages do not have identical forms and their partial similarity implies different degrees of recognition and comprehensibility. For example, the Romanian word lun˘ a (moon) is closer to its Latin etymon luna than the word b˘ atrân (old) to its etymon veteranus, and the Romanian word vânt (wind) is closer to its French cognate pair vent than the word castel (castle) to its cognate pair château.</p><p>In this paper we investigate the orthographic similarity between Romanian and related lan- guages. Romanian is a Romance language, be- longing to the Italic branch of the Indo-European language family, and is of particular interest re- garding its geographic setting. It is surrounded by Slavic languages and its relationship with the big Romance kernel was difficult. Besides gen- eral typological comparisons that can be made between any two or more languages, Romanian can be studied based on comparisons of ge- netic and geographical nature, participating in nu- merous areally-based similarities that define the Balkan convergence area. <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Joseph (1999)</ref> states that, regarding the genetic relationships, Roma- nian can be studied in the context of those lan- guages most closely related to it and that the well-studied Romance languages enable compar- isons that might not be possible otherwise, within less well-documented families of languages. The position of Romanian within the Romance fam- ily is controversial <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">(McMahon and McMahon, 2003)</ref>: either marginal or more integrated within the group, depending on the versions of the cog- nate lists that are used in the analysis.</p><p>In Section 3.1 we apply our method on Roma- nian in different stages of its evolution, running our experiments on high-volume corpora from three historical periods: the period approximately between 1642 and 1743, the second half of 19 th century <ref type="bibr">(1870 -1889)</ref>, and the present period. In Section 3.2 we make use of a fourth corpus, Eu- roparl, with a double goal: on the one hand, to check if degrees of similarity between Romanian and other languages in the present period are con- sistent across two different corpora, and on the other hand, to investigate whether there are dif- ferences between the overall degrees of similarity obtained for the entire corpus and those obtained in various experiments at sentence level. The con- clusions of our paper are outlined in Section 4.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Methodology and Algorithm</head><p>In this section we introduce a technique for deter- mining the orthographic similarity of languages. In order to obtain accurate results, we investigate both etymons and cognates. First, we automati- cally identify etymons and cognates, then we mea- sure the distances between related words, and fi- nally we compute the overall degrees of similarity between pairs of languages. We also applied this method for investigating the mutual intelligibility of the Romance languages, and preliminary results are presented in (Ciobanu and Dinu, 2014b).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">Similarity Method</head><p>Let C tw 1 , w 2 , ..., w N words u be a corpus in L 1 and let L 2 be a related language. We assume, with- out any loss of generality, that the elements of C are ordered such that C L tw 1 , w 2 , ..., w N lingua u is the subset of C containing all the words that have an etymon or a cognate pair in L 2 . We use the following notations: N words is the number of token words in C, N lingua is the number of token words in C L , λ is the empty string and x i is the etymon or cognate pair of w i in L 2 . Given a string distance ∆, we define the distance between L 1 and L 2 (non-metric distance), with frequency support from corpus C, as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">∆pL1, L2q 1 ¡ N lingua N words ° N lingua i1 ∆pwi, xiq N words (1)</formula><p>Hence, the similarity between languages L 1 and L 2 is defined as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">SimpL1, L2q 1 ¡ ∆pL1, L2q (2)</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">Algorithm</head><p>We present here the algorithm based on linguistic relationships detection and string similarity meth- ods for determining the orthographic similarity between languages, with frequency support from corpora in the source language. This algorithm,  represented in <ref type="figure">Figure 2</ref>, is applicable to any lan- guage. After a preprocessing phase, which is de- tailed in Subsection 2.</p><p>2.1, we analyze words and begin by identifying their etymologies.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2.1">Preprocessing</head><p>Given a corpus C, we start by preprocessing the text.</p><p>Step 1. Data Cleaning. We perform basic word segmentation, using whitespace and punc- tuation marks as delimiters and we lower-case all words. We remove from the datasets tokens that are irrelevant for our investigation, such as dates, numbers and non-textual annotations marked by non-alphanumeric characters.</p><p>Step 2. Stop Words Removal. We focus on analyzing word content and, in order to obtain relevant results, we remove stop words from the datasets. We use the lists of stop words for Roma- nian provided by the Apache Lucene 2 text search engine library. In <ref type="table">Table 1</ref> we list the total number of stop words from each corpus.</p><p>Step 3. Lemmatization. We use lemmas for identifying words' definitions in dictionaries and for computing adequate distances between words and their cognates or etymons. We use the Dex- online 3 machine-readable dictionary to lemmatize Romanian words.</p><p>Step 4. Diacritics Removal. Many words have undergone transformations by the augmentation of language-specific diacritics when entering a new language. From an orthographic perspective, the resemblance of words is higher between words without diacritics than between words with dia- critics. For example, the orthographic distance is higher for the Romanian word amicit¸ieamicit¸ie (friend- ship) and its French cognate pair amitié than for their corresponding forms without diacritics, am- icitie and amitie. For this reason, in this step of our procedure we create two versions of each dataset, with and without diacritics, in order to fur- ther investigate the influence of the diacritics on the cross-language orthographic similarity. In Ro- manian, 5 diacritics are used today: ˘ a, ˆ ı, ˆ a, s ¸, t ¸.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2.2">Relationships Identification</head><p>Step 1. Etymology Detection. For most words, etymological dictionaries offer a unique etymol- ogy, but when more options are possible for ex- plaining a word's etymology (there are words whose etymology was and remains difficult to ascertain), dictionaries may provide multiple al- ternatives. For example, the Romanian word parlament (parliament) has a double etymology: French (with the etymon parlement) and Italian (with the etymon parlamento). We account for all the given etymological hypotheses, enabling our method to provide more accurate results. For determining words' etymologies we use the Dexonline machine-readable dictionary, which is an aggregation of over 30 Romanian dictionaries. By parsing its definitions, we are able to automat- ically extract information regarding words' ety- mologies and etymons. The most frequently used pattern is shown below.</p><p>&lt;abbr class="abbrev" title="limba language_name"&gt; language_abbreviation &lt;/abbr&gt; &lt;b&gt; origin_word &lt;/b&gt;</p><p>As an example, we provide below an excerpt from a Dexonline entry which uses this pattern to <ref type="bibr">3</ref> http://dexonline.ro specify the etymology of the Romanian word capi- tol (chapter), which has double etymology: Latin (with the etymon capitulum) and Italian (with the etymon capitolo).</p><p>&lt;b&gt; CAP´ITOLCAP´CAP´ITOL &lt;/b&gt; &lt;abbr class="abbrev" title="limba italiana"&gt; it. &lt;/abbr&gt; &lt;b&gt; capitolo &lt;/b&gt; &lt;abbr class="abbrev" title="limba latina"&gt; lat. &lt;/abbr&gt; &lt;b&gt; capitulum &lt;/b&gt;</p><p>Step 2. Cognate Identification. Cognates are words in different languages having the same ety- mology and a common ancestor. The methods for cognate detection proposed so far are mostly based on orthographic/phonetic and semantic similari- ties <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">(Kondrak, 2001;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Frunza et al., 2005</ref>), but the term "cognates" is often used with a somewhat dif- ferent meaning, denoting words with high ortho- graphic/phonetic and cross-lingual meaning simi- larity, the condition of common etymology being left aside. We focus on etymology and we intro- duce an automatic strategy for detecting pairs of</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>INPUT TEXT</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Stop words removal</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Lemmatization</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>GENETIC RELATIONSHIPS IDENTIFICATION</head><p>Etymology detection</p><p>Cognate identification</p><p>Language clustering</p><p>Orthographic similarity computation</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>SIMILARITY HIERARCHY</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Romanian dictionaries</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>LANGUAGE SIMILARITY COMPUTATION</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Foreign languages dictionaries</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>TEXT PROCESSING</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Words distances measuring</head><p>Figure 2: Algorithm for determining the ortho- graphic similarity between related languages. victoria (lat.) victorie (ro.) e t y m o n e t y m o n cognates vittoria (it.) cognates between two given languages, which en- ables the identification of all cognate pairs for the studied corpus. Considering a set of words in a given language L, to identify the cognate pairs between L and a re- lated language L', we first determine the etymolo- gies of the given words. Then we translate in L' all words without L' etymology. We consider cog- nate candidates pairs formed of input words and their translations. Using electronic dictionaries, we extract etymology-related information for the translated words. To identify cognates, we com- pare, for each pair of candidates, the etymologies and the etymons. If they match, we identify the words as being cognates.</p><p>In our previous work (Ciobanu and Dinu, 2014a) we applied this method on a Romanian dic- tionary, while here we extract cognates from Ro- manian corpora. We identify cognate pairs be- tween Romanian and six other languages: Ital- ian, French, Spanish, Portuguese, Turkish and En- glish. We use electronic dictionaries <ref type="bibr">4</ref> to extract etymology-related information and Google Trans- late <ref type="bibr">5</ref> to translate Romanian words. We are re- stricted in our investigation by the available re- sources, but we plan to extend our method to other related languages as well. We selected these six languages for the following reason: the first four in our list are Romance languages, and our intuition is that there are numerous words in these languages which share a common ancestor with Romanian words. We investigate the cog- nate pairs for Turkish because many French words were imported in both Romanian and Turkish in the 19 th century, and we believe that accounting for Romanian-Turkish cognates would provide a more accurate result for the similarity of these lan-  <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">Table 2</ref> we report the number of Romanian words having an etymon or a cognate pair in the six related languages.</p><note type="other">guages. As for English, we decided to investigate the cognate pairs for this language in order to ana- lyze to what extent the influence of English on Ro- manian increases across time. In</note><p>Step 3. Evaluation. In order to evaluate our au- tomatic method for extracting etymology-related information and for detecting related words, we excerpt a sample of 500 words for each of the considered languages (Romanian, French, Italian, Spanish, Portuguese, Turkish and English). The samples are drawn using a proportionate stratifi- cation sampling method with regard to the length of the lemmas in our datasets. We manually deter- mine the etymologies of the words in the samples, and we compare these results with the automati- cally obtained etymologies. We compute the accu- racy for etymology extraction for each language, and we obtain the following results: 95.8% accu- racy for Romanian, 97.8% for Italian, 96.8% for French, 96.6% for Spanish, 97.0% for Portuguese, 96.0% for Turkish and, finally, 97.2% for English.  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2.3">Linguistic Distances</head><p>Various approaches have been previously em- ployed for assessing the orthographic distance or similarity between related words. Their per- formance has been investigated and compared <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">(Frunza et al., 2005;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b32">Rama and Borin, 2014</ref>), but a clear conclusion cannot be drawn with respect to which method is the most appropriate for a given task. We employ three metrics to determine the orthographic similarity between related words. In Subsection 3.1.2 we investigate to what extent the similarity scores computed with each of these met- rics differ, and whether the differences are statisti- cally significant. We use the following metrics:</p><p>• LCSR: The longest common subsequence ratio <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">(Melamed, 1995)</ref> is the longest common subsequence of two strings u and v divided by the length of the longer string. We sub- tract this value from 1, in order to obtain the distance between two words.</p><p>• EDIT: The edit distance <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">(Levenshtein, 1965)</ref> counts the minimum number of operations (insertion, deletion and substitution) required to transform one string into another. We use a normalized version of the edit distance, di- viding it by the length of the longer string.</p><p>• RD: The rank distance (Dinu and <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Dinu, 2005</ref>) is used to measure the similarity be- tween two ranked lists. A ranking of a set of n objects can be represented as a permuta- tion of the integers 1, 2, ..., n. Let S be a set of ranking results, σ  S. σpiq represents the rank of object i in the ranking result σ. The rank distance is computed as: RDpσ, τ q ° n i1 |σpiq ¡ τ piq|. The ranks of the ele- ments are assigned from bottom up, i.e. from n to 1, using the Borda count method (de Borda, 1781). The elements which do not oc- cur in any of the rankings receive the rank 0. To extend the rank distance to strings, we index each occurrence of a given letter a with a k , where k is the number of its pre- vious occurrences, and then apply the rank distance on the new indexed strings, which become rankings in this situation. In order to normalize it, we divide the rank distance by the maximum possible distance between two strings u and v ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Dinu and Sgarro, 2006</ref>):</p><p>∆ max pu, vq |u|p|u| 1q{2 |v|p|v| 1q{2.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Experiments and Results</head><p>In this section we present the results obtained by applying our method for determining orthographic similarity on Romanian datasets. To our knowledge, only basic lexicostatistical methods (generally based on different dictionar- ies or versions of the representative vocabulary of Romanian) which compute the percentage of words with a given etymology have been applied for determining the relationships between Roma- nian and related languages. Because of the diffi- culty of setting the bounds between the basic lex- icon and the remaining words, <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">Graur (1968)</ref> uses in his experiments three concentric versions of the basic Romanian lexicon. <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Dinu (1996)</ref> reevaluates the etymology detection for the three versions of the basic Romanian lexicon and reclassifies the lexical material. He argues against grouping to- gether all the words with Slavic origins, without differentiation between Old Slavic and languages such as Bulgarian, Russian, Ukrainian and Polish. <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">Sala (1988)</ref> builds a version of the representative vocabulary of Romanian comprising 2588 words, which we use in our experiments as well.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Romanian Evolution</head><p>We apply our similarity method on high-volume Romanian corpora from three distinct historical periods of time, with different cultural, econom- ical, political and social contexts. In <ref type="table">Table 1</ref> we report statistics for these corpora and for the basic Romanian lexicon.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1.1">Data</head><p>The first corpus consists of the transcription of the parliamentary debates held in the Romanian Par- liament from 1996 to 2007 <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">(Grozea, 2012)</ref>. The second corpus consists of the publishing works of Mihai Eminescu <ref type="bibr">(Eminescu, 1980</ref><ref type="bibr">(Eminescu, 1985</ref>), the lead- ing Romanian poet. His works provide an insight- ful description of the period between 1870 and 1889, with respect to its cultural, economical, so- cial and political aspects, including some major events in the Romanian history. Many researchers consider that Eminescu had a crucial influence on Romanian, his contribution to modern language development being highly appreciated. The third corpus dates back to the period approximately be- tween 1642 and 1743, the beginning period of the Romanian writing. Miron Costin, Grigore Ure- che and Ion Neculce are Romanian chroniclers whose main works follow one another in creat- ing one of the most detailed and valuable descrip- tions of Moldavia in that period, "Letopiset¸ulLetopiset¸ul T ¸ ˘ arii Moldovei". Along with them, Dimitrie Cantermir contributed to the early development of the Roma- nian writing, having written what is considered to be the first attempt at a socio-political novel ("Isto- ria Ieroglific˘ a", 1703-1705). Their chronicles ac- count for social, cultural, economical and political events with the purpose of recreating historical pe- riods of time. We also use the basic Romanian lex- icon <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">(Sala, 1988)</ref>, abbreviated RVR, for our exper- iments. The Dexonline machine-readable dictio- nary, which we use for determining the etymolo- gies for the Romanian words, aggregates defini-  <ref type="table">Table 3</ref>: Results for the Romanian datasets. In the D and ND columns we provide the average degrees of similarity for the datasets with and without diacritics. For languages for which we determine cognate pairs (besides etymons), we report both versions of the results, before and after cognate identification.</p><p>In the %words column we provide the percentage of words having an etymon or a cognate pair in each language. The results are ordered according to the ranking of similarity for the corpus comprising the parliamentary debates after identifying cognates and with diacritics included.</p><p>tions from over 30 dictionaries ranging from 1927 to the present time and contains archaisms and obsolete words (which are marked accordingly); therefore, we are able to identify etymologies for words in all used corpora.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1.2">Results</head><p>In this subsection we present and analyze the main results drawn from our research. In <ref type="table">Table 3</ref> we list the output of our method for each corpus, with and without diacritics 6 . We report the similarity between Romanian and related languages, provid- ing the average value of the three metrics used. In the %words column we provide, for each corpus, the percentage of words having an etymon or a cognate pair in a given language (the typical mea- sure used in lexicostatistical comparison, i.e., the 0 distance function). The results for the Romanian datasets are plotted in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 4</ref> and <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Figure 5</ref>.</p><p>Cognate Influence. <ref type="table">Table 3</ref> and <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 4</ref> present the gain obtained by cognate analysis. Ac- counting for cognates leads to an increase of sim- ilarity between Romanian and Spanish and Por- tuguese with almost 300%, and between Roma- nian and Italian with almost 20%. Another spec- tacular increase of closeness is for Turkish, which draws closer to Romanian with more than 500% <ref type="bibr">6</ref> The complete ranking of similarity is available online at http://nlp.unibuc.ro/resources/rosim.pdf.</p><p>by using the cognate gain. The degree of sim- ilarity is not given by the contribution of words inherited in Romanian from Turkish (about 1%), but by the pairs of shared cognates. Both Ro- manian and Turkish borrowed words from French massively towards the end of the 19 th century. Thus, most pairs of Romanian-Turkish cognates have common French ancestors, and words in Ro- manian and Turkish which resemble are actually loans from the same French words. We also notice a significant increase in similarity between Roma- nian and English in the modern period. This in- crease is natural and probably arises for the simi- larity between English and most of the other lan- guages as well. We notice that this increase is due preponderantly to the cognate pairs. Most of the Romanian-English cognates have a Romance common ancestor (78.4% Latin, 4.2% French, 3.4% Italian), and 11.8% have a Greek common ancestor, counted at lemma level on the corpus comprising the parliamentary debates.</p><p>Romanian Evolution. Some significant results can be observed in the evolution of Romanian: the degrees of similarity between Romanian and all the Romance languages has increased significantly from the Chronicles period until today. Besides them, German is the only language to which Ro- manian drew closer (a possible explanation might be the fact that, after the establishment of Germans in Banat and Transylvania, many German words entered the basic Romanian lexicon). On the con- trary, the similarity between Romanian and almost all the Slavic languages decreased in the same pe- riod. Russian is the only Slavic language which preserved its degree of similarity with Romanian (being, in the 2000s, the only Slavic language among the top 10 most closely related languages with Romanian, on the ninth position, with a de- gree of similarity of less than 4%). In the 18 th and 19 th centuries, the transition to the Latin alpha- bet and the desire to restore Romanian's Latin ap- pearance contributed to the decrease of the Slavic influence <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">(Ghet¸ieGhet¸ie, 1978)</ref>. In fact, all Slavic in- fluences in the 2000s sum up to 8.9%, in con- trast with Latin influences, reaching 61.8%. Greek is the only language which reaches its peak re- garding the similarity with Romanian in the 19 th century (due to the brief Phanariot dominance in the 19 th century). Therefore, Romanian preserved its Latin character all along, and the influence of the non-Latin languages on Romanian (overesti- mated in some works) was in fact not so signif- icant. This fact supports Darwin's theory <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Darwin, 1859)</ref>, which states that the genealogy of lan- guages is consistent with the genealogy of the na- tions (analyzed based on DNA similarity).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Romance Germanic Slavic</head><p>Orthographic Metrics. In order to compare the similarity scores computed with the three metrics used, we conduct hypothesis tests <ref type="bibr" target="#b36">(Sheskin, 2003)</ref> to determine whether the differences between the results obtained with each metric are statistically significant. We extract a sample of 5,000 words and we compute the pairwise differences between the similarity scores. Using the R v3.1.0 software environment for statistical computing <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">(R Core Team, 2014)</ref>, we perform the one-way ANOVA F-test, with the null hypothesis H 0 : µ EDIT µ LCSR µ RD (where µ ∆ is the mean of the val-ues computed with the ∆ metric) and the alterna- tive hypothesis H a : not all µ EDIT , µ LCSR , µ RD are equal. Since the p-value of 2.88e-05 is much smaller than the 0.05 significance level, we have very strong evidence to reject the null hypothesis that the mean computed values for the three met- rics are all equal. Further, we perform post-hoc comparisons applying pairwise t-tests with Bon- feronni correction for the p-value, in order to an- alyze the differences between the metrics. For each pair of metrics, p 3 0.05. The differences are statistically significant, but we notice that they are small. Applying a two-sampled t-test, we ob- tain a [0.012, 0.015] confidence interval for the mean difference between EDIT and LCSR, [0.015, 0.018] for EDIT and RD, and [0.001, 0.003] for RD and LCSR, at 95% confidence level. More- over, computing Spearman's rank correlation co- efficient for the rankings obtained by each metric for each dataset, we observe a very high corre- lation between them (ρ ¡ 0.98 for each pair of variables). Thus, we conclude that reporting the average of the three metrics is relevant for our ex- periments, as differences are small and do not in- fluence the ranking.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Europarl Experiments</head><p>We continue our investigation regarding the sim- ilarity of natural languages with two additional experiments. First, we want to see if degrees of similarity between Romanian and other lan- guages in the present period are consistent across two different corpora. In the second experi- ment we are interested to see if there are differ- ences between the overall degrees of similarity obtained for the entire corpus (the bag-of-words model) and those obtained in various experiments at sentence level. Our main corpus is Europarl ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">Koehn, 2005)</ref>. More specifically, we use the por- tions larger than 2KB collected between 2007 and 2011 from the Romanian subcorpus of Europarl. The corpus is tokenized and sentence-aligned in 21 languages. For preprocessing this corpus, we discard all the transcribers' descriptions of the par- liamentary sessions (such as "The President in- terrupted the speaker" or "The session was sus- pended at 19:30 and resumed at 21:00").</p><p>Exp. #1. In a first step, we apply the methodol- ogy described in Section 2 on the entire Europarl corpus for Romanian, using a bag-of-words model for the entire corpus, in which we account for the overall frequencies of the words. In this experi- ment, as in the previous ones, we cannot detect outliers, i.e., sentences which are unbalanced re- garding the etymologies of the comprised words. For this reason, we conduct a second experiment which addresses this potential issue.</p><p>Exp. #2. We determine sentence-level ortho- graphic similarity and we aggregate the results to compute the average values for the related lan- guages. In this second experiment, we apply the methodology described in Section 2 for each sen- tence in the Europarl corpus for Romanian. For each sentence we obtain a ranking of related lan- guages and, in order to obtain a ranking of sim- ilarity for the entire corpus, we compute the av- erage degrees of similarity: for each related lan- guage, we sum up the degrees of similarity for all the sentences and divide this value by the number of sentences in the corpus.</p><p>Exp. #3. Because the interpretation of statis- tics derived from datasets that include outliers may be misleading, we compute the standard quartiles Q1, <ref type="bibr">Q2 and Q3 (Sheskin, 2003</ref>) with regard to the length of the sentences. We use the interquartile range IQR Q3 ¡ Q1 to find outliers in the data. We consider outliers the observations that fall below the lower fence LF = Q1 ¡ 1.5pIQRq or above the upper fence U F = Q3 1.5pIQRq.</p><p>We apply our methodology again only for the sen- tences having the length in the rLF, U F s range.  Spanish <ref type="figure">Figure 6</ref>: Distribution of the Romanian sentences in Europarl based on their similarity with the top 5 ranked languages. The OX axis represents the degree of similarity normalized to <ref type="bibr">[0,</ref><ref type="bibr">1]</ref>.</p><p>Exp. #4. As a last experiment, for each language L we consider as observations the degrees of sim- ilarity between Romanian and L, we discard out- liers and we compute the average value of the ob- servations inside the rLF, U F s range. For each language, we determine the distribution of the sen- tences according to their similarity with the given language (the histograms for the top 5 languages are presented in <ref type="figure">Figure 6</ref>). In <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Figure 7</ref> we report the top 20 languages in the ranking of similarity for Europarl, emphasiz- ing the gain obtained by identifying cognates. In <ref type="table" target="#tab_6">Table 4</ref> we report the similarity scores for the top 20 languages in the rankings of similarity for all the 4 experiments: overall similarity for the entire Europarl corpus (Exp. #1), sentence-level similar- ity (Exp. #2), similarity for the sentences having the length in the rLF, U F s range (Exp. #3), and similarity for the sentences having the similarity between Romanian and each related language in the rLF, U F s range (Exp. #4).</p><p>Some remarks are immediate. We observe that the differences between the values obtained for the entire corpus (Exp. #1) and those ob- tained in various experiments at sentence level (Exp. #2 -#4) are very small (an exception is Exp. #4, for languages whose degrees of similarity with Romanian are of less than 10%). We test the bag-of-words model on two corpora from the same period (the Parliament corpus and Europarl -in Exp. #1) and we notice that the results are consis- tent across different corpora (0.98 Spearman's ρ). The only significant difference is for Portuguese, which is closer to Romanian as measured on Eu- roparl than on the Parliament corpus.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Conclusions and Future Work</head><p>In this paper we proposed a computational method for determining cross-language orthographic similarity, with application on Romanian. We investigated etymons and cognates and we con- ducted a fine-grained analysis of the orthographic similarity between Romanian and related lan- guages. Our results provide a new insight into the classification and evolution of Romanian. We plan to apply our similarity method on a corpus of spoken language, and to extend our analysis to other languages as well, as we gain access to available resources. We further intend to combine our orthographic approach with syntactic and semantic evidence for a wider perspective on language similarity.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 1: Schema for determining the orthographic similarity between related languages with frequency support from corpus C.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Figure 3: Word-etymon and cognate pairs.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 4 :</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Figure 4: Degrees of similarity for the Romanian datasets. For French, Italian, Spanish, Portuguese, Turkish and English, the values obtained after the cognate identification phase are also plotted.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>Figure 5 :</head><label>5</label><figDesc>Figure 5: Degrees of similarity for the language families. Iranian and Baltic have a degree of similarity of less than 0.5.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head>Figure 7 :</head><label>7</label><figDesc>Figure 7: Degrees of similarity for Europarl.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3" validated="false"><head>Table 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Number of Romanian token words having 
etymons or cognate pairs in related languages. 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_6" validated="false"><head>Table 4 :</head><label>4</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Results for Europarl on the entire corpus 
(Exp. #1) and at sentence level (Exp. #2 -#4). </table></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> http://www.wordgumbo.com/ie/cmp/iedata.txt</note>

			<note place="foot" n="2"> http://lucene.apache.org</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgements</head><p>We thank the anonymous reviewers for their help-ful and constructive comments. We thank Raluca Vasilache for the help with evaluating the auto-matic method for detecting related words. The contribution of the authors to this paper is equal. Research supported by CNCS UEFISCDI, project number PNII-ID-PCE-2011-3-0959.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Mapping the Origins and Expansion of the Indo-European Language Family</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alexander</forename><forename type="middle">V</forename><surname>Alekseyenko</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Quentin</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Atkinson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Remco</forename><surname>Bouckaert</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alexei</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Drummond</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Dunn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Russell</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Gray</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Simon</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Greenhill</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Philippe</forename><surname>Lemey</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marc</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Suchard</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">337</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6097</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="957" to="960" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">How Old is the Indo-European Language Family? Illumination or More Moths to the Flame?</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Quentin</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Atkinson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Russell</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Gray</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Phylogenetic Methods and the Prehistory of Languages</title>
		<editor>Peter Forster and Colin Renfrew</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="91" to="109" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>McDonald Institute for Archaeological Research</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">From Words to Dates: Water into Wine, Mathemagic or Phylogenetic Inference?</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Quentin</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Atkinson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Russell</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Gray</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Geoff</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Nicholls</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Welch</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Transactions of the Philological Society</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">103</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="193" to="219" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">An Experimental Study Comparing Linguistic Phylogenetic Reconstruction Methods. Diachronica</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Francois</forename><surname>Barbançon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Steven</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Evans</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Luay</forename><surname>Nakhleh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Don</forename><surname>Ringe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tandy</forename><surname>Warnow</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">30</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="143" to="170" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Key Terms in Second Language Acquisition</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alessandro</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Benati</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bill</forename><surname>Vanpatten</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">International Journal of Applied Linguistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">21</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="270" to="273" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">How to Show Languages are Related: Methods for Distant Genetic Relationship</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lyle</forename><surname>Campbell</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">The Handbook of Historical Linguistics</title>
		<editor>Brian D. Joseph and Richard W. Janda</editor>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Blackwell</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Building a Dataset of Multilingual Cognates for the Romanian Lexicon</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alina</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Maria</forename><surname>Ciobanu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Liviu</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Dinu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 9th International Conference on Language Resources and Evaluation, LREC 2014</title>
		<meeting>the 9th International Conference on Language Resources and Evaluation, LREC 2014</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1038" to="1043" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">On the Romance Languages Mutual Intelligibility</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alina</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Maria</forename><surname>Ciobanu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Liviu</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Dinu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 9th International Conference on Language Resources and Evaluation, LREC 2014</title>
		<meeting>the 9th International Conference on Language Resources and Evaluation, LREC 2014</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3313" to="3318" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">On the Origin of Species by Means of Natural Selection, or the Preservation of Favoured Races in the Struggle for Life</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Charles</forename><surname>Robert</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Darwin</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1859" />
			<publisher>John Murray</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Mémoire sur lesÉlections les´lesÉlections au Scrutin. Histoire de l&apos;Académie Royale des Sciences</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jean-Charles De</forename><surname>Borda</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1781" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">String Similarity Measures and PAM-like Matrices for Cognate Identification. Bucharest Working Papers in Linguistics</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Antonella</forename><surname>Delmestri</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nello</forename><surname>Cristianini</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="71" to="82" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">On the Syllabic Similarities of Romance Languages</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Anca</forename><surname>Dinu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Liviu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Dinu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 6th International Conference on Computational Linguistics and Intelligent Text Processing</title>
		<meeting>the 6th International Conference on Computational Linguistics and Intelligent Text Processing<address><addrLine>CICLing</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="785" to="788" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A LowComplexity Distance for DNA Strings</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Liviu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Andrea</forename><surname>Dinu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Sgarro</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Fundam. Inform</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">73</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="361" to="372" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Personalitatea Limbii Române. Cartea Româneasc˘ a</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mihai</forename><surname>Dinu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The Comparative Method Reviewed: Regularity and Irregularity in Language Change</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mark</forename><surname>Durie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Malcolm</forename><surname>Ross</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
			<publisher>Oxford University Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">An Indoeuropean Classification: a Lexicostatistical Experiment</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Isidore</forename><surname>Dyen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Joseph</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Kruskal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Paul</forename><surname>Black</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Transactions of the Americal Philosophical Society</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">82</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="132" />
			<date type="published" when="1992" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<monogr>
				<title level="m">Mihai Eminescu. 1980-1985. Opere. Vol IX-XIII. Publicistic˘ a. Editura Academiei Române</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Automatic Identification of Cognates and False Friends in French and English</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Oana</forename><surname>Frunza</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Diana</forename><surname>Inkpen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Grzegorz</forename><surname>Kondrak</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the International Conference on Recent Advances in Natural Language Processing</title>
		<meeting>the International Conference on Recent Advances in Natural Language Processing</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="251" to="257" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Istoria Limbii Române Literare. Privire Sintetic˘ a. Editura S ¸ tiint¸ific˘tiint¸ific˘ a s ¸i Enciclopedic˘ a</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Ion Ghet¸ieghet¸ie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1978" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Phonetic and Lexical Predictors of Intelligibility</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Charlotte</forename><surname>Gooskens</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wilbert</forename><surname>Heeringa</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Karin</forename><surname>Beijering</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">International Journal of Humanities and Arts Computing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1-2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="63" to="81" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Contribution of Linguistic Factors to the Intelligibility of Closely Related Languages</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Charlotte</forename><surname>Gooskens</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Multilingual and Multicultural Development</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">28</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">445</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Tendint¸eleTendint¸ele Actuale ale Limbii Române. Editura S ¸ tiint¸ific˘tiint¸ific˘ a</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alexandru</forename><surname>Graur</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1968" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Experiments and Results with Diacritics Restoration in Romanian</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Cristian</forename><surname>Grozea</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 15th International Conference on Text, Speech and Dialogue, TSD 2012</title>
		<meeting>the 15th International Conference on Text, Speech and Dialogue, TSD 2012</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="199" to="206" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Machine Translation of Very Close Languages</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jan</forename><surname>Hajič</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jan</forename><surname>Hric</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Vladislav</forename><surname>Kubon</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 6th Conference on Applied Natural Language Processing</title>
		<meeting>the 6th Conference on Applied Natural Language Processing</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="7" to="12" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Romanian and the Balkans: Some Comparative Perspectives</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Brian</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Joseph</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">The Emergence of the Modern Language Sciences</title>
		<editor>Sheila Embleton, John E. Joseph, and Hans-Joseph Niederehe</editor>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>John Benjamins Publishing Company</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Europarl: A Parallel Corpus for Statistical Machine Translation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Philipp</forename><surname>Koehn</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 10th Machine Translation Summit, AAMT 2005</title>
		<meeting>the 10th Machine Translation Summit, AAMT 2005</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="79" to="86" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Identifying Cognates by Phonetic and Semantic Similarity</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Grzegorz</forename><surname>Kondrak</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2nd Meeting of the North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics on Language Technologies</title>
		<meeting>the 2nd Meeting of the North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics on Language Technologies</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="8" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Translationese and Its Dialects</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Moshe</forename><surname>Koppel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Noam</forename><surname>Ordan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 49th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics: Human Language Technologies, HLT 2011</title>
		<meeting>the 49th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics: Human Language Technologies, HLT 2011</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1318" to="1326" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Binary Codes Capable of Correcting Deletions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Vladimir</forename><forename type="middle">I</forename><surname>Levenshtein</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Insertions, and Reversals. Soviet Physics Doklady</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="707" to="710" />
			<date type="published" when="1965" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Finding Families: Quantitative Methods in Language Classification</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">April</forename><surname>Mcmahon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Robert</forename><surname>Mcmahon</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Transactions of the Philological Society</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">101</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="7" to="55" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Automatic Evaluation and Uniform Filter Cascades for Inducing N-Best Translation Lexicons</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dan</forename><surname>Melamed</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 3rd Workshop on Very Large Corpora</title>
		<meeting>the 3rd Workshop on Very Large Corpora</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="184" to="198" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>R Core Team</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">R: A Language and Environment for Statistical Computing. R Foundation for Statistical Computing</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Vienna, Austria</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Comparative Evaluation of String Similarity Measures for Automatic Language Classification</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Taraka</forename><surname>Rama</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lars</forename><surname>Borin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Sequences in Language and Text</title>
		<editor>George K. Mikros and Ján Macutek</editor>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>De Gruyter Mouton</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Indo-European and Computational Cladistics</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Don</forename><surname>Ringe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ann</forename><surname>Taylor</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tandy</forename><surname>Warnow</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Transactions of the Philological Society</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">100</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="59" to="129" />
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Vocabularul Reprezentativ al Limbilor Romanice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marius</forename><surname>Sala</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Editura Academiei</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1988" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Machine Translation for Closely Related Language Pairs</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kevin</forename><surname>Scannell</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Workshop on Strategies for Developing Machine Translation for Minority Languages</title>
		<meeting>the Workshop on Strategies for Developing Machine Translation for Minority Languages</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="103" to="107" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Handbook of Parametric and Nonparametric Statistical Procedures</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>David</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Sheskin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
			<publisher>CRC Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
