<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T12:25+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">GloVe: Global Vectors for Word Representation</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date>October 25-29, 2014</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jeffrey</forename><surname>Pennington</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Computer Science Department</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Stanford University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>94305</postCode>
									<settlement>Stanford</settlement>
									<region>CA</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Richard</forename><surname>Socher</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Computer Science Department</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Stanford University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>94305</postCode>
									<settlement>Stanford</settlement>
									<region>CA</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christopher</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Manning</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Computer Science Department</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Stanford University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>94305</postCode>
									<settlement>Stanford</settlement>
									<region>CA</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">GloVe: Global Vectors for Word Representation</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2014 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP)</title>
						<meeting>the 2014 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP) <address><addrLine>Doha, Qatar. c</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="1532" to="1543"/>
							<date type="published">October 25-29, 2014</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Recent methods for learning vector space representations of words have succeeded in capturing fine-grained semantic and syntactic regularities using vector arithmetic , but the origin of these regularities has remained opaque. We analyze and make explicit the model properties needed for such regularities to emerge in word vectors. The result is a new global log-bilinear regression model that combines the advantages of the two major model families in the literature: global matrix factorization and local context window methods. Our model efficiently leverages statistical information by training only on the nonzero elements in a word-word co-occurrence matrix, rather than on the entire sparse matrix or on individual context windows in a large corpus. The model produces a vector space with meaningful sub-structure, as evidenced by its performance of 75% on a recent word analogy task. It also outperforms related models on similarity tasks and named entity recognition.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Semantic vector space models of language repre- sent each word with a real-valued vector. These vectors can be used as features in a variety of ap- plications, such as information retrieval <ref type="bibr">(Manning et al., 2008)</ref>, document classification <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">(Sebastiani, 2002</ref>), question answering ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">Tellex et al., 2003)</ref>, named entity recognition ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">Turian et al., 2010)</ref>, and parsing ( ).</p><p>Most word vector methods rely on the distance or angle between pairs of word vectors as the pri- mary method for evaluating the intrinsic quality of such a set of word representations. Recently, <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">Mikolov et al. (2013c)</ref> introduced a new evalua- tion scheme based on word analogies that probes the finer structure of the word vector space by ex- amining not the scalar distance between word vec- tors, but rather their various dimensions of dif- ference. For example, the analogy "king is to queen as man is to woman" should be encoded in the vector space by the vector equation king − queen = man − woman. This evaluation scheme favors models that produce dimensions of mean- ing, thereby capturing the multi-clustering idea of distributed representations <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Bengio, 2009)</ref>.</p><p>The two main model families for learning word vectors are: 1) global matrix factorization meth- ods, such as latent semantic analysis (LSA) <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Deerwester et al., 1990</ref>) and 2) local context window methods, such as the skip-gram model of <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">Mikolov et al. (2013c)</ref>. Currently, both families suffer sig- nificant drawbacks. While methods like LSA ef- ficiently leverage statistical information, they do relatively poorly on the word analogy task, indi- cating a sub-optimal vector space structure. Meth- ods like skip-gram may do better on the analogy task, but they poorly utilize the statistics of the cor- pus since they train on separate local context win- dows instead of on global co-occurrence counts.</p><p>In this work, we analyze the model properties necessary to produce linear directions of meaning and argue that global log-bilinear regression mod- els are appropriate for doing so. We propose a spe- cific weighted least squares model that trains on global word-word co-occurrence counts and thus makes efficient use of statistics. The model pro- duces a word vector space with meaningful sub- structure, as evidenced by its state-of-the-art per- formance of 75% accuracy on the word analogy dataset. We also demonstrate that our methods outperform other current methods on several word similarity tasks, and also on a common named en- tity recognition (NER) benchmark.</p><p>We provide the source code for the model as well as trained word vectors at http://nlp. stanford.edu/projects/glove/.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Related Work</head><p>Matrix Factorization Methods. Matrix factor- ization methods for generating low-dimensional word representations have roots stretching as far back as LSA. These methods utilize low-rank ap- proximations to decompose large matrices that capture statistical information about a corpus. The particular type of information captured by such matrices varies by application. In LSA, the ma- trices are of "term-document" type, i.e., the rows correspond to words or terms, and the columns correspond to different documents in the corpus. In contrast, the Hyperspace Analogue to Language (HAL) <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">(Lund and Burgess, 1996)</ref>, for example, utilizes matrices of "term-term" type, i.e., the rows and columns correspond to words and the entries correspond to the number of times a given word occurs in the context of another given word.</p><p>A main problem with HAL and related meth- ods is that the most frequent words contribute a disproportionate amount to the similarity measure: the number of times two words co-occur with the or and, for example, will have a large effect on their similarity despite conveying relatively little about their semantic relatedness. A number of techniques exist that addresses this shortcoming of HAL, such as the COALS method ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">Rohde et al., 2006</ref>), in which the co-occurrence matrix is first transformed by an entropy-or correlation-based normalization. An advantage of this type of trans- formation is that the raw co-occurrence counts, which for a reasonably sized corpus might span 8 or 9 orders of magnitude, are compressed so as to be distributed more evenly in a smaller inter- val. A variety of newer models also pursue this approach, including a study <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Bullinaria and Levy, 2007</ref>) that indicates that positive pointwise mu- tual information (PPMI) is a good transformation. More recently, a square root type transformation in the form of Hellinger PCA (HPCA) <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Lebret and Collobert, 2014</ref>) has been suggested as an effec- tive way of learning word representations.</p><p>Shallow Window-Based Methods. Another approach is to learn word representations that aid in making predictions within local context win- dows. For example, <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Bengio et al. (2003)</ref> intro- duced a model that learns word vector representa- tions as part of a simple neural network architec- ture for language modeling. <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Collobert and Weston (2008)</ref> decoupled the word vector training from the downstream training objectives, which paved the way for <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Collobert et al. (2011)</ref> to use the full context of a word for learning the word represen- tations, rather than just the preceding context as is the case with language models.</p><p>Recently, the importance of the full neural net- work structure for learning useful word repre- sentations has been called into question. The skip-gram and continuous bag-of-words (CBOW) models of <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Mikolov et al. (2013a)</ref> propose a sim- ple single-layer architecture based on the inner product between two word vectors. <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Mnih and Kavukcuoglu (2013)</ref> also proposed closely-related vector log-bilinear models, vLBL and ivLBL, and <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Levy et al. (2014)</ref> proposed explicit word embed- dings based on a PPMI metric.</p><p>In the skip-gram and ivLBL models, the objec- tive is to predict a word's context given the word itself, whereas the objective in the CBOW and vLBL models is to predict a word given its con- text. Through evaluation on a word analogy task, these models demonstrated the capacity to learn linguistic patterns as linear relationships between the word vectors.</p><p>Unlike the matrix factorization methods, the shallow window-based methods suffer from the disadvantage that they do not operate directly on the co-occurrence statistics of the corpus. Instead, these models scan context windows across the en- tire corpus, which fails to take advantage of the vast amount of repetition in the data.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">The GloVe Model</head><p>The statistics of word occurrences in a corpus is the primary source of information available to all unsupervised methods for learning word represen- tations, and although many such methods now ex- ist, the question still remains as to how meaning is generated from these statistics, and how the re- sulting word vectors might represent that meaning. In this section, we shed some light on this ques- tion. We use our insights to construct a new model for word representation which we call GloVe, for Global Vectors, because the global corpus statis- tics are captured directly by the model. First we establish some notation. Let the matrix of word-word co-occurrence counts be denoted by X, whose entries X i j tabulate the number of times word j occurs in the context of word i. Let X i = k X ik be the number of times any word appears in the context of word i. Finally, let P i j = P( j |i) = X i j /X i be the probability that word j appear in the <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>: Co-occurrence probabilities for target words ice and steam with selected context words from a 6 billion token corpus. Only in the ratio does noise from non-discriminative words like water and fashion cancel out, so that large values (much greater than 1) correlate well with properties specific to ice, and small values (much less than 1) correlate well with properties specific of steam. We begin with a simple example that showcases how certain aspects of meaning can be extracted directly from co-occurrence probabilities. Con- sider two words i and j that exhibit a particular as- pect of interest; for concreteness, suppose we are interested in the concept of thermodynamic phase, for which we might take i = ice and j = steam. The relationship of these words can be examined by studying the ratio of their co-occurrence prob- abilities with various probe words, k. For words k related to ice but not steam, say k = solid, we expect the ratio P ik /P j k will be large. Similarly, for words k related to steam but not ice, say k = gas, the ratio should be small. For words k like water or fashion, that are either related to both ice and steam, or to neither, the ratio should be close to one. <ref type="table">Table 1</ref> shows these probabilities and their ratios for a large corpus, and the numbers confirm these expectations. Compared to the raw probabil- ities, the ratio is better able to distinguish relevant words (solid and gas) from irrelevant words (water and fashion) and it is also better able to discrimi- nate between the two relevant words.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Probability and Ratio</head><p>The above argument suggests that the appropri- ate starting point for word vector learning should be with ratios of co-occurrence probabilities rather than the probabilities themselves. Noting that the ratio P ik /P j k depends on three words i, j, and k, the most general model takes the form,</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">F (w i , w j , ˜ w k ) = P ik P j k ,<label>(1)</label></formula><p>where w ∈ R d are word vectors and˜wand˜ and˜w ∈ R d are separate context word vectors whose role will be discussed in Section 4.2. In this equation, the right-hand side is extracted from the corpus, and F may depend on some as-of-yet unspecified pa- rameters. The number of possibilities for F is vast, but by enforcing a few desiderata we can select a unique choice. First, we would like F to encode the information present the ratio P ik /P j k in the word vector space. Since vector spaces are inher- ently linear structures, the most natural way to do this is with vector differences. With this aim, we can restrict our consideration to those functions F that depend only on the difference of the two target words, modifying Eqn. <ref type="formula" target="#formula_0">(1)</ref> to,</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">F (w i − w j , ˜ w k ) = P ik P j k .<label>(2)</label></formula><p>Next, we note that the arguments of F in Eqn. <ref type="formula" target="#formula_1">(2)</ref> are vectors while the right-hand side is a scalar. While F could be taken to be a complicated func- tion parameterized by, e.g., a neural network, do- ing so would obfuscate the linear structure we are trying to capture. To avoid this issue, we can first take the dot product of the arguments,</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">F (w i − w j ) T ˜ w k = P ik P j k ,<label>(3)</label></formula><p>which prevents F from mixing the vector dimen- sions in undesirable ways. Next, note that for word-word co-occurrence matrices, the distinction between a word and a context word is arbitrary and that we are free to exchange the two roles. To do so consistently, we must not only exchange w ↔ ˜ w but also X ↔ X T . Our final model should be in- variant under this relabeling, but Eqn. <ref type="formula" target="#formula_2">(3)</ref> is not. However, the symmetry can be restored in two steps. First, we require that F be a homomorphism between the groups (R, +) and (R &gt;0 , ×), i.e.,</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">F (w i − w j ) T ˜ w k = F (w T i ˜ w k ) F (w T j ˜ w k ) ,<label>(4)</label></formula><p>which, by Eqn. <ref type="formula" target="#formula_2">(3)</ref>, is solved by,</p><formula xml:id="formula_4">F (w T i ˜ w k ) = P ik = X ik X i .<label>(5)</label></formula><p>The solution to Eqn. <ref type="formula" target="#formula_3">(4)</ref> is F = exp, or,</p><formula xml:id="formula_5">w T i ˜ w k = log(P ik ) = log(X ik ) − log(X i ) . (6)</formula><p>Next, we note that Eqn. <ref type="formula">(6)</ref> would exhibit the ex- change symmetry if not for the log(X i ) on the right-hand side. However, this term is indepen- dent of k so it can be absorbed into a bias b i for w i . Finally, adding an additional bias˜bbias˜ bias˜b k for˜wfor˜ for˜w k restores the symmetry,</p><formula xml:id="formula_6">w T i ˜ w k + b i + ˜ b k = log(X ik ) .<label>(7)</label></formula><p>Eqn. <ref type="formula" target="#formula_6">(7)</ref> is a drastic simplification over Eqn. <ref type="formula" target="#formula_0">(1)</ref>, but it is actually ill-defined since the logarithm di- verges whenever its argument is zero. One reso- lution to this issue is to include an additive shift in the logarithm, log(X ik ) → log(1 + X ik ), which maintains the sparsity of X while avoiding the di- vergences. The idea of factorizing the log of the co-occurrence matrix is closely related to LSA and we will use the resulting model as a baseline in our experiments. A main drawback to this model is that it weighs all co-occurrences equally, even those that happen rarely or never. Such rare co- occurrences are noisy and carry less information than the more frequent ones -yet even just the zero entries account for 75-95% of the data in X, depending on the vocabulary size and corpus.</p><p>We propose a new weighted least squares re- gression model that addresses these problems. Casting Eqn. <ref type="formula" target="#formula_6">(7)</ref> as a least squares problem and introducing a weighting function f (X i j ) into the cost function gives us the model</p><formula xml:id="formula_7">J = V i, j=1 f X i j w T i ˜ w j + b i + ˜ b j − log X i j 2 ,<label>(8)</label></formula><p>where V is the size of the vocabulary. The weight- ing function should obey the following properties:</p><p>1. f (0) = 0. If f is viewed as a continuous function, it should vanish as x → 0 fast enough that the lim x→0 f (x) log 2 x is finite.</p><p>2. f (x) should be non-decreasing so that rare co-occurrences are not overweighted.</p><p>3. f (x) should be relatively small for large val- ues of x, so that frequent co-occurrences are not overweighted.</p><p>Of course a large number of functions satisfy these properties, but one class of functions that we found to work well can be parameterized as, The performance of the model depends weakly on the cutoff, which we fix to x max = 100 for all our experiments. We found that α = 3/4 gives a mod- est improvement over a linear version with α = 1. Although we offer only empirical motivation for choosing the value 3/4, it is interesting that a sim- ilar fractional power scaling was found to give the best performance in (Mikolov et al., 2013a).</p><formula xml:id="formula_8">f (x) = (x/x max ) α if x &lt; x max 1 otherwise .<label>(9)</label></formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Relationship to Other Models</head><p>Because all unsupervised methods for learning word vectors are ultimately based on the occur- rence statistics of a corpus, there should be com- monalities between the models. Nevertheless, cer- tain models remain somewhat opaque in this re- gard, particularly the recent window-based meth- ods like skip-gram and ivLBL. Therefore, in this subsection we show how these models are related to our proposed model, as defined in Eqn. (8).</p><p>The starting point for the skip-gram or ivLBL methods is a model Q i j for the probability that word j appears in the context of word i. For con- creteness, let us assume that Q i j is a softmax,</p><formula xml:id="formula_9">Q i j = exp(w T i ˜ w j ) V k=1 exp(w T i ˜ w k ) .<label>(10)</label></formula><p>Most of the details of these models are irrelevant for our purposes, aside from the the fact that they attempt to maximize the log probability as a con- text window scans over the corpus. Training pro- ceeds in an on-line, stochastic fashion, but the im- plied global objective function can be written as,</p><formula xml:id="formula_10">J = − i ∈corpus j ∈context(i) log Q i j .<label>(11)</label></formula><p>Evaluating the normalization factor of the soft- max for each term in this sum is costly. To al- low for efficient training, the skip-gram and ivLBL models introduce approximations to Q i j . How- ever, the sum in Eqn. (11) can be evaluated much more efficiently if we first group together those terms that have the same values for i and j,</p><formula xml:id="formula_11">J = − V i=1 V j=1 X i j log Q i j ,<label>(12)</label></formula><p>where we have used the fact that the number of like terms is given by the co-occurrence matrix X. Recalling our notation for X i = k X ik and P i j = X i j /X i , we can rewrite J as,</p><formula xml:id="formula_12">J = − V i=1 X i V j=1 P i j log Q i j = V i=1 X i H (P i ,Q i ) ,<label>(13)</label></formula><p>where H (P i ,Q i ) is the cross entropy of the dis- tributions P i and Q i , which we define in analogy to X i . As a weighted sum of cross-entropy error, this objective bears some formal resemblance to the weighted least squares objective of Eqn. (8). In fact, it is possible to optimize Eqn. <ref type="formula" target="#formula_0">(13)</ref> directly as opposed to the on-line training methods used in the skip-gram and ivLBL models. One could inter- pret this objective as a "global skip-gram" model, and it might be interesting to investigate further. On the other hand, Eqn. (13) exhibits a number of undesirable properties that ought to be addressed before adopting it as a model for learning word vectors.</p><p>To begin, cross entropy error is just one among many possible distance measures between prob- ability distributions, and it has the unfortunate property that distributions with long tails are of- ten modeled poorly with too much weight given to the unlikely events. Furthermore, for the mea- sure to be bounded it requires that the model dis- tribution Q be properly normalized. This presents a computational bottleneck owing to the sum over the whole vocabulary in Eqn. (10), and it would be desirable to consider a different distance measure that did not require this property of Q. A natural choice would be a least squares objective in which normalization factors in Q and P are discarded,</p><formula xml:id="formula_13">ˆ J = i, j X i ˆ P i j − ˆ Q i j 2<label>(14)</label></formula><p>wherê P i j = X i j andˆQandˆ andˆQ i j = exp(w T i ˜ w j ) are the unnormalized distributions. At this stage another problem emerges, namely that X i j often takes very large values, which can complicate the optimiza- tion. An effective remedy is to minimize the squared error of the logarithms ofˆPofˆ ofˆP andˆQandˆ andˆQ instead,</p><formula xml:id="formula_14">ˆ J = i, j X i logˆPlogˆ logˆP i j − logˆQlogˆ logˆQ i j 2 = i, j X i w T i ˜ w j − log X i j 2 .<label>(15)</label></formula><p>Finally, we observe that while the weighting factor X i is preordained by the on-line training method inherent to the skip-gram and ivLBL models, it is by no means guaranteed to be optimal. In fact, <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Mikolov et al. (2013a)</ref> observe that performance can be increased by filtering the data so as to re- duce the effective value of the weighting factor for frequent words. With this in mind, we introduce a more general weighting function, which we are free to take to depend on the context word as well.</p><p>The result is,</p><formula xml:id="formula_15">ˆ J = i, j f (X i j ) w T i ˜ w j − log X i j 2 ,<label>(16)</label></formula><p>which is equivalent 1 to the cost function of Eqn. <ref type="formula" target="#formula_7">(8)</ref>, which we derived previously.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Complexity of the model</head><p>As can be seen from Eqn. <ref type="formula" target="#formula_7">(8)</ref> and the explicit form of the weighting function f (X ), the computational complexity of the model depends on the number of nonzero elements in the matrix X. As this num- ber is always less than the total number of en- tries of the matrix, the model scales no worse than O(|V | 2 ). At first glance this might seem like a sub- stantial improvement over the shallow window- based approaches, which scale with the corpus size, |C|. However, typical vocabularies have hun- dreds of thousands of words, so that |V | 2 can be in the hundreds of billions, which is actually much larger than most corpora. For this reason it is im- portant to determine whether a tighter bound can be placed on the number of nonzero elements of X.</p><p>In order to make any concrete statements about the number of nonzero elements in X, it is neces- sary to make some assumptions about the distribu- tion of word co-occurrences. In particular, we will assume that the number of co-occurrences of word i with word j, X i j , can be modeled as a power-law function of the frequency rank of that word pair, r i j :</p><formula xml:id="formula_16">X i j = k (r i j ) α .<label>(17)</label></formula><p>The total number of words in the corpus is pro- portional to the sum over all elements of the co- occurrence matrix X,</p><formula xml:id="formula_17">|C| ∼ i j X i j = | X | r =1 k r α = k H | X |,α ,<label>(18)</label></formula><p>where we have rewritten the last sum in terms of the generalized harmonic number H n, m . The up- per limit of the sum, |X |, is the maximum fre- quency rank, which coincides with the number of nonzero elements in the matrix X. This number is also equal to the maximum value of r in Eqn. <ref type="formula" target="#formula_0">(17)</ref> such that X i j ≥ 1, i.e., |X | = k 1/α . Therefore we can write Eqn. <ref type="formula" target="#formula_0">(18)</ref> as,</p><formula xml:id="formula_18">|C| ∼ |X | α H | X |,α .<label>(19)</label></formula><p>We are interested in how |X | is related to |C| when both numbers are large; therefore we are free to expand the right hand side of the equation for large |X |. For this purpose we use the expansion of gen- eralized harmonic numbers <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Apostol, 1976)</ref>,</p><formula xml:id="formula_19">H x, s = x 1−s 1 − s + ζ (s) + O(x −s ) if s &gt; 0, s 1 ,<label>(20)</label></formula><p>giving,</p><formula xml:id="formula_20">|C| ∼ |X | 1 − α + ζ (α) |X | α + O(1) ,<label>(21)</label></formula><p>where ζ (s) is the Riemann zeta function. In the limit that X is large, only one of the two terms on the right hand side of Eqn. (21) will be relevant, and which term that is depends on whether α &gt; 1,</p><formula xml:id="formula_21">|X | = O(|C|) if α &lt; 1, O(|C| 1/α ) if α &gt; 1.<label>(22)</label></formula><p>For the corpora studied in this article, we observe that X i j is well-modeled by Eqn. (17) with α = 1.25. In this case we have that |X | = O(|C| 0.8 ).</p><p>Therefore we conclude that the complexity of the model is much better than the worst case O(V 2 ), and in fact it does somewhat better than the on-line window-based methods which scale like O(|C|).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Experiments</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">Evaluation methods</head><p>We conduct experiments on the word analogy task of <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Mikolov et al. (2013a)</ref>, a variety of word similarity tasks, as described in ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Luong et al., 2013)</ref>, and on the CoNLL-2003 shared benchmark <ref type="table">Table 2</ref>: Results on the word analogy task, given as percent accuracy. Underlined scores are best within groups of similarly-sized models; bold scores are best overall. HPCA vectors are publicly available 2 ; (i)vLBL results are from ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Mnih et al., 2013)</ref>; skip-gram (SG) and CBOW results are from (Mikolov et al., 2013a,b); we trained SG † and CBOW † using the word2vec tool 3 . See text for details and a description of the SVD models. Word analogies. The word analogy task con- sists of questions like, "a is to b as c is to ?" The dataset contains 19,544 such questions, di- vided into a semantic subset and a syntactic sub- set. The semantic questions are typically analogies about people or places, like "Athens is to Greece as Berlin is to ?". The syntactic questions are typically analogies about verb tenses or forms of adjectives, for example "dance is to dancing as fly is to ?". To correctly answer the question, the model should uniquely identify the missing term, with only an exact correspondence counted as a correct match. We answer the question "a is to b as c is to ?" by finding the word d whose repre- sentation w d is closest to w b − w a + w c according to the cosine similarity. 4  <ref type="figure">Figure 2</ref>: Accuracy on the analogy task as function of vector size and window size/type. All models are trained on the 6 billion token corpus. In (a), the window size is 10. In (b) and (c), the vector size is 100.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Model</head><p>Word similarity. While the analogy task is our primary focus since it tests for interesting vector space substructures, we also evaluate our model on a variety of word similarity tasks in <ref type="table">Table 3</ref>. These include <ref type="bibr">WordSim-353 (Finkelstein et al., 2001</ref>), MC <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">(Miller and Charles, 1991)</ref>, RG <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">(Rubenstein and Goodenough, 1965)</ref>, SCWS ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Huang et al., 2012)</ref>, and RW ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Luong et al., 2013)</ref>. Named entity recognition. The CoNLL-2003 English benchmark dataset for NER is a collec- tion of documents from Reuters newswire articles, annotated with four entity types: person, location, organization, and miscellaneous. We train mod- els on CoNLL-03 training data on test on three datasets: 1) ConLL-03 testing data, 2) ACE Phase 2 (2001-02) and ACE-2003 data, and 3) MUC7 Formal Run test set. We adopt the BIO2 annota- tion standard, as well as all the preprocessing steps described in ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">Wang and Manning, 2013)</ref>. We use a comprehensive set of discrete features that comes with the standard distribution of the Stanford NER model ( <ref type="bibr">Finkel et al., 2005)</ref>. A total of 437,905 discrete features were generated for the CoNLL- 2003 training dataset. In addition, 50-dimensional vectors for each word of a five-word context are added and used as continuous features. With these features as input, we trained a conditional random field (CRF) with exactly the same setup as the CRF join model of ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">Wang and Manning, 2013</ref>).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">Corpora and training details</head><p>We trained our model on five corpora of varying sizes: a 2010 Wikipedia dump with 1 billion to- kens; a 2014 Wikipedia dump with 1.6 billion to- kens; Gigaword 5 which has 4.3 billion tokens; the combination Gigaword5 + Wikipedia2014, which the analogy task. This number is evaluated on a subset of the dataset so it is not included in <ref type="table">Table 2</ref>. 3COSMUL performed worse than cosine similarity in almost all of our experiments. has 6 billion tokens; and on 42 billion tokens of web data, from Common Crawl <ref type="bibr">5</ref> . We tokenize and lowercase each corpus with the Stanford to- kenizer, build a vocabulary of the 400,000 most frequent words 6 , and then construct a matrix of co- occurrence counts X. In constructing X, we must choose how large the context window should be and whether to distinguish left context from right context. We explore the effect of these choices be- low. In all cases we use a decreasing weighting function, so that word pairs that are d words apart contribute 1/d to the total count. This is one way to account for the fact that very distant word pairs are expected to contain less relevant information about the words' relationship to one another.</p><p>For all our experiments, we set x max = 100, α = 3/4, and train the model using AdaGrad <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Duchi et al., 2011</ref>), stochastically sampling non- zero elements from X, with initial learning rate of 0.05. We run 50 iterations for vectors smaller than 300 dimensions, and 100 iterations otherwise (see Section 4.6 for more details about the convergence rate). Unless otherwise noted, we use a context of ten words to the left and ten words to the right.</p><p>The model generates two sets of word vectors, W and˜Wand˜ and˜W . When X is symmetric, W and˜Wand˜ and˜W are equivalent and differ only as a result of their ran- dom initializations; the two sets of vectors should perform equivalently. On the other hand, there is evidence that for certain types of neural networks, training multiple instances of the network and then combining the results can help reduce overfitting and noise and generally improve results ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Ciresan et al., 2012)</ref>. With this in mind, we choose to use the sum W + ˜ W as our word vectors. Doing so typ- ically gives a small boost in performance, with the biggest increase in the semantic analogy task.</p><p>We compare with the published results of a va- riety of state-of-the-art models, as well as with our own results produced using the word2vec tool and with several baselines using SVDs. With word2vec, we train the skip-gram (SG † ) and continuous bag-of-words (CBOW † ) models on the 6 billion token corpus (Wikipedia 2014 + Giga- word 5) with a vocabulary of the top 400,000 most frequent words and a context window size of 10. We used 10 negative samples, which we show in Section 4.6 to be a good choice for this corpus.</p><p>For the SVD baselines, we generate a truncated matrix X trunc which retains the information of how frequently each word occurs with only the top 10,000 most frequent words. This step is typi- cal of many matrix-factorization-based methods as the extra columns can contribute a disproportion- ate number of zero entries and the methods are otherwise computationally expensive.</p><p>The singular vectors of this matrix constitute the baseline "SVD". We also evaluate two related baselines: "SVD-S" in which we take the SVD of √ X trunc , and "SVD-L" in which we take the SVD of log(1+ X trunc ). Both methods help compress the otherwise large range of values in X. <ref type="bibr">7</ref> </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3">Results</head><p>We present results on the word analogy task in Ta- ble 2. The GloVe model performs significantly better than the other baselines, often with smaller vector sizes and smaller corpora. Our results us- ing the word2vec tool are somewhat better than most of the previously published results. This is due to a number of factors, including our choice to use negative sampling (which typically works bet- ter than the hierarchical softmax), the number of negative samples, and the choice of the corpus.</p><p>We demonstrate that the model can easily be trained on a large 42 billion token corpus, with a substantial corresponding performance boost. We note that increasing the corpus size does not guar- antee improved results for other models, as can be seen by the decreased performance of the SVD- <ref type="bibr">7</ref> We also investigated several other weighting schemes for transforming X; what we report here performed best. Many weighting schemes like PPMI destroy the sparsity of X and therefore cannot feasibly be used with large vocabularies. With smaller vocabularies, these information-theoretic trans- formations do indeed work well on word similarity measures, but they perform very poorly on the word analogy task. <ref type="table">Table 3</ref>: Spearman rank correlation on word simi- larity tasks. All vectors are 300-dimensional. The CBOW * vectors are from the word2vec website and differ in that they contain phrase vectors. L model on this larger corpus. The fact that this basic SVD model does not scale well to large cor- pora lends further evidence to the necessity of the type of weighting scheme proposed in our model. <ref type="table">Table 3</ref> shows results on five different word similarity datasets. A similarity score is obtained from the word vectors by first normalizing each feature across the vocabulary and then calculat- ing the cosine similarity. We compute Spearman's rank correlation coefficient between this score and the human judgments. CBOW * denotes the vec- tors available on the word2vec website that are trained with word and phrase vectors on 100B words of news data. GloVe outperforms it while using a corpus less than half the size. <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">Table 4</ref> shows results on the NER task with the CRF-based model. The L-BFGS training termi- nates when no improvement has been achieved on the dev set for 25 iterations. Otherwise all config- urations are identical to those used by <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">Wang and Manning (2013)</ref>. The model labeled Discrete is the baseline using a comprehensive set of discrete features that comes with the standard distribution of the Stanford NER model, but with no word vec- tor features. In addition to the HPCA and SVD models discussed previously, we also compare to the models of <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Huang et al. (2012)</ref>  <ref type="figure">(HSMN)</ref> and <ref type="bibr">Collobert and Weston (2008) (CW)</ref>. We trained the CBOW model using the word2vec tool 8 . The GloVe model outperforms all other methods on all evaluation metrics, except for the CoNLL test set, on which the HPCA method does slightly better. We conclude that the GloVe vectors are useful in downstream NLP tasks, as was first shown for neural vectors in ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">Turian et al., 2010</ref>).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Model</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.4">Model Analysis: Vector Length and Context Size</head><p>In <ref type="figure">Fig. 2</ref>, we show the results of experiments that vary vector length and context window. A context window that extends to the left and right of a tar- get word will be called symmetric, and one which extends only to the left will be called asymmet- ric. In (a), we observe diminishing returns for vec- tors larger than about 200 dimensions. In (b) and (c), we examine the effect of varying the window size for symmetric and asymmetric context win- dows. Performance is better on the syntactic sub- task for small and asymmetric context windows, which aligns with the intuition that syntactic infor- mation is mostly drawn from the immediate con- text and can depend strongly on word order. Se- mantic information, on the other hand, is more fre- quently non-local, and more of it is captured with larger window sizes.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.5">Model Analysis: Corpus Size</head><p>In <ref type="figure">Fig. 3</ref>, we show performance on the word anal- ogy task for 300-dimensional vectors trained on different corpora. On the syntactic subtask, there is a monotonic increase in performance as the cor- pus size increases. This is to be expected since larger corpora typically produce better statistics. Interestingly, the same trend is not true for the se- mantic subtask, where the models trained on the smaller Wikipedia corpora do better than those trained on the larger Gigaword corpus. This is likely due to the large number of city-and country- based analogies in the analogy dataset and the fact that Wikipedia has fairly comprehensive articles for most such locations. Moreover, Wikipedia's  <ref type="figure">Figure 3</ref>: Accuracy on the analogy task for 300- dimensional vectors trained on different corpora.</p><p>entries are updated to assimilate new knowledge, whereas Gigaword is a fixed news repository with outdated and possibly incorrect information.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.6">Model Analysis: Run-time</head><p>The total run-time is split between populating X and training the model. The former depends on many factors, including window size, vocabulary size, and corpus size. Though we did not do so, this step could easily be parallelized across mul- tiple machines (see, e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Lebret and Collobert (2014)</ref> for some benchmarks). Using a single thread of a dual 2.1GHz Intel Xeon E5-2658 ma- chine, populating X with a 10 word symmetric context window, a 400,000 word vocabulary, and a 6 billion token corpus takes about 85 minutes. Given X, the time it takes to train the model de- pends on the vector size and the number of itera- tions. For 300-dimensional vectors with the above settings (and using all 32 cores of the above ma- chine), a single iteration takes 14 minutes. See <ref type="figure">Fig. 4</ref> for a plot of the learning curve.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.7">Model Analysis: Comparison with word2vec</head><p>A rigorous quantitative comparison of GloVe with word2vec is complicated by the existence of many parameters that have a strong effect on per- formance. We control for the main sources of vari- ation that we identified in Sections 4.4 and 4.5 by setting the vector length, context window size, cor- pus, and vocabulary size to the configuration men- tioned in the previous subsection. The most important remaining variable to con- trol for is training time. For GloVe, the rele- vant parameter is the number of training iterations. For word2vec, the obvious choice would be the number of training epochs. Unfortunately, the code is currently designed for only a single epoch:   <ref type="figure">Figure 4</ref>: Overall accuracy on the word analogy task as a function of training time, which is governed by the number of iterations for GloVe and by the number of negative samples for CBOW (a) and skip-gram (b). In all cases, we train 300-dimensional vectors on the same 6B token corpus (Wikipedia 2014 + Gigaword 5) with the same 400,000 word vocabulary, and use a symmetric context window of size 10.</p><p>it specifies a learning schedule specific to a single pass through the data, making a modification for multiple passes a non-trivial task. Another choice is to vary the number of negative samples. Adding negative samples effectively increases the number of training words seen by the model, so in some ways it is analogous to extra epochs. We set any unspecified parameters to their de- fault values, assuming that they are close to opti- mal, though we acknowledge that this simplifica- tion should be relaxed in a more thorough analysis.</p><p>In <ref type="figure">Fig. 4</ref>, we plot the overall performance on the analogy task as a function of training time.</p><p>The two x-axes at the bottom indicate the corre- sponding number of training iterations for GloVe and negative samples for word2vec. We note that word2vec's performance actually decreases if the number of negative samples increases be- yond about 10. Presumably this is because the negative sampling method does not approximate the target probability distribution well. <ref type="bibr">9</ref> For the same corpus, vocabulary, window size, and training time, GloVe consistently outperforms word2vec. It achieves better results faster, and also obtains the best results irrespective of speed.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Conclusion</head><p>Recently, considerable attention has been focused on the question of whether distributional word representations are best learned from count-based</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: Weighting function f with α = 3/4.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3" validated="false"><head>Table 4 : F1 score on NER task with 50d vectors. Discrete is the baseline without word vectors. We use publicly-available vectors for HPCA, HSMN, and CW. See text for details.</head><label>4</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Model 
Dev Test ACE MUC7 
Discrete 91.0 85.4 77.4 
73.4 
SVD 
90.8 85.7 77.3 
73.7 
SVD-S 91.0 85.5 77.6 
74.3 
SVD-L 90.5 84.8 73.6 
71.5 
HPCA 92.6 88.7 81.7 
80.7 
HSMN 90.5 85.7 78.7 
74.7 
CW 
92.2 87.4 81.7 
80.2 
CBOW 93.1 88.2 82.2 
81.1 
GloVe 
93.2 88.3 82.9 
82.2 

</table></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> We could also include bias terms in Eqn. (16).</note>

			<note place="foot" n="2"> http://lebret.ch/words/ 3 http://code.google.com/p/word2vec/ 4 Levy et al. (2014) introduce a multiplicative analogy evaluation, 3COSMUL, and report an accuracy of 68.24% on</note>

			<note place="foot" n="5"> To demonstrate the scalability of the model, we also trained it on a much larger sixth corpus, containing 840 billion tokens of web data, but in this case we did not lowercase the vocabulary, so the results are not directly comparable. 6 For the model trained on Common Crawl data, we use a larger vocabulary of about 2 million words.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="8"> We use the same parameters as above, except in this case we found 5 negative samples to work slightly better than 10.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="9"> In contrast, noise-contrastive estimation is an approximation which improves with more negative samples. In Table 1 of (Mnih et al., 2013), accuracy on the analogy task is a non-decreasing function of the number of negative samples. methods or from prediction-based methods. Currently, prediction-based models garner substantial support; for example, Baroni et al. (2014) argue that these models perform better across a range of tasks. In this work we argue that the two classes of methods are not dramatically different at a fundamental level since they both probe the underlying co-occurrence statistics of the corpus, but the efficiency with which the count-based methods capture global statistics can be advantageous. We construct a model that utilizes this main benefit of count data while simultaneously capturing the meaningful linear substructures prevalent in recent log-bilinear prediction-based methods like word2vec. The result, GloVe, is a new global log-bilinear regression model for the unsupervised learning of word representations that outperforms other models on word analogy, word similarity, and named entity recognition tasks.</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>We thank the anonymous reviewers for their valu-able comments. Stanford University gratefully acknowledges the support of the Defense Threat Reduction Agency (DTRA) under Air Force Re-search Laboratory (AFRL) contract no. FA8650-10-C-7020 and the Defense Advanced Research Projects Agency (DARPA) Deep Exploration and Filtering of Text (DEFT) Program under AFRL contract no. FA8750-13-2-0040. Any opinions, findings, and conclusion or recommendations ex-pressed in this material are those of the authors and do not necessarily reflect the view of the DTRA, AFRL, DEFT, or the US government.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tom</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Apostol</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Introduction to Analytic Number Theory. Introduction to Analytic Number Theory</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1976" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Don&apos;t count, predict! A systematic comparison of context-counting vs. context-predicting semantic vectors</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marco</forename><surname>Baroni</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Georgiana</forename><surname>Dinu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Germán</forename><surname>Kruszewski</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ACL</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Learning deep architectures for AI. Foundations and Trends in Machine Learning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yoshua</forename><surname>Bengio</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A neural probabilistic language model</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yoshua</forename><surname>Bengio</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Réjean</forename><surname>Ducharme</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">JMLR</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1137" to="1155" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Pascal Vincent, and Christian Janvin</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Extracting semantic representations from word cooccurrence statistics: A computational study</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">John</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Bullinaria</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Joseph</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Levy</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Behavior Research Methods</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">39</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="510" to="526" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Deep neural networks segment neuronal membranes in electron microscopy images</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dan</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Ciresan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alessandro</forename><surname>Giusti</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Luca</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jürgen</forename><surname>Gambardella</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Schmidhuber</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">NIPS</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2852" to="2860" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A unified architecture for natural language processing: deep neural networks with multitask learning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ronan</forename><surname>Collobert</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jason</forename><surname>Weston</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of ICML</title>
		<meeting>ICML</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="160" to="167" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ronan</forename><surname>Collobert</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jason</forename><surname>Weston</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Léon</forename><surname>Bottou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Karlen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Koray</forename><surname>Kavukcuoglu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Pavel</forename><surname>Kuksa</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Natural Language Processing</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2493" to="2537" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Indexing by latent semantic analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Scott</forename><surname>Deerwester</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Susan</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Dumais</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">George</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Furnas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Thomas</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Landauer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Richard</forename><surname>Harshman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of the American Society for Information Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page">41</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1990" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Adaptive subgradient methods for online learning and stochastic optimization</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">John</forename><surname>Duchi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Elad</forename><surname>Hazan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yoram</forename><surname>Singer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<publisher>JMLR</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="page">12</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Placing search in context: The concept revisited</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lev</forename><surname>Finkelstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Evgenly</forename><surname>Gabrilovich</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yossi</forename><surname>Matias</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ehud</forename><surname>Rivlin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Zach</forename><surname>Solan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gadi</forename><surname>Wolfman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Eytan</forename><surname>Ruppin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 10th international conference on World Wide Web</title>
		<meeting>the 10th international conference on World Wide Web</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="406" to="414" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Improving Word Representations via Global Context and Multiple Word Prototypes</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Eric</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Richard</forename><surname>Socher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christopher</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Manning</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Andrew</forename><forename type="middle">Y</forename><surname>Ng</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ACL</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Word embeddings through Hellinger PCA</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rémi</forename><surname>Lebret</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ronan</forename><surname>Collobert</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">EACL</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Linguistic regularities in sparse and explicit word representations</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Omer</forename><surname>Levy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yoav</forename><surname>Goldberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Israel</forename><surname>Ramatgan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Producing high-dimensional semantic spaces from lexical co-occurrence</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kevin</forename><surname>Lund</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Curt</forename><surname>Burgess</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Behavior Research Methods, Instrumentation, and Computers</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">28</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="203" to="208" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Better word representations with recursive neural networks for morphology</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Minh-Thang</forename><surname>Luong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Richard</forename><surname>Socher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christopher D</forename><surname>Manning</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Efficient Estimation of Word Representations in Vector Space</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tomas</forename><surname>Mikolov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kai</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Greg</forename><surname>Corrado</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jeffrey</forename><surname>Dean</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ICLR Workshop Papers</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Distributed representations of words and phrases and their compositionality</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tomas</forename><surname>Mikolov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ilya</forename><surname>Sutskever</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kai</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Greg</forename><surname>Corrado</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jeffrey</forename><surname>Dean</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">NIPS</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3111" to="3119" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Linguistic regularities in continuous space word representations</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tomas</forename><surname>Mikolov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Geoffrey</forename><surname>Wen Tau Yih</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Zweig</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">HLTNAACL</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Contextual correlates of semantic similarity</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>George</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Walter</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Miller</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Charles</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Language and cognitive processes</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="28" />
			<date type="published" when="1991" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Learning word embeddings efficiently with noise-contrastive estimation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Andriy</forename><surname>Mnih</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Koray</forename><surname>Kavukcuoglu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">NIPS</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">An improved model of semantic similarity based on lexical co-occurence</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Douglas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Laura</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Rohde</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Gonnerman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Plaut</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Communications of the ACM</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="627" to="633" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Contextual correlates of synonymy</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Herbert</forename><surname>Rubenstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">John</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Goodenough</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Communications of the ACM</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="627" to="633" />
			<date type="published" when="1965" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Machine learning in automated text categorization</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Fabrizio</forename><surname>Sebastiani</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">ACM Computing Surveys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">34</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="47" />
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Parsing With Compositional Vector Grammars</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Richard</forename><surname>Socher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">John</forename><surname>Bauer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christopher</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Manning</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Andrew</forename><forename type="middle">Y</forename><surname>Ng</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ACL</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Quantitative evaluation of passage retrieval algorithms for question answering</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Stefanie</forename><surname>Tellex</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Boris</forename><surname>Katz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jimmy</forename><surname>Lin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Aaron</forename><surname>Fernandes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gregory</forename><surname>Marton</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the SIGIR Conference on Research and Development in Informaion Retrieval</title>
		<meeting>the SIGIR Conference on Research and Development in Informaion Retrieval</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Introduction to the CoNLL-2003 shared task: Language-independent named entity recognition</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Erik</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">CoNLL-2003</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Tjong Kim Sang and Fien De Meulder</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Word representations: a simple and general method for semi-supervised learning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Joseph</forename><surname>Turian</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lev</forename><surname>Ratinov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yoshua</forename><surname>Bengio</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of ACL</title>
		<meeting>ACL</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="384" to="394" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Effect of non-linear deep architecture in sequence labeling</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mengqiu</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Christopher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Manning</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 6th International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing</title>
		<meeting>the 6th International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>IJCNLP</note>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
