<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T11:50+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Constructing Information Networks Using One Single Model</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date>October 25-29, 2014</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Qi</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">†</forename><surname>Heng</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ji</forename></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yu</forename><surname>Hong</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">School of Computer Science and Technology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Soochow University</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sujian</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="laboratory">Key Laboratory of Computational Linguistics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Peking University</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>MOE</addrLine>
									<country>China †</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">¶</forename></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Computer Science Department</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Constructing Information Networks Using One Single Model</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2014 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP)</title>
						<meeting>the 2014 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP) <address><addrLine>Doha, Qatar. c</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="1846" to="1851"/>
							<date type="published">October 25-29, 2014</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>In this paper, we propose a new framework that unifies the output of three information extraction (IE) tasks-entity mentions , relations and events as an information network representation, and extracts all of them using one single joint model based on structured prediction. This novel formulation allows different parts of the information network fully interact with each other. For example, many relations can now be considered as the resultant states of events. Our approach achieves substantial improvements over traditional pipelined approaches, and significantly advances state-of-the-art end-to-end event argument extraction.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Information extraction (IE) aims to discover entity mentions, relations and events from unstructured texts, and these three subtasks are closely inter- dependent: entity mentions are core components of relations and events, and the extraction of rela- tions and events can help to accurately recognize entity mentions. In addition, the theory of eventu- alities <ref type="bibr">(Dölling, 2011)</ref> suggested that relations can be viewed as states that events start from and result in. Therefore, it is intuitive but challenging to ex- tract all of them simultaneously in a single model. Some recent research attempted to jointly model multiple IE subtasks (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(Roth and Yih, 2007;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Riedel and McCallum, 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Yang and Cardie, 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Riedel et al., 2009;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Singh et al., 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Li et al., 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Li and Ji, 2014)</ref>). For example, <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Roth and Yih (2007)</ref> conducted joint inference over entity mentions and relations; Our previous work jointly extracted event triggers and arguments ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Li et al., 2013)</ref>, and entity mentions and relations <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Li and Ji, 2014</ref>). However, a single model that can ex- tract all of them has never been studied so far.  For the first time, we uniformly represent the IE output from each sentence as an information net- work, where entity mentions and event triggers are nodes, relations and event-argument links are arcs. We apply a structured perceptron framework with a segment-based beam-search algorithm to con- struct the information networks <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Collins, 2002;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Li et al., 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Li and Ji, 2014</ref>). In addition to the per- ceptron update, we also apply k-best MIRA <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(McDonald et al., 2005</ref>), which refines the perceptron update in three aspects: it is flexible in using var- ious loss functions, it is a large-margin approach, and it can use mulitple candidate structures to tune feature weights.</p><p>In an information network, we can capture the interactions among multiple nodes by learning joint features during training. In addition to the cross-component dependencies studied in <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Li et al., 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Li and Ji, 2014)</ref>, we are able to cap- ture interactions between relations and events. For example, in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref>, if we know that the Person mention "Asif Mohammed Hanif " is an Attacker of the Attack event triggered by "detonated", and the Weapon mention "explosives" is an Instrument, we can infer that there exists an Agent-Artifact relation between them. Similarly we can infer the Physical relation between "Asif Mohammed Hanif " and "Tel Aviv".</p><p>However, in practice many useful interactions are missing during testing because of the data spar-sity problem of event triggers. We observe that 21.5% of event triggers appear fewer than twice in the ACE'05 1 training data. By using only lexical and syntactic features we are not able to discover the corresponding nodes and their connections. To tackle this problem, we use FrameNet ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Baker and Sato, 2003)</ref> to generalize event triggers so that semantically similar triggers are clustered in the same frame.</p><p>The following sections will elaborate the de- tailed implementation of our new framework.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Approach</head><p>We uniformly represent the IE output from each sentence as an information network y = (V, E). Each node v i ∈ V is represented as a triple u i , v i , t i of start index u i , end index v i , and node type t i . A node can be an entity mention or an event trigger. A particular type of node is ⊥ (nei- ther entity mention nor event trigger), whose max- imal length is always 1. Similarly, each infor- mation arc e j ∈ E is represented as u j , v j , r j , where u j and v j are the end offsets of the nodes, and r j is the arc type. For instance, in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Fig- ure 1</ref>, the event trigger "detonated" is represented as 4, 4, Attack, the entity mention "Asif Mo- hammed Hanif " is represented as 1, 3, Person, and their argument arc is 4, 3, Attacker. Our goal is to extract the whole information network y for a given sentence x.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">Decoding Algorithm</head><p>Our joint decoding algorithm is based on ex- tending the segment-based algorithm described in our previous work <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Li and Ji, 2014)</ref>. Let x = (x 1 , ..., x m ) be the input sentence. The decoder performs two types of actions at each token x i from left to right:</p><p>• NODEACTION(i, j): appends a new node j, i, t ending at the i-th token, where i − d t &lt; j ≤ i, and d t is the maximal length of type-t nodes in training data.</p><p>• ARCACTION(i, j): for each j &lt; i, incremen- tally creates a new arc between the nodes ending at the j-th and i-th tokens respectively: i, j, r.</p><p>After each action, the top-k hypotheses are se- lected according to their features f (x, y ) and 1 http://www.itl.nist.gov/iad/mig//tests/ace weights w:</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">best k y ∈buffer f (x, y ) · w</formula><p>Since a relation can only occur between a pair of entity mentions, an argument arc can only occur between an entity mention and an event trigger, and each edge must obey certain entity type con- straints, during the search we prune invalid AR- CACTIONs by checking the types of the nodes ending at the j-th and the i-th tokens. Finally, the top hypothesis in the beam is returned as the final prediction. The upper-bound time complexity of the decoding algorithm is</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">O(d · b · m 2 )</formula><p>, where d is the maximum size of nodes, b is the beam size, and m is the sentence length. The actual execution time is much shorter, especially when entity type constraints are applied.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">Parameter Estimation</head><p>For each training instance (x, y), the structured perceptron algorithm seeks the assignment with the highest model score:</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">z = argmax y ∈Y(x)</formula><p>f (x, y ) · w and then updates the feature weights by using:</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">w new = w + f (x, y) − f (x, z)</formula><p>We relax the exact inference problem by the afore- mentioned beam-search procedure. The stan- dard perceptron will cause invalid updates be- cause of inexact search. Therefore we apply early- update ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Collins and Roark, 2004</ref>), an instance of violation-fixing methods ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Huang et al., 2012</ref>). In the rest of this paper, we override y and z to denote prefixes of structures. In addition to the simple perceptron update, we also apply k-best MIRA ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">McDonald et al., 2005</ref>), an online large-margin learning algorithm. During each update, it keeps the norm of the change to feature weights w as small as possible, and forces the margin between y and the k-best candidate z greater or equal to their loss L(y, z). It is formu- lated as a quadratic programming problem:</p><formula xml:id="formula_4">min w new − w s.t. w new f (x, y) − w new f (x, z) ≥ L(y, z) ∀z ∈ best k (x, w)</formula><p>We employ the following three loss functions for comparison:</p><p>Freq.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Relation Type</head><p>Event Type <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">Arg-1  Arg-2  Example  159</ref> Physical Transport Artifact Destination He (arg-1) was escorted (trigger) into Iraq (arg-2) . 46</p><p>Physical Attack Target Place Many people <ref type="bibr">(arg-1)</ref> were in the cafe (arg-2) during the blast (trigger) . 42</p><p>Agent-Artifact Attack Attacker Instrument Terrorists (arg-1) might use (trigger) the devices (arg-2) as weapons. 41 <ref type="table">Physical  Transport  Artifact  Origin</ref> The truck (arg-1) was carrying (trigger) Syrians fleeing the war in Iraq <ref type="bibr">(arg-2)</ref> . 33</p><p>Physical Meet Entity Place They (arg-1) have reunited (trigger) with their friends in Norfolk <ref type="bibr">(arg-2)</ref> . 32</p><p>Physical Die Victim Place Two Marines (arg-1) were killed (trigger) in the fighting in Kut <ref type="bibr">(arg-2)</ref> . 28</p><p>Physical Attack Attacker Place Protesters (arg-1) have been clashing (trigger) with police in Tehran <ref type="bibr">(arg-2)</ref> . <ref type="bibr">26</ref> ORG-Affiliation End-Position Person Entity NBC (arg-2) is terminating (trigger) freelance reporter Peter Arnett (arg-1) . <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>: Frequent overlapping relation and event types in the training set.</p><p>• The first one is F 1 loss:</p><formula xml:id="formula_5">L 1 (y, z) = 1 − 2 · |y ∩ z| |y| + |z|</formula><p>When counting the numbers, we treat each node and arc as a single unit. For example, in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Fig- ure 1</ref>, |y| = 6.</p><p>• The second one is 0-1 loss:</p><formula xml:id="formula_6">L 2 (y, z) = 1 y = z 0 y = z</formula><p>It does not discriminate the extent to which z deviates from y.</p><p>• The third loss function counts the difference be- tween y and z:</p><formula xml:id="formula_7">L 3 (y, z) = |y| + |z| − 2 · |y ∩ z|</formula><p>Similar to F 1 loss function, it penalizes both missing and false-positive units. The difference is that it is sensitive to the size of y and z.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3">Joint Relation-Event Features</head><p>By extracting three core IE components in a joint search space, we can utilize joint features over multiple components in addition to factorized fea- tures in pipelined approaches. In addition to the features as described in ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Li et al., 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Li and Ji, 2014</ref>), we can make use of joint features be- tween relations and events, given the fact that relations are often ending or starting states of events (Dölling, 2011). <ref type="table">Table 1</ref> shows the most frequent overlapping relation and event types in our training data. In each partial structure y dur- ing the search, if both arguments of a relation par- ticipate in an event, we compose the correspond- ing argument roles and relation type as a joint fea- ture for y . For example, for the structure in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Fig- ure 1</ref>   </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.4">Semantic Frame Features</head><p>One major challenge of constructing information networks is the data sparsity problem in extract- ing event triggers. For instance, in the sen- tence: "Others were mutilated beyond recogni- tion." The Injure trigger "mutilated" does not oc- cur in our training data. But there are some sim- ilar words such as "stab" and "smash". We uti- lize FrameNet ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Baker and Sato, 2003)</ref> to solve this problem. FrameNet is a lexical resource for semantic frames. Each frame characterizes a ba- sic type of semantic concept, and contains a num- ber of words (lexical units) that evoke the frame. Many frames are highly related with ACE events. For example, the frame "Cause harm" is closely related with Injure event and contains 68 lexical units such as "stab", "smash" and "mutilate". <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 2</ref> compares the distributions of trigger words and their frame IDs in the training data. We can clearly see that the trigger word distribution suffers from the long-tail problem, while Frames reduce the number of triggers which occur only  once in the training data from 100 to 60 and al- leviate the sparsity problem. For each token, we exploit the frames that contain the combination of its lemma and POS tag as features. For the above example, "Cause harm" will be a feature for "mu- tilated". We only consider tokens that appear in at most 2 frames, and omit the frames that occur fewer than 20 times in our training data.</p><formula xml:id="formula_8">Methods Entity Mention (%) Relation (%) Event Trigger (%) Event Argument (%) P R F 1 P R F 1 P R F 1 P R F 1 Pipelined</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Experiments</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Data and Evaluation</head><p>We use ACE'05 corpus to evaluate our method with the same data split as in ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Li and Ji, 2014</ref>). Ta- ble 2 summarizes the statistics of the data set. We report the performance of extracting entity men- tions, relations, event triggers and arguments sep- arately using the standard F 1 measures as defined in <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(Ji and Grishman, 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Chan and Roth, 2011</ref>):</p><p>• An entity mention is correct if its entity type (7 in total) and head offsets are correct.</p><p>• A relation is correct if its type (6 in total) and the head offsets of its two arguments are correct.</p><p>• An event trigger is correct if its event subtype (33 in total) and offsets are correct.</p><p>• An argument link is correct if its event subtype, offsets and role match those of any of the refer- ence argument mentions.</p><p>In this paper we focus on entity arguments while disregard values and time expressions because they can be most effectively extracted by hand- crafted patterns (Chang and Manning, 2012).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Results</head><p>Based on the results of our development set, we trained all models with 21 iterations and chose the beam size to be 8. For the k-best MIRA updates, we set k as 3. <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">Table 3</ref> compares the overall perfor- mance of our approaches and baseline methods.</p><p>Our joint model with perceptron update out- performs the state-of-the-art pipelined approach in ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Li et al., 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Li and Ji, 2014)</ref>, and further improves the joint event extraction system in ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Li et al., 2013</ref>) (p &lt; 0.05 for entity mention extrac- tion, and p &lt; 0.01 for other subtasks, accord- ing to Wilcoxon Signed RankTest). For the k- best MIRA update, the L 3 loss function achieved better performance than F 1 loss and 0-1 loss on all sub-tasks except event argument extraction. It also significantly outperforms perceptron update on relation extraction and event argument extrac- tion (p &lt; 0.01). It is particularly encouraging to see the end output of an IE system (event argu- ments) has made significant progress (12.2% ab- solute gain over traditional pipelined approach).   <ref type="table" target="#tab_6">Table 4</ref> lists the weights of the most significant features about event triggers. The 3 rd , 6 th , and 9 th rows are joint relation-event features. For in- stance, Physical(Artifact, Destination) means the arguments of a Physical relation participate in a Transport event as Artifact and Destination. We can see that both the joint relation-event features and FrameNet based features are of vital impor- tance to event trigger labeling. We tested the im- pact of each type of features by excluding them in the experiments of "MIRA w/ L 3 loss". We found that FrameNet based features provided 0.8% and 2.2% F 1 gains for event trigger and argument la- beling respectively. Joint relation-event features also provided 0.6% F 1 gain for relation extraction.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3">Discussions</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3.1">Feature Study</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3.2">Remaining Challenges</head><p>Event trigger labeling remains a major bottleneck. In addition to the sparsity problem, the remain- ing errors suggest to incorporate external world knowledge. For example, some words act as trig- gers for some certain types of events only when they appear together with some particular argu- ments:</p><p>• "Williams picked up the child again and this time, threw Attack her out the window."</p><p>The word "threw" is used as an Attack event trigger because the Victim argument is a "child".</p><p>• "Ellison to spend $10.3 billion to get Merge Org his company." The common word "get" is tagged as a trigger of Merge Org, because its object is "company".</p><p>• "We believe that the likelihood of them using Attack those weapons goes up."</p><p>The word "using" is used as an Attack event trigger because the Instrument argument is "weapons".</p><p>Another challenge is to distinguish physical and non-physical events. For example, in the sentence:</p><p>• "we are paying great attention to their ability to defend Attack on the ground.", our system fails to extract "defend" as an Attack trigger. In the training data, "defend" appears mul- tiple times, but none of them is tagged as Attack.</p><p>For instance, in the sentence:</p><p>• "North Korea could do everything to defend it- self. "</p><p>"defend" is not an Attack trigger since it does not relate to physical actions in a war. This challenge calls for deeper understanding of the contexts. Finally, some pronouns are used to refer to ac- tual events. Event coreference is necessary to rec- ognize them correctly. For example, in the follow- ing two sentences from the same document:</p><p>• "It's important that people all over the world know that we don't believe in the war Attack .",</p><p>• "Nobody questions whether this Attack is right or not."</p><p>"this" refers to "war" in its preceding contexts. Without event coreference resolution, it is difficult to tag it as an Attack event trigger.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Conclusions</head><p>We presented the first joint model that effectively extracts entity mentions, relations and events based on a unified representation: information networks. Experiment results on ACE'05 cor- pus demonstrate that our approach outperforms pipelined method, and improves event-argument performance significantly over the state-of-the-art. In addition to the joint relation-event features, we demonstrated positive impact of using FrameNet to handle the sparsity problem in event trigger la- beling.</p><p>Although our primary focus in this paper is in- formation extraction in the ACE paradigm, we be- lieve that our framework is general to improve other tightly coupled extraction tasks by capturing the inter-dependencies in the joint search space.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: Information Network Representation. Information nodes are denoted by rectangles. Arrows represent information arcs.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2: Distribution of triggers and their frames.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" validated="false"><head>Asif Mohammed Hanif detonated explosives in Tel Aviv</head><label>Asif</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Attack 
Person 
Weapon 
Geopolitical Entity 

Place 

Instrument 
Attacker 

Agent-Artifact 

Physical 

x 1 
x 2 
x 3 
x 4 
x 5 
x 6 
x 7 x 8 
x: 

y: 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" validated="false"><head>Table 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Data set 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4" validated="false"><head>Table 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Overall performance on test set. 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_6" validated="false"><head>Table 4 : Top Features about Event Triggers.</head><label>4</label><figDesc></figDesc><table></table></figure>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>We thank the three anonymous reviewers for their insightful comments. This work was supported by the U.S. Army Research Laboratory under Coop-erative Agreement No. W911NF-09-2-0053 (NS-CTA), U.S. NSF CAREER Award under Grant IIS-0953149, U.S. DARPA Award No. FA8750-13-2-0041 in the Deep Exploration and Filtering of Text (DEFT) Program, IBM Faculty Award, Google Research Award, Disney Research Award and RPI faculty start-up grant. The views and con-clusions contained in this document are those of the authors and should not be interpreted as rep-resenting the official policies, either expressed or implied, of the U.S. Government. The U.S. Gov-ernment is authorized to reproduce and distribute reprints for Government purposes notwithstanding any copyright notation here on.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The framenet data and software</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Collin</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Baker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hiroaki</forename><surname>Sato</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. ACL</title>
		<meeting>ACL</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="161" to="164" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Exploiting syntactico-semantic structures for relation extraction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yee</forename><surname>Seng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chan</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dan</forename><surname>Roth</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. ACL</title>
		<meeting>ACL</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="551" to="560" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Sutime: A library for recognizing and normalizing time expressions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Angel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christopher</forename><surname>Chang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Manning</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. LREC</title>
		<meeting>LREC</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3735" to="3740" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Incremental parsing with the perceptron algorithm</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Collins</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Brian</forename><surname>Roark</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. ACL</title>
		<meeting>ACL</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="111" to="118" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Discriminative training methods for hidden markov models: Theory and experiments with perceptron algorithms</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Collins</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. EMNLP</title>
		<meeting>EMNLP</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="8" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Aspectual coercion and eventuality structure</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Johannes</forename><surname>Dölling</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="189" to="226" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Structured perceptron with inexact search</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Liang</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Suphan</forename><surname>Fayong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yang</forename><surname>Guo</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. HLT-NAACL</title>
		<meeting>HLT-NAACL</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="142" to="151" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Refining event extraction through cross-document inference</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Heng</forename><surname>Ji</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ralph</forename><surname>Grishman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. ACL</title>
		<meeting>ACL</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Incremental joint extraction of entity mentions and relations</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Qi</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Heng</forename><surname>Ji</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. ACL</title>
		<meeting>ACL</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Joint event extraction via structured prediction with global features</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Qi</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ji</forename><surname>Heng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Liang</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. ACL</title>
		<meeting>ACL</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="73" to="82" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Online large-margin training of dependency parsers</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ryan</forename><surname>Mcdonald</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Koby</forename><surname>Crammer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Fernando</forename><surname>Pereira</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. ACL</title>
		<meeting>ACL</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="91" to="98" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Fast and robust joint models for biomedical event extraction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sebastian</forename><surname>Riedel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Andrew</forename><surname>Mccallum</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. EMNLP</title>
		<meeting>EMNLP</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A markov logic approach to bio-molecular event extraction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sebastian</forename><surname>Riedel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hong-Woo</forename><surname>Chun</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Toshihisa</forename><surname>Takagi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jun&amp;apos;ichi</forename><surname>Tsujii</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. the Workshop on Current Trends in Biomedical Natural Language Processing: Shared Task</title>
		<meeting>the Workshop on Current Trends in Biomedical Natural Language essing: Shared Task</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Global inference for entity and relation identification via a lin-ear programming formulation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dan</forename><surname>Roth</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wen-Tau</forename><surname>Yih</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Introduction to Statistical Relational Learning. MIT</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Joint inference of entities, relations, and coreference</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sameer</forename><surname>Singh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sebastian</forename><surname>Riedel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Brian</forename><surname>Martin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jiaping</forename><surname>Zheng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Andrew</forename><surname>Mccallum</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. CIKM Workshop on Automated Knowledge Base Construction</title>
		<meeting>CIKM Workshop on Automated Knowledge Base Construction</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Joint inference for fine-grained opinion extraction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bishan</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Claire</forename><surname>Cardie</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. ACL</title>
		<meeting>ACL</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1640" to="1649" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
