<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T13:04+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">The Overall Markedness of Discourse Relations</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
				<availability status="unknown"><p>Copyright Association for Computational Linguistics</p>
				</availability>
				<date type="published" when="2015-09">September 2015. 2015</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lifeng</forename><surname>Jin</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Linguistics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">The Ohio State University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marie-Catherine</forename><surname>De Marneffe</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Linguistics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">The Ohio State University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">The Overall Markedness of Discourse Relations</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2015 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</title>
						<meeting>the 2015 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing <address><addrLine>Lisbon, Portugal</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="17" to="21"/>
							<date type="published" when="2015-09">September 2015. 2015</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Discourse relations can be categorized as continuous or discontinuous in the hypothesis of continuity (Murray, 1997), with continuous relations expressing normal succession of events in discourse such as temporal, spatial or causal. Asr and Dem-berg (2013) propose a markedness measure to test the prediction that discontin-uous relations may have more unambigu-ous connectives, but restrict the marked-ness calculation to relations with explicit connectives only. This paper extends their measure to explicit and implicit relations and shows that results from this extension better fit the continuity hypothesis predictions both for the English Penn Discourse (Prasad et al., 2008) and the Chinese Discourse (Zhou and Xue, 2015) Treebanks.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Discourse relations between units of text are cru- cial for the production and understanding of dis- course. Different taxonomies of discourse rela- tions have been proposed <ref type="bibr">(i.a. Hobbs (1985)</ref>, <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Lascarides and Asher (1993)</ref> and <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Knott and Sanders (1998)</ref>). One taxonomy is based on deictic conti- nuity ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Segal et al., 1991;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Murray, 1997)</ref>: continu- ity in the sense of <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Segal et al. (1991)</ref> means that the same frame of reference is maintained, for ex- ample by subsequent sentences talking about the same event, without a shift in perspective <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Asr and Demberg, 2012)</ref>. For instance, a causal relation such as I was tired, so I drank a cup of coffee. is continuous, and adversatives show discontinuous relations: I drank a cup of coffee but I was still tired. Other continuous relations include temporal succession, topic succession and so on. The conti- nuity hypothesis predicts that sentences connected by continuous relations are easier to understand than ones connected by discontinuous relations.</p><p>Previous work on continuity hypothesis <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(Maury and Teisserenc, 2005;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Cain and Nash, 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Hoek and Zufferey, 2015)</ref> suggests that discourse connectives are indicators of the continuity of discourse and help the interlocutors predict the level of continuity of upcoming sentences. <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Segal et al. (1991)</ref> propose that connectives which signal discontinuous discourse relations, such as but, are the marked ones because they indicate harder-to-comprehend content. <ref type="bibr">Demberg (2012, 2013)</ref> extend this idea to discourse rela- tions, proposing that discourse relations which are discontinuous, or posing a conceptual difficulty <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Haspelmath, 2006</ref>), may be less explicitly con- veyed in text, or more explicitly marked by a con- nective which unambiguously conveys that spe- cific relation than continuous ones. They propose a new measure called markedness to capture this, but when computed on the Penn Discourse Tree- bank, results do not fit the continuity theory well. This paper improves on <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Asr and Demberg (2013)</ref>'s measure and shows that the results on the Penn Discourse and the Chinese Discourse Treebanks fit the continuity hypothesis very well.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Discourse Treebanks</head><p>Penn Discourse Treebank The Penn Discourse Treebank (PDTB) is a corpus of Wall Street Jour- nal articles annotated with discourse relations ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Prasad et al., 2008)</ref>. The discourse relations are organized in a hierarchical structure with three lev- els: a level 1 (e.g. TEMPORAL), level 1/level 2 (e.g. TEMPORAL.Asynchronous) or level 1/level 2/level 3 (e.g. TEMPORAL.Asynchronous.succession) re- lation can appear between two clauses within a sentence. Discourse relations with overt discourse connectives are annotated as "Explicit", whereas the relations with no discourse connective are an- notated as "Implicit". The "AltLex" category is used when a non-connective expression conveys the relation. <ref type="table">Table 1</ref> gives the distribution of the relation categories in the corpus.</p><p>Some connectives are labeled with multiple re- lations when it was difficult to pinpoint exactly one exact discourse relation for it. We follow <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Asr and Demberg (2013)</ref> and treat these cases as if there are multiple instances of the connective, each with one of the labels it received. This gives us a total of 35,870 relation instances. Chinese Discourse Treebank The Chinese Dis- course Treebank (CDTB, Zhou and Xue 2014) fol- lows the PDTB annotation style and has annota- tions for 164 documents from Xinhua News. The main difference between CDTB and PDTB is that CDTB has a flat structure of only ten relations compared to the hierarchical relation structure in PDTB. <ref type="table">Table 1</ref> gives the distribution of the rela- tion categories.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Rethinking the Markedness Measure</head><p>To quantify the conceptual difficulty of dis- course relations, <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Asr and Demberg (2013)</ref> propose an information-theoretic measure "markedness", which tells us how tightly and uniquely a relation is associated with a connective. The measure uses normalized point-wise mutual information:</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">npmi(r; c) = log p(r)p(c) log p(r, c) − 1 (1)</formula><p>to get the markedness of a discourse relation:</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">markedness(r) = c p(c|r) npmi(r; c) + 1 2 (2)</formula><p>where r is a relation and c is a discourse connec- tive. <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Asr and Demberg (2013)</ref> propose this mea- sure in the surprisal framework of Levy <ref type="formula">(2008)</ref>, and restrict the scope of the data to only Explicit relations in PDTB. We will call this measure with only explicit relations "M-exp". Since surprisal is defined as the probability of a word given previous words and context (3), this restriction on the scope of relations does not seem reasonable. Surprisal is defined as</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">surprisal ∝ − log p(w i |w 1...i−1 , CON T EXT ) (</formula><p>3) It can be argued that at the current word w i−1 , the distribution of upcoming discourse relations, available in CONTEXT, should play a role in de- termining the probability of the upcoming word w i . In the surprisal model, the domain for w i should be the same as w i−1 , which is all possible words. However, if we only calculate the distri- bution of explicit connectives as proposed by <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Asr and Demberg (2013)</ref>, the candidates for w i will change according to the prediction of whether an explicit relation is coming up or not. If the upcom- ing relation is an implicit relation, one then has ac- cess to a distribution of words without the connec- tives, whereas if one predicts an explicit relation, then one predicts the next word using a distribu- tion of all the connectives as in M-exp. However surprisal should not be a model of deterministic decision making. It is more likely the case that given CONTEXT, one assigns probabilities to all words given the preceding context, which includes the case where no connective, in other words a zero or null connective, is predicted. The null connective may also be viewed as the probability mass for all the non-connective words predicted by CONTEXT where the connective is predicted to be omitted ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Asr and Demberg, 2015)</ref>.</p><p>The markedness measure can be analyzed in terms of point-wise mutual information (pmi), in- dicating the amount of information one relation has for the distribution of the words that follow it <ref type="bibr">(Hume, 2011)</ref>. Because pmi is proportionate to npmi, we can rewrite (2) as</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">markedness(r) ∝ c p(c|r)pmi(r; c) (4)</formula><p>We also have the mutual information measure:</p><formula xml:id="formula_4">I(X; Y ) = y x p(x, y)pmi(x; y) (5)</formula><p>For the mutual information of y i in Y :  Therefore, the markedness measure can be under- stood as the Kullback-Leibler divergence of the univariate distribution of X from the conditional distribution of X given y i (a discourse relation in our case). This shows the influence a relation has on the unigram distribution of words. Discourse relations strongly associated with certain connec- tives will have larger values of this measure than the ones with a weak association. In the previ- ous discussion of surprisal, we have seen that one may treat the implicit cases as predicting a null connective, which will then expand the domain of X from explicit cases to all implicit and explicit cases. With this setup, we calculate "M-all" using all explicit and implicit relations, with a null con- nective accompanying all the implicit relations. Continuity hypothesis has been linked with cog- nitive difficulties in discourse processing in previ- ous studies ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Segal et al., 1991;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Murray, 1997</ref>). The markedness measure can also be linked to process- ing difficulties through surprisal theory. Surprisal theory proposes that processing difficulty during sentence processing can be seen as the work in- curred by resource allocation during parallel dis- ambiguation <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Levy, 2008)</ref>. If a relation has a high markedness value, it indicates that this relation has a strong influence on the distribution of upcoming candidate words. The stronger the influence is, the higher the resource allocation cost will be for the relation, thus more difficult to process.  ous (see <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">Table 2</ref> which gives the classification of discourse relations according to the continu- ity hypothesis). It should therefore have a high markedness value. However, M-exp assigns a low markedness to TEMPORAL, which Asr and Dem- berg (2013) note is unexpected. They ascribe this to the fact that temporal discourse connec- tives are often used to mark CONTINGENCY rela- tions. However because of the high counts of Ex- plicit connectives in TEMPORAL, whenever there is a connective that can indicate CONTINGENCY or TEMPORAL, one is more likely to predict TEM- PORAL because of fewer null connective cases for TEMPORAL. In surprisal terms, whenever one pre- dicts that there is a TEMPORAL relation next, one will more likely predict that there is an explicit dis- course connective signaling the relation.</p><formula xml:id="formula_5">I(X; Y = y i ) = x p(x, y i )pmi(x; y i ) p(y i ) = D KL (p(x|y i ) p(x)) = x p(x|y i )pmi(x; y i ) ∝ markedness(y i ) (6)</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Level 1 Relation Level 2 Relation Level 3 Relation Continuity</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Results on PDTB</head><p>EXPANSION is the least marked of all the rela- tions in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref> with M-all. An analysis of the level 2 relations explains this fact. E x p a n s i o n . A l t e r n a t i v e E x p a n s i o n . C o n j u n c t i o n E x p a n s i o n . E x c e p t i o n E x p a n s i o n . I n s t a n t i a t i o n E x p a n s i o n . L i s t E x p a n s i o n . pares both measures for the level 2 relations. 1 Us- ing M-all, it is easy to see that discontinuous re- lations and ambiguous relations are more marked than the continuous ones. In the case of EXPAN- SION, the level 2 continuous relations are among the least marked ones, which are keeping the over- all markedness low. Also, the ones which are dis- continuous, especially Exception, are rare, so their influence to the overall score for EXPANSION is small. The most frequent relation, Conjunction, can be viewed as sometimes continuous and some- times discontinuous, therefore the overall marked- ness rating for it is in the middle. All these fac- tors contribute to the lowest markedness for EX- PANSION. For CONTINGENCY, Condition is not classified as continuous or discontinuous, and it is highly marked, thus driving the overall score high. However if Condition is removed, then CONTIN- GENCY will be the least marked relation at the level 1. At the level 3, there are two discontinuous rela- tions of interest: precedence (e.g. I had a cup of coffee before I took a bath) and succession (e.g. I took a bath after I had a cup of coffee) under the TEMPORAL.Asynchronous relation. <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">Table 3</ref> compares the markedness measures for both rela- tions. <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Asr and Demberg (2013)</ref> mention that there is no significant markedness distinction for them and we can see that precedence is slightly more marked than succession in M-exp, but the differ- 1 Pragmatic relations are not shown due to their small number of occurrences.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Metric</head><p>Precedence Succession  ence is small. M-all however shows that succes- sion is more marked than precedence, reflecting the fact that precedence is easier to understand. For precedence, the arguments can be in a nor- mal temporal order, i.e. a forward temporal or- der (Arg1-Conn-Arg2, e.g. I had some coffee be- fore I went out.) or in a backward temporal order (Conn-Arg2-Arg1, e.g. Before I went out, I had some coffee.). For succession, the temporal or- der and the argument order are reversed. <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">Table 4</ref> gives the counts in PTDB for both precedence and succession with different argument orders, show- ing that Arg1-Conn-Arg2 is the most frequent con- struction for both relations, which is forward tem- poral order for precedence and backward tempo- ral order for succession, despite the fact that both of the relations can follow a forward temporal or- der. Therefore the results from M-all match the continuity hypothesis prediction that events in for-ward temporal order are easier to understand, thus less marked, than events in backward temporal or- der. <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Asr and Demberg (2012)</ref> explain that the rel- atively high count of Conn-Arg2-Arg1 construc- tions in succession is due to the fact that this con- struction actually places the events in the forward temporal order. We also notice that precedence has a lot more implicit occurrences than succession, meaning that inferring a normal temporal relation is much easier than inferring a reversed temporal relation. The results for CDTB, in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Figure 3</ref>, shows the same trends as for English: overall, the marked- ness computed by M-all better fits the continuity hypothesis. EXPANSION is considered by M-exp as the second highest marked relation, whereas the continuity hypothesis predicts it to be one of the lowest marked relation, which is correctly cap- tured by M-all. The reason for it to be low may be that discontinuous relations included by EXPAN- SION are rare so the frequent continuous relations dominate, just as for English. Using M-exp, CAU- SATION is around the middle, but M-all correctly lowers it to the third least marked relation. TEM- PORAL is now the second highest marked relation among all relations, as opposed to the second least marked one. Importantly, M-all correctly shows that discourses relations in English and Chinese behave similarly in terms of markedness, which indicates that the continuity hypothesis is valid across languages. <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Sanders (2005)</ref> proposes the causality-by- default hypothesis, claiming that CAUSATION is the default discourse relation when processing dis- course. However, looking at M-all scores for both languages, it is clear that CAUSATION is not the least marked relation in either language. In fact, EXPANSION can actually be seen as the least marked common relation in both languages, which may indicate that EXPANSION is the default dis- course relation cross-linguistically, yet more in- vestigations are needed to decide which one in EXPANSION is the default. CONJUNCTION is also among the least marked relations in Chinese, with 89% of its instances being implicit, but in English, CONJUNCTION has an average markedness score. This shows that there are also differences among languages on judgments of continuity of specific relations.</p><formula xml:id="formula_6">M-exp 0.799 0.783 M-all 0.494 0.687</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Results on CDTB and Comparison</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Conclusion</head><p>The continuity hypothesis predicts that discontinu- ous discourse relations are less expected than con- tinuous relations and should be more marked. We expand <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Asr and Demberg (2013)</ref>'s measure from explicit relations only to explicit and implicit re- lations. We show that the results from that expan- sion fit the predictions of the theory very well, and such evidence demonstrates that discontinuous re- lations are indeed cognitively more difficult to pro- cess. Further we show that such difficulty is con- sistent across languages, indicating that discourse relations may not be influenced by idiosyncrasies of specific languages. Apart from the markedness measure, <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Asr and Demberg (2012)</ref> proposed an "implicitness" measure, modeling the continuity of a relation using the ratio of implicit cases to all cases. Incorporating explicit and implicit relations into the markedness measure has the advantage of not only providing a single measure but also one which better fits the continuity hypothesis and sur- prisal theory.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 compares</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1 compares the markedness of the PDTB level 1 relations as computed by the M-exp and M-all measures. According to the continuity hypothesis, the TEMPORAL relation is discontinu</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: Comparison of markedness measures for PDTB level 1 relations.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 2</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>Figure 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2: Comparison of markedness measures for PDTB level 2 relations.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head>Figure 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Figure 3: Markedness comparison for CDTB.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" validated="false"><head>Table 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Continuity of relations according to the continuity hypothesis (Asr and Demberg, 2012). 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3" validated="false"><head>Table 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Precedence and Succession Markedness. 

Arg1-Conn-Arg2 
Conn-Arg2-Arg1 
Implicit Explicit Implicit Explicit 

Precedence 
567 
931 
0 
55 
Succession 
171 
867 
0 
234 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4" validated="false"><head>Table 4 :</head><label>4</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Counts for different argument orders of 
Precedence and Succession. 

</table></figure>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgements</head><p>We thank William Schuler for productive discus-sions of the work presented here as well as our anonymous reviewers for their helpful comments.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Implicitness of discourse relations</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Torabi</forename><surname>Fatemeh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Vera</forename><surname>Asr</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Demberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of COLING 2012</title>
		<meeting>COLING 2012</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2669" to="2684" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">On 1118 the information conveyed by discourse markers</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Torabi</forename><surname>Fatemeh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Vera</forename><surname>Asr</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Demberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Fourth Annual Workshop on Cognitive Modeling and Computational Linguistics (CMCL)</title>
		<meeting>the Fourth Annual Workshop on Cognitive Modeling and Computational Linguistics (CMCL)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="84" to="93" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Association for Computational Linguistics</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Uniform surprisal at the level of discourse relations: negation markers and discourse connective omission</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Torabi</forename><surname>Fatemeh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Vera</forename><surname>Asr</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Demberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 11th International Conference on Computational Semantics</title>
		<meeting>the 11th International Conference on Computational Semantics</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="118" to="128" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The influence of connectives on young readers&apos; processing and comprehension of text</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kate</forename><surname>Cain</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hannah</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Nash</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Educational Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">103</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="429" to="441" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Against markedness (and what to replace it with)</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Martin</forename><surname>Haspelmath</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Linguistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">42</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="25" to="70" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">On the coherence and structure of discourse</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jerry R</forename><surname>Hobbs</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1985" />
			<publisher>CSLI</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Factors influencing the implicitation of discourse relations across languages</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jet</forename><surname>Hoek</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sandrine</forename><surname>Zufferey</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings 11th Joint ACLISO Workshop on Interoperable Semantic Annotation</title>
		<meeting>11th Joint ACLISO Workshop on Interoperable Semantic Annotation</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
			<biblScope unit="page">39</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>isa-11</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The Blackwell Companion to Phonology: Suprasegmental and prosodic phonology</title>
		<editor>Elizabeth Hume. 2011. Markedness. In Marc van Oostendrop, Colin J. Ewen, Elizabeth Hume, and Keren Rice</editor>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>John Wiley &amp; Sons</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="79" to="106" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The classification of coherence relations and their linguistic markers: An exploration of two languages</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alistair</forename><surname>Knott</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ted</forename><forename type="middle">J M</forename><surname>Sanders</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Pragmatics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">30</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="135" to="175" />
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Temporal interpretation, discourse relations, and common sense entailment</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alex</forename><surname>Lascarides</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nicholas</forename><surname>Asher</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Linguistics and Philosophy</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">16</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="437" to="493" />
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Expectation-based syntactic comprehension</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Roger</forename><surname>Levy</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">106</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1126" to="1177" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The role of connectives in science text comprehension and memory</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Pascale</forename><surname>Maury</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Amélie</forename><surname>Teisserenc</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Language and Cognitive Processes</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="489" to="512" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Connectives and narrative text: The role of continuity</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>John</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Murray</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Memory &amp; Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">25</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="227" to="236" />
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Penn Discourse TreeBank 2.0</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rashmi</forename><surname>Prasad</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nikhil</forename><surname>Dinesh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alan</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Eleni</forename><surname>Miltsakaki</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Livio</forename><surname>Robaldo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Aravind</forename><surname>Joshi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bonnie</forename><surname>Webber</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of LREC</title>
		<meeting>LREC</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Coherence, causality and cognitive complexity in discourse</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ted</forename><surname>Sanders</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Symposium on the Exploration and Modelling of Meaning</title>
		<meeting>the Symposium on the Exploration and Modelling of Meaning</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The role of interclausal connectives in narrative structuring: Evidence from adults&apos; interpretations of simple stories</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Erwin</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Segal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Judith</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Duchan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Paula</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Scott</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Discourse Processes</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="27" to="54" />
			<date type="published" when="1991" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The Chinese Discourse TreeBank: a Chinese corpus annotated with discourse relations. Language Resources and Evaluation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yuping</forename><surname>Zhou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nianwen</forename><surname>Xue</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">49</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="397" to="431" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
