<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T10:52+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Wikification of Concept Mentions within Spoken Dialogues Using Domain Constraints from Wikipedia</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
				<availability status="unknown"><p>Copyright Association for Computational Linguistics</p>
				</availability>
				<date type="published" when="2015-09">September 2015. 2015</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Seokhwan</forename><surname>Kim</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Human Language Technology Department Institute for Infocomm Research</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>138632</postCode>
									<country key="SG">Singapore</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rafael</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Banchs</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Human Language Technology Department Institute for Infocomm Research</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>138632</postCode>
									<country key="SG">Singapore</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Haizhou</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Human Language Technology Department Institute for Infocomm Research</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>138632</postCode>
									<country key="SG">Singapore</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Wikification of Concept Mentions within Spoken Dialogues Using Domain Constraints from Wikipedia</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2015 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</title>
						<meeting>the 2015 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing <address><addrLine>Lisbon, Portugal</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="17" to="21"/>
							<date type="published" when="2015-09">September 2015. 2015</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>While most previous work on Wikification has focused on written texts, this paper presents a Wikification approach for spoken dialogues. A set of analyzers are proposed to learn dialogue-specific properties along with domain knowledge of conversations from Wikipedia. Then, the analyzed properties are used as constraints for generating candidates, and the candidates are ranked to find the appropriate links. The experimental results show that our proposed approach can significantly improve the performances of the task in human-human dialogues.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Linking mentions in natural language to the relevant concepts in knowledge-bases plays a key role in better understanding the meanings of expressions as well as further populating knowledge-bases with less human effort. Espe- cially, Wikipedia has been widely used as a major target resource for linking. Most previous work on this Wikipedia-based linking task called Wiki- fication <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(Mihalcea and Csomai, 2007</ref>) has focused on resolving ambiguities and variabilities of the expressions in written texts including newswire collections <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">(McNamee and Dang, 2009;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Ji et al., 2010;</ref>) or microblog posts <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Genc et al., 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Cassidy et al., 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Guo et al., 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Huang et al., 2014</ref>).</p><p>But writing and reading are not the only ways for exchange of information, since many commu- nications between people in real life are performed through spoken dialogues also. Thus, we could expect to improve the understanding capabilities of applications based on Wikification and broaden the coverage of the contents in knowledge-bases, if Wikification is successfully performed also for human-human spoken conversations.</p><p>In this work, we focus on the following differ- ences between spoken dialogues and written texts as sources for Wikification. Firstly, at least two speakers are engaged in a dialogue session, while the texts in newswire or microblogs are mostly written by a single author. Thus, the viewpoint of each speaker should be considered separately or jointly depending on the situation. Secondly, the correspondence between mentions and concepts in spoken dialogues tends to be dependent not only on the contexts explicitly mentioned in a given di- alogue, but also on other information inferred by speakers based on their background knowledge. The other difference is that spoken utterances are more likely to be informal and noisy than writ- ten sentences, which makes expressions more am- biguous and variable.</p><p>To solve these issues, we propose a three step approach for Wikification on spoken dialogues. At the first step, a set of classifiers are used for an- alyzing the dialogue-specific aspects of a given mention. According to the analyzed results, the criteria in selecting concept candidates is deter- mined, and then a ranking is performed on the fil- tered candidates to identify the concept that is the most relevant to the mention.</p><p>While many researchers have worked on link- ing named-entities ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Bunescu and Pasca, 2006;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Cucerzan, 2007;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b14">McNamee and Dang, 2009;</ref>) or other types of concept mentions <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(Mihalcea and Csomai, 2007;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Milne and Witten, 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Ferragina and Scaiella, 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b18">Ratinov et al., 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Mendes et al., 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Cheng and Roth, 2013)</ref> to the relevant articles in Wikipedia, all the noun phrases includ- ing not only named entities or base noun phrases, but also complex or recursive noun phrases in a di- alogue are considered as instances to be linked in this work. For the concept candidates, we divide every article into sub-sections and consider each section as a unit along with article-level concepts. Step 1</p><p>Step 2</p><p>Step 3</p><p>Figure 1: Overall architecture of three-step ap- proach for Wikification on spoken dialogues</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Method</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">Mention Analysis</head><p>The first step in our proposed approach <ref type="figure">(Figure 1</ref>) is analyzing the following four types of binary properties of a given mention: linking validity (LV ), in-dialogue reference (ID), domain rele- vance (DR), and speaker relatedness (SR). Linking validity of the mention is determined by the decision whether it is matched with any Wikipedia concept or not. Since only the men- tions assigned with positive validity values are proceeded to the further processes, this classifi- cation can be considered as a joint task for target mention identification and NIL detection.</p><p>Another type of analysis focuses on the refer- ences between the mention and the linking his- tory. If the mention is matched with one in the set of concepts for the previous mentions in the same session, it has a positive value for the in-dialogue reference property.</p><p>The other two types of properties are defined for indicating the relevances of the mention to the contents that are specific to the target domain or the profiles of each speaker in the conversation. For these analyses, the whole Wikipedia collection is partitioned into subsets according to the domain or speaker-relevances. In this work, the concepts in these subsets are automatically collected with no manual effort by utilizing the domain knowl- edge also from Wikipedia. First, we retrieve the 'List' or 'Index' pages in Wikipedia that are re- Guide: In the morning I suggest to you to go to Botanical Garden.</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">LV ID DR SRG SRT + - - - - LV ID DR SRG SRT + - + + -</formula><p>Tourist: Oh, we also have Botanical Garden.  <ref type="figure">Figure 2</ref>: Examples of annotations for mention analysis: SR G and SR T denote guide and tourist relatedness, respectively. lated to the topic or the profile of a speaker. Then, all the articles listed on these seed pages are col- lected and considered as the related concepts in the corresponding sets.</p><p>Since every property has a positive or a negative value as a result, each analysis can be considered as a binary classification problem. In this work, we train support vector machines (SVM) <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Cortes and Vapnik, 1995)</ref> from the dialogues annotated with the corresponding labels as shown in <ref type="figure">Figure 2</ref> based on the features listed in <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">Candidate Generation</head><p>After analyzing the above property values of a given mention, a set of concepts to be disam- biguated are selected from Wikipedia. These can- didates are retrieved from a Lucene 1 index on the whole Wikipedia collection with the fields of ar- ticle title, section title, redirection, category, and body texts. Each query to the search engine is pre- pared with the combination of the mention phrase and its analyzed properties as constraints for fil- tering. If the value for in-dialogue reference is positive, the searching is restricted to the set of concepts linked with the previous mentions in the same session. Similarly, the domain relevance and speaker relatedness values provide the filter- ing condition within the corresponding subsets in- troduced in Section 2.1.</p><p>One practical issue on this candidate generation step is how to combine the multiple constraints when we have more than one positive proper- ties for a given mention. The simplest way is taking the intersection of the corresponding con- straints. However, we should consider the fact that the properties assigned automatically can be erroneous, since none of the analyzer is perfect.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Level</head><p>Name Description Mention SP the speaker who spoke that mention WM word n-grams within the mention LM lemma n-grams within the mention PM POS n-grams within the mention NE named entities within the mention NP base noun phrases within the men- tion Utterance BW the words before the mention AW the words after the mention BL the lemmas before the mention AL the lemmas after the mention BP the POS tags before the mention AP the POS tags after the mention IU whether the mention previously oc- curs in the same utterance Dialogue EO whether the phrase is previously mentioned in the dialogue history EOS whether the phrase is previously mentioned by the same speaker in the history Wikipedia IW whether the phrase is a title of an entry in Wikipedia IWD whether the phrase is a title of an entry in the set of domain-relevant concepts IWS k whether the phrase is a title of an entry in the set of k-th speaker- relevant concepts <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>: List of features for training the models for mention analysis</p><p>For the noisy cases, the intersection-based filtering could be risky, because the errors are also jointly accumulated. To circumvent the impact of errors from the previous step, we also try to use the union of the constraints and compare it with the intersec- tion case later in Section 3.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3">Candidate Ranking</head><p>In this work, linking a given mention to its most relevant concept is determined by ranking SVM <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(Joachims, 2002</ref>) which is a pairwise rank- ing algorithm learned from the ranked lists. where f (m) is the annotation of m in the train- ing dataset. The list of candidates assigned with their scores provides the relative orders for a given mention, and it can be converted into a set of Name Description SP the speaker who spoke that mention WM word n-grams within the surface of m WT word n-grams within the title of c EMT whether the surface of m is same as the title of c EMR whether the surface of m is same as one of re- directions to c MIT whether the surface of m is a sub-string of the title of c TIM whether the title of c is a sub-string of the m's surface form MIR whether the surface of m is a sub-string of a re- directed title to c RIM whether a re-directed title to c is a sub-string of the m's surface form PMT similarity score based on edit distance between the surface of m and the title of c PMR maximum similarity score between the surface of m and the redirected titles to c OC whether c previously occurred in the full dialogue history OCw whether c occurred within w previous turns with w ∈ {1, 3, 5, 10} </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Evaluation</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Data</head><p>To demonstrate the effectiveness of our approach to Wikification on spoken dialogues, we per- formed experiments on a dialogue corpus which consists of 35 sessions collected from human- human conversations in English about tourism in Singapore between actual tour guides in Sin- gapore and tourists from the Philippines. All the recorded dialogues with the total length of 21 hours were manually transcribed, then the 31,034 utterance were pre-processed by Stanford CoreNLP toolkit 2 . Each noun phrase in the con- stituent trees provided by the parser is consid- ered as an instance for Wikification and manu- ally annotated with the corresponding concept in Wikipedia. 34,949 mentions have been linked to the concepts in Wikipedia. As a pool for candidate generation, we built a Lucene index based on Wikipedia database dump as of January 2015 which has 4,797,927 articles and 25,577,464 sections in total. From this collec- tion, 11,128 and 27,186 articles have been consid- ered as Singapore-related and Philippines-related concepts, respectively, for the filtering based on domain and speaker relevances.   </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Mention Analysis</head><p>Based on the annotated dialogues, we built four mention analyzers for LV , ID, SR G , and SR T , where SR G is for the guides and SR T is for the tourists in the conversations. In this work, only the information where each speaker is from was con- sidered as a profile to analyze the speaker-related properties. Since all the guides participated in the data collection are from Singapore and the main topic of the conversations is also about Singapore, we omitted DR which should have the same re- sults as SR G in the experiments.</p><p>For each analyzer, we trained the SVM models using SVM light 3 with the features in <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>. All the evaluations were performed in five-fold cross validation to the manual annotations with preci- sion, recall, and F-measure. <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">Table 3</ref> compares the performances of the seven combinations of feature sets for each analyzer. Based on these results, we selected the model that achieved the best performance for each analyzer to process the mentions for the further steps.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3">Candidate Generation</head><p>For each mention in the corpus, we prepared four sets of candidates with different filtering con- straints. While the first baseline set was retrieved with no filtering, the others were generated ac- cording to the procedure described in Section 2.2. When more than one positive values were pro- vided from mention analyzers, intersection and union operators were applied for combining mul- tiple constraints. In the last set, the property val- ues manually annotated in the training data were <ref type="bibr">3</ref>   <ref type="table">Table 4</ref>: Comparisons of the performances of Wikification on spoken dialogues considered as the correct constraints, which is in- tended for comparing with the others to investigate the influence of errors in mention analysis. For ev- ery set, we retrieved top 100 candidates satisfying the given constraints from the Lucene index with Wikipedia collection and added one more special candidate for NIL detection.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.4">Candidate Ranking</head><p>For each set of candidates, we trained a ranking function using SVM rank4 with the features in Ta- ble 2. Both training and testing the ranking models were performed also based on five-fold cross vali- dation with the same divisions as the former eval- uation. After getting the ranking results, we took the top-ranked candidate for each list and consid- ered it as a result of Wikification for the corre- sponding mention. <ref type="table">Table 4</ref> compares the final performances of Wikification obtained by ranking on the candi- dates generated with different sets of constraints. Both approaches, intersection and union, outper- formed the baseline by 12.60 and 13.50 in F- measure, respectively. While the intersection strat- egy contributed to produce more precise outputs than the others even including the case with man- ual filtering, the other proposed approach with union achieved more gain in recall with slightly better F-measure than the former one.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Conclusions</head><p>This paper presented a Wikification approach for spoken dialogues. In this approach, a set of dialogue-specific properties were analyzed for generating concept candidates. Then, supervised ranking was performed on these candidates to identify the relevant concepts. Experimental re- sults show that the proposed constraints help to improve the performances of the task on spoken dialogues.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>4</head><label></label><figDesc>For each pair of a mention m in the training data and its candidate concept c, the ranking score s(m, c) is assigned as follows:if c is the exactly same as f (m), 3 if c is the parent article of f (m), 2 if c belongs to the same article but different section of f (m), 1 otherwise.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Features</head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" validated="false"><head>Table 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>List of features for training the ranking SVM model pairwise constraints which are trained by ranking SVM with the features in Table 2.</figDesc><table></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4" validated="false"><head>Table 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Comparisons of the performances in 
F-measure of mention analyzers with different 
combinations of features: M,U,D,W denotes 
mention-level, utterance-level, dialogue-level, and 
Wikipedia features, respectively 

</table></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> http://lucene.apache.org/</note>

			<note place="foot" n="2"> http://nlp.stanford.edu/software/corenlp.shtml</note>

			<note place="foot" n="4"> http://www.cs.cornell.edu/people/tj/svm light/svm rank.html</note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Using Encyclopedic Knowledge for Named entity Disambiguation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Razvan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marius</forename><surname>Bunescu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Pasca</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">EACL</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="9" to="16" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Analysis and Enhancement of Wikification for Microblogs with Context Expansion</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Taylor</forename><surname>Cassidy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Heng</forename><surname>Ji</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lev-Arie</forename><surname>Ratinov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Arkaitz</forename><surname>Zubiaga</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hongzhao</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">COLING</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="441" to="456" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Relational inference for wikification</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xiao</forename><surname>Cheng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dan</forename><surname>Roth</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2013 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</title>
		<meeting>the 2013 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1787" to="1796" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Supportvector networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Corinna</forename><surname>Cortes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Vladimir</forename><surname>Vapnik</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Machine learning</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="273" to="297" />
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Large-Scale Named Entity Disambiguation Based on Wikipedia Data</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Silviu Cucerzan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">EMNLP-CoNLL</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="708" to="716" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Tagme: on-the-fly annotation of short text fragments (by wikipedia entities)</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Paolo</forename><surname>Ferragina</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ugo</forename><surname>Scaiella</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 19th ACM international conference on Information and knowledge management</title>
		<meeting>the 19th ACM international conference on Information and knowledge management</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1625" to="1628" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Discovering context: Classifying tweets through a semantic transform based on wikipedia. Foundations of Augmented Cognition</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yegin</forename><surname>Genc</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yasuaki</forename><surname>Sakamoto</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jeffrey V</forename><surname>Nickerson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="page">484</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">To Link or Not to Link? A Study on End-toEnd Tweet Entity Linking</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Stephen</forename><surname>Guo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ming-Wei</forename><surname>Chang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Emre</forename><surname>Kiciman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">HLT-NAACL</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1020" to="1030" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A generative entitymention model for linking entities with knowledge base</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xianpei</forename><surname>Han</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Le</forename><surname>Sun</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 49th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics: Human Language Technologies</title>
		<meeting>the 49th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics: Human Language Technologies</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="945" to="954" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Collective entity linking in web text: a graph-based method</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xianpei</forename><surname>Han</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Le</forename><surname>Sun</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jun</forename><surname>Zhao</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 34th international ACM SIGIR conference on Research and development in Information Retrieval</title>
		<meeting>the 34th international ACM SIGIR conference on Research and development in Information Retrieval</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="765" to="774" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Collective tweet wikification based on semi-supervised graph regularization</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hongzhao</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yunbo</forename><surname>Cao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xiaojiang</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Heng</forename><surname>Ji</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chin-Yew</forename><surname>Lin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the ACL</title>
		<meeting>the ACL<address><addrLine>Baltimore, Maryland</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Overview of the tac 2010 knowledge base population track</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Heng</forename><surname>Ji</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ralph</forename><surname>Grishman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hoa</forename><forename type="middle">Trang</forename><surname>Dang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kira</forename><surname>Griffitt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Joe</forename><forename type="middle">Ellis</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Third Text Analysis Conference</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>TAC</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Overview of tac-kbp2014 entity discovery and linking tasks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Heng Ji</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Dang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Nothman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Hachey</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. Text Analysis Conference (TAC2014)</title>
		<meeting>Text Analysis Conference (TAC2014)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Optimizing search engines using clickthrough data</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Thorsten</forename><forename type="middle">Joachims</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the eighth ACM SIGKDD international conference on Knowledge discovery and data mining</title>
		<meeting>the eighth ACM SIGKDD international conference on Knowledge discovery and data mining</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="133" to="142" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Overview of the tac 2009 knowledge base population track</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Paul</forename><surname>Mcnamee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hoa</forename><forename type="middle">Trang</forename><surname>Dang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Text Analysis Conference (TAC)</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="111" to="113" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dbpedia spotlight: shedding light on the web of documents</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Max</forename><surname>Pablo N Mendes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Andrés</forename><surname>Jakob</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christian</forename><surname>García-Silva</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Bizer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 7th International Conference on Semantic Systems</title>
		<meeting>the 7th International Conference on Semantic Systems</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="8" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Wikify!: linking documents to encyclopedic knowledge</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rada</forename><surname>Mihalcea</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Andras</forename><surname>Csomai</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the sixteenth ACM conference on Conference on information and knowledge management</title>
		<meeting>the sixteenth ACM conference on Conference on information and knowledge management</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="233" to="242" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Learning to link with wikipedia</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Milne</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ian</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Witten</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 17th ACM conference on Information and knowledge management</title>
		<meeting>the 17th ACM conference on Information and knowledge management</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="509" to="518" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Local and global algorithms for disambiguation to wikipedia</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lev</forename><surname>Ratinov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dan</forename><surname>Roth</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Doug</forename><surname>Downey</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mike</forename><surname>Anderson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 49th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics: Human Language Technologies</title>
		<meeting>the 49th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics: Human Language Technologies</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1375" to="1384" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
