<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T11:52+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Indicative Tweet Generation: An Extractive Summarization Problem?</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
				<availability status="unknown"><p>Copyright Association for Computational Linguistics</p>
				</availability>
				<date type="published" when="2015-09">September 2015. 2015</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Priya</forename><surname>Sidhaye</surname></persName>
							<email>priya.sidhaye@mail.mcgill.ca</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">School of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">School of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">McGill University Montreal</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>H3A 0E9</postCode>
									<region>QC</region>
									<country key="CA">Canada</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jackie</forename><surname>Chi</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">McGill University Montreal</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>H3A 0E9</postCode>
									<region>QC</region>
									<country key="CA">Canada</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kit</forename><surname>Cheung</surname></persName>
							<email>jcheung@cs.mcgill.ca</email>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">McGill University Montreal</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>H3A 0E9</postCode>
									<region>QC</region>
									<country key="CA">Canada</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Indicative Tweet Generation: An Extractive Summarization Problem?</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2015 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</title>
						<meeting>the 2015 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing <address><addrLine>Lisbon, Portugal</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="17" to="21"/>
							<date type="published" when="2015-09">September 2015. 2015</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Social media such as Twitter have become an important method of communication, with potential opportunities for NLG to facilitate the generation of social media content. We focus on the generation of indicative tweets that contain a link to an external web page. While it is natural and tempting to view the linked web page as the source text from which the tweet is generated in an extractive summarization setting, it is unclear to what extent actual indicative tweets behave like extrac-tive summaries. We collect a corpus of indicative tweets with their associated articles and investigate to what extent they can be derived from the articles using ex-tractive methods. We also consider the impact of the formality and genre of the article. Our results demonstrate the limits of viewing indicative tweet generation as extractive summarization, and point to the need for the development of a methodology for tweet generation that is sensitive to genre-specific issues.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>With the rise in popularity of social media, mes- sage broadcasting sites such as Twitter and other microblogging services have become an important means of communication, with an estimated 500 million tweets being written every day <ref type="bibr">1</ref> . In addi- tion to individual users, various organizations and public figures such as newspapers, government officials and entertainers have established them- selves on social media in order to disseminate in- formation or promote their products.</p><p>While there has been recent progress in the development of Twitter-specific POS taggers, parsers, and other tweet understanding tools ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">Owoputi et al., 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Kong et al., 2014</ref>), there has been little work on methods for generating tweets, despite the utility this would have for users and organizations.</p><p>In this paper, we study the generation of the par- ticular class of tweets that contain a link to an ex- ternal web page that is composed primarily of text. Given the short length of a tweet, the presence of a URL in the tweet is a strong signal that the tweet is functioning to help Twitter users decide whether to read the full article. This class of tweets, which we call indicative tweets, represents a large sub- set of tweets overall, constituting more than half of the tweets in our data set. Indicative tweets would appear to be the easiest to handle using cur- rent methods in text summarization, because there is a clear source of input from which a tweet could be generated. In effect, the tweet would be acting as an indicative summary of the article it is being linked to, and it would seem that existing meth- ods in summarization can be applied. It should be noted that a tweet being indicative does not pre- clude it from also providing a critical evaluation of the linked article.</p><p>There has in fact been some work along these lines, within the framework of extractive summa- rization. <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Lofi and Krestel (2012)</ref> describe a system to generate tweets from local government records through keyphrase extraction. Lloret and Palo- mar (2013) compares various extractive summa- rization algorithms applied on Twitter data to gen- erate tweets from documents.</p><p>Lofi and Krestel do not provide a formal evalua- tion of their model, while Lloret and Palomar com- pared overlap between system-generated and user- generated tweets using ROUGE <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(Lin, 2004</ref>). Un- fortunately, they also show that there is little corre- lation between ROUGE scores and the perceived quality of the tweets when rated by human users for indicativeness and interest. More scrutiny is required to determine whether the wholesale adop- tion of methods and evaluation schemes from ex- tractive summarization is justified.</p><p>Beyond issues of evaluation measures, it is also unclear whether extraction is the strategy em- ployed by human tweeters. One of the origi- nal motivations behind extractive summarization was the observation that human summary writers tended to extract snippets of key phrases from the source text <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">(Mani, 2001</ref>). And while it may be true that an automatic tweet generation system need not necessarily follow the same approach to writ- ing as human tweeters, it is still necessary to know what proportion of tweets could be accounted for in an extractive summarization paradigm.</p><p>With indicative tweets, an additional issue arises in that the genre of the source text is not constrained; for example it may be a news article or an informal blog post. This may be vastly dif- ferent from the desired formality of tweet itself, and thus, a genre-appropriate extract may not be available.</p><p>We begin to address the above issues through a study that examines to what extent tweet gener- ation can be viewed as an extractive summariza- tion problem. We extracted a dataset of indica- tive tweets containing a link to an external article, including the documents linked to by the tweets. We used this data and applied unigram, bigram and LCS (longest common subsequence) match- ing techniques inspired by ROUGE to determine what proportion of tweets can be found in the linked article. Even with the permissive unigram match measure, we find that well under half of the tweet can be found in the linked article. We also use stylistic analysis on the articles to examine the role that genre differences between the source text and the target tweet play, and find that it is easier to extract tweets from more formal articles than less formal ones.</p><p>Our results point to the need for the devel- opment of a methodology for indicative tweet generation, rather than to expropriate the extrac- tive summarization paradigm that was developed mostly on news text. Such a methodology will ide- ally be sensitive to stylistic factors as well as the underlying intent of the tweet.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Background and Related Work</head><p>There have been studies on a number of different issues related to Twitter data, including classifying tweets and sentiment analysis of tweets. <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Ghosh et al. (2011)</ref> classified the retweeting activity of users based on time intervals between retweets of a sin- gle user and frequency of retweets from unique users. 'Retweet' here means the occurrence of the same URL in a different tweet. The study was able to classify the retweeting as automatic or robotic retweeting, campaigns, news, blogs and so on, based on the time-interval and user-frequency distributions. In another study, <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Chen et al. (2012)</ref> were able to extract sentiment expressions from a corpus of tweets including both formal words and informal slang that bear sentiment.</p><p>Other studies using Twitter data include O' <ref type="bibr">Connor et al. (2010)</ref>, who use topic summa- rization for a given search for better browsing. <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Chakrabarti and Punera (2011)</ref> generate an event summary by learning about the event using a Hidden Markov Model over the tweets describ- ing it. <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">Wang et al. (2014)</ref> generate a coherent event summary by treating summarization as an optimization problem for topic cohesion. Inouye and Kalita (2011) compare multiple summariza- tion techniques to generate a summary of multi- post blogs on Twitter. <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">Wei and Gao (2014)</ref> use tweets to help in generating better summaries of news articles.</p><p>As described in Section 1, we analyze tweet generation using measures inspired by extrac- tive summarization evaluation. There has been one study comparing different text summariza- tion techniques for tweet generation by <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Lloret and Palomar (2013)</ref>. Summarization systems were used to generate sentences lesser than 140 charac- ters in length by summarizing documents, which could then be taken to be tweets. The system- generated tweets were evaluated using ROUGE measures <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(Lin, 2004</ref>). The ROUGE-1, ROUGE-2 and ROUGE-L measures were used, and a human- written reference tweet was taken to be the gold standard.</p><p>The limits of extractive summarization have been studied by <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">He et al. (2000)</ref>. They compare user preferences for various types of summaries of an audio-visual presentation. They demonstrate that the most preferred method of summarization is highlights and notes provided by the author, rather than transcripts or slides from the presen- tation. <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Conroy et al. (2006)</ref> computed an oracle ROUGE score to investigate the same issue of the limits of extraction for news text.</p><p>These studies show that extractive summariza- tion algorithms may not generate good quality summaries despite giving high ROUGE evalua- tion scores. <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Cheung and Penn (2013)</ref> show that for the news genre, extractive summarization sys- tems that are optimized for centrality-that is, get- ting the core parts of the text into the summary- cannot perform well when compared to model summaries, since the model summaries are ab- stracted from the document to a large extent.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Data Extraction and Preprocessing</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Using Twitter for Data Extraction</head><p>As mentioned earlier, there have been numerous studies that used data from the public Twitter feeds. However, none of the datasets in those stud- ies focused on tweets and related articles linked to these tweets. The dataset of <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Lloret and Palomar (2013)</ref> is an exception, as it contains tweets and the news articles they link to, but it only con- tains 200 English tweet-article pairs. Wei and Gao (2014) also constructed a dataset that contains both tweets and articles linked through them, but this data only deals with news text, and does not contain the variety of topics we wanted in the data. We therefore chose to build our own dataset. This section describes extraction, cleaning and other preprocessing of the data.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Extracting Data</head><p>Data was extracted from Twitter using the Twit- ter REST API using 51 search terms, or hashtags. These hashtags were chosen from a range of topics including pop culture, international summit meet- ings discussing political issues, lawsuits and tri- als, social issues and health care issues. All these hashtags were trending (being tweeted about at a high rate) at the time of extraction of the data. To get a broader sample, the data was extracted over the course of 15 days in November, 2014, which gave us multiple news stories to choose from for the search terms. The search terms were chosen so that there would be broad representation in terms of various stylistic properties of text like formal- ity, subjectivity, etc. For example, searches related to politics would be more formal, while those re- lated to films would be informal, and would also have a lot more opinion pieces about them. A few examples of the search terms and their distribution in genre are shown in <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>.</p><p>We extracted about 30,000 tweets, of which more than half, or around 16,000, contained URLs to an external news article, photo on photo sharing sites, or video. The data from the tweets was cleaned by remov- ing the tweets that were not in English as well as the retweets; i.e., re-publications of a tweet by a different user.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Politics</head><p>We deduplicated the 16,000 extracted URLs into 6,003 unique addressed, then extracted and preprocessed their contents. The newspaper package 2 was used to extract article text and the title from the web page. Since we are interested in text articles that can serve as the source text for summarization algorithms, we needed to re- move photos and video links such as those from Instagram and YouTube. To do so, we removed those links that contained fewer than a threshold of 150 words. After this preprocessing, the number of useful articles was reduced from 6003 to 3066. There were some further tweet-article pairs where the text of the tweets was identical, these were re- moved by further preprocessing and the number of unique tweet-article pairs came down to 2471.</p><p>The final version of the data consists of tweets along with other information about the tweet, such as links to articles, hashtags, time of publication, etc. We also retain the linked article text and pre- processed it using the CoreNLP toolkit ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Manning et al., 2014</ref>). This includes the URL itself and the text extracted from the article, as well as some ex- tracted information such as sentence boundaries, POS tags for tokens, parse trees and dependency trees. These annotations are used later during our analysis in Section 4. <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">Table 2</ref> shows an example of an entry in the dataset.  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Analysis</head><p>We now describe the analyses we performed on the data. Our goal is to investigate what propor- tion of the indicative tweets that we extracted can be found in the articles that they link to, in order to determine whether indicative tweet generation can be viewed as an extractive summarization prob- lem. <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">Table 3</ref> gives an example of data where the tweet that was shared about the article does not come directly from the article text, while <ref type="table">Table 4</ref> shows a tweet that was almost entirely extracted from the text of the article, but changed a little for the purpose of readability.  We first compute the proportion of tweets that can be recovered directly from the article in its en- tirety (Section 4.1). Then, we calculate the degree of overlap in terms of unigrams and bigrams be- tween the tweet and the text of the document (Sec- tions 4.2, 4.3).</p><p>In addition, we consider locality within the arti- cle when computing the overlap. For the unigram analysis, we performed a variant of the analysis, Tweet Officer Wilson will be returned to active duty if no indictment, says #Ferguson Police Chief http://t.co/zrRIBxMUYJ Title Jackson clarifies comments on Wilson's future status Text ...Chief Jackson said if the grand jury does not indict Wilson, he will imme- diately return to active duty.... <ref type="table">Table 4</ref>: Example of a tweet, title of the article and the text when tweet can be extracted from text. The matched portions of the tweet and article are in bold.</p><p>in which we computed the overlap within three- sentence windows in the source article (Section 4.4). We also compute the least common subse- quences between the tweet and the document (Sec- tion 4.5). This was done to investigate whether sentence compression techniques could be applied to local context windows to generate the tweet. These calculations are analogous to the ROUGE-1, -2 and -L style calculations. These results give an indication of the degree to which the tweet is extracted from the document text.</p><p>For all these analyses, the stop words have been eliminated from the tweet as well as the doc- ument, so that only the informative words are taken into consideration. The comparisons were made without lemmatization or stemming, to ad- here closely to existing work in extractive sum- marization, where the only modifications to the source text are removing discourse cue words or removing words by sentence compression tech- niques. The hashtags, references (@) and URLs from the tweets were all removed for analysis.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">Exact Match Calculations</head><p>We first checked for a complete substring match of the tweet in the text. Out of the 2471 unique instances of tweet and article pairs, a complete match was found only 23 times. In 9 cases out of these, the tweet text matched the title of the arti- cle, which our preprocessing tool did not correctly separate from the body of the article. In the other cases, the text of the tweet appears in its entirety inside the body of the article. This suggests that the user chose the sentence that either seemed to be the most conclusive contribution of the article, or expressed the opinion of the user to be tweeted. An example for this is detailed in <ref type="table" target="#tab_6">Table 5</ref>.</p><p>Apart from the 9 times where the tweet was matched with title in the article, we also checked to see if the tweet text matched with the arti- cle titles that were separately extracted by the newspaper package in order to determine if tweets could be generated using the headline gen- eration methods. We found that it did not match with the titles. However, even though there are no exact matches, there might still be matches where the tweet is a slight modification of the headline of the article, and can be measured using a partial match measure.   </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">Percentage Match for Unigrams</head><p>Next, we did a percentage match with the text of the article. This was a bag-of-words check using unigram overlap between the tweet and the doc- ument. Let unigrams(x) be the set of unigrams for some text x, then u, the percentage of match- ing unigrams found between a given tweet, t and a given article, a, can be defined as u = |unigrams(t) ∩ unigrams(a)| |unigrams(t)| * 100 (1) <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref> shows the percentage of matches in the tweet and the article text as compared to the num- ber of unigrams in the tweet. The mean match percentage is 29.53% and standard deviation is 20.2%. The mean of this distribution shows that the number of matched unigrams from a tweet in the article are fairly low. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 2</ref> shows the num- ber of articles with a certain number of matching unigrams. The graph shows that the most common number of unigrams matched was 2. The num- ber of articles with higher unigrams matched goes on decreasing. The slight rise at the end -more than 10 matched unigrams -is accounted for by the completely matched tweets described above.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3">Percentage Match for Bigrams</head><p>Similar to the unigram matching techniques, the bigram percentage matching was also calculated. The text of the tweet was converted into bigrams and we then looked for those bigrams in the ar- ticle text. The percentage was calculated similar to the unigram matching done earlier. For the set of bigrams for a text x, bigrams(x), percentage of matching bigrams b for the tweet t and article a is: <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 3</ref> shows the percentages of matched bi- grams found. The mean is 10.73 with a standard deviation of 18.5. As seen in the figure, most of the tweet-article pairs have no matched bigrams. The percentage then increases to reflect the com- plete matches found above. <ref type="figure">Figure 4</ref> shows frequency of the number of tweet-article pairs for the number of bigrams matched. There are no matched bigrams for most of the pairs. A smaller number of articles had one matched bigram, and the number decreased until the end, where it increases a little at more than 10 matched bigrams because of exact tweet matches.</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">b = |bigrams(t) ∩ bigrams(a)| |bigrams(t)| * 100 (2)</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.4">Percentage Match Inside a Window in the Article Text</head><p>The next analysis checks for a significant word matching inside a three-sentence window inside the article text. We used a three sentence long win- dow using the sentence boundary information ob- tained during preprocessing. A window of three sentences was chosen to give a smaller context for the tweet to be extracted from than the entire arti- cle. The number was chosen as a moderate context window size as not too small to reduce it to a sen- tence level, and not too big for the context to be diluted. This was done to investigate whether a pseudo-extractive multi-sentence compression ap- proach could convert a small number of sentences into a tweet. After the text of the window was extracted, we performed a similar analysis as the last one, ex- cept on a smaller set of sentences. The match- ing percentages from all three-sentence windows in the articles were computed and the maximum out of these was taken for the final results. Let a sentence window w i be the set of three consec- utive sentences starting from the sentence number i. For this window, the unigram match in the tweet t, and the window is the unigram match u calcu- lated above. Then, the maximum match from all the windows, uw is</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">uw = max w i ∈S u(t, w i )<label>(3)</label></formula><p>The result from this experiment is shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Fig- ure 5</ref>. Here, the mean of the values is 26.6% and deviation 17%. Again this shows that only a small proportion of tweets can be generated even with an approach that combines unigrams from multi- ple sentences in the article.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.5">Longest Common Subsequence Match Inside a Window for the Text</head><p>The percentage match analyses were a bag-of- words approach that disregarded the order of the words inside the texts and tweets. To respect the order of the words in the sentence of the tweet, we also used the least common subsequence al- gorithm between the tweet text and the document text. This subsequence matching was done inside a sentence window of 5 sentences. Again, the fi- nal result for the article was the window in which the maximum percentage was recorded among all windows. The percentage match was calculated using the number of words in the tweet as the de- nominator. If lcs(t, a) is the longest common subsequence between the tweet t and article a, unigrams(x) is the set of unigrams for a text x, then the percentage of match for the lcs as compared to the tweet, l is l = |lcs(t, a)| |unigrams(t)| * 100 (4)</p><p>These numbers are shown in <ref type="figure">Figure 6</ref>. The mean here is 44.6% and the standard deviation is 22.7%.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Interaction with Formality</head><p>As seen in the results of the analyses performed in Section 4, the tweets have little in common with the articles they are linked to. This shows that extractive summarization algorithms can only re- cover a small proportion of the indicative tweets.</p><p>To tie in the results of the findings above with some intuitive notions about the text and see how formality interacts with the results, we also cal- culated the formality of the articles. This formal- ity score was correlated with the longest common subsequence measure that we defined above.</p><p>We assume that the formality of an article can be estimated by the formality of the words and <ref type="figure">Figure 6</ref>: Percentages of words matching in tweet and document text using an LCS algorithm. Mean is 44.6%, which is shown by the red horizontal line, and standard deviation is 22.7%. phrases in the article. We used the formality lex- icon of <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Brooke and Hirst (2013)</ref>. They calculate formality scores for words and sentences by train- ing a model on a large corpus based on the ap- pearance of words in specific documents. Their model represents words as vectors and the formal and informal seeds appear in opposite halves of the graphs, suggesting that we can use these seeds to determine if an article is formal or informal. The lexicon consists of words and phrases and their de- gree of formality. Thus, more formal words are marked on a positive scale and informal words like those occurring in colloquial language are marked on a negative scale.</p><p>Let the set of formality expressions from the lexicon be L, and the formality score for an ex- pression e be score(e). Let the set of all substrings from the article substrings(a) be S. Then, the for- mality score f for an article a is the number of formal expressions per 10 words in article is</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">f = e∈L&amp;e∈S score(e) |unigrams(a)| * 10 (5)</formula><p>The formality lexicon gave positive weights for formal expressions and negative for informal ex- pressions. When we computed f using both for- mal and informal expressions, we found that the informal words predominated and "swamped" the signal of the formal words, leading to incompre- hensible results. Thus, we discarded the informal words and used only the weights from the formal words in our final calculations. To check that these formality scores made sense intuitively, we calcu- lated the average formality score for the articles belonging to each hashtag and ordered them, as shown in <ref type="table">Table 7</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Lowest</head><p>Highest #theforceawakens #KevinVickers #TaylorSwift #erdogan #winteriscoming #apec This formality score for each article was cor- related with the percentage of match obtained us- ing the longest common subsequence algorithm. The Pearson correlation value was 0.41, with a p- value of 7.08e-66, indicating that the interaction between formality and overlap was highly signifi- cant. Hence, we can say that the more formal the subject or the article, the better the tweet can be extracted from the article. <ref type="table">Table 7</ref> gives an exam- ple of the formality of the article, which is a low 4.2 formality words per 10 words, where the tweet is not extracted from the article, but rephrased from the article instead.  <ref type="table">Table 7</ref>: Example of a tweet, title of the article where the formality of the article is over the mean, and the tweet is extracted from the article.</p><p>We speculate that tweets associated with less formal articles may contain more abbreviations and non-standard words or spellings, which de- creases the amount of overlap. We plan to experi- ment with tweet normalization systems to account for this factor.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Discussions</head><p>Having presented the above statistics showing that only a small portion of indicative tweets can be recovered from the article they link to if viewed as an extractive summarization problem, the question then becomes, how should we view the process of tweet generation?</p><p>We think that one promising direction is to model more explicitly the intent, or the purpose of the tweets. There have been several studies on classifying intents in tweets, but in many cases the intents are general, high-level intents of the tweets, more akin to classifying the topic or genre of the tweet than the intent. <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Wang et al. (2015)</ref> clas- sify intents as food and drink, travel, career and so on, ones that can directly be used as intents for purchasing and can be utilized for advertisements. They also focus on finding tweets with intent and then classifying those. <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Banerjee et al. (2012)</ref> an- alyze real time data to detect presence of intents in tweets. <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Gómez-Adorno et al. (2014)</ref> use fea- tures from text and stylistics to determine user in- tentions, which are classified as news report, opin- ion, publicity and so on. <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Mohammad et al. (2013)</ref> study the classification of user intents specifically for tweets related to elections. They study one election and classify tweets as ones that agree or disagree with the candidate, ones that are meant for humour, support and so on.</p><p>These definitions of intent, while a promising start, will not be sufficient for tweet generation. For this purpose, intent would be the reason the user chose to share the article with that particu- lar text. This would include reasons like support some cause, promote a product or an article, agree or disagree with an event, or express an opinion about it. Identifying these intents will help pro- vide parameters for generating tweets.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7">Conclusion</head><p>We have described a study that investigates whether indicative tweet generation can be viewed as an extractive summarization problem. By ana- lyzing a collection of indicative tweets that we col- lected according to measures inspired by extrac- tive summarization evaluation measures, we find that most tweets cannot be recovered from the ar- ticle that they link to, demonstrating a limit to the effectiveness of extractive methods.</p><p>We further performed an analysis to deter- mine the role of formality differences between the source article and the Twitter genre. We find evi- dence that formality is an important factor, as the less formal the source article is, the less extrac-tive the tweets seem to be. Future methods that can change the level of formality of a piece of text without changing the contents will be needed, as will those that explicitly consider the intended use of the tweet.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: Distribution of unigram match percentage over unique tweets and articles. The mean is 29.53%, indicated by the red horizontal line, with a standard deviation of 20.2%</figDesc><graphic url="image-1.png" coords="5,72.00,62.81,226.77,170.08" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2: Histogram of number of unique tweetarticle pairs vs number of unigrams matched. The mean number of unigrams matched per tweetarticle pair is 3.9.</figDesc><graphic url="image-2.png" coords="5,307.28,62.81,226.77,170.08" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Figure 3: Distribution of bigram match percentage over the tweet-article pair. The mean here is 10.73% shown by the red horizontal line, with a standard deviation of 18.5%</figDesc><graphic url="image-3.png" coords="6,72.00,62.81,226.77,170.08" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>Figure 5 :</head><label>5</label><figDesc>Figure 5: Percentages of common words in tweet and a three sentence window in the article. The maximum match from all percentages is chosen for an article. The red horizontal line is the mean is 26.6%, and standard deviation 17%.</figDesc><graphic url="image-5.png" coords="7,72.00,62.81,226.77,170.08" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" validated="false"><head>Table 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Example of a tweet, title of the article and 
the text. 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4" validated="false"><head>Table 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Example of a tweet, title of the article and 
the text when tweet cannot be extracted from text. 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_6" validated="false"><head>Table 5 :</head><label>5</label><figDesc>Example where tweet is extracted as is from the text, matched portion in bold.</figDesc><table></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_7" validated="false"><head>Table 6 :</head><label>6</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Table of hashtags (broadly, topics) with 
highest and lowest formality according to the lex-
icon. 

</table></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> https://about.twitter.com/company</note>

			<note place="foot" n="2"> https://pypi.python.org/pypi/newspaper</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>We would like to thank the anonymous review-ers for their comments and suggestions, and Julian Brooke for the formality lexicon used in a part of this study.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Towards analyzing micro-blogs for detection and classification of real-time intentions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nilanjan</forename><surname>Banerjee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dipanjan</forename><surname>Chakraborty</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Anupam</forename><surname>Joshi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sumit</forename><surname>Mittal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Angshu</forename><surname>Rai</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Balaraman</forename><surname>Ravindran</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ICWSM</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="391" to="394" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A multidimensional bayesian approach to lexical style</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Julian</forename><surname>Brooke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Graeme</forename><surname>Hirst</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">HLT-NAACL</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="673" to="679" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Event summarization using tweets</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Deepayan</forename><surname>Chakrabarti</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kunal</forename><surname>Punera</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">ICWSM</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="66" to="73" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Extracting diverse sentiment expressions with target-dependent polarity from twitter</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lu</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wenbo</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Meenakshi</forename><surname>Nagarajan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Shaojun</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Amit P</forename><surname>Sheth</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ICWSM</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="50" to="57" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Towards robust abstractive multi-document summarization: A caseframe analysis of centrality and domain</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jackie</forename><forename type="middle">Chi</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kit</forename><surname>Cheung</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gerald</forename><surname>Penn</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ACL (1)</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1233" to="1242" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Topic-focused multi-document summarization using an approximate oracle score</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Judith</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>John M Conroy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dianne P O&amp;apos;</forename><surname>Schlesinger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Leary</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the COLING/ACL on Main conference poster sessions</title>
		<meeting>the COLING/ACL on Main conference poster sessions</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="152" to="159" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rumi</forename><surname>Ghosh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tawan</forename><surname>Surachawala</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kristina</forename><surname>Lerman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:1106.0346</idno>
		<title level="m">Entropy-based classification of&apos;retweeting&apos;activity on twitter</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
<note type="report_type">arXiv preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Content and style features for automatic detection of users intentions in tweets</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Helena</forename><surname>Gómez-Adorno</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Pinto</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Manuel</forename><surname>Montes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Grigori</forename><surname>Sidorov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rodrigo</forename><surname>Alfaro</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Advances in Artificial Intelligence-IBERAMIA 2014</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="120" to="128" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Comparing presentation summaries: slides vs. reading vs. listening</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Liwei</forename><surname>He</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Elizabeth</forename><surname>Sanocki</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Anoop</forename><surname>Gupta</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jonathan</forename><surname>Grudin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the SIGCHI conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems</title>
		<meeting>the SIGCHI conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="177" to="184" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Comparing twitter summarization algorithms for multiple post summaries</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Inouye</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Kalita</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Privacy, Security, Risk and Trust (PASSAT) and 2011 IEEE Third Inernational Conference on Social Computing (SocialCom)</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>IEEE</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="298" to="306" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>IEEE Third International Conference on</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A dependency parser for tweets</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lingpeng</forename><surname>Kong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nathan</forename><surname>Schneider</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Swabha</forename><surname>Swayamdipta</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Archna</forename><surname>Bhatia</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chris</forename><surname>Dyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Noah</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Smith</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2014 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP)</title>
		<meeting>the 2014 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP)<address><addrLine>Doha, Qatar</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2014-10" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1001" to="1012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Rouge: A package for automatic evaluation of summaries</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chin-Yew</forename><surname>Lin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Text Summarization Branches Out: Proceedings of the ACL-04 Workshop</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="74" to="81" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Towards automatic tweet generation: A comparative study from the text summarization perspective in the journalism genre</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Elena</forename><surname>Lloret</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Manuel</forename><surname>Palomar</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Expert Systems with Applications</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">40</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">16</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="6624" to="6630" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">iparticipate: Automatic tweet generation from local government data</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christoph</forename><surname>Lofi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ralf</forename><surname>Krestel</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Database Systems for Advanced Applications</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="295" to="298" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Automatic summarization</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Inderjeet</forename><surname>Mani</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
			<publisher>John Benjamins Publishing</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The stanford corenlp natural language processing toolkit</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mihai</forename><surname>Christopher D Manning</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">John</forename><surname>Surdeanu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jenny</forename><surname>Bauer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Finkel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Steven</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Bethard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Mcclosky</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of 52nd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics: System Demonstrations</title>
		<meeting>52nd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics: System Demonstrations</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="55" to="60" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Identifying purpose behind electoral tweets</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Saif</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Svetlana</forename><surname>Mohammad</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Joel</forename><surname>Kiritchenko</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Martin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Second International Workshop on Issues of Sentiment Discovery and Opinion Mining</title>
		<meeting>the Second International Workshop on Issues of Sentiment Discovery and Opinion Mining</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="9" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Tweetmotif: Exploratory search and topic summarization for Twitter</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O&amp;apos;</forename><surname>Brendan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michel</forename><surname>Connor</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Krieger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Ahn</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ICWSM</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="384" to="385" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Improved part-of-speech tagging for online conversational text with word clusters</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Olutobi</forename><surname>Owoputi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O&amp;apos;</forename><surname>Brendan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chris</forename><surname>Connor</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kevin</forename><surname>Dyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nathan</forename><surname>Gimpel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Noah</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Schneider</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Smith</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2013 Conference of the North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics: Human Language Technologies</title>
		<meeting>the 2013 Conference of the North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics: Human Language Technologies<address><addrLine>Atlanta, Georgia</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2013-06" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="380" to="390" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Socially-informed timeline generation for complex events</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lu</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Claire</forename><surname>Cardie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Galen</forename><surname>Marchetti</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of Human Language Technologies: The 2015 Annual Conference of the North American Chapter of the ACL</title>
		<meeting>Human Language Technologies: The 2015 Annual Conference of the North American Chapter of the ACL</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1055" to="1065" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Mining user intents in twitter: A semi-supervised approach to inferring intent categories for tweets</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jinpeng</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gao</forename><surname>Cong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xin</forename><forename type="middle">Wayne</forename><surname>Zhao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xiaoming</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Twenty-Ninth AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="339" to="345" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Utilizing microblogs for automatic news highlights extraction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Zhongyu</forename><surname>Wei</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wei</forename><surname>Gao</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of COLING 2014, the 25th International Conference on Computational Linguistics: Technical Papers</title>
		<meeting>COLING 2014, the 25th International Conference on Computational Linguistics: Technical Papers</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="872" to="883" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
