<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T12:44+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Experiments in Open Domain Deception Detection</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
				<availability status="unknown"><p>Copyright Association for Computational Linguistics</p>
				</availability>
				<date type="published" when="2015-09">September 2015. 2015</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Verónica</forename><surname>Pérez-Rosas</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Computer Science and Engineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Michigan</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rada</forename><surname>Mihalcea</surname></persName>
							<email>mihalcea@umich.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Computer Science and Engineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Michigan</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Experiments in Open Domain Deception Detection</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2015 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</title>
						<meeting>the 2015 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing <address><addrLine>Lisbon, Portugal</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="17" to="21"/>
							<date type="published" when="2015-09">September 2015. 2015</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>The widespread use of deception in online sources has motivated the need for methods to automatically profile and identify deceivers. This work explores deception, gender and age detection in short texts using a machine learning approach. First, we collect a new open domain deception dataset also containing demographic data such as gender and age. Second, we extract feature sets including n-grams, shallow and deep syntactic features, semantic features, and syntactic complexity and readability metrics. Third, we build clas-sifiers that aim to predict deception, gender , and age. Our findings show that while deception detection can be performed in short texts even in the absence of a predetermined domain, gender and age prediction in deceptive texts is a challenging task. We further explore the linguistic differences in deceptive content that relate to deceivers gender and age and find evidence that both age and gender play an important role in people&apos;s word choices when fabricating lies.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Given the potential ethical and security risks as- sociated with deceitful interactions, it is important to build computational tools able not only to detect deceivers but also to provide insights into the na- ture of deceptive behaviors. In particular, informa- tion related to the demographics of the deceivers could be potentially useful, as recent studies have shown that online users lie frequently about their appearance, gender, age or even education level.</p><p>There are multiple scenarios where it would be desirable to identify deceivers' demographics; for instance, identifying the age and gender of SMS senders or Twitter users might help improve parental controls, spam filtering, and user's secu- rity and privacy.</p><p>In this paper, we present a study on deception detection in an open domain, and also present an analysis of deceptive behavior in association with gender and age. Unlike previous studies, where domain-specific conversational transcripts and re- views have been used, this research targets the identification of deceit in short texts where domain and context are not available. We aim to build deception, age, and gender classifiers using short texts, and also explore the prediction of gender and age in deceptive content. Moreover, we present an analysis of the topics discussed by deceivers given their age and gender based on the assumption that, when lying in an open domain setting, deceivers will show natural bias towards specific topics re- lated to gender and age.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Related work</head><p>To date, several studies have explored the iden- tification of deceptive content in a variety of do- mains, including online dating, forums, social net- works, and consumer reviews. ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Toma and Hancock, 2010</ref>) conducted linguistic analyses in on- line dating profiles and identified correlations be- tween deceptive profiles and self references, nega- tions, and lower levels of words usage. A study for deception detection on essays and product re- views is presented in <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Feng et al., 2012)</ref>. <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(Ott et al., 2011</ref>) addressed the identification of spam in consumer reviews and also studied the human capability of detecting deceptive reviews, which was found not better than chance. In a follow- ing study, <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Ott et al., 2013</ref>) presented an analy- sis of the sentiment associated to deceitful reviews focusing particularly in those containing negative sentiment as it largely affects consumer purchase decisions. More recently ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Yu et al., 2015)</ref>  <ref type="table">pre- sented a study where authors analyze the role of  deception in online networks by detecting decep- tive groups in a social elimination-game.</ref> This previous work has shown the effectiveness of features derived from text analysis, which fre- quently includes basic linguistic representations such as n-grams and sentence counts statistics ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Mihalcea and Strapparava, 2009;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Ott et al., 2011</ref>) and also more complex linguistic features derived from syntactic context free grammar trees and part of speech tags <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Feng et al., 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Xu and Zhao, 2012)</ref>. Other studies have focused on deception clues inspired from psychological studies. For instance, following the hypothesis that deceivers might create less complex sentences <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(DePaulo et al., 2003)</ref>, researchers have incorporated syntactic complexity measures into the analysis. ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Yancheva and Rudzicz, 2013</ref>) presented a study based on the analysis of syntactic units and found that syntac- tic complexity correlates with deceiver's age. Psy- cholinguistics lexicons, such as Linguistic Inquiry and Word Count (LIWC) <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Pennebaker and Francis, 1999</ref>), have also been used to build deception models using machine learning approaches <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Mihalcea and Strapparava, 2009;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Almela et al., 2012)</ref> and showed that the use of semantic information is helpful for the automatic identification of deceit.</p><p>While there is a significant body of work on computational deception detection, except for ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Yancheva and Rudzicz, 2013)</ref> who considered the relation between syntactic constructs and de- ceivers' age, to our knowledge there are no com- putational analyses of demographics in deceptive content. However, there have been a number of psychological studies on the role of gender and age in deceptive behavior. These studies have found interesting associations between deception and gender. For instance, ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Toma et al., 2008</ref>) iden- tified differences in self-presentation among gen- ders. In this study men were found to lie more about their height and women lied more about their weight. ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Kaina et al., 2011)</ref> found that fe- males are more easily detectable when lying than their male counterparts. ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Tilley et al., 2005</ref>) re- ported that females are more successful in decep- tion detection than male receivers.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Open Domain Deception Dataset</head><p>We started our study by collecting a new open do- main deception dataset consisting of freely con- tributed truths and lies. We used Amazon Me- chanical Turk and asked each worker to contribute seven lies and seven truths, on topics of their own choice, each of them consisting of one single sen- tence. In an attempt to obtain truths and lies that represent everyday lying behavior, we asked our contributors to provide plausible lies and avoid non-commonsensical statements such as "I can fly." Since we did not enforce a particular topic, resulting truths and lies are open domain. Sample truths and lies are presented in <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>. Note that the collected lies might include statements that are somehow unrealistic, even if plausible, e.g., "I own two Ferraris, one red and one black". We decided to also include these statements in order to aid the identification of differences in deceivers and true-tellers language, as we hypothesize that they might help reveal topics that naturally occur in truths and lies.</p><p>Additionally, we collect demographic data from the contributors, including their gender, age, coun- try of origin, and education level. To avoid spam, contributions were manually verified by one of the paper authors. The final dataset consists of 7168 sentences from 512 unique contributors. Since each contributor provided seven lies and seven truths the dataset contains a total of 3584 truths and 3584 lies respectively. Participant's ages range from 18 to 72 years, with an average age of 34.14 and a standard deviation of 12.67.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Features</head><p>In this section, we describe the sets of features ex- tracted, which will then be used to build our clas- sifiers.</p><p>Unigrams We extract unigrams derived from the bag of words representation of truths and lies present in our dataset.</p><p>Shallow and deep syntax features These fea- tures consist of part of speech (POS) tags and lexicalized production rules derived from Probabilistic Context Free Grammar (PCFG) trees, obtained with the Berkeley Parser ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Petrov et al., 2006</ref>).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Female</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Lie</head><p>Truth I won 1 billion dollars in the Illinois state lottery last year and gave it all away to my mother.</p><p>My daughter is my best friend in the whole wide world, and i would give my life for hers. On my last birthday i turned 119 years old and went sky diving as a gift to myself.</p><p>I graduated with a degree in information systems 10 years ago and still can't find a good job. I'm allergic to alcohol Giraffes are taller than zebras. Male Lie Truth Barak obama was my guest last night; he offered me the administrative assistant job at white house in Washington.</p><p>Internet is one of the greatest invention of his- tory of humankind with its ability to speed up the communication. I own two Ferraris, one red and one black I love to play soccer with my friends I wake up at 11 o clock every day I wake up at 6 am because I have to work at 7 am <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>: Sample open-domain lies and truths provided by male and a female participants</p><p>Semantic features These features include the 80 semantic classes present in the LIWC lexi- con. Each feature represents the number of words in a sentence belonging to a specific semantic class.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Readability and Syntactic Complexity features</head><p>This set includes the Flesch-Kincaid and Gunning Fog readability scores and 14 indexes of syntactic complexity derived from the syntactic analysis of each sentence; performed with the tool provided by Lu (Lu, 2010).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Classification of Deception, Gender, and Age in Short Texts</head><p>Our first experiment seeks to evaluate whether de- ception detection can be conducted using the open domain deception dataset described above. We performed the evaluations at user level, by collaps- ing all the lies from one user into one instance, and all the truths into another instance. We build deception classifiers using the SVM algorithm <ref type="bibr">1</ref> and the different sets of features. We performed a five-fold cross-validation, by training each time on 80% of the users and testing on the remaining 20%. During our evaluations truths and lies pertaining to a particular user were either on the training or testing set. Classification results on individual and combined sets of features are pre- sented in <ref type="table">Table 3</ref>. The best performing set of fea- 1 As implemented in the Weka toolkit, with default param- eter settings. tures are the POS tags, followed by features de- rived from production rules. The remaining sets of features achieved accuracy values ranging from 54% to 65%, which still represent a noticeable im- provement over the random baseline. Note that we experimented with a few more feature sets combi- nations, including the use of all the features to- gether, however we did not observe significant im- provements.</p><p>To analyze the impact of the amount of data on the classifier learning process, we plot the learn- ing curves on the different sets of features using incremental amounts of data as shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref>. Evaluations were conducted using five-fold cross validations on each incremental fraction of data. The learning trend suggests that most classifiers benefit from increasing amounts of training data. <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Female  298  Male  214   Age  Young ( 35 years)</ref> 319 Middle-aged/Elder (&gt;35 years) 193  <ref type="table">Table 3</ref>: SVM classifiers trained for three predic- tion tasks: deception, gender, and age.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Gender</head><p>However, except for the POS features, the overall performance seems to stabilize when using 90% of the training data.</p><p>As a second experiment, we evaluate the abil- ity of the classifier to predict gender and age in short open domain deceptive texts. Given the con- tributors' age distribution, which lies mainly in the range of 30-45 years, we opted to cluster the par- ticipants age into into two groups: young ( 35 years) and middle-aged/elder (&gt;35 years). Class distributions for age and gender are shown in Ta- ble 2. We performed the age prediction task on the two groups using the different sets of features and SVM classifiers. Classification accuracies are shown in <ref type="table">Table 3</ref>. Reported baselines consist of a majority class baseline. Results show low to moderate improvement over the baseline for gen- der classification, with the combination of seman- tic features and unigrams being the best perform- ing feature set. However, our classifiers performed poorly in the age prediction task, with accuracies below the majority class baseline.</p><p>Overall, the results suggest that age and gender prediction are challenging tasks when conducted in open domain deception data. One possible ex- planation for this is that the lack of context intro- duces noise into the analysis. For instance, the fol- lowing sentence: "I'm 50 years old" can belong to either a male or a female, and it might be a lie for younger people or a truth for older people.  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Lies</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Analyzing Language Used by Deceivers Given Age and Gender</head><p>In order to explore language differences among deceivers and true-tellers, we use the linguis- tic ethnography method <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Mihalcea and Pulman, 2009)</ref> and obtain the most dominant semantic word classes in the LIWC lexicon associated to truth and lies provided by males and females. Re- sults are shown in <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">Table 4</ref>. From this table, we observe interesting patterns in word usage that are shared among genders. For instance, spon- taneous lies often include negation, certain, and you words, which is in line with previous work on domain-specific deception <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Mihalcea and Strapparava, 2009</ref>) that suggested that liars try to rein- force their lies through the use of stronger word- ing and detachment from the self. On the other hand, people appear to be less likely to lie when talking about their family, religion, and describing positive experiences. There are also LIWC classes associated to a specific gender. Male lies contain references to friends and others, while female lies contain references to money and future. Similarly, female true-tellers use metaphor words while male true-tellers use words related to sports and music.  We also evaluate differences in word usage that might be attributed to deceiver's age. Resulting dominant classes and their scores are presented in <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">Table 5</ref>. The analyses show interesting differences for deceiver's word usage across age. For instance, regardless of their gender, older deceivers use ref- erences to anxiety, money, and motion. On the other hand, younger deceivers language includes anger, negate, and death words. These differences suggest that indeed gender and age play a role on people words choices while fabricating lies.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Lies</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7">Conclusions</head><p>In this paper, we presented our initial experiments in open domain deception detection. We target- ted the deception detection on short text to address the cases where context is not available. In real settings, this can be useful when receiving a text message or when looking at anonymous posts in forums. We collected a new deception dataset con- sisting of one-sentence truths and lies, along with the demographics of the deceivers. Through sev- eral experiments, we showed that this data can be used to build deception classifiers for short open domain text. However, the classifiers do not per- form very well while trying to predict gender and age. We further explored linguistic differences in deceptive content that relate to deceivers gen- der and age and found evidence that both age and gender play an important role on people's word choices when fabricating lies.</p><p>The dataset introduced in this paper is publicly available from http://lit.eecs.umich.edu.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: Learning curves for deception detection using five feature sets</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" validated="true"><head>Table 2 : Class distribution for gender and age</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Feature set 
Deception Gender 
Age 
Baseline 
50.00% 
58.00% 62.00% 
Unigrams 
60.89% 
54.25% 51.12% 
Semantic 
60.21% 
57.28% 61.83% 
POS 
69.50% 
49.95% 52.39% 
CFG 
65.39% 
52.19% 54.74% 
Readability 
54.44% 
58.16% 62.26% 
Uni+Semantic 
62.17% 
63.04% 51.51% 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" validated="false"><head>Table 4 :</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Results from LIWC word class analysis for short open domain truths and lies.</figDesc><table></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4" validated="false"><head>Table 5 :</head><label>5</label><figDesc>Results from LIWC word class analysis for short open domain truths and lies.</figDesc><table></table></figure>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>This material is based in part upon work sup-ported by National Science Foundation awards #1344257 and #1355633, by grant #48503 from the John Templeton Foundation, and by DARPA-BAA-12-47 DEFT grant #12475008. Any opin-ions, findings, and conclusions or recommenda-tions expressed in this material are those of the authors and do not necessarily reflect the views of the National Science Foundation, the John Tem-pleton Foundation, or the Defense Advanced Re-search Projects Agency.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Seeing through deception: A computational approach to deceit detection in written communication</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">References´</forename><surname>References´a</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Almela</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Valencia-García</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Cantos</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Workshop on Computational Approaches to Deception Detection</title>
		<meeting>the Workshop on Computational Approaches to Deception Detection<address><addrLine>Avignon, France</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012-04" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="15" to="22" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Association for Computational Linguistics</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Cues to deception</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Depaulo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Lindsay</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Malone</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Muhlenbruck</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Charlton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Cooper</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Bulletin</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">129</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Syntactic stylometry for deception detection</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Feng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Banerjee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Choi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 50th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics: Short Papers</title>
		<meeting>the 50th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics: Short Papers<address><addrLine>Stroudsburg, PA, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="171" to="175" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Deception detection in multicultural coalitions: Foundations for a cognitive model</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Kaina</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Ceruti</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Mcgirr</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Law</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<publisher>DTIC Document</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
<note type="report_type">Technical report</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Automatic analysis of syntactic complexity in second language writing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Lu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">International Journal of Corpus Linguistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="474" to="496" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Linguistic ethnography: Identifying dominant word classes in text</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Mihalcea</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Pulman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Computational Linguistics and Intelligent Text Processing</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="594" to="602" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The lie detector: Explorations in the automatic recognition of deceptive language</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Mihalcea</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Strapparava</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL 2009)</title>
		<meeting>the Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL 2009)<address><addrLine>Singapore</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Finding deceptive opinion spam by any stretch of the imagination</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Ott</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Choi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Cardie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Hancock</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 49th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics: Human Language Technologies</title>
		<meeting>the 49th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics: Human Language Technologies<address><addrLine>Stroudsburg, PA, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="309" to="319" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Negative deceptive opinion spam</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Ott</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Cardie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Hancock</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2013 Conference of the North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics: Human Language Technologies, Short Papers</title>
		<meeting>the 2013 Conference of the North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics: Human Language Technologies, Short Papers<address><addrLine>Atlanta, Georgia, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2013-06" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Linguistic inquiry and word count: LIWC</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Pennebaker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Francis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
			<publisher>Erlbaum Publishers</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Learning accurate, compact, and interpretable tree annotation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Petrov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Barrett</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Thibaux</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Klein</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 21st International Conference on Computational Linguistics and the 44th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics, ACL-44</title>
		<meeting>the 21st International Conference on Computational Linguistics and the 44th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics, ACL-44<address><addrLine>Stroudsburg, PA, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="433" to="440" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Association for Computational Linguistics</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Gender differences in deception and its detection under varying electronic media conditions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Tilley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>George</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Marett</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Proceedings of the 38th Annual Hawaii International Conference on System Sciences (HICSS&apos;05)-Track 1</title>
		<meeting>the the 38th Annual Hawaii International Conference on System Sciences (HICSS&apos;05)-Track 1<address><addrLine>Washington, DC, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>IEEE Computer Society</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">01</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">24</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>HICSS &apos;05</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Reading between the lines: Linguistic cues to deception in online dating profiles</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Toma</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Hancock</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2010 ACM Conference on Computer Supported Cooperative Work, CSCW &apos;10</title>
		<meeting>the 2010 ACM Conference on Computer Supported Cooperative Work, CSCW &apos;10<address><addrLine>New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="5" to="8" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Separating fact from fiction: An examination of deceptive self-presentation in online dating profiles</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Toma</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Hancock</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Ellison</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Personality and Social Psychology Bulletin</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">34</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1023" to="1036" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Using deep linguistic features for finding deceptive opinion spam</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Q</forename><surname>Xu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Zhao</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">The COLING 2012 Organizing Committee</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Mumbai, India</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012-12" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1341" to="1350" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Proceedings of COLING 2012: Posters</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Automatic detection of deception in child-produced speech using syntactic complexity features</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Yancheva</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Rudzicz</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 51st Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the 51st Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics<address><addrLine>Sofia, Bulgaria</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2013-08" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="944" to="953" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Detecting deceptive groups using conversations and network analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Yu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Tyshchuk</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Ji</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Wallace</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 53rd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics and the 7th International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing of the Asian Federation of Natural Language Processing</title>
		<meeting>the 53rd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics and the 7th International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing of the Asian Federation of Natural Language Processing<address><addrLine>Beijing, China</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Long Papers</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2015-07-26" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="857" to="866" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
