<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T12:13+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Sieve-Based Spatial Relation Extraction with Expanding Parse Trees</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
				<availability status="unknown"><p>Copyright Association for Computational Linguistics</p>
				</availability>
				<date type="published" when="2015-09">September 2015. 2015</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jennifer</forename><forename type="middle">D &amp;apos;</forename><surname>Souza</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Human Language Technology Research Institute University of Texas at Dallas Richardson</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>75083-0688</postCode>
									<region>TX</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Vincent</forename><surname>Ng</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Human Language Technology Research Institute University of Texas at Dallas Richardson</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>75083-0688</postCode>
									<region>TX</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Sieve-Based Spatial Relation Extraction with Expanding Parse Trees</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2015 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</title>
						<meeting>the 2015 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing <address><addrLine>Lisbon, Portugal</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="17" to="21"/>
							<date type="published" when="2015-09">September 2015. 2015</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>A key challenge introduced by the recent SpaceEval shared task on spatial relation extraction is the identification of MOVELINKs, a type of spatial relation in which up to eight spatial elements can participate. To handle the complexity of extracting MOVELINKs, we combine two ideas that have been successfully applied to information extraction tasks, namely tree kernels and multi-pass sieves, proposing the use of an expanding parse tree as a novel structured feature for training MOVELINK classifiers. Our approach yields state-of-the-art results on two key tasks in SpaceEval.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Spatial relation extraction is the task of determin- ing the relation among a set of spatial elements. Although it has thus far received much less atten- tion than temporal relation extraction, there has been a surge of interest in it in recent years, as evidenced by the organization of the three shared tasks on spatial relation extraction, namely the spatial role labeling tasks in 2012 ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Kordjamshidi et al., 2012</ref>) and 2013 ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Kolomiyets et al., 2013)</ref>, as well as this year's SpaceEval task ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Pustejovsky et al., 2015)</ref>. The task has also evolved over the years, with new types of spatial elements and/or spatial relations being defined in each shared task. For instance, while the first two shared tasks have focused on extracting spatial relations between stationary objects, SpaceEval examines for the first time spatial relations on objects in motion.</p><p>Extracting spatial relations on objects in mo- tion, or MOVELINKs, is very challenging. The challenge stems in part from the fact that a MOVELINK involves two mandatory participants (with roles mover and trigger) and up to six op- tional participants (with other semantic roles). As an example, consider the MOVELINK that can be extracted from the sentence "John walked from Boston to Cambridge". As shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref>, this MOVELINK involves six spatial elements: "John" as the mover, "walked" as the trigger, "Boston" as the source, "Cambridge" as the goal, and "from" and "to" as the motion signals.</p><p>Given the complexity of MOVELINKs, any ap- proach that attempts to jointly identify all the spa- tial elements involved in a MOVELINK and their roles is computationally infeasible. On the other extreme, one can tackle the task by identifying each element involved in a MOVELINK indepen- dently of the other elements. In fact, this is roughly the approach adopted by our participating sys- tem in SpaceEval <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(D'Souza and Ng, 2015)</ref>, which achieved the best results in one of the SpaceE- val tasks involving MOVELINK extraction. Specif- ically, this system trains one classifier for each optional role r to identify the filler for r in a MOVELINK independently of the other optional roles. Although this approach has achieved state- of-the-art performance, it is arguably not ideal: in- tuitively, dependencies exist among elements of different roles, and not capturing them may harm system performance.</p><p>Our goal in this paper is to advance the state of the art in spatial relation extraction, focusing on the extraction of MOVELINKs by addressing the aforementioned weakness. The key question is: how can we capture the dependencies among the spatial elements involved without sacrificing computational tractability? To address this ques- tion, we combine two ideas that have been suc- cessfully applied to a variety of information ex- traction tasks, namely multi-pass sieves <ref type="bibr">(Raghu-nathan et al., 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Lee et al., 2013</ref>) and tree kernels <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Moschitti, 2004;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Moschitti, 2006</ref>). Re- call that a sieve-based approach is composed of a pipeline of sieves ordered by precision, where the decisions made by earlier sieves can be exploited by later sieves in order to incrementally construct a complex structure. When applied to MOVELINK identification, we can create a sieve for identifying each role, so that (1) spatial elements correspond- ing to different roles are incrementally added to a MOVELINK, and (2) earlier attachment decisions can be exploited as additional contextual informa- tion by later sieves. Hence, compared to a joint approach, a sieve-based approach achieves com- putational tractability by modeling partial, rather than full dependencies among the spatial elements.</p><p>While a sieve-based approach allows us to ex- ploit additional contextual information provided by earlier sieves, we still have to specify how we encode such contextual information. Motivated by the successful application of tree kernels to rela- tion extraction (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Zelenko et al. (2003)</ref>, <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Culotta and Sorensen (2004)</ref>, <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Bunescu and Mooney (2005)</ref>, <ref type="bibr">Zhou et al. (2007)</ref>), we propose to (1) encode the syntactic context in which the spa- tial elements extracted by the sieves appear us- ing a syntactic parse tree, and then (2) employ the tree as an (additional) structured feature for train- ing the classifier associated with each sieve. This novel combination of sieves and tree-based struc- tured features results in what we call an expand- ing parse tree. Specifically, as a spatial element for a MOVELINK is extracted by a (role-specific) sieve, it will be added to the structured feature for the classifier associated with the following sieve. In other words, the parse tree corresponding to the structured feature will keep expanding as we move along the sieves in the pipeline. This con- trasts with previous applications of tree kernels, where a structured feature is created from a static parse subtree for extracting exactly two arguments involved in a relation. To our knowledge, this is the first attempt to combine sieves and parse trees to create expanding trees to extract complex rela- tions involving multiple arguments.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Corpus and Task Definition</head><p>In this section, we introduce our corpus and the spatial relation extraction task. Owing to space limitations, we will only discuss those aspects that are relevant to the SpaceEval tasks we focus on.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">The SpaceEval Corpus</head><p>We use as our corpus the SpaceEval training cor- pus, which is a subset of ISO-SpaceBank <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">(Pustejovsky and Yocum, 2013)</ref>. The corpus consists of 59 travel narratives annotated with seven types of spatial elements <ref type="table">(Table 1)</ref> and three types of spatial relations <ref type="table">(Table 2)</ref>, following the ISO- Space (2012) annotation specifications. Different types of spatial elements have different attributes. The only attribute that is relevant to our work is semantic type, which is one of the attributes of a spatial entity. Semantic type expresses the type of the relation it triggers and can take one of three values: topological, directional, or both.</p><p>What is missing in <ref type="table">Table 2</ref> about spatial rela- tions is that each element participating in a re- lation has a role. Each QSLINK/OLINK involves exactly three elements participating as trajector (the object of interest), landmark (the ground- ing location), and trigger (the relation indicator). On the other hand, a MOVELINK has two fixed participants and up to six optional participants. The two mandatory MOVELINK participants are mover (object in motion) and trigger (verb de- noting motion). Five of the optional participants express different aspects of the mover in space, namely, source (the spatial element at the begin- ning of the motion path), midpoint (the spatial elements along the motion path), goal (the spatial element at the end of the motion path), path (the spatial element that reflects the path of motion), and landmark (the grounding location). The sixth optional participant, motion signal, con- nects the spatial aspect to the mover. Note that all spatial relations are intra-sentential.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">The Spatial Relation Extraction Task</head><p>Given a set of n spatial elements, the spatial rela- tion extraction task aims to (1) determine whether the elements form a spatial relation of a par- ticular type, and if so, (2) classify the roles of each participating element. For example, from the sentence "The cup is on the table", two re- lations can be extracted: QSLINK(cup trajector , table landmark , on trigger ) and OLINK(cup trajector , table landmark , on trigger ).</p><p>As another exam- ple, from the sentence "John walked from Boston to Cambridge", a MOVELINK with partici- pants John mover , walked trigger , from motion signal , Boston source , to motion signal , and Cambridge goal can be extracted. A geographic entity or region (e.g., lakes, mountains) or an administrative entity (e.g., towns, countries) path A location where the focus is on the potential for traversal (e.g., road) spatial entity A spatially relevant entity that is neither a place nor a path (e.g., car) non-motion event An event that does not involve movement but is directly related to another spatial element motion event A species of event that involves movement (e.g., arrived) motion signal A particle, preposition, verb, or adverb that encodes path or manner information about a motion event spatial signal A preposition/prepositional phrase that reveals the relationship between two locations (e.g., north of) <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>: Seven types of spatial elements in SpaceEval.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Relation Description</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>QSLINK</head><p>Exists between stationary spatial elements with a regional connection. E.g., in "The cup is on the table", the regions of "cup" and "table" are externally connected and hence they are involved in a QSLINK.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>OLINK</head><p>Exists between stationary spatial elements expressing their relative or absolute orientations. E.g., in the above sentence, "cup" and "table" are involved in an OLINK, which conveys that "cup" is oriented above "table".</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>MOVELINK</head><p>Exists between spatial elements in motion. E.g., in "John walked from Boston to Cambridge", there is a MOVELINK involving mover "John", motion verb "walked", source "Boston", and goal "Cambridge". <ref type="table">Table 2</ref>: Three types of spatial relations in SpaceEval.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Related Work</head><p>Broadly speaking, existing spatial relation extrac- tion systems have adopted either a pipeline ap- proach or a joint approach to these subtasks. Given a set of spatial elements, a pipeline spatial relation extraction system (1) extracts the triggers, (2) de- termines whether a spatial relation exists between each extracted trigger and each of the remaining spatial elements, and (3) classifies the role of each non-trigger in each pair of spatially-related ele- ments ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Kordjamshidi et al., 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Bastianelli et al., 2013;</ref>. The major weakness of pipeline approaches is that errors in trigger identification can propagate to the relation classification component, whose errors can in turn propagate to the role labeling component. To address this weakness, <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">Roberts et al. (2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b7">2013)</ref> investigated joint approaches. Given a set of spatial elements with an assign- ment of roles to each element, a joint spatial re- lation extraction system uses a binary classifier to determine whether these elements form a spa- tial relation with the roles correctly assigned to all participating elements. In other words, the clas- sifier will output a 1 if and only if (1) the ele- ments in the set form a relation and (2) their roles in the relation are correct. The systems participat- ing in SpaceEval all seem to be in favor of joint approaches <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(D'Souza and Ng, 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Nichols and Botros, 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b21">Salaberri et al., 2015</ref>).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Baseline System</head><p>To ensure that we have a state-of-the-art baseline system for spatial relation extraction, we employ our SpaceEval participating system <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(D'Souza and Ng, 2015)</ref>, which achieved the best results on task 3a in the official SpaceEval evaluation. <ref type="bibr">1</ref> This Baseline system performs joint role la- beling and relation classification using an ensem- ble of classifiers. Specifically, it trains one clas- sifier for extracting QSLINKs and OLINKs, and seven classifiers for extracting MOVELINKs. Cre- ating these eight classifiers permits (1) separating the treatment of MOVELINKs from QSLINKs and OLINKs (because the former involves objects in motion while the latter involve stationary objects); and (2) simplifying the extraction of MOVELINKs (because its optional participants are extracted in- dependently of each other by these classifiers).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">Training the Baseline Classifiers</head><p>In this subsection, we describe how we train the Baseline classifiers, which include one clas- sifier for identifying QSLINKs and OLINKs (Sec- tion 4.1.1) and seven classifiers for identifying MOVELINKs (Section 4.1.2).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1.1">The LINK Classifier</head><p>We collapse QSLINKs and OLINKs to a single re- lation type, LINK, identifying these two types of links using the LINK classifier. To understand why we can do this, recall from Section 2.1 that in QS- LINKs and OLINKs, the trigger has to be a spatial signal element having a semantic type attribute. If its semantic type is topological, it triggers a QS- LINK; if it is directional, it triggers an OLINK; and if it is both, it triggers both relation types. Hence, if a LINK is identified by our classifier, we can sim- ply use the semantic type of the relation's trigger to determine whether the relation is a QSLINK, an OLINK, or both.</p><p>We create training instances for training a LINK classifier as follows. Following the joint ap- proach described above, we create one training instance for each possible role labeling of each triplet of distinct spatial elements in each sen- tence in a training document. The role labels assigned to the spatial elements in each triplet are subject to the following constraints: (1) each triplet contains a trajector, a landmark, and a trigger; (2) neither the trajector nor the landmark are of type spatial signal or motion signal; and (3) the trigger is a spatial signal. These role constraints are derived from the data annotation scheme. Note that a LINK may have at most one implicit participant. For instance, the relation LINK(balloon trajector , up trigger ) extracted from the sentence "The balloon went up" has an implicit landmark. To allow for implicit partic- ipants, from each training instance we have cre- ated thus far, we create three additional training instances, where exactly one of the three partici- pants has the value IMPLICIT.</p><p>A training instance is labeled as positive if and only if the elements in the triplet form a rela- tion and their roles are correct. As an example, for the QSLINK and OLINK sentence in <ref type="table">Table 2</ref>, exactly one positive instance, LINK(cup trajector , table landmark , on trigger ), will be created.</p><p>Each instance is represented using the 31 fea- tures, which can be broadly divided into seven types: lexical, grammatical, semantic, positional, distance, entity attributes, and entity roles. <ref type="bibr">2</ref> We train the LINK classifier using the SVM learning algorithm as implemented in the SVM light soft- ware package <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Joachims, 1999</ref>). To optimize clas- sifier performance, we tune two parameters, the regularization parameter C and the cost-factor pa- rameter J, to maximize F-score on the develop- ment data. <ref type="bibr">3</ref> Since joint tuning of these parameters is computationally expensive, we employ a hill- climbing algorithm to find a local maximum, al- tering one parameter at a time to optimize F-score by holding the other parameter fixed.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1.2">The Seven MOVELINK Classifiers</head><p>If we adopted the aforementioned joint method as is for extracting MOVELINKs, each instance would correspond to an octuple of the form (trigger i , mover j , source k , midpoint m , goal n , landmark o , path p , motion signal r ), where each participant in the octuple is either a dis- tinct spatial element with a role or the NULL el- ement (if it is not present in the relation). How- ever, generating role permutations for octuples from all spatial elements in a sentence is com- putationally infeasible. For this reason, we sim- plify MOVELINK extraction as follows. First, we decompose the MOVELINK octuple into seven smaller tuples including one pair and six triplets. These seven tuples are: <ref type="bibr">[1]</ref> (trigger i , mover j ); <ref type="bibr">[2]</ref> (trigger i , mover j , source k ); <ref type="bibr">[3]</ref> (trigger i , mover j , midpoint m ); <ref type="bibr">[4]</ref> (trigger i , mover j , goal n ); <ref type="bibr">[5]</ref> (trigger i , mover j , landmark o ); <ref type="bibr">[6]</ref> (trigger i , mover j , path p ); and <ref type="bibr">[7]</ref> (trigger i , mover j , motion signal r ). Then, we create seven separate classifiers for identifying these seven MOVELINK tuples, respectively.</p><p>Using this decomposition for MOVELINK in- stances, we can generate instances for each clas- sifier using the aforementioned joint approach as is. For instance, to train classifier <ref type="bibr">[1]</ref>, we gener- ate pairs of the form (trigger i , mover j ), where trigger i and mover j are spatial elements pro- posed as a candidate trigger and a candidate mover, respectively. Positive training instances are those (trigger i , mover j ) pairs annotated as being part of a MOVELINK in the training data, while the rest of the candidate pairs are negative training instances. The instances for training the remaining six classifiers are generated similarly.</p><p>As in the LINK classifier, we enforce global role constraints when creating training instances for the MOVELINK classifiers. Specifically, the roles assigned to the spatial elements in each training instance of each MOVELINK classifier are subject to six constraints: (1) the trigger has type motion event; (2) the mover has type place, path, spa- tial entity, or non-motion event; (3) the source, the goal, and the landmark can be NULL or have type place, path, spatial entity, or non-motion event; (4) the midpoint can be NULL or have type place, path, or spatial entity; (5) the path can be NULL or have type path; and (6) the motion signal can be NULL or have type motion signal.</p><p>Our method for decomposing the octuple by role can be justified as follows. Since trigger and mover are mandatory MOVELINK participants, we have a classifier for classifying this core aspect of a MOVELINK. The next six classifiers, <ref type="bibr">[2]</ref> to <ref type="bibr">[7]</ref>, aim to improve the core MOVELINK ex- traction by exploiting the contextual dependencies with each of its unique spatial aspects, namely source, midpoint, goal, landmark, path, and motion signal.</p><p>As an example, for the MOVELINK sentence in <ref type="table">Table 2</ref>, we will create three positive in- stances: (John mover , walked trigger ) for classi- fier <ref type="bibr">[1]</ref>, (John mover , walked trigger , Boston source ) for classifier <ref type="bibr">[2]</ref>, and (John mover , walked trigger , Cambridge goal ) for classifier <ref type="bibr">[4]</ref>.</p><p>We represent each training instance using the 31 features that were used to train the LINK classi- fier. We train each of the MOVELINK classifiers using SVM light . We tune the C and J parameters to maximize F-score on the development data us- ing the hill-climbing algorithm described earlier. <ref type="bibr">4</ref> </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">Applying the Baseline Classifiers</head><p>After training, we apply the resulting classifiers to classify the test instances, which are created in the same way as the training instances. As noted be- fore, each LINK extracted from a test document by the LINK classifier is further qualified as QS- LINK, OLINK, or both based on the semantic type of its trigger. The MOVELINKs are extracted from a test document by combining the outputs from the seven MOVELINK classifiers.</p><p>There is a caveat, however: different MOVELINK classifiers can make conflicting decisions. For instance, classifier <ref type="bibr">[1]</ref> might mis- classify (John mover , walked trigger ) as negative, whereas classifier <ref type="bibr">[2]</ref> might correctly classify (John mover , walked trigger , Boston source ) as pos- itive. To resolve these conflicting decisions, we give preference to positive decisions, meaning that in this case we will posit "John" and "walked" as having the roles of mover and trigger respectively. There are two more sources of conflicts. First, a spatial element may be assigned different roles for a given MOVELINK by different classifiers. Second, the global constraint that each MOVELINK can have at most one source, at most one goal, and at most one landmark can be violated. To resolve these conflicts, we select for each spatial element the role that was predicted with highest confidence by the SVM classifiers subject to the global constraint. <ref type="bibr">5</ref> </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Our Multi-Pass Sieve Approach</head><p>In this section, we describe two methods for em- ploying sieves for extracting spatial relations.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.1">Using Sieves without Trees</head><p>To motivate our first method, recall that the Base- line resolves conflicting decisions in a heuristic manner. For instance, it prefers positive to nega- tive decisions, effectively favoring recall over pre- cision for spatial relation extraction. It is not clear whether this ad-hoc decision is good or not. As another example, when more than one role is assigned to the same spatial element in a MOVELINK, it favors the role associated with the highest SVM confidence. This, however, is also an ad-hoc decision: recall that each classifier's pa- rameters are tuned independently of the others, so different confidence values assigned by different classifiers are not directly comparable.</p><p>Employing sieves for spatial relation extrac- tion obviates the need for such ad-hoc decisions. In our implementation, we have eight sieves, each of which corresponds to exactly one of the eight classifiers employed by the Baseline. Re- call from the introduction that these sieves are ordered as a pipeline. So, whenever a con- flict arises, earlier sieves' decisions have prece- dence over later sieves' decisions. Returning to the conflicting decisions mentioned before, if sieve 1 misclassifies (John mover , walked trigger ) as negative, whereas sieve 2 correctly classifies (John mover , walked trigger , Boston source ) as posi- tive, then we will posit that no MOVELINK exists between "John" and "walked" because we have more confidence in sieve 1's decision than sieve 2's decision. As another example, if two classi- fiers assign different roles to the same spatial ele- ment, then we will choose the role assigned by the classifier associated with the earlier sieve.</p><p>Given the above discussion, it should be clear that the ordering of the sieves is important. Typ- ically, sieves are ordered by precision, with the hope of reducing the number of erroneous deci-sions passed from the earlier sieves to the later sieves (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">Raghunathan et al. (2010)</ref>, <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Lee et al. (2013)</ref>, <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Chambers et al. (2014)</ref>). Motivated by this observation, we order the sieves as follows. We set sieve 0 to be the LINK classifier and sieve 1 to be the (trigger, mover) classifier, and then order the remaining sieves by precision. Specifically, we compute the precision of each sieve on the devel- opment data, then add sieves into the pipeline in decreasing order of precision.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.2">Using Sieves with Trees</head><p>Next, we describe our second method for applying sieves to spatial relation extraction. To motivate this method, recall that one important property of a sieve-based approach is that later sieves can ex- ploit earlier sieves' decisions when making their own decisions. However, our first method of using sieves makes limited use of the decisions made by earlier sieves. In particular, while each sieve ex- ploits the knowledge of whether a spatial element has been assigned a role by an earlier sieve, it does not exploit the knowledge of what the role is.</p><p>Our second method exploits the role decisions made by earlier sieves, but another question arises: how can we encode these role decisions so that they can be best exploited by later sieves? One possibility is to employ them as additional fea- tures for training the classifiers associated with later sieves. Motivated by previous work on tree kernels for relation extraction, we employ parse trees as a structured feature to encode the syntac- tic relationships among the roles extracted so far for a given MOVELINK.</p><p>We create the structured feature as follows. To strike a better balance between having a rich repre- sentation of the context surrounding a spatial rela- tion and improving the learner's ability to general- ize, we extract a subtree from a parse tree and use it as the value of the structured feature. Specif- ically, given relation candidate triplet (e 1 ,e 2 ,e 3 ), where spatial elements e 1 , e 2 , and e 3 are posited in roles r 1 , r 2 , and r 3 , respectively, and the asso- ciated syntactic parse tree T , we extract our parse subtree from T as follows. First, we identify the smallest subtree that covers all three spatial ele- ments and call its root r. Second, for each path from each spatial element to r, we include in the parse subtree all the nodes that lie on the path and their immediate children. Third, we simplify the subtree by removing the POS nodes above each spatial element, effectively attaching it to its grandparent. Finally, for better generalization, we replace each spatial element with its role. Since this subtree centers on a spatial relation, we call it a spatial relation centered tree (SRCT). As mentioned before, we will use SRCTs in com- bination with our sieve-based approach. This re- sults in a novel application of structured features: to our knowledge, all trees that were previously used as structured features were static. By con- trast, SRCTs expand as we move along the sieve pipeline. We will discuss examples of how to cre- ate SRCTs below.</p><p>Creating training instances with structured fea- tures is straightforward. Recall that a structured feature is used as an additional feature when train- ing each classifier. In other words, it will be used in combination with the original 31 features. The training instance creation method used by the Baseline remains unchanged. All we need to do is to add a SRCT as a structured feature to each training instance.</p><p>Consider the sentence "John walked from Boston to Cambridge", whose parse tree is shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Figure 2(a)</ref>. Since only one MOVELINK can be extracted from it, only one positive training instance will be created for each classifier. As- sume that sieve 1 contains the (trigger, mover) classifier; sieve 2 contains the (trigger, mover, motion signal) classifier; and sieve 3 contains the (trigger, mover, goal) classifier. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">Figure 3(a)</ref> shows the SRCTs used in the corresponding posi- tive instances, while <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">Figure 3(b)</ref> shows the SRCTs associated with randomly chosen negative in- stances used to train the classifiers in these sieves.</p><p>To train a classifier on instances containing the original 31 features and SRCTs, we employ SVM light−T K <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Moschitti, 2004;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Moschitti, 2006</ref>), which (1) trains an SVM classifier using the 31 features with a linear kernel; (2) trains an SVM classifier using only the SRCTs with a convolution   kernel; and (3) combines these two kernels using a composite kernel. Specifically, we define compos- ite kernel K c for combining linear kernel K l and convolution kernel K t as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">K c (F 1 , F 2 ) = K l (F 1 , F 2 ) + T · K t (T 1 , T 2 ),</formula><p>where F 1 and F 2 are the set of 31 features from two training instances, T 1 and T 2 are their SRCTs, and T is the combination parameter. We em- ploy the hill-climbing algorithm described before to tune the C, J and T parameters to maximize F-score on the development data. <ref type="bibr">6</ref> The test instances with structured features are created in the same way as the training instances, with one notable difference. Note that roles are used to create structured features. While they are available in training, they are not available in the test documents. Hence, to create SRCTs for a test instance, we have to employ the roles predicted by preceding sieves. This is precisely how we exploit the role decisions made by earlier sieves in later sieves. This also explains why the SRCTs expand: more and more roles will be attached to a SRCT as it passes through the sieve pipeline.</p><p>As an example, consider the test sentence "He biked to Maine from Cambridge", whose parse tree is shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Figure 2(b)</ref>. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_8">Figure 4(a)</ref> shows the SRCTs generated when each sieve makes the correct decisions. Specifically, sieve 1 correctly identifies "He" as the mover and "biked" as the trigger. The roles (correctly) extracted by sieve 1 (shown in boxes) are incorporated into the SRCT created in sieve 2. Similarly, the motion signals   shows the SRCTs generated for misclassified in- stances. Assume that sieve 1 misclassifies the test instance underlying the SRCT (as positive). As we can see, this mistake is propagated to the SRCTs generated in later sieves.</p><p>Note that the precision of a sieve may change with the addition of SRCTs. For this reason, the sieves need to be reordered using the algorithm de- scribed in the previous subsection.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Evaluation</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.1">Experimental Setup</head><p>SpaceEval tasks. We evaluate our approach in tasks 1d and 3a of SpaceEval. These two tasks evaluate a system's ability to extract (trajector, landmark, trigger) triplets in QSLINKs and OLINKs as well as (trigger, mover) pairs in MOVELINKs using gold spatial elements (1d) and automatically extracted spatial elements (3a). To extract the spatial elements needed for task 3a, we follow <ref type="bibr">Bastianelli et al.'s (2013)</ref>   to us at the time of writing, we conduct our evaluation on the SpaceEval training corpus, which contains 1890 spatial relations (886 QS- LINKs, 225 OLINKs, and 779 MOVELINKs) and 1139 MOVELINK optional roles (95 sources, 65 midpoints, 310 goals, 77 landmarks, 100 paths, and 492 motion signals). We partition the 59 narratives in the corpus into five folds and report five-fold cross-validation results. In each fold ex- periment, we employ three folds for training, one fold for development, and one fold for testing.</p><p>Evaluation metrics. To evaluate the results for the two SpaceEval tasks, we employ the official SpaceEval scoring program, which reports results in terms of recall, precision, and F-score on the three types of spatial relations in isolation and in combination. To evaluate the results for extracting MOVELINK optional roles, we compute the recall, precision, and F-score for each role. <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Tables 3a and 3b</ref> show the spatial relation ex- traction results for three systems -the Base- line (row 1), our Sieve approach without SRCTs (row 2), and our Sieve approach with SRCTs (row 3) -obtained using gold and extracted spa- tial elements, respectively.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.2">Results and Discussion</head><p>The official scoring program reports spatial re- lation extraction results in terms of recall (R), precision (P), and F-score (F). For QSLINKs and OLINKs, it reports results on (1) extracting spatially-related (trajector, landmark, trigger) triplets (see the "True" columns) and (2) identify- ing that no spatial relation exists among a (can- didate trajector, candidate landmark, candidate trigger) triplet (see the "False" columns). For MOVELINKs, it reports results on (1) extracting spatially-related (trigger, mover) pairs (see the "True" columns) and (2) identifying that no spa- tial relation exists between a (candidate trigger, candidate mover) pair (see the "False" columns). Since the pairs/triplets without links considerably outnumber those with links, the OVERALL scores are dominated by the performances on "False", which, as expected, are high.</p><p>Of particular interest are the MOVELINK scores under the "True" columns. When gold spatial el- ements are used, Sieve significantly outperforms Baseline (p &lt; 0.001) owing to substantial gains in precision with smaller losses in recall. 8 Adding SRCTs to Sieve further boosts performance signif- icantly (p &lt; 0.005). As we can see, Sieve+SRCTs outperforms Baseline by 8.4% absolute F-score on extracting (trigger, mover) pairs. With respect to the OVERALL score, which also takes into ac- count QSLINKs and OLINKs, Sieve+SRCTs out- performs Baseline significantly by 1.7% absolute F-score. Similar trends can be observed for the results obtained using extracted spatial elements. Note that Baseline and Sieve have the same QS- LINK and OLINK results because the LINK classi- fier is associated with the first sieve. <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">Tables 4a and 4b</ref> show the results on extract- ing MOVELINK optional roles using gold and extracted spatial elements, respectively. When gold elements are used, Sieve insignificantly out- performs Baseline on source, midpoint, and motion signal. When used with SRCTs, Sieve insignificantly outperforms Baseline on source, midpoint, path, and motion signal. Overall, Sieve+SRCTs insignificantly outperforms Base- line by 3.0% absolute F-score. <ref type="bibr">9</ref> While the results   <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">Table 5</ref> shows the results of these systems on extracting entire MOVELINKs, where a MOVELINK is considered correctly extracted if all of its partic- ipating elements and their roles are correct. Note that none of the SpaceEval tasks employ this strin- gent but informative evaluation measure. As we can see, Sieve+SRCTs insignificantly outperforms Baseline by 2.3-3.0% absolute F-score, regardless of whether gold or extracted elements are used.</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">source midpoint goal landmark path motion-signal OVERALL R P F R P F R P F R P F R P F R P F R P F</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.3">Error Analysis</head><p>In this subsection, we analyze the errors made by the best-performing system, Sieve+SRCTs, with respect to the extraction of MOVELINKs given our focus on this type of spatial relation.</p><p>Extracting (mover, trigger) pairs. The major source of recall error stems from the system's in- ability to extract movers that are unseen in the training data. This error could be addressed using a named entity recognizer and WordNet categories related to people, places, animals, etc. The major source of precision error arises from missing gold annotations. Consider the sentence "I found my- self biking..." Our system correctly extracted "bik- ing" as the trigger and "I" as the mover, but was considered wrong because "myself", not "I", was annotated as the mover in the gold standard.</p><p>Extracting optional roles. A major source of recall/precision error stems from the system's in- ability to exploit contextual cues that are reli- able indicators of a particular role. For instance, a statistical analysis of the training data reveals that sources are commonly preceded by prepo- sitions such as "from" and "or", whereas goals opment data are not necessarily the same as those that yield the best results on the test data.  are commonly associated with verbs such as "re- turn", "visit", "arrive", and "reach". This prob- lem could be addressed by encoding these cues explicitly as additional features for training the role-specific classifiers. Another source of recall error can be attributed to the lack of background knowledge. Consider the sentence "We had only 70 more km to Cluj taking this way, but if get- ting back to Ciucea and on to Cluj the normal way would have been 25 km longer". Despite correctly extracting "Cluj" as the goal, the system failed to extract "Ciucea" as the midpoint. This prob- lem could be alleviated by exploiting geographi- cal knowledge concerning these cities in external knowledge sources such as Wikipedia.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7">Conclusions</head><p>We have examined the under-studied task of spa- tial relation extraction, focusing on spatial rela- tions of objects in motion. Our approach exploited expanding parse trees, which resulted from a novel combination of multi-pass sieves and tree ker- nels, achieving state-of-the-art results on two key SpaceEval tasks. To facilitate comparison with fu- ture work on this task, we released the source code of our spatial relation extraction system. <ref type="bibr">10</ref> GuoDong Zhou, Min Zhang, DongHong Ji, and QiaoMing Zhu. 2007. Tree kernel-based relation extraction with context-sensitive structured parse tree information. In Proceedings of the 2007 Joint Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Lan- guage Processing and Computational Natural Lan- guage Learning, pages 728-736.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: A MOVELINK example.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>2</head><label></label><figDesc>Space limitations preclude a description of these fea- tures. See D'Souza and Ng (2015) for details. 3 C is chosen from the set {0.01, 0.05, 0.1, 0.5, 1.0, 10.0, 50.0, 100.0}, and J is chosen from the set {0.01, 0.05, 0.1, 0.5, 1.0, 2.0, 4.0, 6.0}. All other learning parameters are set to their default values. In particular, a linear kernel is used.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>Figure 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2: Syntactic parse trees for two example sentences containing MOVELINKs.</figDesc><graphic url="image-3.png" coords="6,417.77,71.56,102.05,69.39" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head>(</head><label></label><figDesc>a) SRCTs associated with positive training instances in sieves 1, 2, and 3. (b) SRCTs associated with randomly chosen negative training instances in sieves 1, 2, and 3.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><head>Figure 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Figure 3: SRCTs associated with training instances created for the sentence in Figure 2a.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_6"><head>.</head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 3: SRCTs associated with training instances created for the sentence in Figure 2a.</figDesc><graphic url="image-8.png" coords="7,144.60,143.85,68.03,56.11" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_8"><head>Figure 4 :</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Figure 4: SRCTs associated with test instances for the sentence in Figure 2b.</figDesc><graphic url="image-14.png" coords="7,379.87,137.72,68.03,57.43" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_9"><head>(</head><label></label><figDesc>correctly) extracted by sieve 2 are incorporated into the SRCT created in sieve 3. Figure 4(b)</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" validated="false"><head>Table 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Results for extracting spatial relations. 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3" validated="false"><head>Table 4 :</head><label>4</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Results for extracting MOVELINK optional roles. 

obtained using extracted elements exhibit different 
trends, Sieve+SRCTs's OVERALL improvement 
of 6.1% absolute F-score over Baseline is signifi-
cant (p &lt; 0.001). 
</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4" validated="false"><head>Table 5 :</head><label>5</label><figDesc>Results for extracting entire MOVELINKs using gold and extracted elements.</figDesc><table></table></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> Since the official annotated test data is not available to us, we cannot compare our results with the shared task systems&apos; official results, but comparing against a state-of-the-art baseline will enable us to determine whether our approach is better than the best existing spatial relation extraction system.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="4"> See Footnote 3 for the set of values of C and J used for parameter tuning.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="5"> We use the distance from the hyperplane as a measure of an SVM classifier&apos;s confidence.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="6"> To tune T , we attempted values between 0 and 2 in increments of 0.2. To tune C and J, we attempted the values specified in Footnote 3.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="7"> We train two CRF models using CRF++ (https:// taku910.github.io/crfpp/), one to extract motion signals and the other to extract the remaining six types of spatial elements (see Table 1). The reason is that motion signal is the only type of spatial element that can overlap with other types. When predicting spatial signals, we also predict their semantic types, since the LINK classifier needs this attribute to distinguish between QSLINKs and OLINKs (see Section 4.1.1). To increase recall, we use the 10-best outputs returned by the CRFs as candidate spatial elements.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="8"> All statistical significance tests are paired t-tests, with p set to 0.05 unless otherwise stated. 9 A closer examination of the results reveals why the improvement is insignificant: since many roles occur infrequently in the corpus, the parameters learned from the devel</note>

			<note place="foot" n="10"> See our website at http://www.hlt.utdallas. edu/ ˜ jld082000/spatial-relations/ for details.</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>We thank the three anonymous reviewers for their comments. This work was supported in part by NSF <ref type="bibr">Grants IIS-1147644 and IIS-1219142.</ref> </p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Unitor-HMM-TK: Structured kernel-based learning for spatial role labeling</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Emanuele</forename><surname>Bastianelli</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Danilo</forename><surname>Croce</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Daniele</forename><surname>Nardi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Roberto</forename><surname>Basili</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 7th International Workshop on Semantic Evaluation</title>
		<meeting>the 7th International Workshop on Semantic Evaluation</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="573" to="579" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A shortest path dependency kernel for relation extraction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Razvan</forename><surname>Bunescu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Raymond</forename><surname>Mooney</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of Human Language Technology Conference and Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</title>
		<meeting>Human Language Technology Conference and Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="724" to="731" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dense event ordering with a multi-pass architecture</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nathanael</forename><surname>Chambers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Taylor</forename><surname>Cassidy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bill</forename><surname>Mcdowell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Steven</forename><surname>Bethard</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Transactions of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="273" to="284" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dependency tree kernels for relation extraction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Aron</forename><surname>Culotta</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jeffrey</forename><surname>Sorensen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 42nd Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics, Main Volume</title>
		<meeting>the 42nd Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics, Main Volume</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="423" to="429" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">UTD: Ensemble-based spatial relation extraction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D&amp;apos;</forename><surname>Jennifer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Vincent</forename><surname>Souza</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Ng</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 9th International Workshop on Semantic Evaluation</title>
		<meeting>the 9th International Workshop on Semantic Evaluation</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="862" to="869" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Making large-scale SVM learning practical</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Thorsten</forename><forename type="middle">Joachims</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Advances in Kernel Methods-Support Vector Learning</title>
		<editor>Bernhard Scholkopf and Alexander Smola</editor>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>MIT Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="44" to="56" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Oleksandr</forename><surname>Kolomiyets</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Parisa</forename><surname>Kordjamshidi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Steven</forename><surname>Bethard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marie-Francine</forename><surname>Moens</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Task 3: Spatial role labeling</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Semeval</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 7th International Workshop on Semantic Evaluation</title>
		<meeting>the 7th International Workshop on Semantic Evaluation</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="255" to="266" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Global machine learning for spatial ontology population</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Parisa</forename><surname>Kordjamshidi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marie-Francine</forename><surname>Moens</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Web Semantics: Science, Services and Agents on the World Wide Web</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">30</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">C</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3" to="21" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Spatial role labeling: Towards extraction of spatial relations from natural language</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Parisa</forename><surname>Kordjamshidi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Martijn</forename><surname>Van Otterlo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mariefrancine</forename><surname>Moens</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">ACM Transactions on Speech and Language Processing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">4</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">SemEval-2012 Task 3: Spatial role labeling</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Parisa</forename><surname>Kordjamshidi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Steven</forename><surname>Bethard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mariefrancine</forename><surname>Moens</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 6th International Workshop on Semantic Evaluation</title>
		<meeting>the 6th International Workshop on Semantic Evaluation</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="365" to="373" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Deterministic coreference resolution based on entity-centric, precision-ranked rules</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Heeyoung</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Angel</forename><surname>Chang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yves</forename><surname>Peirsman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nathanael</forename><surname>Chambers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mihai</forename><surname>Surdeanu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dan</forename><surname>Jurafsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Computational Linguistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">39</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="885" to="916" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A study on convolution kernels for shallow statistic parsing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alessandro</forename><surname>Moschitti</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 42nd Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics, Main Volume</title>
		<meeting>the 42nd Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics, Main Volume</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="335" to="342" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Making tree kernels practical for natural language processing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alessandro</forename><surname>Moschitti</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 11th Conference of the European Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the 11th Conference of the European Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="113" to="120" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">SpRLCWW: Spatial relation classification with independent multi-class models</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Eric</forename><surname>Nichols</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Fadi</forename><surname>Botros</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 9th International Workshop on Semantic Evaluation</title>
		<meeting>the 9th International Workshop on Semantic Evaluation</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="895" to="901" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Capturing motion in ISO-SpaceBank</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">James</forename><surname>Pustejovsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Zachary</forename><surname>Yocum</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 9th Joint ISO-ACL SIGSEM Workshop on Interoperable Semantic Annotation</title>
		<meeting>the 9th Joint ISO-ACL SIGSEM Workshop on Interoperable Semantic Annotation</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="25" to="34" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A linguistically grounded annotation language for spatial information</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">James</forename><surname>Pustejovsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jessica</forename><surname>Moszkowicz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marc</forename><surname>Verhagen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">TAL</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">53</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="87" to="113" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">James</forename><surname>Pustejovsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Parisa</forename><surname>Kordjamshidi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mariefrancine</forename><surname>Moens</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Aaron</forename><surname>Levine</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Seth</forename><surname>Dworman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Zachary</forename><surname>Yocum</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">SemEval-2015 Task 8: SpaceEval. In Proceedings of the 9th International Workshop on Semantic Evaluation</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="884" to="894" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A multipass sieve for coreference resolution</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Heeyoung</forename><surname>Karthik Raghunathan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nate</forename><surname>Sudarshan Rangarajan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mihai</forename><surname>Chambers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dan</forename><surname>Surdeanu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christopher</forename><surname>Jurafsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Manning</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2010 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</title>
		<meeting>the 2010 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="492" to="501" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">UTDSpRL: A joint approach to spatial role labeling</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kirk</forename><surname>Roberts</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sanda</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Harabagiu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 6th International Workshop on Semantic Evaluation</title>
		<meeting>the 6th International Workshop on Semantic Evaluation</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="419" to="424" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Recognizing spatial containment relations between event mentions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kirk</forename><surname>Roberts</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michael</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Skinner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sanda</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Harabagiu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 10th International Conference on Computational Semantics-Long Papers</title>
		<meeting>the 10th International Conference on Computational Semantics-Long Papers</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="216" to="227" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">IXAGroupEHUSpaceEval: (X-Space) A WordNet-based approach towards the automatic recognition of spatial information following the ISO-Space annotation scheme</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Haritz</forename><surname>Salaberri</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Olatz</forename><surname>Arregi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Beñat</forename><surname>Zapirain</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 9th International Workshop on Semantic Evaluation</title>
		<meeting>the 9th International Workshop on Semantic Evaluation</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="856" to="861" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Kernel methods for relation extraction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dmitry</forename><surname>Zelenko</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chinatsu</forename><surname>Aone</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Anthony</forename><surname>Richardella</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Machine Learning Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1083" to="1106" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
