<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T12:27+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Syntax-based Rewriting for Simultaneous Machine Translation</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
				<availability status="unknown"><p>Copyright Association for Computational Linguistics</p>
				</availability>
				<date type="published" when="2015-09">September 2015. 2015</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">He</forename><surname>He</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep3">Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">University of Maryland</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">University of Colorado</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit3">UMIACS University of Maryland</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><roleName>II</roleName><forename type="first">Alvin</forename><surname>Grissom</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep3">Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">University of Maryland</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">University of Colorado</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit3">UMIACS University of Maryland</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jordan</forename><surname>Boyd-Graber</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep3">Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">University of Maryland</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">University of Colorado</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit3">UMIACS University of Maryland</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jordan</forename><forename type="middle">Boyd</forename><surname>Graber}</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep3">Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">University of Maryland</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">University of Colorado</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit3">UMIACS University of Maryland</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hal</forename><surname>Daumé</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep3">Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">University of Maryland</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">University of Colorado</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit3">UMIACS University of Maryland</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Iii</forename></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep3">Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">University of Maryland</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">University of Colorado</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit3">UMIACS University of Maryland</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Syntax-based Rewriting for Simultaneous Machine Translation</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2015 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</title>
						<meeting>the 2015 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing <address><addrLine>Lisbon, Portugal</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="17" to="21"/>
							<date type="published" when="2015-09">September 2015. 2015</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Divergent word order between languages causes delay in simultaneous machine translation. We present a sentence rewriting method that generates more mono-tonic translations to improve the speed-accuracy tradeoff. We design grammati-cality and meaning-preserving syntactic transformation rules that operate on constituent parse trees. We apply the rules to reference translations to make their word order closer to the source language word order. On Japanese-English translation (two languages with substantially different structure), incorporating the rewritten , more monotonic reference translation into a phrase-based machine translation system enables better translations faster than a baseline system that only uses gold reference translations.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Simultaneous interpretation is challenging because it demands both quality and speed. Conventional batch translation waits until the entire sentence is completed before starting to translate. This merely optimizes translation quality and often introduces undesirable lag between the speaker and the audi- ence. Simultaneous interpretation instead requires a tradeoff between quality and speed. A common strategy is to translate independently translatable segments as soon as possible. Various segmenta- tion methods ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Fujita et al., 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr">Oda et al., 2014</ref>) reduce translation delay; they are limited, however, by the unavoidable word reordering between lan- guages with drastically different word orders. We show an example of Japanese-English translation in <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref>. Consider the batch translation: in En- glish, the verb change comes immediately after the subject We, whereas in Japanese it comes at the end of the sentence; therefore, to produce an intelligible English sentence, we must translate the object after the final verb is observed, resulting in one large and painfully delayed segment.</p><p>To reduce structural discrepancy, we can apply syntactic transformations to make the word order of one language closer to the other. Consider the monotone translation in <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref>. By passivizing the English sentence, we can cache the subject and begin translating before observing the final verb. Furthermore, by using the English possessive, we mimic the order of the Japanese genitive construc- tion. These transformations enable us to divide the input into shorter segments, thus reducing transla- tion delay.</p><p>To produce such monotone translations, a straightforward approach is to incorporate inter- pretation data into the learning of a machine trans- lation (MT) system, because human interpreters use a variety of strategies ( <ref type="bibr">Shimizu et al., 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Camayd-Freixas, 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr">Tohyama and Matsubara, 2006</ref>) to fine-tune the word order. <ref type="bibr">Shimizu et al. (2013)</ref> shows that this approach improves the speed-accuracy tradeoff. However, existing paral- lel simultaneous interpretation corpora ( <ref type="bibr">Shimizu et al., 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Matsubara et al., 2002;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Bendazzoli and Sandrelli, 2005</ref>) are often small, and collecting new data is expensive due to the inherent costs of recording and transcribing speeches <ref type="bibr">(Paulik and Waibel, 2010)</ref>. In addition, due to the intense time pressure during interpretation, human interpreta- tion has the disadvantage of simpler, less precise diction (Camayd-Freixas, 2011; Al- <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Khanji et al., 2000</ref>) compared to human translations done at the translator's leisure, allowing for more introspection and precise word choice.</p><p>We aim to address the data scarcity problem and combine translators' lexical precision and inter- preters' syntactic flexibility. We propose to rewrite the reference translation in a way that uses the original lexicon, obeys standard grammar rules of ! We-TOP government-GEN structure and composition-ACC change should COP Source:</p><p>|| ! We should change the structure and composition of the government || || || ! the government's structure and composition should be changed by us Batch:</p><p>Monotone:</p><p>Figure 1: Divergent word order between language pairs can cause long delays in simultaneous translation: Segments (||) mark the portions of the sentence that can be translated together. (Case markers: topic (TOP), genitive (GEN), accusative (ACC), copula (COP).) the target language, preserves the original seman- tics, and yields more monotonic translations. We then train the MT system with the rewritten refer- ences so that it learns how to produce low-latency translations from the data. A data-driven approach to learning these rewriting rules is hampered by the dearth of parallel data: we have few examples of text that have been both interpreted and trans- lated. Therefore, we design syntactic transforma- tion rules based on linguistic analysis of the source and the target languages. We apply these rules to parsed text and decide whether to accept the rewrit- ten sentence based on the amount of delay reduc- tion. In this work, we focus on Japanese to English translation, because (i) Japanese and English have significantly different word orders (SOV vs. SVO); and consequently, (ii) the syntactic constituents re- quired earlier by an English sentence often come late in the corresponding Japanese sentence.</p><p>We evaluate our approach using standard ma- chine translation data (the Reuters newsfeed Japanese-English corpus) in a simultaneous trans- lation setting. Our experimental results show that including the rewritten references into the learning of a phrase-based MT system results in a better speed-accuracy tradeoff against both the original and the rewritten reference translations.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">The Problem of Delay Reduction</head><p>Simultaneous interpretation has two goals: produc- ing good translations and producing them promptly. However, most existing parallel corpora and MT systems do not address the issue of delay during translation. We explicitly adapt the training data by rewriting rules to reduce delay. We first define translation delay and describe-in general terms- our rewriting rules. In the next section, we describe the rules in more detail.</p><p>While we are motivated by real-time interpreta- tion, to simplify our problem, we assume that we have perfect text input. Given this constraint, a typ- ical simultaneous interpretation system <ref type="bibr">(Sridhar et al., 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Fujita et al., 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr">Oda et al., 2014</ref>) pro- duces partial translations of consecutive segments in the source sentence and concatenates them to produce a complete translation. We define the trans- lation delay of a sentence as the average number of tokens the system has to observe between trans- lation of two consecutive segments (denoted by # words/seg). 1 For instance, the minimum delay of 1 word/seg is achieved when we translate immedi- ately upon hearing a word. At test time, when the input is segmented, the delay is the average seg- ment length. During the data preprocessing step of rewriting, we calculate delay from word alignments (Section 4).</p><p>Given a reference batch translation x, we ap- ply a set of rewriting rules R to x to minimize its delay. A rewriting rule r ∈ R is a mapping that takes the constituent parse tree of x as input and outputs a modified parse tree, which specifies a rewritten sentence x . The tree-editing operation includes node deletion, insertion, and swapping, as well as induced changes of word form and node label. A valid transformation rule should rearrange constituents in x to follow the word order of the input sentence as closely as possible, subject to grammatical constraints and preservation of the original meaning.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Transformation Rules</head><p>We design a variety of syntactic transformation rules for Japanese-English translation motivated by their structural differences. Our rules cover verb, noun, and clause reordering. While we specifi- cally focus on Japanese to English, many rules are broadly applicable to SOV to SVO languages.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Verb Phrases</head><p>The most significant difference between Japanese and English is that the head of a verb phrase comes at the end of Japanese sentences. In English, it occu- pies one of the initial positions. We now introduce rules that can postpone a head verb.</p><p>Passivization and Activization In Japanese, the standard structure of a sentence is NP 1 NP 2 verb, where case markers following the verb indicate the voice of the sentence. However, in English, we have NP 1 verb NP 2 , where the form of the verb indicates its voice. Changing the voice is particu- larly useful when NP 2 (object in an active-voice sentence and subject in a passive-voice sentence) is long. By reversing positions of verb and NP 2 , we are not held back by the upcoming verb and can start to translate NP 2 immediately. <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref> shows an example in which passive voice can help make the target and source word orders more compatible, but it is not the case that passivizing every sentence would be a good idea; sometimes making a pas- sive sentence active makes the word orders more compatible if the objects are relatively short: O: The talk was denied by the boycott group spokesman. R: The boycott group spokesman denied the talk.</p><p>Quotative Verbs Quotative verbs are verbs that, syntactically and semantically, resemble said and often start an independent clause. Such verbs are frequent, especially in news, and can be moved to the end of a sentence: O: They announced that the president will re- structure the division. R: The president will restructure the division, they announced.</p><p>In addition to quotative verbs, candidates typi- cally include factive (e.g., know, realize, observe), factive-like (e.g., announce, determine), belief (e.g., believe, think, suspect), and antifactive (e.g., doubt, deny) verbs. When these verbs are followed by a clause (S or SBAR), we move the verb and its sub- ject to the end of the clause.</p><p>While some exploratory work automatically ex- tracts factive verbs, to our knowledge, an exhaus- tive list does not exist. To obtain a list with rea- sonable coverage, we exploit the fact that Japanese has an unambiguous quotative particle, to, that pre- cedes such verbs. <ref type="bibr">2</ref> We identify all of the verbs in the Kyoto corpus (Neubig, 2011) marked by the quotative particle and translate them into English. We then use these as our quotative verbs. <ref type="bibr">3</ref> </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Noun Phrases</head><p>Another difference between Japanese and English lies in the order of adjectives and the nouns they modify. We identify two situations where we can take advantage of the flexibility of English gram- mar to favor sentence structures consistent with positions of nouns in Japanese.</p><p>Genitive Reordering In Japanese, genitive con- structions always occur in the form of X no Y, where Y belongs to X. In English, however, the order may be reversed through the of construction. Therefore, we transform constructions NP 1 of NP 2 to possessives using the apostrophe-s, NP 2 '(s) NP 1 ( <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref>). We use simple heuristics to decide if such a transformation is valid. For example, when X / Y contains proper nouns (e.g., the City of New York), numbers (e.g., seven pounds of sugar), or pronouns (e.g., most of them), changing them to the possessive case is not legal.</p><p>that Clause In English, clauses are often modi- fied through a pleonastic pronoun. E.g., It is ADJP to/that SBAR/S. In Japanese, however, the subject (clause) is usually put at the beginning. To be con- sistent with the Japanese word order, we move the modified clause to the start of the sentence: To S/SBAR is ADJP. The rewritten English sentence is still grammatical, although its structure is less frequent in common English usage. For example, O: It is important to remain watchful. R: To remain watchful is important. <ref type="bibr">2</ref> We use a morphological analyzer to distinguish between the conjunction and quotative particles. Examples of words marked by this particle include (expect), (say), (seem), (assume), (believe) and so on. <ref type="bibr">3</ref> We also include the phrase It looks like. We new world the love Source:</p><p>Delay:</p><p>We love the new world Target:</p><p>1 4</p><p>We new world the love Source:</p><p>Delay:</p><p>The new world is loved by us New target:</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">2 1 2</formula><p>Figure 2: An example of applying the passivization rule to create a translation reference that is more monotonic.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3">Conjunction Clause</head><p>In Japanese, clausal conjunctions are often marked at the end of the initial clause of a compound sen- tence. In English, however, the order of clauses is more flexible. We can therefore reduce delay by reordering the English clauses to mirror how they typically appear in Japanese. Below we describe rules reversing the order of clauses connected by these conjunctions:</p><p>• Clausal conjunctions: because (of), in order to • Contrastive conjunctions: despite, even though, although • Conditionals: (even) if, as a result (of) • Misc: according to</p><p>In standard Japanese, such conjunctions include no de, kara, de mo and so on. The sentence often appears in the form of S 2 conj, S 1 . In English, however, two common constructions are S 1 conj S 2 : We should march because win- ter is coming. conj S 2 , S 1 : Because winter is coming, we should march.</p><p>To follow the Japanese clause order, we adapt the above two constructions to S 2 , conj' S 1 : Winter is coming, because of this, we should march.</p><p>Here conj' represents the original conjunction word appended with simple pronouns/phrases to refer to S 2 . For example, because → because of this, even if → even if this is the case.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Sentence Rewriting Process</head><p>We now turn our attention to the implementation of the syntactic transformation rules described above. Applying a transformation consists of three steps:</p><p>1. Detection: Identify nodes in the parse tree for which the transformation is applicable; 2. Modification: Transform nodes and labels; 3. Evaluation: Compute delay reduction, and decide whether to accept the rewritten sen- tence. <ref type="figure">Figure 2</ref> illustrates the process using passivization as an example. In the detection step, we find the subtree that satisfies the condition of applying a rule. In this case, we look for an S node whose chil- dren include an NP (denoted by NP 1 ), the subject, and a VP to its right, such that the VP node has a leaf VB*, the main verb, 4 followed by another NP (denoted by NP 2 ), the object. We allow the par- ent nodes (S and VP) to have additional children besides the matched ones. They are not affected during the transformation. In the modification step, we swap the subject node and object node; we add the verb be in its correct form by checking the tense of the verb and the form of NP 2 ; 5 and we add the preposition by before the subject. The process is executed recursively throughout the parse tree.</p><p>Although our rules are designed to minimize long range reordering, there are exceptions. <ref type="bibr">6</ref> Thus applying a rule does not always reduce delay. In the evaluation step, we compare translation delay before and after applying the rule. We accept a rewritten sentence if its delay is reduced; other- wise, we revert to the input sentence. Since we do not segment sentences during rewriting, we must estimate the delay.</p><p>To estimate the delay, we use word alignments. <ref type="figure">Figure 2c</ref> shows the source Japanese sentence in its word-for-word English translation and align- ments from the target words to the source words. The first English word, We, is aligned to the first Japanese word; it can thus be treated as an inde- pendent segment and translated immediately. The second English word, love, is aligned to the last Japanese word, which means the system cannot start to translate until four more Japanese words are revealed. This alignment therefore forms a seg- ment with delay of four words/seg. Alignments of the following words come before the source word aligned to love; hence, they are already translated in the previous segment and we do not double count their delay. In this example, the delay of the orig- inal sentence is 2.5 word/seg; after rewriting, it is reduced to 1.7 word/seg. Therefore, we accept the rewritten sentence. However, when the subject phrase is long and the object phrase is short, a swap may not reduce delay.</p><p>We can now formally define the delay. Let e i be the ith target word in the input sentence x and a i be the maximum index among indices of source words that e i aligned to. We define the delay of e i as</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">d i = max(0, a i − max j&lt;i a j ). The delay of x is then N i=1 d i /N ,</formula><p>where the sum is over all aligned words except punctuation and stopwords.</p><p>Given a set of rules, we need to decide which rules to apply and in what order. Fortunately, our rules have little interaction with each other, and the order of application has a negligible effect. We apply the rules, roughly, sequentially in order of complexity: if the output of current rule is not ac- cepted, the sentence is reverted to the last accepted version.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Train Tune Test</head><p>Ja 21.3M 30.2k 23.3k En-GD 16.8M 23.8k 18.5k En-RW 16.8M 24.1k 18.7k <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>: Number of words in the training, tuning, and test datasets. En-GD and En-RW represent the gold reference set and the rewritten reference set.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Experiments</head><p>We evaluate our method on the Reuters Japanese- English corpus of news articles <ref type="bibr">(Utiyama and Isahara, 2003</ref>). For training the MT system, we also include the EIJIRO dictionary entries and the ac- companying example sentences. <ref type="bibr">7</ref> Statistics of the dataset are shown in <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>. The rewritten trans- lation is generally slightly longer than the gold translation because our rewriting often involves inserting pronouns (e.g. it, this) for antecedents.</p><p>We use the TreebankWordTokenizer from NLTK ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Bird et al., 2009</ref>) to tokenize En- glish sentences and Kuromoji Japanese mor- phological analyzer 8 to tokenize Japanese sen- tences. Our phrase-based MT system is trained by Moses ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">Koehn et al., 2003</ref>) with standard parameters settings. We use GIZA++ (Och and Ney, 2003) for word alignment and k-best batch MIRA (Cherry and Foster, 2012) for tuning. The translation quality is evaluated by <ref type="bibr">BLEU (Papineni et al., 2002</ref>) and RIBES ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Isozaki et al., 2010)</ref>. <ref type="bibr">9</ref> To obtain the parse trees for English sentences, we use the Stanford Parser ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Klein and Manning, 2003)</ref> and the included English model.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.1">Quality of Rewritten Translations</head><p>After applying the rewriting rules (Section 4), Ta- ble 2 shows the percentage of sentences that are candidates and how many rewrites are accepted. The most generalizable rules are passivization and delaying quotative verbs. We rewrite 32.2% of sen- tences, reducing the delay from 9.9 words/seg to 6.3 words/seg per segment for rewritten sentences and from 7.8 words/seg to 6.7 words/seg overall. verb voice noun conj.</p><p>Applicable % 39.9 50.0 26.4 4.8 Accepted % 22.5 24.0 51.2 38.4 <ref type="table">Table 2</ref>: Percentage of sentences that each rule category can be applied to (Applicable) and the percentage of sentences for which the rule results in a more monotonic sentence (Accepted).</p><p>We evaluate the quality of our rewritten sen- tences from two perspectives: grammaticality and preserved semantics. To examine how close the rewritten sentences are to standard English, we train a 5-gram language model using the English data from the Europarl corpus, consisting of 46 million words, and use it to compute perplexity. Rewriting references increases the perplexity un- der the language model only slightly: from 332.0 to 335.4. To ensure that rewrites leave meaning unchanged, we use the SEMAFOR semantic role labeler ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Das et al., 2014</ref>) on the original and mod- ified sentence; for each role-labeled token in the reference sentence, we examine its corresponding role in the rewritten sentence and calculate the aver- age accuracy acrosss all sentences. Even ignoring benign lexical changes-for example, he becom- ing him in a passivized sentence-95.5% of the words retain their semantic roles in the rewritten sentences.</p><p>Although our rules are conservative to minimize corruption, some errors are unavoidable propaga- tion of parser errors. For example, the sentence the London Stock Exchange closes at 1230 GMT today is parsed as: <ref type="bibr">10</ref> (S (NP the London Stock Exchange) (VP (VBZ closes) (PP at 1230) (NP GMT today))) GMT today is separated from the PP as an NP and is mistaken as the object. The passive version is then GMT today is closed at 1230 by the London Stock Exchange. Such errors could be reduced by skip- ping nodes with low inside/outside scores given by the parser, or skipping low-frequency patterns. However, we leave this for future work.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.2">Segmentation</head><p>At test time, we use right probability <ref type="bibr">(Fujita et al., 2013, RP)</ref> to decide when to start translating a sentence. As we read in the source Japanese sen- tence, if the input segment matches an entry in the learned phrase table, we query the RP of the Japanese/English phrase pair. A higher RP indicates that the English translation of this Japanese phrase will likely be followed by the translation of the next Japanese phrase. In other words, translation of the two consecutive Japanese phrases is mono- tonic, thus, we can begin translating immediately. Following <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">(Fujita et al., 2013)</ref>, if the RP of the current phrase is lower than a fixed threshold, we cache the current phrase and wait for more words from the source sentence; otherwise, we translate all cached phrases. Finally, translations of segments are concatenated to form a complete translation of the input sentence.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.3">Speed/Accuracy Trade-off</head><p>To show the effect of rewritten references, we com- pare the following MT systems:</p><p>• GD: only gold reference translations;</p><p>• RW: only rewritten reference translations;</p><p>• RW+GD: both gold and the rewritten refer- ences; and • RW-LM+GD: using gold reference transla- tions but using the rewritten references for training the LM and for tuning.</p><p>For RW+GD and RW-LM+GD, we interpolate the language models of GD and RW. The interpolat- ing weight is tuned with the rewritten sentences. For RW+GD, we combine the translation models (phrase tables and reordering tables) of RW and GD by fill-up combination <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Bisazza et al., 2011)</ref>, where all entries in the tables of RW are preserved and entries from the tables of GD are added if new. Increasing the RP threshold increases interpreta- tion delay but improves the quality of the transla- tion. We set the RP threshold at 0.0, 0.2, 0.4, 0.8 and finally 1.0 (equivalent to batch translation). <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 3</ref> shows the BLEU/RIBES scores vs. the number of words per segement as we increase the threshold. Rewritten sentences alone do not sig- nificantly improve over the baseline. We suspect this is because the transformation rules sometimes generate ungrammatical sentences due to parsing errors, which impairs learning. However, combin- ing RW and GD results in a better speed-accuracy tradeoff: the RW+GD curve completely dominates other curves in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 3a,</ref>   the same as GD, the major improvement likely comes from the translation model from rewritten sentences. The right two plots recapitulate the evaluation with the RIBES metric. This result is less clear, as MT systems are optimized for BLEU and RIBES penalizes word reordering, making it difficult to compare systems that intentionally change word order. Nevertheless, RW is comparable to GD on gold references and superior to the baseline on rewritten references.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.4">Effect on Verbs</head><p>Rewriting training data not only creates lower la- tency simultaneous translations, but it also im- proves batch translation. One reason is that SOV to SVO translation often drops the verb because of long range reordering. (We see this for Japanese here, but this is also true for German.) Similar word orders in the source and target results in less re- ordering and improves phrase-based <ref type="bibr">MT</ref>   Ref he also said that the real dangers for the euro lay in the potential for divergences in the domestic policy needs among the various participating nations of the single currency.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>GD</head><p>he also for the euro, is a real danger to launch a single currency in many different countries and domestic policies on the need for the possibility of a difference.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>RW</head><p>he also for the euro is a real danger to launch a single currency in many different countries and domestic policies to the needs of the possibility of a difference, he said.  <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">Table 4</ref> compares translations by GD and RW. RW correctly puts the verb said at the end, while GD drops the final verb. However, RW still produces he at the beginning (also the first word in the Japanese source sentence). This is because our current seg- mentation strategy do not preserve words for later translation-a note-taking strategy used by human interpreters.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.5">Error Analysis</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Related Work</head><p>Previous approaches to simultaneous machine translation have employed explicit interpretation strategies for coping with delay. Two major ap- proaches are segmentation and prediction. Most segmentation strategies are based on heuristics, such as pauses in speech <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Fügen et al., 2007;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Bangalore et al., 2009)</ref>, comma predic- tion ( <ref type="bibr">Sridhar et al., 2013</ref>) and phrase reordering probability ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Fujita et al., 2013)</ref>. Learning-based methods have also been proposed. <ref type="bibr">Oda et al. (2014)</ref> find segmentations that maximize the BLEU score of the final concatenated translation by dynamic programming. <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Grissom II et al. (2014)</ref> formulate simultaneous translation as a sequential decision making problem and uses reinforcement learning to decide when to translate. One limitation of these methods is that when learning with standard batch MT corpus, their gain can be restricted by natural word reordering between the source and the target sentences, as explained in Section 1.</p><p>In an SOV-SVO context, methods to predict un- seen words are proposed to alleviate the above re- striction. <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">Matsubara et al. (1999)</ref> predict the En- glish verb in the target sentence and integrates it syntactically. <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Grissom II et al. (2014)</ref> predict the fi- nal verb in the source sentence and decide when to use the predicted verb with reinforcement learning. Nevertheless, unless the predictor considers con- textual and background information, which human interpreters often rely on for prediction <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(Hönig, 1997;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Camayd-Freixas, 2011</ref>), such a prediction task is inherently hard.</p><p>Unlike previous approaches to simultaneous translation, we directly adapt the training data and transform a translated sentence to an "interpreted" one. We can, therefore, take advantage of the abun- dance of parallel batch-translated corpora for train- ing a simultaneous MT system. In addition, as a data preprocessing step, our approach is orthogonal to the others, with which it can be easily combined.</p><p>This work is also related to preprocessing re- ordering approaches ( <ref type="bibr">Xu et al., 2009;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Collins et al., 2005;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Galley and Manning, 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Hoshino et al., 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Hoshino et al., 2014</ref>) in batch MT for language pairs with substantially different word or- ders. However, our problem is different in several ways. First, while the approaches resemble each other, our motivation is to reduce translation delay. Second, they reorder the source sentence, which is nontrivial and time-consuming when the sentence is incrementally revealed. Third, rewriting the tar- get sentence requires the output to be grammatical (for it to be used as reference translation), which is not a concern when rewriting source sentences.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7">Conclusion</head><p>Training MT systems with more monotonic (interpretation-like) sentences improves the speed- accuracy tradeoff for simultaneous machine trans- lation. By designing syntactic transformations and rewriting batch translations into more monotonic translations, we reduce the translation delay. MT systems trained on the rewritten reference transla- tions learn interpretation strategies implicitly from the data.</p><p>Our rewrites are based on linguistic knowledge and inspired by techniques used by human inter- preters. They cover a wide range of reordering phe- nomena between Japanese and English, and more generally, between SOV and SVO languages. A nat- ural extension is to automatically extract such rules from parallel corpora. While there exist approaches that extract syntactic tree transformation rules auto- matically, one of the difficulties is that most parallel corpora is dominated by lexical paraphrasing in- stead of syntactic paraphrasing. 62 monologue corpus for simultaneous machine inter- pretation research. In Proceedings of the Language Resources and Evaluation Conference (LREC).</p><p>Graham Neubig. 2011. The Kyoto free translation task.</p><p>Available online at http://www. phontron. com/kftt. Masao Utiyama and Hitoshi Isahara. 2003. Reliable measures for aligning japanese-english news articles and sentences. In Proceedings of the annual meet- ing of the Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Franz Josef Och and Hermann</head><p>Peng Xu, Jaeho Kang, Michael Ringgaard, , and Franz Och. 2009. Using a dependency parser to improve SMT for subject-object-verb language. In Proceed- ings of the Conference of the North American Chap- ter of the Association for Computational Linguistics (NAACL).</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Figure 3: Speed/accuracy tradeoff curves: BLEU (left) / RIBES (right) versus translation delay (average number of words per segment).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Ney. 2003 .</head><label>2003</label><figDesc>A system- atic comparison of various statistical alignment mod- els. Computational Linguistics, 29(1):19-51. Yusuke Oda, Graham Neubig, Sakriani Sakti, Tomoki Toda, and Satoshi Nakamura. 2014. Optimizing seg- mentation strategies for simultaneous speech transla- tion. In Proceedings of the Association for Compu- tational Linguistics (ACL), June. Kishore Papineni, Salim Roukos, Todd Ward, , and Wei-Jing Zhu. 2002. BLEU: a method for automatic evaluation of machine translation. In Proceedings of the annual meeting of the Association for Computa- tional Linguistics (ACL). Matthias Paulik and Alex Waibel. 2010. Spoken lan- guage translation from parallel speech audio: Simul- taneous interpretation as slt training data. In Pro- ceedings of the International Conference on Acous- tics, Speech, and Signal Processing (ICASSP). Hiroaki Shimizu, Graham Neubig, Sakriani Sakti, Tomoki Toda, and Satoshi Nakamura. 2013. Con- structing a speech translation system using simulta- neous interpretation data. In Proceedings of Inter- national Workshop on Spoken Language Translation (IWSLT). Hiroaki Shimizu, Graham Neubig, Sakriani Sakti, Tomoki Toda, and Satoshi Nakamura. 2014. Collec- tion of a simultaneous translation corpus for compar- ative analysis. In International Language Resources and Evaluation (LREC). Vivek Kumar Rangarajan Sridhar, John Chen, Srinivas Bangalore Andrej Ljolje, and Rathinavelu Chengal- varayan. 2013. Segmentation strategies for stream- ing speech translation. In Proceedings of the Con- ference of the North American Chapter of the Asso- ciation for Computational Linguistics (NAACL). Hitomi Tohyama and Shigeki Matsubara. 2006. Col- lection of simultaneous interpreting patterns by us- ing bilingual spoken monologue corpus. In Proceed- ings of the Language Resources and Evaluation Con- ference (LREC).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" validated="false"><head>Table 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Number of verbs in the test set transla-
tion produced by different models and the gold 
reference translation. Boldface indicates the num-
ber is significantly larger than others (excluding 
the gold ref) according to two-sample t-tests with 
p &lt; 0.001. 

et al., 2005; Xu et al., 2009). Table 3 shows the 
number of verbs in the translations of the test sen-
tences produced by GD, RW, RW+GD, as well as 
the number in the gold reference translation. Both 
RW and RW+GD produce more verbs (a statistically 
significant result), although RW+GD captures the 
most verbs. </table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3" validated="false"><head>Table 4 :</head><label>4</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Example of translation produced by GD 
and RW. 

</table></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> Ideally, delay should be based on time lapse. However, timestamping is not applicable to typical MT corpus, therefore we approximate it by number of tokens and ignore decoding time.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="4"> The main verb excludes be and have when it indicates tense (e.g., have done). 5 We use the Nodebox linguistic library (https://www. nodebox.net/code) to detect and modify word forms.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="6"> For example, in clause transformation, the Japanese conjunction moshi, which is clause initial, may appear at the beginning of a sentence to emphasize conditionals, although its appearance is relatively rare. 7 Available at http://eijiro.jp 8 Available at http://www.atilika.org/ 9 In contrast to BLEU, RIBES is an order-sensitive metric commonly used for translation between Japanese and English.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="10"> For simplicity we show the shallow parse only.</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>This work was supported by NSF grant IIS-1320538. Boyd-Graber is also partially supported by NSF grants CCF-1409287 and NCSE-1422492. Daumé III and He are also partially supported by NSF grant IIS-0964681. Any opinions, findings, conclusions, or recommendations expressed here are those of the authors and do not necessarily re-flect the view of the sponsor.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">On the use of compensatory strategies in simultaneous interpretation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Raja</forename><surname>Al-Khanji</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Said</forename><surname>El-Shiyab</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Riyadh</forename><surname>Hussein</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal des Traducteurs</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">45</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="548" to="577" />
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Real-time incremental speech-tospeech translation of dialogs</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Srinivas</forename><surname>Bangalore</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Vivek</forename><surname>Kumar Rangarajan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Prakash</forename><surname>Sridhar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ladan</forename><surname>Kolan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Aura</forename><surname>Golipour</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Jimene</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Conference of the North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics (NAACL)</title>
		<meeting>the Conference of the North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics (NAACL)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">An approach to corpus-based interpreting studies: Developing EPIC (european parliament interpreting corpus)</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Claudio</forename><surname>Bendazzoli</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Annalisa</forename><surname>Sandrelli</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of Challenges of Multidimensional Translation</title>
		<meeting>Challenges of Multidimensional Translation</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Natural Language Processing with Python</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Steven</forename><surname>Bird</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ewan</forename><surname>Klein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Edward</forename><surname>Loper</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<pubPlace>O&apos;Reilly Media</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Fill-up versus interpolation methods for phrase-based SMT adaptation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Arianna</forename><surname>Bisazza</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nick</forename><surname>Ruiz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marcello</forename><surname>Federico</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of International Workshop on Spoken Language Translation (IWSLT)</title>
		<meeting>International Workshop on Spoken Language Translation (IWSLT)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Cognitive theory of simultaneous interpreting and training</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Erik</forename><surname>Camayd-Freixas</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 52nd Conference of the American Translators Association</title>
		<meeting>the 52nd Conference of the American Translators Association</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Batch tuning strategies for statistical machine translation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Colin</forename><surname>Cherry</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">George</forename><surname>Foster</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Conference of the North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics (NAACL)</title>
		<meeting>the Conference of the North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics (NAACL)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Clause restructuring for statistical machine translation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Collins</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Philipp</forename><surname>Koehn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ivona</forename><surname>Kučerová</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the annual meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL)</title>
		<meeting>the annual meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Framesemantic parsing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dipanjan</forename><surname>Das</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Desai</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>André</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nathan</forename><surname>Martins</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Noah</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Schneider</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Smith</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Computational Linguistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">40</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Simultaneous translation of lectures and speeches</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christian</forename><surname>Fügen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alex</forename><surname>Waibel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Muntsin</forename><surname>Kolss</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Machine Translation</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">21</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="209" to="252" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Simple, lexicalized choice of translation timing for simultaneous speech translation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tomoki</forename><surname>Fujita</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Graham</forename><surname>Neubig</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sakriani</forename><surname>Sakti</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tomoki</forename><surname>Toda</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Satoshi</forename><surname>Nakamura</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of Interspeech</title>
		<meeting>Interspeech</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A simple and effective hierarchical phrase reordering model</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michel</forename><surname>Galley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christopher</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Manning</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP)</title>
		<meeting>Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Don&apos;t until the final verb wait: Reinforcement learning for simultaneous machine translation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alvin</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Grissom</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><forename type="middle">I</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">He</forename><surname>He</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jordan</forename><surname>Boyd-Graber</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">John</forename><surname>Morgan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hal</forename><surname>Daumé</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Iii</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</title>
		<meeting>Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>EMNLP</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Using text mappings in teaching consecutive interpreting. Translation and Translation Theory</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Hans</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Hönig</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="19" to="34" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Two-stage pre-ordering for Japanese-to-English statistical machine translation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sho</forename><surname>Hoshino</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yusuke</forename><surname>Miyao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Katsuhito</forename><surname>Sudoh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Masaaki</forename><surname>Nagata</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence (IJCNLP)</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Japanese to english machine translation using preordering and compositional distributed semantics</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sho</forename><surname>Hoshino</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hubert</forename><surname>Soyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yusuke</forename><surname>Miyao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Akiko</forename><surname>Aizawa</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Workshop on Asian Translation</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Automatic evaluation of translation quality for distant language pairs</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hideki</forename><surname>Isozaki</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tsutomu</forename><surname>Hirao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kevin</forename><surname>Duh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Katsuhito</forename><surname>Sudoh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hajime</forename><surname>Tsukada</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</title>
		<meeting>Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>EMNLP</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Accurate unlexicalized parsing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dan</forename><surname>Klein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christopher</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Manning</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the annual meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL)</title>
		<meeting>the annual meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Moses: Open source toolkit for statistical machine translation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Philipp</forename><surname>Koehn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hieu</forename><surname>Hoang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alexandra</forename><surname>Birch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chris</forename><surname>Callison-Burch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marcello</forename><surname>Federico</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Brooke Cowan Nicola</forename><surname>Bertoldi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wade</forename><surname>Shen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Richard</forename><forename type="middle">Zens</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christine</forename><surname>Moran</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chris</forename><surname>Dyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ondřej</forename><surname>Bojar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alexandra</forename><surname>Constantin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Evan</forename><surname>Herbs</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the annual meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL)</title>
		<meeting>the annual meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Sync/trans: Simultaneous machine interpretation between English and Japanese</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Shigeki</forename><surname>Matsubara</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Katsuhiko</forename><surname>Toyama</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yasuyoshi</forename><surname>Inagaki</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Advanced Topics in Artificial Intelligence</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="134" to="143" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Bilingual spoken</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Shigeki</forename><surname>Matsubara</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Akira</forename><surname>Takagi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nobuo</forename><surname>Kawaguchi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yasuyoshi</forename><surname>Inagaki</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
