<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T11:04+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Modeling Tweet Arrival Times using Log-Gaussian Cox Processes</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
				<availability status="unknown"><p>Copyright Association for Computational Linguistics</p>
				</availability>
				<date type="published" when="2015-09">September 2015. 2015</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michal</forename><surname>Lukasik</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Srijith</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Trevor</forename><surname>Cohn</surname></persName>
							<email>t.cohn@unimelb.edu.au</email>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computing and Information Systems</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">The University of Melbourne</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kalina</forename><surname>Bontcheva</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">The University of Sheffield</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Modeling Tweet Arrival Times using Log-Gaussian Cox Processes</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2015 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</title>
						<meeting>the 2015 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing <address><addrLine>Lisbon, Portugal</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="17" to="21"/>
							<date type="published" when="2015-09">September 2015. 2015</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Research on modeling time series text corpora has typically focused on predicting what text will come next, but less well studied is predicting when the next text event will occur. In this paper we address the latter case, framed as modeling continuous inter-arrival times under a log-Gaussian Cox process, a form of inhomo-geneous Poisson process which captures the varying rate at which the tweets arrive over time. In an application to rumour modeling of tweets surrounding the 2014 Ferguson riots, we show how inter-arrival times between tweets can be accurately predicted, and that incorporating textual features further improves predictions .</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Twitter is a popular micro-blogging service which provides real-time information on events happen- ing across the world. Evolution of events over time can be monitored there with applications to dis- aster management, journalism etc. For example, Twitter has been used to detect the occurrence of earthquakes in Japan through user posts ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Sakaki et al., 2010)</ref>. Modeling the temporal dynamics of tweets provides useful information about the evo- lution of events. Inter-arrival time prediction is a type of such modeling and has application in many settings featuring continuous time streaming text corpora, including journalism for event monitor- ing, real-time disaster monitoring and advertising on social media. For example, journalists track several rumours related to an event. Predicted ar- rival times of tweets can be applied for ranking rumours according to their activity and narrow the interest to investigate a rumour with a short inter- arrival time over that of a longer one.</p><p>Modeling the inter-arrival time of tweets is a challenging task due to complex temporal patterns exhibited. Tweets associated with an event stream arrive at different rates at different points in time. For example, <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1a</ref> shows the arrival times (denoted by black crosses) of tweets associated with an example rumour around Ferguson riots in 2014. Notice the existence of regions of both high and low density of arrival times over a one hour interval. We propose to address inter-arrival time prediction problem with log-Gaussian Cox pro- cess (LGCP), an inhomogeneous Poisson process (IPP) which models tweets to be generated by an underlying intensity function which varies across time. Moreover, it assumes a non-parametric form for the intensity function allowing the model com- plexity to depend on the data set. We also pro- vide an approach to consider textual content of tweets to model inter-arrival times. We evaluate the models using Twitter rumours from the 2014 Ferguson unrest, and demonstrate that they pro- vide good predictions for inter-arrival times, beat- ing the baselines e.g. homogeneous Poisson Pro- cess, Gaussian Process regression and univariate Hawkes Process. Even though the central appli- cation is rumours, one could apply the proposed approaches to model the arrival times of tweets corresponding to other types of memes, e.g. dis- cussions about politics. This paper makes the following contributions: 1. Introduces log-Gaussian Cox process to predict tweet arrival times. 2. Demonstrates how incor- porating text improves results of inter-arrival time prediction.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Related Work</head><p>Previous approaches to modeling inter-arrival times of tweets ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Perera et al., 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Sakaki et al., 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Esteban et al., 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Doerr et al., 2013)</ref> were not complex enough to consider their time vary- ing characteristics. <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Perera et al. (2010)</ref>  inter-arrival times as independent and exponen- tially distributed with a constant rate parameter. A similar model is used by <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Sakaki et al. (2010)</ref> to monitor the tweets related to earthquakes. The re- newal process model used by <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Esteban et al. (2012)</ref> assumes the inter-arrival times to be independent and identically distributed. <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Gonzalez et al. (2014)</ref> attempts to model arrival times of tweets using a Gaussian process but assumes the tweet arrivals to be independent every hour. These approaches do not take into account the varying characteristics of arrival times of tweets.</p><p>Point processes such as Poisson and Hawkess process have been used for spatio-temporal model- ing of meme spread in social networks <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">(Yang and Zha, 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Simma and Jordan, 2010)</ref>. Hawkes processes <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">(Yang and Zha, 2013)</ref> were also found to be useful for modeling the underlying network structure. These models capture relevant network information in the underlying intensity function. We use a log-Gaussian cox process which provides a Bayesian method to capture relevant information through the prior. It has been found to be use- ful e.g. for conflict mapping (Zammit-Mangion et al., 2012) and for frequency prediction in Twit- ter ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Lukasik et al., 2015</ref>).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Data &amp; Problem</head><p>In this section we describe the data and we formal- ize the problem of modeling tweet arrival times.</p><p>Data We consider the Ferguson rumour data set ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Zubiaga et al., 2015</ref>), consisting of tweets on ru- mours around 2014 Ferguson unrest. It consists of conversational threads that have been manually labeled by annotators to correspond to rumours 1 . Since some rumours have few posts, we consider only those with at least 15 posts in the first hour as they express interesting behaviour ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Lukasik et al., 2015)</ref>. This results in 114 rumours consisting of a total of 4098 tweets.</p><p>Problem Definition Let us consider a time in- terval <ref type="bibr">[0,</ref><ref type="bibr">2]</ref> measured in hours, a set of rumours</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">R = {E i } n i=1</formula><p>, where rumour E i consists of a set of m i posts</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">E i = {p i j } m i j=1 . Posts are tuples p i j = (x i j , t i j )</formula><p>, where x i j is text (in our case a vec- tor of Brown clusters counts, see section 5) and t i j is time of occurrence of post p i j , measured in time since the first post on rumour E i .</p><p>We introduce the problem of predicting the ex- act time of posts in the future unobserved time in- terval, which is studied as inter-arrival time pre- diction. In our setting, we observe posts over a target rumour i for one hour and over refer- ence rumours (other than i) for two hours. Thus, the training data set is</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">R O = {E O i } n i=1</formula><p>, where of posts about rumour i in the future one hour time interval.</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">E O i = {p i j } m O i 1 (m O i</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Model</head><p>The problem of modeling the inter-arrival times of tweets can be solved using Poisson processes <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Perera et al., 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Sakaki et al., 2010)</ref>. A homo- geneous Poisson process (HPP) assumes the in- tensity to be constant (with respect to time and the rumour statistics). It is not adequate to model the inter-arrival times of tweets because it assumes constant rate of point arrival across time. Inhomo- geneous Poisson process (IPP) ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Lee et al., 1991)</ref> can model tweets occurring at a variable rate by considering the intensity to be a function of time, i.e. λ(t). For example, in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1a</ref> we show in- tensity functions learnt for two different IPP mod- els. Notice how the generated arrival times vary according to the intensity function values.</p><p>Log-Gaussian Cox process We consider a log-Gaussian Cox process (LGCP) <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Møller and Syversveen, 1998</ref>), a special case of IPP, where the intensity function is assumed to be stochas- tic. The intensity function λ(t) is modeled using a latent function f (t) sampled from a Gaussian process <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Rasmussen and Williams, 2005</ref>). To en- sure positivity of the intensity function, we con- sider λ(t) = exp (f (t)). This provides a non- parametric Bayesian approach to model the inten- sity function, where the complexity of the model is learnt from the training data. Moreover, we can define the functional form of the intensity function through appropriate GP priors.</p><p>Modeling inter-arrival time Inhomogeneous Poisson process (unlike HPP) uses a time vary- ing intensity function and hence, the distribution of inter-arrival times is not independent and iden- tically distributed <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Ross, 2010)</ref>. In IPP, the number of tweets y occurring in an interval <ref type="bibr">[s, e]</ref> is Poisson distributed with rate e s λ(t)dt.</p><formula xml:id="formula_4">p(y|λ(t), [s, e]) = Poisson(y| e s λ(t)dt) = ( e s λ(t)dt) y exp(− e s λ(t)dt) y!<label>(1)</label></formula><p>Assume that n th tweet occurred at time E n = s and we are interested in the inter-arrival time T n of the next tweet. The arrival time of next tweet E n+1 can be obtained as E n+1 = E n + T n . The cumulative distribution for T n , which provides the probability that a tweet occurs by time s + u can be obtained as 2</p><formula xml:id="formula_5">p(T n ≤ u) = 1 − p(T n &gt; u|λ(t), E n = s) = 1 − p(0 events in [s, s + u]|λ(t)) = 1 − exp(− s+u s λ(t)dt) = 1 − exp(− u 0 λ(s + t)dt)<label>(2)</label></formula><p>The derivation is obtained by considering a Poisson probability for 0 counts with rate parame- ter given by s+u s λ(t)dt and applying integration by substitution to obtain (2). The probability den- sity function of the random variable T n is obtained by taking the derivative of (2) with respect to u:</p><formula xml:id="formula_6">p(T n = u) = λ(s + u) exp(− u 0 λ(s + t)dt).<label>(3)</label></formula><p>The computational difficulties arising from inte- gration are dealt by assuming the intensity func- tion to be constant in an interval and approximat- ing the inter-arrival time density as <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Møller and Syversveen, 1998;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Vanhatalo et al., 2013)</ref> </p><formula xml:id="formula_7">p(T n = u) = λ(s + u) exp(−uλ(s + u 2 )).<label>(4)</label></formula><p>We associate a distinct intensity function λ i (t) = exp(f i (t)) with each rumour E i as they have varying temporal profiles. The la- tent function f i is modelled to come from a zero mean Gaussian process (GP) <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Rasmussen and Williams, 2005</ref>) prior with covariance de- fined by a squared exponential (SE) kernel over time, k time (t, t ) = a exp(−(t − t ) 2 /l). We con- sider the likelihood of posts E O i over the entire training period to be product of Poisson distri- bution (1) over equal length sub-intervals with the rate in a sub-interval [s, e] approximated as (e − s) exp(f i ( 1 2 (s + e))). The likelihood of posts in the rumour data is obtained by taking the prod- uct of the likelihoods over individual rumours.</p><p>The distribution of the posterior p(f i |E O i ) is intractable and a Laplace approximation <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Rasmussen and Williams, 2005</ref>) is used to obtain the posterior. The predictive distribution f i (t i * ) at time t i * is obtained using the approximated posterior. The intensity function value at the point t i * is then obtained as</p><formula xml:id="formula_8">λ i (t i * |E O i ) = exp f i (t i * ) p f i (t i * )|E O i df i (t i * ).</formula><p>Algorithm 1 Importance sampling for predicting the next arrival time 1: Input: Intensity function λ(t), previous ar- rival time s, proposal distribution q(t) = exp(t; 2), number of samples N 2: for i = 1 to N do 3:</p><p>Sample u i ∼ q(t).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>4:</head><p>Obtain weights w i = p(u i ) q(u i ) , where p(t) is given by (4). 5: end for 6: Predict expected inter-arrival time as</p><formula xml:id="formula_9">¯ u = N i=1 u i w i N j=1 w j 7:</formula><p>Predict the next arrival time as ¯ t = s + ¯ u. 8: Return: ¯ t Importance sampling We are interested in pre- dicting the next arrival time of a tweet given the time at which the previous tweet was posted. This is achieved by sampling the inter-arrival time of occurrence of the next tweet using equation <ref type="formula" target="#formula_7">(4)</ref>. We use the importance sampling scheme <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Gelman et al., 2003)</ref> where an exponential distribution is used as the proposal density. We set the rate pa- rameter of this exponential distribution to 2 which generates points with a mean value around 0.5. Assuming the previous tweet occurred at time s, we obtain the arrival time of next tweet as outlined in Algorithm 1. We run this algorithm sequen- tially, i.e. the time ¯ t returned from Algorithm 1 becomes starting time s in the next iteration. We stop at the end of the interval of interest, for which a user wants to find times of post occurrences.</p><p>Incorporating text We consider adding the kernel over text from posts to the previously introduced kernel over time.</p><p>We join text from the observed posts together, so a dif- ferent component is added to kernel values across different rumours. The full kernel then takes form k TXT <ref type="figure">((t, i)</ref> </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Experiments</head><p>Data preprocessing In our experiments, we consider the first two hours of each rumour lifes- pan. The posts from the first hour of a target ru- mour is considered as observed (training data) and we predict the arrival times of tweets in the sec- ond hour. We consider observations over equal sized time intervals of length six minutes in the rumour lifespan for learning the intensity func- tion. The text in the tweets is represented by using Brown cluster ids associated with the words. This is obtained using 1000 clusters acquired on a large scale Twitter corpus ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Owoputi et al., 2013</ref>).</p><p>Evaluation metrics Let the arrival times pre- dicted by a model be ( ˆ t 1 , . . . , ˆ t M ) and let the actual arrival times be (t 1 , . . . , t N ). We intro- duce two metrics based on root mean squared er- ror (RMSE) for evaluating predicted inter-arrival times. First is aligned root mean squared er- ror (ARMSE), where we align the initial K = min(M, N ) arrival times and calculate the RMSE between such two subsequences.</p><p>The sec- ond is called penalized root mean squared error (PRMSE). In this metric we penalize approaches which predict a different number of inter-arrival times than the actual number. The PRMSE met- ric is defined as the square root of the following expression.</p><formula xml:id="formula_10">1 K K i=1 ( ˆ t i − t i ) 2 + I[M &gt; N ] M i=N +1 (T − ˆ t i ) 2 +I[M &lt; N ] N i=M +1 (T − t i ) 2<label>(5)</label></formula><p>The second and third term in <ref type="formula" target="#formula_10">(5)</ref>  to 1000 (above the maximum count yielded by any rumour from our dataset), thus reducing the error from this method. We also compare against Hawkes Process (HP) <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">(Yang and Zha, 2013</ref>), a self exciting point process where an occurrence of a tweet increases the probability of tweets arriving soon after- wards. We consider a univariate Hawkes pro- cess where the intensity function is modeled as λ i (t) = µ + t i j &lt;t k time (t i j , t). The kernel pa- rameters and µ are learnt by maximizing the like- lihood. We apply the importance sampling algo- rithm discussed in Algorithm 1 for generating ar- rival times for Hawkess process. We consider this baseline only in the single-task setting, where ref- erence rumours are not considered.</p><p>LGCP settings In the case of LGCP, the model parameters of the intensity function associated with a rumour are learnt from the observed inter- arrival times from that rumour alone. LGCP Pooled and LGCPTXT consider a different setting where this is learnt additionally using the inter- arrival times of all other rumours observed over the entire two hour life-span.</p><p>Results <ref type="table">Table 1</ref> reports the results of predicting arrival times of tweets in the second hour of the rumour lifecycle. In terms of ARMSE, LGCP is the best method, performing better than LGCP- TXT (though not statistically significantly) and outperforming other approaches. However, this metric does not penalize for the wrong number of predicted arrival times. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1b</ref> depicts an example rumour, where LGCP greatly overesti- mates the number of points in the interval of inter- est. Here, the three points from the ground truth (denoted by black crosses) and the initial three points predicted by the LGCP model (denoted by red pluses), happen to lie very close, yielding a low ARMSE error. However, LGCP predicts a large number of arrivals in this interval making it a bad model compared to LGCPTXT which predicts only four points (denoted by blue dots). ARMSE fails to capture this and hence we use PRMSE. Note that Hawkes Process is performing worse than the LGCP approach.</p><p>According to PRMSE, LGCPTXT is the most successful method, significantly outperforming all other according to Wilcoxon signed rank test. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Fig- ure 1a</ref> depicts the behavior of LGCP and LGCP- TXT on rumour 39 with a larger number of points from the ground truth. Here, LGCPTXT predicts relatively less number of arrivals than LGCP. The performance of Hawkes Process is again worse than the LGCP approach. The self excitory nature of Hawkes process may not be appropriate for this dataset and setting, where in the second hour the number of points tends to decrease as time passes.</p><p>We also note, that GPLIN performs very poorly according to PRMSE. This is because the inter- arrival times predicted by GPLIN for several ru- mours become smaller as time grows resulting in a large number of arrival times.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Conclusions</head><p>This paper introduced the log-Gaussian Cox pro- cesses for the problem of predicting the inter- arrival times of tweets. We showed how text from posts helps to achieve significant improvements. Evaluation on a set of rumours from Ferguson ri- ots showed efficacy of our methods comparing to baselines. The proposed approaches are generaliz- able to problems other than rumours, e.g. disaster management and advertisement campaigns.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: Intensity functions and corresponding predicted arrival times for different methods across example Ferguson rumours. Arrival times predicted by LGCP are denoted by red pluses, LGCPTXT by blue dots, and ground truth by black crosses. Light regions denote uncertainty of predictions.</figDesc></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> For a fully automated approach, a system for early detection of rumours (Zhao et al., 2015) could be run first and our models then applied to the resulting rumours.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="2"> We suppress the conditioning variables for brevity.</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>Work partially supported by the European Union under grant agreement No. 611233 PHEME.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Lognormal infection times of online information spread</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christian</forename><surname>Doerr</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Norbert</forename><surname>Blenn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Piet</forename><surname>Van Mieghem</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">PLOS ONE</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Analysis of Twitter Traffic based on Renewal Densities</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Esteban</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Ortega</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Mcpherson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Sathiamoorthy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>ArXiv e-prints</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Bayesian Data Analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Andrew</forename><surname>Gelman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">John</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Carlin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hal</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Stern</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Donald</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Rubin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
			<publisher>Chapman and Hall/CRC</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">On the tweet arrival process at twitter: analysis and applications</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Roberto</forename><surname>Gonzalez</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alfonso</forename><surname>Muñoz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">José</forename><forename type="middle">Alberto</forename><surname>Hernández</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ruben</forename><surname>Cuevas</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Trans. Emerging Telecommunications Technologies</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">25</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="273" to="282" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Modeling and simulation of a nonhomogeneous poisson process having cyclic behavior</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Crawford</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Wilson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Communications in Statistics Simulation</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="777" to="809" />
			<date type="published" when="1991" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Point process modelling of rumour dynamics in social media</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michal</forename><surname>Lukasik</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Trevor</forename><surname>Cohn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kalina</forename><surname>Bontcheva</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 53rd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics and the 7th International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing of the Asian Federation of Natural Language Processing</title>
		<meeting>the 53rd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics and the 7th International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing of the Asian Federation of Natural Language Processing</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="518" to="523" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Log Gaussian Cox processes</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jesper</forename><surname>Møller</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Anne</forename><forename type="middle">Randi</forename><surname>Syversveen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Scandinavian Journal of Statistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="451" to="482" />
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Improved part-of-speech tagging for online conversational text with word clusters</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Olutobi</forename><surname>Owoputi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chris</forename><surname>Dyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kevin</forename><surname>Gimpel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nathan</forename><surname>Schneider</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Noah</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Smith</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of NAACL</title>
		<meeting>NAACL</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Twitter analytics: Architecture, tools and analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Rohan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sruthy</forename><surname>Perera</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Anand</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Subbalakshmi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Chandramouli</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Military Communications Conference</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2186" to="2191" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Gaussian Processes for Machine Learning (Adaptive Computation and Machine Learning)</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Carl</forename><forename type="middle">Edward</forename><surname>Rasmussen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christopher</forename><forename type="middle">K I</forename><surname>Williams</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
			<publisher>The MIT Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Introduction to Probability Models, Tenth Edition</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Sheldon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Ross</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<publisher>Academic Press, Inc</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Orlando, FL, USA</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Earthquake shakes twitter users: Real-time event detection by social sensors</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Takeshi</forename><surname>Sakaki</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Makoto</forename><surname>Okazaki</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yutaka</forename><surname>Matsuo</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 19th International Conference on World Wide Web, WWW &apos;10</title>
		<meeting>the 19th International Conference on World Wide Web, WWW &apos;10</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="851" to="860" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Modeling events with cascades of poisson processes</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Aleksandr</forename><surname>Simma</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Michael</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Jordan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">UAI</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="546" to="555" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Gpstuff: Bayesian modeling with gaussian processes</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jarno</forename><surname>Vanhatalo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jaakko</forename><surname>Riihimäki</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jouni</forename><surname>Hartikainen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Pasi</forename><surname>Jylänki</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ville</forename><surname>Tolvanen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Aki</forename><surname>Vehtari</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Mach. Learn. Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1175" to="1179" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Mixture of mutually exciting processes for viral diffusion</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hong</forename><surname>Shuang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hongyuan</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Zha</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ICML</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">28</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="9" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Point process modelling of the afghan war diary</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Andrew</forename><surname>Zammit-Mangion</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Dewar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Visakan</forename><surname>Kadirkamanathan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Guido</forename><surname>Sanguinetti</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences</title>
		<meeting>the National Academy of Sciences</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">109</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="12414" to="12419" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Early detection of rumors in social media from enquiry posts</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Zhe</forename><surname>Zhao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Paul</forename><surname>Resnick</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Qiaozhu</forename><surname>Mei</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">International World Wide Web Conference Committee (IW3C2)</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Towards detecting rumours in social media</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Arkaitz</forename><surname>Zubiaga</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Maria</forename><surname>Liakata</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rob</forename><surname>Procter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kalina</forename><surname>Bontcheva</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Peter</forename><surname>Tolmie</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">AAAI Workshop on AI for Cities</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
