<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T12:16+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">A quantitative analysis of gender differences in movies using psycholinguistic normatives</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
				<availability status="unknown"><p>Copyright Association for Computational Linguistics</p>
				</availability>
				<date type="published" when="1996">1996-2001. September 2015. 2015</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Anil</forename><surname>Ramakrishna</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nikolaos</forename><surname>Malandrakis</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Elizabeth</forename><surname>Staruk</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Shrikanth</forename><surname>Narayanan</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science</orgName>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Electrical Engineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Southern California</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Los Angeles</settlement>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">A quantitative analysis of gender differences in movies using psycholinguistic normatives</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2015 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</title>
						<meeting>the 2015 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing <address><addrLine>Lisbon, Portugal</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="17" to="21"/>
							<date type="published" when="1996">1996-2001. September 2015. 2015</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Direct content analysis reveals important details about movies including those of gender representations and potential biases. We investigate the differences between male and female character depic-tions in movies, based on patterns of language used. Specifically, we use an automatically generated lexicon of linguistic norms characterizing gender ladenness. We use multivariate analysis to investigate gender depictions and correlate them with elements of movie production. The proposed metric differentiates between male and female utterances and exhibits some interesting interactions with movie genres and the screenplay writer gender.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Gender has been an important research topic in the social sciences, with studies conducted on the ef- fect of gender on various aspects of human percep- tion and expression ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Benshoff and Griffin, 2011)</ref> as well as investigations of the societal <ref type="bibr">(BehmMorawitz and Mastro, 2008)</ref> and career implica- tions of gender and possible underlying biases. Previous studies report significant implications of gender on career progress in medicine ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Sidhu et al., 2009)</ref>, information technology ( <ref type="bibr">Cohoon and Aspray, 2006</ref>), politics <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Niven, 2006</ref>) and show- business <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">(Smith, 2010)</ref>.</p><p>In this paper we investigate the depictions of the genders in feature films, through the analysis of their respective dialogues. The differences in depiction are a contentious subject, since aspects of these can be viewed as the result of stereotyp- ing or gender bias, with the relative presence of women being a well investigated subject <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Bielby and Bielby, 1996;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Lincoln and Allen, 2004</ref>). We are interested in the existing gender depictions, re- gardless of relative frequencies, as well as any fac- tors that may affect them. While popular tools such as the Bechdel test provide a test for detecting female presence in the movies, we hope to iden- tify more subtle forms of gender differences across character gender from the dialogues. Our aim is to devise a non-binary metric that can be used to compare or rank movies, characters and perhaps individual utterances.</p><p>To analyze the dialogues we propose using a metric of language gender ladenness, a num- ber representing a normative rating of the "per- ceived feminine or masculine association" ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Paivio et al., 1968</ref>) of language. The metric, as origi- nally defined, is meant to provide an indication of gender-specificity of individual words, with ex- treme values assigned to highly stereotypical con- cepts. Generating this rating for male and fe- male character dialogues and comparing the char- acter gender with this rating of "language gender" should allow us to observe stereotypical behavior.</p><p>Word based ratings such as the gender laden- ness are referred to as linguistic norms (or psy- cholinguistic norms when corresponding to psy- chological constructs) and are popular in cognitive psychology <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Clark and Paivio, 2004</ref>) and some computational disciplines, such as sentiment anal- ysis (Nielsen, 2011) and opinion mining. To uti- lize gender ladenness, we follow an approach sim- ilar to simple sentiment analysis, with word-level norms automatically generated based on a small starting set of manually annotated norms and sen- tence (and higher) level norms estimated through word-level norm statistics. The resulting algo- rithm allows us to estimate gender ladenness at any arbitrary granularity.</p><p>We use these ratings of dialogue language to quantify the depictions of male and female char- acters and attempt to relate the observed gender ladenness with objective factors.</p><p>In section 2 and 3 we describe the data corpus and the feature extraction process respectively. We detail the experimental procedure in section 4 and analysis in section 5 and conclude with future ex- tensions in section 6.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Estimating Gender Ladenness</head><p>Gender Ladenness, as defined in <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Clark and Paivio, 2004</ref>) represents the degree of perceived "feminine or masculine association" on a numeri- cal scale ranging from very masculine to very fem- inine. It is important to note that there was no re- striction to what "association" may mean: while it is reasonable to assume that associations of the form "A is B" or "A has B" would dominate an- notator perception, that does not preclude other forms of association. Because of that, referring to the norms as indicators of how masculine or femi- nine the words are is not entirely accurate, though it is a reasonable approximation. The original rat- ings were re-scaled to [−1, 1] for our purposes, with lower values indicating a masculine associ- ation and high values indicating a feminine asso- ciation. Some sample words, utterances and their corresponding ratings are presented in <ref type="table">Table 1</ref> and <ref type="table">Table 3</ref>. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref> shows the average gender laden- ness across all utterances for the major characters of a few movies. The annotations as a whole are reflective of stereotypical views of gender roles, e.g., words related to war and violence have a strong masculine association, whereas words re- lated to family or positive emotions carry strong feminine associations. The manual annotations from <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Clark and Paivio, 2004</ref>) contain ratings for only 925 words, which are not enough to provide sufficient coverage. Therefore we use a lexicon expansion method, in- spired by the work of ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Malandrakis et al., 2013)</ref> to estimate the gender ladennessˆgladennessˆ ladennessˆg(w i ) of word w i using the semantic similarities s() between w i and reference words or concepts c j , asˆg</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">asˆ asˆg(w i ) = θ 0 + N j=1 θ j s(w i , c j ),<label>(1)</label></formula><p>where the terms θ i are trained model parameters. Given a manually annotated lexicon and a set of reference words, this equation can be used to cre- ate a linear system. Solving the system via Least Squares Estimation (LSE) gives us the parameters θ and an equation that can be used to generate gen- der ladenness for any new set of words.</p><p>Gender ladenness for larger lexical units is gen- erated via simple statistics, as the average of word gender ladenness over all content words (adjec- tives, nouns, verbs and adverbs).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Data</head><p>Our primary data source is the Movie DiC corpus (Banchs, 2012) which includes 619 movie scripts parsed from The Internet Movie Script Database <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(IMSDb, 2015)</ref>. The xml formatted scripts con- tain transcripts with speaker information as well as some structural information. Additional metadata for each movie were collected from the Internet Movie Database <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(IMDb, 2015</ref>).</p><p>Since our goal was to analyze gender depic- tions, we had to annotate each script utterance with a gender label. The process was complicated by inconsistencies between the information contained in the IMDb and Movie DiC corpora, like mis- matched names, particularly for minor characters. Initially the script character names were cleaned using simple heuristics, such as the removal of all instances of the possessive "'s". The IMDb api <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(IMDbPY, 2015)</ref> was used to recover candi- date movies matching the script movie name and, in the case of multiple candidates, the best candi- date was selected based on the number of character names matching the script. Character names were compared using the Jaro-Winkler distance <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(Winkler, 1990</ref>). Having achieved a one to one map- ping between IMDb and Movie DiC, we assigned a gender label to each matched character, using the gender predictor (NamSor Applied Onomas- tics, 2015). To make these predictions, we first use the name of the corresponding actor portraying that role; if there was no character match, we use the name of the character. Finally, we calculate a confidence score of our gender assignment per ut- terance for each movie, equal to the percentage of utterances with perfectly matched character name and a high confidence by the gender predictor. For the movies for which the confidence scores are not satisfactory, we manually match the script charac- ters with IMDb's characters and annotate genders. In our experiments, we did this manual annotation with roughly 75 movies.</p><p>Having a mapping of scripts to IMDb en- tries, we collected more information about the movie such as the list of genres it belongs to and the members of the production team (producers, scriptwriters, directors), and followed a similar process as described above to assign genders to all persons. While movies may be created by multi- ple scriptwriters and directors, we retain only the first name, the primary credit, in each category. We removed infrequent genres and movies which belonged only to the removed genres. We also fil- tered out utterances with missing or incorrect char- acter information and the utterances correspond- ing to characters for which the gender predictor fails to make confident predictions.</p><p>Movies with missing fields were also removed, leaving us with a total of 568 movies after the aforementioned pre-processing steps. <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Table 2</ref> lists some descriptive statistics of the processed movie <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Property Name Female Male  Total  Movie Utterances 107372 256274 363646  Producers  746  2974  3720  Directors  33  572  605  Assistant Directors 846  2739  3585  Screenplay Writers 130  1217  1347  Casting Directors  548  195  743</ref>   <ref type="table">Table 3</ref>: Average gender ladenness for sample ut- terances from the dataset corpus. At least in terms of raw frequencies, the gender ratio is clearly skewed towards male, par- ticularly in the case of directors and with the ex- ception of casting directors. The norm generating equation (1) requires a se- mantic similarity estimate s(), which for the pur- poses of this paper is the cosine of context vectors generated over a large corpus of raw web text. The corpus was created by posing a query to the Ya- hoo! search engine for every word in the English version of the aspell spell-checker and collecting the top 500 result previews. Each preview is com- posed of a title and a sample of the content, each being a single sentence. Overall the collected cor- pus contains approximately 117 million sentences.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Experimental Procedure</head><p>The descriptive feature in this method is gender ladenness, so we extracted an estimate for each utterance of every movie. Initially, all utterances were part-of-speech tagged and non-content words were removed. Then, word-level gender landen- ness norms were generated for every remaining word.</p><p>To generate word-level norms, we used equa- tion (1) with the intermediate seed words w i be- ing the top 10000 most frequent words in our cor- pus of web text with length longer that 3 char- acters. For each word in our corpus, we gener- ated a binary weighted context vector (of window size 1) of size ∼ 125000. Then, for each word of interest we calculated a 10000 place similar- ity vector, containing the cosine similarity scores between the context vector of said word and the context vectors of the 10000 intermediate seeds.</p><p>Using the training set we generated a K × 10000 matrix of similarities to the seed words and ap- plied dimensionality reduction via Principal Com- ponent Analysis (PCA), keeping the first N = 300 components. These transformed similarities be- came the similarity terms s() of equation <ref type="formula" target="#formula_0">(1)</ref> and were used to train the model. For any word in the scripts, a 10000 place similarity vector is gen- erated and transformed using the pre-calculated PCA matrix, then equation <ref type="formula" target="#formula_0">(1)</ref> is used to create the gender ladenness estimate.</p><p>Ratings were generated at the utterance level, and collective ratings (per character, gender or movie) were calculated as utterance rating aver- ages.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Results</head><p>To evaluate the word norm generation algorithm, we performed a 10-fold cross-validation experi- ment on the 925 manually annotated norms in ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Paivio et al., 1968</ref>). The generated norms were evaluated against the ground truth and the method achieved a 0.801 Pearson correlation to the ground truth. While there is no comparable result in lit- erature, the resulting performance appears suffi- ciently high.</p><p>We first investigated the overall gender laden- ness of movies, represented as the average of all utterance level scores, with respect to the genre(s) the movie belongs to. The independent variables for this analysis were nine binary indicator vari- ables, one for each of the most frequent genre la- bels in our movie corpus, with values of zero if the movie does not belong to the specific genre and one if it does. The particular representa- tion of genres as separate variables was chosen because each movie can belong to multiple gen- res. Interaction terms were included. Running n- way ANOVA with the aggregate gender ladenness across both character genders as the dependent variable revealed significant differences between genres, with Action movies leaning towards the masculine (p = 0.013) compared to Non-Action movies, a not surprising result.</p><p>A few significant interactions between genres are shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">figure 2</ref>. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Fig. 2a</ref> indicates that among non-drama movies, romantic movies tend to in- To analyze the effect of character gender on the gender ladenness scores, we next ran ANOVA with the character gender and the movie writer's gender as additional independent variables. The dependent variable in this case was the aggregate gender ladenness score across all utterances for male and female characters, so two scores per movie. The interaction of character gender and movie genre is shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">figure 3</ref>. The scores of male and female characters are correlated, which can be attributed to the underlying concepts in the utterances from these movies. The differ- ence between genders is significant (p = 0.034), with male characters consistently using signifi- cantly more masculine language than their female counterparts, a finding that lends some credence to the metric used. Looking at the binary genre variables revealed that Action movies contained significantly more masculine language than Non-Action movies (p &lt; 10 −5 ) and the same holds for Crime movies (p &lt; 10 −5 ). Conversely, Romantic movies leaned towards the more feminine language than non- Romantic movies (p &lt; 10 −5 ) and similarly for Comedy movies compared to non-Comedy movies (p = 0.02). The male -female character gender We include only the screenplay writer's gen- der in our analysis, though both the directors and screenplay writers influence the dialog lines (utter- ances), since the writers are more likely to directly influence the actual language used. In addition, the very small number of female directors in the data, as seen in table 2, leads to a violation of ANOVA's homoscedasticity assumption. Though the writer gender itself was not a significant factor, the inter- action of writer's gender with the Action genre was significant (p = 0.005). The plot illustrating this interaction is shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">figure 4</ref>. It appears that female script writers write more masculine utter- ances compared to their male colleagues, at least for Action movies. We also investigated interac- tions between the writer and character gender, but none proved significant.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Conclusions and Future Work</head><p>We used regression to extrapolate manually an- notated psycholinguistic normatives to movie ut- terances and investigated the use of these met- rics to describe gender depictions. The metric proved successful, showing significant differences between the genders and predictable patterns with respect to movie genres.</p><p>Future work will include the use of further met- rics, with those describing emotions being the first candidates. We also intend to collect more movie and character level metadata to be used in anal- ysis. Finally, it is worth remembering that lan- guage provides only a partial description of de- </p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: Average Gender Ladenness for a few sample movies, marker size proportional to number of utterances. Filled markers: Female characters, Hollow markers: Male characters; PF: Pulp Fiction, KB: Kill Bill, BC: Breakfast Club, AH: Annie Hall.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2: Interactions between genres</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Figure 3: Interaction of movie genre with character gender</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>Figure 4 :</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Figure 4: Interaction of screenplay writer's gender with genre</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" validated="false"><head>Table 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Movie Dataset statistics 

Utterance 
Avg. GL 
Flowers for the Diva. 
0.77 
Yeah, what a woman. 
0.47 
Got the house to yourselves? 
-0.01 
What about the crew? 
-0.51 
Yeah? You and what army? 
-0.85 

</table></figure>

			<note place="foot">J McGrath Cohoon and William Aspray. 2006. Women and information technology: Research on underrepresentation, volume 1. The MIT Press.</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7">Acknowledgements</head><p>The authors gratefully acknowledge support from NSF, Geena Davis Institute on Gender in Media and Google.org.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Movie-Dic: a movie dialogue corpus for research and development</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Rafael E Banchs</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 50th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics: Short Papers</title>
		<meeting>the 50th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics: Short Papers</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="203" to="207" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Association for Computational Linguistics</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Mean girls? the influence of gender portrayals in teen movies on emerging adults&apos; gender-based attitudes and beliefs</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Elizabeth</forename><surname>Behm</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">-Morawitz</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dana</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Mastro</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journalism &amp; Mass Communication Quarterly</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">85</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="131" to="146" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">America on film: Representing race, class, gender, and sexuality at the movies</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Harry</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sean</forename><surname>Benshoff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Griffin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<publisher>John Wiley &amp; Sons</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Women and men in film gender inequality among writers in a culture industry</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Denise</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">William T</forename><surname>Bielby</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Bielby</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Gender &amp; Society</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="248" to="270" />
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>James</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Allan</forename><surname>Clark</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Paivio</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Extensions of the Paivio, Yuille, and Madigan (1968) norms. Behavior Research Methods, Instruments, &amp; Computers</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">36</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="371" to="383" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Internet movie database</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Imdb</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015-06" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Online; accessed</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Imdbpy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015-06" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Internet movie script database</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Imsdb</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015-06" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Online; accessed 10</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Double jeopardy in hollywood: Age and gender in the careers of film actors</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Anne</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Lincoln</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Patrick Allen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Sociological Forum</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="611" to="631" />
			<date type="published" when="1926" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Distributional semantic models for affective text analysis. Audio, Speech, and Language Processing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nikolaos</forename><surname>Malandrakis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alexandros</forename><surname>Potamianos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Elias</forename><surname>Iosif</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Shrikanth</forename><surname>Narayanan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE Transactions on</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">21</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2379" to="2392" />
			<date type="published" when="2013-11" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">NamSor gender API</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015-06" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>NamSor Applied Onomastics</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">A new ANEW: Evaluation of a word list for sentiment analysis in microblogs</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Finnårupfinn˚finnårup</forename><surname>Nielsen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:1103.2903</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
<note type="report_type">arXiv preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Throwing your hat out of the ring: Negative recruitment and the gender imbalance in state legislative candidacy</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Niven</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Politics &amp; Gender</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">04</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="473" to="489" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Concreteness, imagery, and meaningfulness values for 925 nouns</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Allan</forename><surname>Paivio</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Stephen A</forename><surname>John C Yuille</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Madigan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of experimental psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">76</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1p2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1968" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The gender imbalance in academic medicine: a study of female authorship in the united kingdom</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Reena</forename><surname>Sidhu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Praveen</forename><surname>Rajashekhar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Joanne</forename><surname>Victoria L Lavin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">James</forename><surname>Parry</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Anita</forename><surname>Attwood</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David S</forename><surname>Holdcroft</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Sanders</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of the Royal Society of Medicine</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">102</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="337" to="342" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Gender oppression in cinematic content? a look at females on-screen &amp; behindthe-camera in top-grossing 2007 films</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Stacy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Smith</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010-09-02" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Retrieved</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">String comparator metrics and enhanced decision rules in the fellegi-sunter model of record linkage</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>William</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Winkler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1990" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
