<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T10:50+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Semantic Annotation for Microblog Topics Using Wikipedia Temporal Information</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
				<availability status="unknown"><p>Copyright Association for Computational Linguistics</p>
				</availability>
				<date type="published" when="2015-09">September 2015. 2015</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tuan</forename><surname>Tran</surname></persName>
							<email>ttran@L3S.de</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nam</forename><forename type="middle">Khanh</forename><surname>Tran</surname></persName>
							<email>ntran@L3S.de</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Robert</forename><surname>Jäschke</surname></persName>
							<email>jaeschke@L3S.de</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory">L3S Research Center Hannover</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="laboratory">L3S Research Center Hannover</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="laboratory">Asmelash Teka Hadgu L3S Research Center Hannover</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff3">
								<orgName type="laboratory">L3S Research Center Hannover</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Semantic Annotation for Microblog Topics Using Wikipedia Temporal Information</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2015 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</title>
						<meeting>the 2015 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing <address><addrLine>Lisbon, Portugal</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="17" to="21"/>
							<date type="published" when="2015-09">September 2015. 2015</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Trending topics in microblogs such as Twitter are valuable resources to understand social aspects of real-world events. To enable deep analyses of such trends, semantic annotation is an effective approach; yet the problem of annotating microblog trending topics is largely unexplored by the research community. In this work, we tackle the problem of mapping trending Twitter topics to entities from Wikipedia. We propose a novel model that complements traditional text-based approaches by rewarding entities that exhibit a high temporal correlation with topics during their burst time period. By exploiting temporal information from the Wikipedia edit history and page view logs, we have improved the annotation performance by 17-28%, as compared to the competitive baselines.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>With the proliferation of microblogging and its wide influence on how information is shared and digested, the studying of microblog sites has gained interest in recent NLP research. Several ap- proaches have been proposed to enable a deep un- derstanding of information on Twitter. An emerg- ing approach is to use semantic annotation tech- niques, for instance by mapping Twitter informa- tion snippets to canonical entities in a knowledge base or to <ref type="bibr">Wikipedia (Meij et al., 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Guo et al., 2013)</ref>, or by revisiting NLP tasks in the Twitter do- main ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">Owoputi et al., 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Ritter et al., 2011</ref>). Much of the existing work focuses on annotating a single Twitter message (tweet). However, infor- mation in Twitter is rarely digested in isolation, but rather in a collective manner, with the adoption of special mechanisms such as hashtags. When put together, the unprecedentedly massive adoption of Hard to believe anyone can do worse than Russia in #Sochi. Brazil seems to be trying pre;y hard though! spor=ngnews.com… a hashtag within a short time period can lead to bursts and often reflect trending social attention. Understanding the meaning of trending hashtags offers a valuable opportunity for various applica- tions and studies, such as viral marketing, social behavior analysis, recommendation, etc. Unfor- tunately, the task of hashtag annotation has been largely unexplored so far.</p><p>In this paper, we study the problem of annotat- ing trending hashtags on Twitter by entities de- rived from Wikipedia. Instead of establishing a static semantic connection between hashtags and entities, we are interested in dynamically linking the hashtags to entities that are closest to the un- derlying topics during burst time periods of the hashtags. For instance, while '#sochi' refers to a city in Russia, during February 2014, the hash- tag was used to report the 2014 Winter Olympics (cf. <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref>). Hence, it should be linked more to Wikipedia pages related to the event than to the location.</p><p>Compared to traditional domains of text (e.g., news articles), annotating hashtags poses addi- tional challenges. Hashtags' surface forms are very ad-hoc, as they are chosen not in favor of the text quality, but by the dynamics in attention of the large crowd. In addition, the evolution of the semantics of hashtags (e.g., in the case of '#sochi') makes them more ambiguous. Further- more, a hashtag can encode multiple topics at once. For example, in March 2014, '#oscar' refers to the 86th Academy Awards, but at the same time also to the Trial of Oscar Pistorius. Sometimes, it is difficult even for humans to understand a trending hashtag without knowledge about what was hap- pening with the related entities in the real world.</p><p>In this work, we propose a novel solu- tion to these challenges by leveraging temporal knowledge about entity dynamics derived from Wikipedia. We hypothesize that a trending hashtag is associated with an increase in public attention to certain entities, and this can also be observed on Wikipedia. As in <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref>, we can identify 2014 Winter Olympics as a prominent entity for '#sochi' during February 2014, by observing the change of user attention to the entity, for instance via the page view statistics of Wikipedia articles. We exploit both Wikipedia edits and page views for annota- tion. We also propose a novel learning method, inspired by the information spreading nature of so- cial media such as Twitter, to suggest the optimal annotations without the need for human labeling. In summary:</p><p>• We are the first to combine the Wikipedia edit history and page view statistics to overcome the temporal ambiguity of Twitter hashtags.</p><p>• We propose a novel and efficient learning al- gorithm based on influence maximization to automatically annotate hashtags. The idea is generalizable to other social media sites that have a similar information spreading nature.</p><p>• We conduct thorough experiments on a real- world dataset and show that our system can outperform competitive baselines by 17-28%.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Related Work</head><p>Entity Linking in Microblogs The task of se- mantic annotation in microblogs has been recently tackled by different methods, which can be divided into two classes, i.e., content-based and graph- based methods. While the content-based methods ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Meij et al., 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Guo et al., 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Fang and Chang, 2014</ref>) consider tweets independently, the graph-based methods <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Cassidy et al., 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Liu et al., 2013</ref>) use all related tweets (e.g., posted by a user) together. However, most of them focus on entity mentions in tweets. In contrast, we take into account hashtags which reflect the topics dis- cussed in tweets, and leverage external resources from Wikipedia (in particular, the edit history and page view logs) for semantic annotation.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Analysis of Twitter Hashtags</head><p>In an attempt to understand the user interest dynamics on Twitter, a rich body of work analyzes the temporal pat- terns of popular hashtags ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Lehmann et al., 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Naaman et al., 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b27">Tsur and Rappoport, 2012)</ref>. Few works have paid attention to the semantics of hashtags, i.e., to the underlying topics conveyed in the corresponding tweets. Recently, <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Bansal et al. (2015)</ref> attempt to segment a hashtag and link each of its tokens to a Wikipedia page. However, the authors only aim to retrieve entities directly mentioned within a hashtag, which are very few in practice. The external information derived from the tweets is largely ignored. In contrast, we ex- ploit both context information from the microblog and Wikipedia resources.</p><p>Event Mining Using Wikipedia Recently some works exploit Wikipedia for detecting and ana- lyzing events on Twitter ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">Osborne et al., 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Tolomei et al., 2013;</ref>). However, most of the existing studies focus on the statistical signals of Wikipedia (such as the edit or page view volumes). We are the first to combine the content of the Wikipedia edit history and the magnitude of page views to handle trending topics on Twitter.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Framework</head><p>Preliminaries We refer to an entity (denoted by e) as any object described by a Wikipedia ar- ticle (ignoring disambiguation, lists, and redirect pages). The number of times an entity's article has been requested is called the entity view count. The text content of the article is denoted by C(e). In this work, we choose to study hashtags at the daily level, i.e., from the timestamps of tweets we only consider their creation day. A hashtag is called trending at a time point (a day) if the number of tweets where it appears is significantly higher than that on other days. There are many ways to de- tect such trendings. ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Lappas et al., 2009;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Lehmann et al., 2012)</ref>. Each trending hashtag has one or multiple burst time periods, surrounding the trend-ing day, where the users' interest in the underly- ing topic remains stronger than in other periods.</p><p>We denote with T (h) (or T for short) one hashtag burst time period, and with D T (h) the set of tweets containing the hashtag h created during T .</p><p>Task Definition Given a trending hashtag h and the burst time period T of h, identify the top-k most prominent entities to describe h during T . It is worth noting that not all trending hashtags are mapable to Wikipedia entities, as the coverage of topics in Wikipedia is much lower than on Twit- ter. This is also the limitation of systems relying on Wikipedia such as entity disambiguation, which can only disambiguate popular entities and not the ones in the long tail. In this study, we focus on the precision and the popular trending hashtags, and leave the improvement of recall to future work.</p><p>Overview We approach the task in three steps. The first step is to identify all entity candidates by checking surface forms of the constituent tweets of the hashtag. In the second step, we compute different similarities between each candidate and the hashtag, based on different types of contexts, which are derived from either side (Wikipedia or Twitter). Finally, we learn a unified ranking func- tion for each (hashtag, entity) pair and choose the top-k entities with the highest scores. The ranking function is learned through an unsupervised model and needs no human-defined labels.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Entity Linking</head><p>The most obvious resource to identify candidate entities for a hashtag is via its tweets. We follow common approaches that use a lexicon to match each textual phrase in a tweet to a potential en- tity set ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">Shen et al., 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Fang and Chang, 2014)</ref>. Our lexicon is constructed from Wikipedia page ti- tles, hyperlink anchors, redirects, and disambigua- tion pages, which are mapped to the correspond- ing entities. As for the tweet phrases, we extract all n-grams (n ≤ 5) from the input tweets within T . We apply the longest-match heuristic <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">(Meij et al., 2012</ref>): We start with the longest n-grams and stop as soon as the entity set is found, otherwise we continue with the smaller constituent n-grams.</p><p>Candidate Set Expansion While the lexicon- based linking works well for single tweets, ap- plying it on the hashtag level has subtle implica- tions. Processing a huge amount of text, especially during a hashtag burst time period, incurs expen- sive computational costs. Therefore, to guarantee a good recall in this step while still maintaining fea- sible computation, we apply entity linking only on a random sample of the complete tweet set. Then, for each candidate entity e, we include all entities whose Wikipedia article is linked with the article of e by an outgoing or incoming link.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Measuring Entity-Hashtag Similarities</head><p>To rank the entity by prominence, we measure the similarity between each candidate entity and the hashtag. We study three types of similarities:</p><p>Mention Similarity This measure relies on the explicit mentions of entities in tweets. It assumes that entities directly linked from more prominent anchors are more relevant to the hashtag. It is es- timated using both statistics from Wikipedia and tweet phrases, and turns out to be surprisingly ef- fective in practice <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Fang and Chang, 2014</ref>).</p><p>Context Similarity For entities that are not di- rectly linked to mentions (the mention similar- ity is zero) we exploit external resources instead. Their prominence is perceived by users via exter- nal sources, such as web pages linked from tweets, or entity home pages or Wikipedia pages. By ex- ploiting the content of entities from these external sources, we can complement the explicit similarity metrics based on mentions.</p><p>Temporal Similarity The two measures above rely on the textual representation and are degraded by the linguistic difference between the two plat- forms. To overcome this drawback, we incorpo- rate the temporal dynamics of hashtags and enti- ties, which serve as a proxy to the change of user interests towards the underlying topics <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Ciglan and Nørvåg, 2010)</ref>. We employ the correlation be- tween the times series of hashtag adoption and the entity view as the third similarity measure.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3">Ranking Entity Prominence</head><p>While each similarity measure captures one evi- dence of the entity prominence, we need to unify all scores to obtain a global ranking function. In this work, we propose to combine the individual similarities using a linear function:</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">f (e, h) = αf m (e, h)+βf c (e, h)+γf t (e, h) (1)</formula><p>where α, β, γ are model weights and f m , f c , f t are the similarity measures based on mentions, con- text, and temporal information, respectively, be-tween the entity e and the hashtag h. We further constrain that α + β + γ = 1, so that the ranking scores of entities are normalized between 0 and 1, and that our learning algorithm is more tractable. The algorithm, which automatically learns the pa- rameters without the need of human-labeled data, is explained in detail in Section 5.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Similarity Measures</head><p>We now discuss in detail how the similarity mea- sures between hashtags and entities are computed.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">Link-based Mention Similarity</head><p>The similarity of an entity with one individual mention in a tweet can be interpreted as the prob- abilistic prior in mapping the mention to the en- tity via the lexicon. One common way to estimate the entity prior exploits the anchor statistics from Wikipedia links, and has been proven to work well in different domains of text. We follow this ap- proach and define LP (e|m) = |lm(e)| m |l m (e)| as the link prior of the entity e given a mention m, where l m (e) is the set of links with anchor m that point to e. The mention similarity f m is measured as the aggregation of link priors of the entity e over all mentions in all tweets with the hashtag h:</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">f m (e, h) = m (LP (e|m) · q(m))<label>(2)</label></formula><p>where q(m) is the frequency of the mention m over all mentions of e in all tweets of h.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1.1">Context Similarity</head><p>To compute f c , we first construct the contexts for hashtags and entities. The context of a hashtag is built by extracting all words from its tweets. We tokenize and parse the tweets' part-of-speech tags ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">Owoputi et al., 2013)</ref>, and remove words of Twitter-specific tags (e.g., @-mentions, URLs, emoticons, etc.). Hashtags are normalized using the word breaking method by <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">Wang et al. (2011)</ref>. The textual context of an entity is extracted from its Wikipedia article. One subtle aspect is that the articles are not created at once, but are incremen- tally updated over time in accordance with chang- ing information about entities. Texts added in the same time period of a trending hashtag contribute more to the context similarity between the entity and the hashtag. Based on this observation, we use the Wikipedia revision history -an archive of all revisions of Wikipedia articles -to calculate the entity context. We collect the revisions of articles during the time period T , plus one day to acknowl- edge possible time lags. We compute the differ- ence between two consecutive revisions, and ex- tract only the added text snippets. These snippets are accumulated to form the temporal context of an entity e during T , denoted by C T (e). The dis- tribution of a word w for the entity e is estimated by a mixture between the probability of generating w from the temporal context and from the general context C(e) of the entity:</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">ˆ P (w|e) = λ ˆ P (w|M C T (e) )+(1−λ) ˆ P (w|M C(e) )</formula><p>where M C T (e) and M C(e) are the language mod- els of e based on C T (e) and C(e), respec- tively. The probabilityˆPprobabilityˆ probabilityˆP (w|M C(e) ) can be re- garded as corresponding to the background model, whilê P (w|M C T (e) ) corresponds to the fore- ground model in traditional language modeling settings. Here we use a simple maximum like- lihood estimation to estimate these probabilities: </p><formula xml:id="formula_3">ˆ P (w|M C(e) ) = tfw,c |C(e)| andˆPandˆ andˆP (w|M C T (e) ) = tfw,c T |C T (e)| ,</formula><formula xml:id="formula_4">KL(e h) = w ˆ P (w|e) · ˆ P (w|e) ˆ P (w|h) f c (e, h) = e −KL(e h)<label>(3)</label></formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1.2">Temporal Similarity</head><p>The third similarity, f t , is computed using tem- poral signals from both sources -Twitter and Wikipedia. For the hashtags, we build the time series based on the volume of tweets adopt- ing the hashtag h on each day in T : T S h = [n 1 , n 2 , . . . , n |T | ]. Similarly for the entities, we build the time series of view counts for the entity e in T : </p><formula xml:id="formula_5">T S e = [v 1 , v 2 , .</formula><formula xml:id="formula_6">f t (e, h) = min q,δ T S h − δd q (T S e ) T S h<label>(4)</label></formula><p>where d q (T S e ) is the time series derived from T S e by shifting q time units, and ·· is the L 2 norm. It has been proven that Equation 4 has a closed-form solution for δ given fixed q, thus we can design an efficient gradient-based optimization algorithm to compute f t (Yang and Leskovec, 2011).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Entity Prominence Ranking</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.1">Ranking Framework</head><p>To unify the individual similarities into one global metric (Equation 1), we need a guiding premise of what manifest the prominence of an entity to a hashtag. Such a premise can be instructed through manual assessment ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Meij et al., 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Guo et al., 2013</ref>), but it requires human-labeled data and is biased from evaluator to evaluator. Other heuris- tics assume that entities close to the main topic of a text are also coherent to each other (Ratinov et al., 2011; <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Liu et al., 2013</ref>). Based on this, state-of- the-art methods in traditional disambiguation es- timate entity prominence by optimizing the over- all coherence of the entities' semantic relatedness. However, this coherence does not hold for topics in hashtags: Entities reported in a big topic such as the Olympics vary greatly with different sub- events. They are not always coherent to each other, as they are largely dependent on the users' diverse attention to each sub-event. This heterogeneity of hashtags calls for a different premise, abandoning the idea of coherence.</p><p>Influence Maximization (IM) We propose a new approach to find entities for a hashtag. We use an observed behavioral pattern in creating Wikipedia pages for guiding our approach to en- tity prominence: Wikipedia articles of entities that are prominent for a topic are quickly created or updated, 1 and subsequently enriched with links to related entities. This linking process signals the dynamics of editor attention and exposure to the event ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Keegan et al., 2011</ref>). We argue that the pro- cess does not, or to a much lesser degree, happen to more marginal entities or to very general entities. As illustrated in <ref type="figure">Figure 2</ref>, the entities closer to the 2014 Olympics get more updates in the revisions of their Wikipedia articles, with subsequent links pointing to articles of more distant entities. The direction of the links influences the shifting atten- tion of users (Keegan et al., 2011) as they follow the structure of articles in Wikipedia. We assume that, similar to Wikipedia, the entity prominence also influences how users are exposed and spread the hashtag on Twitter. In particular, the initial spreading of a trending hashtag involves more entities in the focus of the topic. Subsequent exposure and spreading of the hashtag then include other related entities (e.g., discussing background or providing context), driven by interests in differ- ent parts of the topic. Based on this assumption, we propose to gauge the entity prominence as its potential in maximizing the information spreading within all entities present in the tweets of the hash- tag. In other words, the problem of ranking the most prominent entities becomes identifying the set of entities that lead to the largest number of en- tities in the candidate set. This problem is known in social network research as influence maximiza- tion ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Kempe et al., 2003</ref>).</p><p>Iterative Influence-Prominence Learning (IPL) IM itself is an NP-hard problem ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Kempe et al., 2003)</ref>. Therefore, we propose an approximation framework, which can jointly learn the influence scores of the entity and the entity prominence together. The framework (called IPL) contains several iterations, each consisting of two steps: (1) Pick up a model and use it to compute the entity influence score. (2) Based on the influence scores, update the entity prominence. In the sequel we de- tail our learning framework.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.2">Entity Graph</head><p>Influence Graph To compute the entity influ- ence scores, we first construct the entity influence graph as follows. For each hashtag h, we construct a directed graph G h = (E h , V h ), where the nodes E h ⊆ E consist of all candidate entities (cf. Sec- tion 3.1), and an edge (e i , e j ) ∈ V h indicates that there is a link from e j 's Wikipedia article to e i 's. Note that edges of the influence graph are inversed in direction to links in Wikipedia, as such a link gives an "influence endorsement" from the desti- nation entity to the source entity.</p><p>Entity Relatedness In this work, we assume that an entity endorses more of its influence score to highly related entities than to lower related ones. We use a popular entity relatedness measure sug- gested by <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Milne and Witten (2008)</ref>:</p><formula xml:id="formula_7">M W (e 1 , e 2 ) = 1 − log(max(|I 1 |,|I 2 |)−log(|I 1 ∩I 2 |))) log(|E|)−log(min(|I 1 |,|I 2 |))</formula><p>where I 1 and I 2 are sets of entities having links to e 1 and e 2 , respectively, and E is the set of all enti- ties in Wikipedia. The influence transition from e i to e j is defined as the normalized value:</p><formula xml:id="formula_8">b i,j = M W (e i , e j ) (e i ,e k )∈V M W (e i , e k )<label>(5)</label></formula><p>Influence Score Let r h be the influence score vector of entities in G h . We can estimate r h effi- ciently using random walk models, similarly to the Algorithm 1: Entity Influence-Prominence Learning Input : h, T, DT (h), B, k, learning rate µ, threshold Output: ω, top-k most prominent entities.</p><p>Initialize: ω := ω (0) Calculate fm, fc, ft, fω := f ω (0) using Eqs. 1, 2, 3, 4 while true dôdô fω := normalize fω Set s h := ˆ fω, calculate r h using Eq. 6 Sort r h , get the top-k entities E(h, k)</p><formula xml:id="formula_9">if e∈E(h,k) L(f (e, h), r(e, h)) &lt; then Stop end ω := ω − µ e∈E(h,k) L(f (e, h), r(e, h)) end return ω, E(h, k)</formula><p>baseline method suggested by <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Liu et al. (2014)</ref>:</p><formula xml:id="formula_10">r h := τ Br h + (1 − τ )s h (6)</formula><p>where B is the influence transition matrix, s h are the initial influence scores that are based on the en- tity prominence model (Step 1 of IPL), and τ is the damping factor.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.3">Learning Algorithm</head><p>Now we detail the IPL algorithm. The objective is to learn the model ω = (α, β, γ) of the global function (Equation 1). The general idea is that we find an optimal ω such that the average error with respect to the top influencing entities is minimized</p><formula xml:id="formula_11">ω = arg min E(h,k) L(f (e, h), r(e, h))</formula><p>where r(e, h) is the influence score of e and h, E(h, k) is the set of top-k entities with highest r(e, h), and L is the squared error loss function,</p><formula xml:id="formula_12">L(x, y) = (x−y) 2 2 .</formula><p>The main steps are depicted in Algorithm 1. We start with an initial guess for ω, and compute the similarities for the candidate entities. Here f m , f c , f t , and f ω represent the similarity score vectors. We use matrix multiplication to calculate the similari- ties efficiently. In each iteration, we first normalize f ω such that the entity scores sum up to 1. A ran- dom walk is performed to calculate the influence score r h . Then we update ω using a batch gradient descent method on the top-k influencer entities. To derive the gradient of the loss function L, we first remark that our random walk Equation 6 is similar to context-sensitive PageRank <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Haveliwala, 2002)</ref>. Using the linearity property ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Fogaras et al., 2005</ref>), we can express r(e, h) as the linear function of in- fluence scores obtained by initializing with the in- dividual similarities f m , f c , and f t instead of f ω . The derivative thus can be written as:</p><formula xml:id="formula_13">L(f (e, h), r(e, h)) = α(r m (e, h) − f m (e, h))+ β(r c (e, h) − f c (e, h)) + γ(r t (e, h) − f t (e, h))</formula><p>where r m (e, h), r c (e, h), r t (e, h) are the compo- nents of the three vector solutions of Equation 6, each having s h replaced by f m , f c , f t respectively.</p><p>Since both B andˆfandˆ andˆf ω are normalized such that their column sums are equal to 1, Equation 6 is convergent <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Haveliwala, 2002</ref>). Also, as discussed above, r h is a linear combination of factors that are independent of ω, hence L is a convex func- tion, and the batch gradient descent is also guaran- teed to converge. In practice, we can utilize sev- eral indexing techniques to significantly speed up the similarity and influence scores calculation.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Experiments and Results</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.1">Setup</head><p>Dataset There is no standard benchmark for our problem, since available datasets on microblog an- notation (such as the Microposts challenge ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Basave et al., 2014)</ref>) do not have global statistics, so we cannot identify the trending hashtags. Therefore, we created our own dataset. We used the Twitter API to collect from the public stream a sample of 500, 551, 041 tweets from January to April 2014. We removed hashtags that were adopted by less than 500 users, having no letters, or having char- acters repeated more than 4 times (e.g., '#oooom- mgg'). We identified trending hashtags by comput- ing the daily time series of hashtag tweet counts, and removing those of which the time series' vari- ance score is less than 900. To identify the hashtag burst time period T , we compute the outlier frac- tion ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Lehmann et al., 2012</ref>) for each hashtag h and day t: p t (h) = |nt−n b | max (n b ,n min ) , where n t is the num- ber of tweets containing h, n b is the median value of n t over all points in a 2-month time window cen- tered on t, and n min = 10 is the threshold to filter low activity hashtags. The hashtag is skipped if its highest outlier fraction score is less than 15. Fi- nally, we define the burst time period of a trending hashtag as the time window of size w, centered at day t 0 with the highest p t 0 (h).</p><p>For the Wikipedia datasets we process the dump from 3rd May 2014, so as to cover all events in the Twitter dataset. We have developed <ref type="bibr">Hedera (Tran and Nguyen, 2014</ref>), a scalable tool for process- ing the Wikipedia revision history dataset based on Map-Reduce paradigm. In addition, we download the Wikipedia page view dataset that stores how many times a Wikipedia article was requested on an hourly level. We process the dataset for the four months of our study and use Hedera to accumulate all view counts of redirects to the actual articles.</p><p>Sampling From the trending hashtags, we sam- ple 30 distinct hashtags for evaluation. Since our study focuses on trending hashtags that are ma- pable to entities in Wikipedia, the sampling must cover a sufficient number of "popular" topics that are seen in Wikipedia, and at the same time cover rare topics in the long tail. To do this, we apply several heuristics in the sampling. First, we only consider hashtags where the lexicon-based link- ing (Section 3.1) results in at least 20 different entities. Second, we randomly choose hashtags to cover different types of topics (long-running events, breaking events, endogenous hashtags). In- stead of inspecting all hashtags in our corpus, we follow <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Lehmann et al. (2012)</ref> and calculate the fraction of tweets published before, during and af- ter the peak. The hashtags are then clustered in this 3-dimensional vector space. Each cluster sug- gests a group of hashtags with a distinct seman- tics ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Lehmann et al., 2012</ref>). We then pick up hash- tags randomly from each cluster, resulting in 200 hashtags in total. From this rough sample, three inspectors carefully checked the tweets and chose 30 hashtags where the meanings and hashtag types were certain to the knowledge of the inspectors.</p><p>Parameter Settings We initialize the similarity weights to 1 3 , the damping factor to τ = 0.85, and the weight for the language model to λ = 0.9. The learning rate µ is empirically fixed to µ = 0.003.  Baseline We compare IPL with other entity an- notation methods. Our first group of baselines in- cludes entity linking systems in domains of gen- eral text, Wikiminer <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(Milne and Witten, 2008)</ref>, and short text, Tagme <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Ferragina and Scaiella, 2012)</ref>. For each method, we use the default param- eter settings, apply them for the individual tweets, and take the average of the annotation confidence scores as the prominence ranking function. The second group of baselines includes systems specif- ically designed for microblogs. For the content- based methods, we compare against <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Meij et al. (2012)</ref>, which uses a supervised method to rank en- tities with respect to tweets. We train the model us- ing the same training data as in the original paper.</p><p>For the graph-based method, we compare against KAURI ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">Shen et al., 2013</ref>), a method which uses user interest propagation to optimize the entity linking scores. To tune the parameters, we pick up four hashtags from different clusters, randomly sample 50 tweets for each, and manually annotate the tweets. For all baselines, we obtained the im- plementation from the authors. The exception is Meij method, where we implemented ourselves, but we clarified with the authors via emails on sev- eral settings. In addition, we also compare three variants of our method, using only local functions for entity ranking (referred to as M , C, and T for mention, context, and time, respectively).</p><p>Evaluation In total, there are 6, 965 entity- hashtag pairs returned by all systems. We employ five volunteers to evaluate the pairs in the range from 0 to 2, where 0 means the entity is noisy or obviously unrelated, 2 means the entity is strongly tied to the topic of the hashtag, and 1 means that although the entity and hashtag might share some common contexts, they are not involved in a di- rect relationship (for instance, the entity is a too general concept such as Ice hockey, as in the case illustrated in <ref type="figure">Figure 2</ref>). The annotators were ad- vised to use search engines, the Twitter search box or Wikipedia archives whenever applicable to get more background on the stories. Inter-annotator agreement under Fleiss score is 0.625. <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">Table 2</ref> shows the performance comparison of the methods using the standard metrics for a ranking system (precision at 5 and 15 and MAP at 15). In general, all baselines perform worse than reported in the literature, confirming the higher complexity of the hashtag annotation task as compared to tra- ditional tasks. Interestingly enough, using our lo- cal similarities already produces better results than Tagme and Wikiminer. The local model f m signif- icantly outperforms both the baselines in all met- rics. Combining the similarities improves the per- formance even more significantly. <ref type="bibr">2</ref> Compared to the baselines, IPL improves the performance by 17-28%. The time similarity achieves the high- est result compared to other content-based mention and context similarities. This supports our assump- tion that lexical matching is not always the best strategy to link entities in tweets. The time series- based metric incurs lower cost than others, yet it produces a considerably good performance. Con- text similarity based on Wikipedia edits does not yield much improvement. This can be explained in two ways. First, information in Wikipedia is largely biased to popular entities, it fails to cap- ture many entities in the long tail. Second, lan- guage models are dependent on direct word rep- resentations, which are different between Twitter and Wikipedia. This is another advantage of non- content measures such as f t . For the second group of baselines (Kauri and Meij), we also observe the reduction in precision, especially for Kauri. This is because the method relies on the coherence of user interests within a group of tweets to be able to perform well, which does not hold in the context of hashtags. One as- tonishing result is that Meij performs better than IPL in terms of P@15. However, it performs worse in terms of MAP and P@5, suggesting that most of the correctly identified entities are ranked lower in the list. This is reasonable, as Meij attempts to optimize (with human supervision effort) the se- mantic agreement between entities and informa- tion found in the tweets, instead of ranking their prominence as in our work. To investigate this case further, we re-examined the hashtags and di- vided them by their semantics, as to whether the hashtags are spurious trends of memes inside so- cial media (endogenous, e.g., "#stopasian2014"), or whether they reflect external events (exogenous, e.g., "#mh370"). The performance of the methods in terms of MAP scores is shown in <ref type="figure">Figure 3</ref>. It can be clearly seen that entity linking methods perform well in the endogenous group, but then deteriorate in the exogenous group. The explanation is that for endogenous hashtags, the topical consonance between tweets is very low, thus most of the as- sessments become just verifying general concepts (such as locations) In this case, topical annotation is trumped by conceptual annotation. However, whenever the hashtag evolves into a meaningful topic, a deeper annotation method will produce a significant improvement, as seen in <ref type="figure">Figure 3</ref>. Finally, we study the impact of the burst time pe- riod on the annotation quality. For this, we expand the window size w (cf. Section 6.1) and examine how different methods perform. The result is de- picted in <ref type="figure">Figure 4</ref>. It is obvious that within the win- dow of 2 months (where the hashtag time series is constructed and a trending time is identified), our method is stable and always outperforms the base- lines by a large margin. Even when the trending hashtag has been saturated, hence introduced more noise, our method is still able to identify the promi- nent entities with high quality.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.2">Results and Discussion</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7">Conclusion and Future Work</head><p>In this work, we address the new problem of topically annotating a trending hashtag using Wikipedia entities, which has many important ap- plications in social media analysis. We study Wikipedia temporal resources and find that using efficient time series-based measures can comple- ment content-based methods well in the domain of Twitter. We propose use similarity measures to model both the local mention-based, as well as the global context-and time-based prominence of entities. We propose a novel strategy of topical annotation of texts using and influence maximiza- tion approach and design an efficient learning algo- rithm to automatically unify the similarities with- out the need of human involvement. The experi- ments show that our method outperforms signifi- cantly the established baselines.</p><p>As future work, we aim to improve the effi- ciency of our entire workflow, such that the anno- tation can become an end-to-end service. We also aim to improve the context similarity between en- tities and the topic, for example by using a deeper distributional semantics-based method, instead of language models as in our current work. In addi- tion, we plan to extend the annotation framework to other types of trending topics, by including the type of out-of-knowledge entities. Finally, we are investigating how to apply more advanced influ- ence maximization methods. We believe that in- fluence maximization has a great potential in NLP research, beyond the scope of annotation for mi- croblogging topics.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>#sochi</head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 1: Example of trending hashtag annotation. During the 2014 Winter Olympics, the hashtag '#sochi' had a different meaning.</figDesc><graphic url="image-1.png" coords="1,314.77,215.32,219.93,97.13" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>where tf w,c and tf w,c T are the term fre- quencies of w in the two text sources of C(e) and C T (e), respectively, and |C(e)| and |C T (e)| are the lengths of the two texts, respectively. We use the same estimation for tweets: ˆ P (w|h) = tf w,D(h) |D(h)| , where D(h) is the concatenated text of all tweets of h in T . We use and normalize the Kullback-Leibler divergence to compare the dis- tributions over all words appearing both in the Wikipedia contexts and the tweets:</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 3 :Figure 4 :</head><label>34</label><figDesc>Figure 3: Performance of the methods for different types of trending hashtags.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3" validated="false"><head>Table 2 : Experimental results on the sampled trending hashtags.</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table></table></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> Osborne et al. (2012) suggested a time lag of 3 hours.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="2"> All significance tests are done against both Tagme and Wikiminer, with a p-value &lt; 0.01.</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>This work was funded by the European Commis-sion in the FP7 project ForgetIT (600826) and the ERC advanced grant ALEXANDRIA (339233), and by the German Federal Ministry of Educa-tion and Research for the project "Gute Arbeit" (01UG1249C). We thank the reviewers for the fruitful discussion and Claudia Niederee from L3S for suggestions on improving Section 5.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Towards deep semantic analysis of hashtags</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Bansal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Bansal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Varma</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ECIR</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="453" to="464" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Making sense of microposts (#microposts2014) named entity extraction &amp; linking challenge</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Cano Basave</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Rizzo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Varga</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Rowe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Stankovic</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Dadzie</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">4th Workshop on Making Sense of Microposts</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Analysis and enhancement of wikification for microblogs with context expansion</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Cassidy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Ji</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L.-A</forename><surname>Ratinov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Zubiaga</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">COLING</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="441" to="456" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">WikiPop: personalized event detection system based on Wikipedia page view statistics</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Ciglan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Nørvåg</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">CIKM</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1931" to="1932" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Entity linking on microblogs with spatial and temporal signals</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Fang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M.-W</forename><surname>Chang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Trans. of the Assoc. for Comp. Linguistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="259" to="272" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Fast and accurate annotation of short texts with Wikipedia pages</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Ferragina</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">U</forename><surname>Scaiella</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE Softw</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">29</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="70" to="75" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Towards scaling fully personalized PageRank: Algorithms, lower bounds, and experiments</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Fogaras</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Rácz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Csalogány</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Sarlós</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Internet Mathematics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="333" to="358" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">To link or not to link? A study on end-to-end tweet entity linking</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Guo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M.-W</forename><surname>Chang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Kıcıman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">NAACL-HLT</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1020" to="1030" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Topic-sensitive PageRank</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Haveliwala</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">WWW</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="517" to="526" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Hot off the wiki: Dynamics, practices, and structures in wikipedia&apos;s coverage of the tohoku catastrophes</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Brian</forename><surname>Keegan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Darren</forename><surname>Gergle</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Noshir</forename><surname>Contractor</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">WikiSym</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="105" to="113" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Maximizing the spread of influence through a social network</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Kempe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Kleinberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Tardos</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">KDD</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="137" to="146" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">On burstiness-aware search for document sequences</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Lappas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Arai</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Platakis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Kotsakos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Gunopulos</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">KDD</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="477" to="486" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dynamical classes of collective attention in Twitter</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Lehmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Gonçalves</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Ramasco</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Cattuto</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">WWW</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="251" to="260" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Entity linking for tweets</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Wu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Zhou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Wei</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Lu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ACL</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1304" to="1311" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Influence maximization over largescale social networks: A bounded linear approach</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Q</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Xiang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Xiong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Tang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">X</forename><surname>Yu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">CIKM</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="171" to="180" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Adding semantics to microblog posts</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Meij</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Weerkamp</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>De Rijke</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">WSDM</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="563" to="572" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Learning to link with Wikipedia</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Milne</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Witten</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">CIKM</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="509" to="518" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Hip and trendy: Characterizing emerging trends on Twitter</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Naaman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Becker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Gravano</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">JASIST</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">62</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="902" to="918" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Bieber no more: First story detection using Twitter and Wikipedia</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Osborne</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Petrovic</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Mccreadie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Macdonald</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Ounis</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Workshop on Time-aware Information Access</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Improved part-of-speech tagging for online conversational text with word clusters</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Owoputi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>O&amp;apos;connor</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Dyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Gimpel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Schneider</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Smith</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">NAACL-HLT</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="380" to="390" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A word at a time: Computing word relatedness using temporal semantic analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Radinsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Agichtein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Gabrilovich</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Markovitch</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">WWW</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="337" to="346" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Local and Global Algorithms for Disambiguation to Wikipedia</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Ratinov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Roth</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Downey</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Anderson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ACL</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1375" to="1384" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Named entity recognition in tweets: an experimental study</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alan</forename><surname>Ritter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sam</forename><surname>Clark</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Oren</forename><surname>Etzioni</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">EMNLP</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1524" to="1534" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Linking named entities in tweets with knowledge base via user interest modeling</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Shen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Luo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">WSDM</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="68" to="76" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Twitter anticipates bursts of requests for Wikipedia articles</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Tolomei</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Orlando</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Ceccarelli</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Lucchese</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Workshop on Data-driven User Behavioral Modelling and Mining from Social Media</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="5" to="8" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Hedera: Scalable indexing, exploring entities in Wikipedia revision history</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Tran</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">Ngoc</forename><surname>Nguyen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ISWC</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="297" to="300" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Analysing the duration of trending topics in Twitter using Wikipedia</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Tran</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Georgescu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Zhu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Kanhabua</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Conf. on Web Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="251" to="252" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">What&apos;s in a hashtag?: Content based prediction of the spread of ideas in microblogging communities</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Tsur</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Rappoport</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">WSDM</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="643" to="652" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Web scale NLP: a case study on URL word breaking</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Thrasher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B.-J</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Hsu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">WWW</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="357" to="366" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Patterns of temporal variation in online media</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Leskovec</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">WSDM</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="177" to="186" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
