<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T12:18+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Intra-sentential Zero Anaphora Resolution using Subject Sharing Recognition</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
				<availability status="unknown"><p>Copyright Association for Computational Linguistics</p>
				</availability>
				<date type="published" when="2015-09">September 2015. 2015</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ryu</forename><surname>Iida</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">National Institute of Information and Communications Technology Kyoto</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>619-0289</postCode>
									<country key="JP">Japan</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kentaro</forename><surname>Torisawa</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">National Institute of Information and Communications Technology Kyoto</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>619-0289</postCode>
									<country key="JP">Japan</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chikara</forename><surname>Hashimoto</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">National Institute of Information and Communications Technology Kyoto</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>619-0289</postCode>
									<country key="JP">Japan</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jong-Hoon</forename><surname>Oh</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">National Institute of Information and Communications Technology Kyoto</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>619-0289</postCode>
									<country key="JP">Japan</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Julien</forename><surname>Kloetzer</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">National Institute of Information and Communications Technology Kyoto</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>619-0289</postCode>
									<country key="JP">Japan</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Intra-sentential Zero Anaphora Resolution using Subject Sharing Recognition</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2015 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</title>
						<meeting>the 2015 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing <address><addrLine>Lisbon, Portugal</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="17" to="21"/>
							<date type="published" when="2015-09">September 2015. 2015</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>In this work, we improve the performance of intra-sentential zero anaphora resolution in Japanese using a novel method of recognizing subject sharing relations. In Japanese, a large portion of intra-sentential zero anaphora can be regarded as subject sharing relations between predicates , that is, the subject of some predicate is also the unrealized subject of other predicates. We develop an accurate rec-ognizer of subject sharing relations for pairs of predicates in a single sentence, and then construct a subject shared predicate network, which is a set of predicates that are linked by the subject sharing relations recognized by our recognizer. We finally combine our zero anaphora resolution method exploiting the subject shared predicate network and a state-of-the-art ILP-based zero anaphora resolution method. Our combined method achieved a significant improvement over the the ILP-based method alone on intra-sentential zero anaphora resolution in Japanese. To the best of our knowledge, this is the first work to explicitly use an independent subject sharing recognizer in zero anaphora resolution.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>In 'pro-dropped' languages such as Japanese, Chi- nese and Italian, pronouns are often unrealized in text. For example, the subject of nomu (take) is omitted in example (1).</p><p>(1) Tom i -wa infuruenza-ni natta-node , Tom-TOP flu-IOBJ had-since punc (ϕ i -ga) kusuri-o non-da .</p><p>he i -SUBJ medicine-OBJ took period</p><p>Since Tom i had the flu, (he i ) took medicine.</p><p>Such unrealized pronouns are regarded as zero anaphors, which are indicated using ϕ in liter- ature, like ϕ i -ga in example (1). Zero anaphor refers to its antecedent somewhere. This phe- nomenon of the reference is called zero anaphora.</p><p>In Japanese, about 60% of subjects appear as zero anaphors in newspaper articles ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Iida et al., 2007b</ref>), and thus zero anaphora resolution is an essential task for developing highly accurate machine trans- lation and information extraction systems.</p><p>In this paper, we propose a novel method of re- solving intra-sentential zero anaphora, in which a subject zero anaphor refers to its antecedent in- side a single sentence. This work does not ad- dress inter-sentential zero anaphora, in which a zero anaphor in a sentence refers to its antecedent in another sentence. The novelty of our method is in the use of subject sharing relations, which are relations between two predicates that share a subject by (zero) anaphora or coreference. For ex- ample, in example (2), there are two subject shar- ing relations for predicate pairs, advance-plan and plan-dispatch, as illustrated in <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref>.  The government i plans that (it i ) will dispatch 50 people to the disaster site and (it i ) is advancing its preparations.</p><p>The most straightforward method to recognize subject sharing relations is to apply a (zero) anaphora resolution system to a sentence and de- tect such relations by recognizing (zero) anaphora, like the relations represented by seifu i and two zero anaphors ϕ i in <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref>. However, to our surprise, we found that a simple supervised clas- sifier that exploits the local contexts surrounding </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>-%).#!/01+!! "6'&amp;62'2&lt;$(+!</head><p>$./! ,-./! 4 #! "5&amp;'$!2(261$'+! !%!%2"3%!"2;%2(0&amp;+! 4/*")!%3%!";3,62*01+! *"#*/*%!#("692(+! 4#!/#54#! ";3,2,*&amp;'!,3*&amp;+! 3=$./! ,-./&amp;0*!! ,12'3(#! <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref>: Example of subject shared predicate net- work predicates achieved a higher accuracy than that of the straightforward method. This suggests that just propagating the realized subject of a predi- cate to the subject zero anaphor of other predicates through recognized subject sharing relations (e.g., propagating subject government of advance to the subject positions of plan and dispatch in <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref>) might lead to a higher accuracy in zero anaphora resolution than the existing zero anaphora reso- lution methods. In addition, a large portion of zero anaphora can be regarded as subject shar- ing relations (e.g., 39% of the intra-sentential zero anaphora in the NAIST Text Corpus ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Iida et al., 2007b</ref>) are such cases). Hence, just by combining our subject zero anaphora method with an existing general anaphora resolution method that covers other types of anaphora, significant improvement of accuracy over all types of anaphora might be achieved. This paper empirically shows that this is actually the case through a series of experiments in which we combine our method with an existing ILP-based zero anaphora resolution method (Iida and Poesio, 2011).</p><p>Our subject zero anaphora resolution method constructs a subject shared predicate network (SSPN), which is a network of predicates in which subject sharing predicates are linked, from the results of our accurate pairwise subject sharing recognizer, which detects the predicate pairs that share a subject. Zero anaphora resolution is done by propagating the realized subject of a predi- cate to the subject zero anaphor of other pred- icates in the SSPN. An important point here is that SSPN was introduced to solve the issue re- lated to our pairwise subject sharing recognizer. Our recognizer is applied only to the restricted pairs of predicates in a sentence, such as predi- cates that have a direct dependency relation be- tween them. This is because our current recog- nizer cannot achieve high accuracy for any pair of predicates. In <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref>, for instance, our rec- ognizer can detect a subject sharing relation be- tween advance and plan and another between plan and dispatch, but it cannot detect one between ad- vance and dispatch. However, in the SSPN, the undetected relations can be derived by connecting the two detected ones, and in the zero anaphora resolution subject government of advance can be successfully propagated to the subject position of dispatch.</p><p>The rest of our paper is organized as follows. In Section 2, we briefly overview previous work on zero anaphora resolution. In Section 3, we overview the procedure of our zero anaphora reso- lution method. We explain the three types of sub- ject sharing relations on which we focus and pro- pose a method of pairwise subject sharing recog- nition for the three types in Section 4. We eval- uate how effectively our method recognizes sub- ject sharing relations for these types in Section 5. After that, we investigate the impact of explic- itly introducing SSPNs in Section 6 and com- pare our zero anaphora resolution method with a state-of-the-art ILP-based method on the task of intra-sentential subject zero anaphora resolution in Section 7. Finally, in Section 8 we summarize this work and discuss future directions.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Related work</head><p>Traditional approaches to zero anaphora reso- lution are based on manually created heuristic rules <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">(Kameyama, 1986;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b26">Walker et al., 1994;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b18">Okumura and Tamura, 1996;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Nakaiwa and Shirai, 1996)</ref>, which are mainly motivated by the rules and preferences introduced in Centering The- ory ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Grosz et al., 1995)</ref>. However, the research trend of zero anaphora resolution has shifted from such rule-based approaches to machine learning- based approaches because in machine learning we can easily integrate many different types of infor- mation, such as morpho-syntactic, semantic and discourse-related information. Researchers have developed methods of zero anaphora resolution for Chinese ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">Zhao and Ng, 2007;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Chen and Ng, 2013</ref>), Japanese ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Seki et al., 2002;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Isozaki and Hirao, 2003;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Iida et al., 2007a;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Taira et al., 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Sasano et al., 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b21">Sasano et al., 2009;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Imamura et al., 2009;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b27">Watanabe et al., 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Hayashibe et al., 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Iida and Poesio, 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b29">Yoshikawa et al., 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Hangyo et al., 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b31">Yoshino et al., 2013)</ref> and <ref type="bibr">Italian (Iida and Poesio, 2011)</ref>. One critical issue in zero anaphora resolution is optimizing the outputs of sub-problems (e.g., zero anaphor detec- tion and antecedent identification). Recent works by <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">Watanabe et al. (2010)</ref>, <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Iida and Poesio (2011)</ref> and <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">Yoshikawa et al. (2011)</ref> revealed that joint in- ference improves the overall performance of zero anaphora resolution. We employed one of these works as a baseline in Section 6.</p><p>Concerning subject sharing recognition, re- lated methods have been explored for pronominal anaphora ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">Yang et al., 2005</ref>) or coreference reso- lution ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Bean and Riloff, 2004;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Bansal and Klein, 2012)</ref>. In these methods, the semantic compatibil- ity between the contexts surrounding an anaphor and its antecedent (e.g., the compatibility of verbs kidnap and release given some arguments) was automatically extracted from raw texts in an un- supervised manner and used as features in a ma- chine learning-based approach. However, because the automatically acquired semantic compatibility is not always true or applicable in the context of any pair of an anaphor and its antecedent, the ef- fectiveness of the compatibility features might be weakened. In contrast, we accurately recognize the explicit subject sharing relations and directly use them for propagating the subject of some pred- icate to the empty subject position of other pred- icates instead of indirectly using the relations as features.</p><p>3 Zero anaphora resolution using subject shared predicate network</p><p>In this section, we first give an overview of the procedure of our zero anaphora resolution method. Intra-sentential zero anaphora resolution in our method is performed in the following five steps, as depicted in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 2</ref>.</p><p>Step 1 The pairwise subject sharing relations be- tween two predicates in a sentence are recog- nized by our subject sharing recognizer.</p><p>Step 2 A subject shared predicate network (SSPN) is constructed based on the results of pairwise subject sharing recognition.</p><p>Step 3 For each predicate in the set of the subject shared predicates in the SSPN, a subject is detected by our subject detector, if one exists.</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">!"#$%&amp;'%()*+,-.% /#01%2-2$3102%% 0#+145,1-! !#"%16%$0#7*82"#+% *-%2%+#-"#-8#! !"#$%9'%!5:;#8"%7#"#8,1-! &lt;#+54"+%16%*-"02=+#-"#-,24% /#01%2-2$3102%0#+145,1-! !"#$%&gt;'%?2*0@*+#%+5:;#8"%+320*-.%0#81.-*,1-! 1"3#0%$0#7*82"#+%% *-%!!?A! !"#$%B'%!5:;#8"% $01$2.2,1-! -1%+5:;#8"!</formula><p>!"#$%C'%!5:;#8"%+320#7%$0#7*82"#% -#"@10D%E!!?AF%81-+"058,1-%! +5:;#8"%+320#7%% $0#7*82"#+%*-%!!?A!</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Figure 2: Procedure of our zero anaphora resolu- tion method</head><p>Step 4 If a subject is detected, it is propagated to the empty subject position of each predicate in the subject shared predicates in the SSPN.</p><p>Step 5 For resolving the potential zero anaphora that were not resolved until Step 4, we apply the existing ILP-based method (Iida and Poe- sio, 2011).</p><p>We define subject sharing relations as follows. Two predicates have a subject sharing relation if and only if they share the same subject that is re- ferred to by (zero) anaphora or coreference. Note that the shared subject does not need to be realized in the text; it can appear as inter-sentential zero anaphora or exophora. In Step 1, the pairwise sub- ject sharing relations between two predicates are recognized, but recognizing the relations between any two predicates in a sentence remains difficult. We thus focus on some typical types of predicate pairs. The details of the predicate pair types will be explained in Section 4.1.</p><p>Given the results of pairwise subject sharing recognition, we construct an SSPN in Step 2. In an SSPN, every predicate in a sentence is a node and only the predicate pairs that were judged to be subject sharing are connected by a link. The ma- jor advantage of explicitly constructing an SSPN is that it enables us to resolve zero anaphora even if a predicate with a subject zero anaphor does not have any direct subject sharing relation with a predicate with a subject, like predicates susumeru (advance) and hakensuru (dispatch) in <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref>. By traversing the paths of the subject sharing re- lations in the SSPN, such predicates can be con- nected to successfully propagate the subject. The effect of introducing SSPNs is empirically evalu- ated in Section 6.</p><p>For use in Step 3, we create a subject detector, which judges whether an argument to a predicate is its subject using SVM light 1 , an implementation of Support Vector Machine <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">(Vapnik, 1998)</ref>, with a polynomial kernel of 2nd degree. The training in- stances of the subject detector are extracted from the predicate-argument relations 2 in the NAIST Text Corpus. The numbers of positive and nega- tive instances are 35,304 and 104,250 respectively. As features, we used the morpho-syntactic infor- mation about the lemmas of the predicate and its argument and the functional words following the predicate and its argument. The results of subject detection with 5-fold cross-validation demonstrate that our subject detector accurately detects sub- jects with performances of 0.949 in recall, 0.855 in precision, and 0.899 in F-score.</p><p>Note that our subject detector checks whether each predicate in an SSPN has a syntactic sub- ject among its arguments. An SSPN can include more than one predicate, and each predicate may have its own subject 3 . In this step, if two or more distinct subjects are detected for predicates in an SSPN, we use the most likely subject (i.e., the subject with the highest SVM score outputted by our subject detector) for subject propagation. Note that subject propagation is not performed if the subject position of a predicate is already filled.</p><p>Up to this point, the zero anaphora of the fol- lowing three cases cannot be resolved: (i) no sub- ject was detected for any predicate in a group linked by the subject sharing relations in the SSPN, (ii) no subject sharing relation was recog- nized for a predicate in the SSPN and (iii) non- 1 http://svmlight.joachims.org/ 2 Note that if a predicate appears in a relative clause and a noun modified by the clause is the semantic subject of the predicate, the noun is not regarded as subject by our subject detector. <ref type="bibr">3</ref> The subject sharing recognizer is likely to regard two predicates, each of which has its own subject, as non-subject sharing predicate pairs, but it is still logically possible that they are judged as subject sharing predicate pairs hence as a part of an SSPN. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Figure 3</ref>: Example of DEP type subject arguments were omitted as zero anaphors. To resolve zero anaphora in these cases, we ap- ply a state-of-the-art ILP-based zero anaphora res- olution method ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Iida and Poesio, 2011</ref>) in Step 5. This method determines zero anaphor and its an- tecedent by joint inference using the results of sub- ject detection, zero anaphor detection and intra- and inter-sentential antecedent identification. In the original method by <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Iida and Poesio (2011)</ref>, the inter-sentential zero anaphora was resolved, but in this work we focus on intra-sentential zero anaphora. To adapt their method for our problem setting, we simply removed the inter-sentential an- tecedent identification model from their method.</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">!"# !! "#$#$%&amp;'()*! "%"&amp;#$%+',)*! -./0)1+$-&amp;'2345! -./0! -./0! 6 !!%7)2"$'4'8&amp;"2*! '4'8&amp;"231$2)9':"4! ;4&lt;.)47'! #)=3134)! "/0! 3&gt;"/0!</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Pairwise subject sharing recognition</head><p>A key component in our zero anaphora resolu- tion method is pairwise subject sharing recogni- tion. In this work, we focus on three types of sub- ject sharing relations (DEP, ADJ and PNP types) as a first step because the instances belonging to the three types occupy 62% of intra-sentential zero anaphora that can be regarded as subject sharing. We developed a method that recognizes each sub- ject sharing type and evaluate it.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">Three types of subject sharing relations</head><p>We first describe the three types of subject sharing relations we focus on.</p><p>DEP A typical type of subject sharing relation is one between two predicates that have a syntac- tical dependency relation. The relation between two predicates, natta (have) and nonda (take), in example (1) in Section 1 is classified as this type because the two predicates have the same subject Tom i (ϕ i ), as illustrated in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Figure 3</ref>. We call this type of subject sharing the DEP type.</p><p>ADJ This type is a subject sharing relation be- tween two adjacent predicates, i.e., a predicate</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">!"#$%#" " !! "#$%&amp;'#()*! &amp;$%'%#()!! "+,(-%,'!./+0*! .123)+-!! .4#%$(5! .123! 6 "! "7)%,!#(#&amp;4,%*! #(#&amp;4,%$+! %)'#/,(! *%+$%,$- !"-#8$9#:*! $;,23! #"#()(#%)(.(!"&lt;,!(,-!9,%0*! /%'")"!! ".#=)':*! 0!(#%,"#%&amp;"1(!"'#(&lt;*! !(".(!"&gt;,?)!,(-,*! .123!</formula><p>.123! <ref type="figure">Figure 4</ref>: Example of ADJ type <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Figure 5</ref>: Example of PNP type pairs that do not have any other predicate between them in the surface order of a sentence. Although two adjacent predicates in a sentence tend to share the same subject, they sometimes cannot be cap- tured as the DEP type due to a long-distance de- pendency between predicates. For example, in ex- ample (3), two adjacent predicates, land and move onto, have the same subject but not a direct depen- dency relation, as illustrated in <ref type="figure">Figure 4</ref>. The airplane safely landed, but its control stick did not work after (it i ) moved onto the taxiway.</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">!"#$# # !"#$%&amp;'($')! %&amp;''(#)*+*!"*+$,-./)! ('#+('(,#)#%(!"0(%&amp;-,)! .0+1&amp;23!! ./*'-(#! .0+1! .0+1! 4 #! "5&amp;'$!*(*6/$')! *(*6/$'-2! '&amp;,*7$(! $-*'-*!".760,*7$()! "-*)"#,!"6,*()! $+1! -8$+1! *9($:!</formula><p>To cover such cases, we also take into account the subject sharing relations of the ADJ type in which two predicates appear adjacently in the surface or- der.</p><p>PNP In addition to the above two types of re- lations, in Japanese predicate pairs often have a subject sharing relation when one of the predi- cates syntactically depends on a noun (or noun phrase) that in turn syntactically depends on the other predicate. Example (4) is classified as such a type because noun houshin (plan) is placed be- tween two predicates, akirakanisita (unveil) and tekkaisuru (abolish), in the dependency path and predicates share subject chiji (governor), as illus- trated in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Figure 5</ref>.</p><formula xml:id="formula_4">(4) chiji i -wa (ϕ i -ga) joukou-o governor-TOP he i -SUBJ stipulation-OBJ tekkaisuru houshin-o akirakanisi-ta . abolish plan-TOP unveil-PAST period</formula><p>The governor i unveiled his plan under which (he i ) will abolish the stipulation.</p><p>We call this type of subject sharing relation the PNP type.</p><p>In this work, we solve the problem of subject sharing recognition as a binary classification prob- lem in which we classify whether two predicates share the same subject. We solve this problem us- ing a supervised approach. We independently ex- tract the training instances for each type from a corpus to which (zero) anaphora, coreference and subjects were annotated. The binary labels of the training instances are classified into the positive class if the subject of the two predicates in an in- stance is shared by coreference or (zero) anaphora, and negative otherwise. To create a classifier, we use SVM light and experiment with both a linear kernel and a polynomial kernel of 2nd degree.</p><p>As features, we use the feature set shown in <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table 1</ref>. Even though these features look simple, we expect them to work well to capture the char- acteristics of each subject sharing type. For ex- ample, as shown in example (5), the (subject) case marker of the argument (mother-SUBJ) between two predicates natta (have) and katta (buy) is a good indicator of non-subject sharing. For recognizing the PNP type of subject sharing relations, whether certain nouns appear between two predicates is an important clue, e.g., koto (complementizer) in example (6) and nouryoku (ability) in example (7).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Name</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Description PoS i (PoS j )</head><p>PoS of p i (p j ) lemma i (lemma j ) lemma of p i (p j ) func w i (func w j ) function words following p i (p j ) case i (case j ) case marker of arguments of p i (p j ) btw case case marker of arguments that appeared between p i and p j NpPoS* PoS of np Np lemma* lemma of np func w np * function words following np case np * case marker of dependents of np n class* noun class of np based on Kazama and Torisawa (2008) p i and p j stand for the left and right predicates in predicate pairs. np is the noun phrase between p i and p j . b i (b j ) stands for the bunsetsu-unit 4 including p i (p j ). The features marked with * are only used for PNP type. The ship i has an ability that (it i ) runs fast.</p><p>To robustly capture this characteristic, we use as features the discrete classes created by the noun clustering algorithm proposed by <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Kazama and Torisawa (2008)</ref>. It follows the distributional hy- pothesis, which states that semantically similar words tend to appear in similar contexts <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Harris, 1954)</ref>. By treating the syntactic dependency re- lations between words as 'contexts,' the clustering method defines a probabilistic model of noun-verb dependencies with hidden classes:</p><formula xml:id="formula_5">p(n, ⟨v, r⟩) = ∑ c p(n|c)p(⟨v, r⟩|c)p(c)</formula><p>where n is a noun, v is a verb or noun on which n depends by grammatical relation r (post-positions in Japanese), and c is a hidden class. The depen- dency relation frequencies were obtained from a 600-million page web corpus, and model parame- ters p(n|c), p(⟨v, r⟩|c) and p(c) were estimated us- ing the EM algorithm <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Hofmann, 1999</ref>). We clus- tered one million nouns into 500 discrete classes by assigning noun n to class c when the model pa- rameter p(c|n) &gt; θ (θ = 0.2).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Experiment 1: pairwise subject sharing recognition</head><p>We first empirically evaluate the performance of our pairwise subject sharing recognition for the DEP, ADJ and PNP types.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.1">Experimental setting</head><p>The training data for the subject sharing recog- nizer were generated from the NAIST Text Cor- pus 1.4 ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Iida et al., 2007b)</ref>, in which (zero) anaphora, coreference and subjects were manu- ally annotated. We automatically extracted pairs of predicates from the corpus. Since the original NAIST Text Corpus has a wide variety of anno- tation noise, we cleaned it up by the following strategy. According to the annotation scheme in the NAIST Text Corpus, predicate-argument rela- tions were annotated for the 'bare predicates' even if the predicates appear in passive or causative sen- tences. In such cases, the annotation was difficult and caused inconsistencies because the annotators needed to imagine the predicate-argument rela- tions for predicates that are not explicitly written, considering case alternation caused by changes of voice and so on. As such, to achieve a higher level of consistency, we modified the annotation scheme for predicate-argument relations by considering 'surface predicates' and re-annotated predicate- argument relations in passive and causative cases, thus reducing the risk of inconsistent annotations caused by case alternation.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>type method</head><p>Recall Precision F-score DEP baseline 0.161 0.505 0.244 proposed (linear) 0.545 0.719 0.620 proposed (poly-2d) 0.578 0.  <ref type="table">Table 2</ref>: Results of subject sharing recognition</p><p>Another important point is that in the NAIST Text Corpus, if the antecedent of a zero anaphor is not explicitly written in the corpus, it is simply an- notated as 'exophoric', and the subject sharing re- lations between two predicates whose subject was annotated as exophoric cannot be captured. In contrast, in our cleaning procedure, the annota- tors additionally annotated such 'exophoric' sub- ject sharing relations to take into account all sub- ject sharing relations in the corpus.</p><p>The predicates in the corpus and their depen- dency relations were detected based on the outputs of a Japanese dependency parser, J.DepP 5 <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">(Yoshinaga and Kitsuregawa, 2009)</ref>. We obtained 49,313 predicate pairs for the DEP type, 86,728 for the ADJ type, and 27,117 for the PNP types. The num- bers of positive instances of DEP, ADJ and PNP types are 9,524, 13,104, and 2,363 respectively. To evaluate the subject sharing recognition, we con- ducted 5-fold cross-validation using these predi- cate pairs and measured the performance using re- call, precision and F-score.</p><p>Note that we also evaluated a baseline method that recognizes subject sharing relations using the results of the state-of-the-art zero anaphora resolu- tion method (Iida and Poesio, 2011) and the sub- ject detector at Step 3 in Section 3.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.2">Results: subject sharing recognition</head><p>We measured the performances of the baseline and our subject sharing recognition method using re- call, precision and F-score for each of the three types of subject sharing relations, which are shown in <ref type="table">Table 2</ref>. The results demonstrate that all of the proposed classifiers solved the problems with high precision. In particular, for each type, the classi- fier using a polynomial kernel achieved more than <ref type="bibr">5</ref> http://www.tkl.iis.u-tokyo.ac.jp/˜ynaga/jdepp/ 70% precision. We thus used the classifiers with a polynomial kernel for evaluations in Section 6. The results also show that the classifier using a polynomial kernel for each type outperformed the baseline method based on the state-of-the-art zero anaphora resolution method. That is, the direct subject sharing recognition using our classifiers has the potential to lead to a significant improve- ment in zero anaphora resolution, which we con- firm through the experiments in Section 7.</p><p>Table 2 also shows that the classifier for the DEP type outperformed those for all of the other types in F-score. The difference reflects the wider vari- ations of the problems in both ADJ and PNP com- pared to the case of DEP. For example, to recog- nize the PNP type of subject sharing relation, our classifier needs to appropriately learn the compli- cated relationship between two predicates and the noun that intervenes between them, a problem we do not need to consider for the DEP type.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Experiment 2: intra-sentential zero anaphora resolution between subjects</head><p>We next investigate the effect of introducing SSPNs. In this experiment, we evaluated the per- formance of intra-sentential zero anaphora resolu- tion only between subjects, i.e., the positive in- stances used in this experiment were limited to the cases where the antecedent of a zero anaphor is the realized subject of a predicate. We evalu- ated a method of zero anaphora resolution using only SSPNs, where intra-sentential zero anaphora is resolved by the first four steps (Steps 1 to 4) in Section 3. We compared it to a baseline that only used the results of pairwise subject sharing recognition without SSPNs: if the subject shar- ing relation between two predicates is recognized by our pairwise subject sharing recognizer and a  <ref type="table">Table 3</ref>: Results of intra-sentential zero anaphora resolution between subjects single subject is detected by our subject detector for one of the two predicates, then the subject fills the empty subject position of the other predicate.</p><p>Note that in this baseline method, transitive sub- ject propagation through more than one subject sharing relation is not performed. Also, if mul- tiple subjects are detected for a predicate, we used the most likely subject to fill the subject position of the predicate, as in our method.</p><p>We conducted 5-fold cross-validation using the modified version of the NAIST Text Corpus pre- sented in Section 5.1. In this evaluation, we used the 8,473 subject zero anaphors that refer to the subject antecedents (46% of all the intra- sentential subject zero anaphora, in which a sub- ject zero anaphor refers to the antecedent that are not limited to subject) in the corpus. We mea- sured the performance using recall, precision and F-score for each of the three types of subject shar- ing relations and their combinations. When com- bining more than one subject sharing recognizer in our method, we construct the SSPN using the sub- ject sharing relations recognized by at least one of those recognizers for transitive subject propa- gation. On the other hand, in the baseline method, the SSPN was not constructed and zero anaphoric relations were identified using only the outputs of our subject detector and one of those recognizers.</p><p>The experimental results shown in <ref type="table">Table 3</ref> clearly demonstrate that the method with SSPNs for each type or a combination of the three types consistently outperformed that without SSPNs ex- cept for the PNP type. This result suggests that multi-step propagation of subjects through more than one subject sharing relation, as done in SSPNs, is an effective way to propagate a sub- ject to a subject position that cannot be reached by a single subject sharing relation. Our results also show that the F-score is improved by com- bining different types of subject sharing relations, and the best F-score, 0.456, was achieved when we used all types of relations, i.e., in the case of DEP+ADJ+PNP with SSPNs.</p><p>7 Experiment 3: intra-sentential subject zero anaphora resolution Finally, we evaluate the performance of intra- sentential subject zero anaphora resolution. In the previous section, we evaluated just a part of our method, i.e., from Step 1 to Step 4 presented in Section 3. In this section, we evaluate the whole method, i.e., from Step 1 to Step 5, against 18,324 subject zero anaphors, which are all subject zero anaphors annotated in our modified version of the NAIST Text Corpus. As a baseline, we employed Iida and Poesio (2011)'s method that was tuned for intra-sentential zero anaphora resolution. The baseline method solves the problems by applying only Step 5 in Section 3 to all the predicates.</p><p>Our results in <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">Table 4</ref> show that all the meth- ods using either each type or a combination of the three types significantly outperformed the base- line <ref type="bibr">6</ref> . The best performing method was DEP+PNP, which achieved 0.380 in F-score, which is 3.6%   <ref type="table">Table 5</ref>: Results of intra-sentential subject zero anaphora resolution (Steps 1 to 4 vs.</p><p>Step 5)</p><p>higher than the baseline. This suggests that our method exploiting subject sharing relations and SSPNs has a positive impact on accuracy of general intra-sentential zero anaphora resolution methods because about 84% of zero anaphors of general intra-sentential zero anaphora appear as subject zero anaphor in our corpus. We also estimate how accurately the method us- ing only the SSPNs evaluated in Section 6 resolves intra-sentential subject zero anaphora in compari- son to the baseline method. The results are shown in <ref type="table">Table 5</ref> and demonstrate that the performance of all the methods without Step 5 does not reach that of the baseline method in F-score. However, they retain high precision that ranges from 60% to 75%, preserving more than 10% of the recall on the DEP, DEP+ADJ, DEP+PNP and DEP+ADJ+PNP methods. Actually, in some of the potential ap- plications of zero anaphora resolution, such as in- formation extraction, methods with high precision and low recall are preferable to ones with low pre- cision and high recall. Our methods with SSPNs alone might be usable in such applications because of their high precision.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="8">Conclusion</head><p>In this paper, we introduced a subject shared pred- icate network (SSPN), which is a network of predicates that are linked by subject sharing re- lations for resolving typical intra-sentential zero anaphora. In our zero anaphora resolution method, zero anaphoric relations are identified by propa- gating a subject through subject sharing paths in the SSPN. To construct SSPNs, we developed a novel method of pairwise subject sharing recog- nition using the local contexts that surround two predicates and demonstrated that it can accurately recognize subject sharing relations. We combined our method of intra-sentential zero anaphora res- olution with Iida and Poesio (2011)'s method and achieved significantly better F-score than Iida and Poesio (2011)'s method alone.</p><p>As future work, we are planning to use commonsense knowledge, such as causal- ity ( ) and script-like knowledge ( , that has been automatically acquired from big data for accurate subject sharing recognition to improve inter- sentential zero anaphora resolution for cases not focused on in this work.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>( 2 )</head><label>2</label><figDesc>seifu i -wa (ϕ i -ga) hisaichi-ni government i -TOP it i -SUBJ disaster site-IOBJ 50 nin-o hakensuru koto-o (ϕ i -ga) 50 people-OBJ dispatch COMP-OBJ it i -SUBJ keikakusi junbisagyo-o susumeru .</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>( 3 )</head><label>3</label><figDesc>hikouki-wa bujini chakurikusi-ta-ga airplane-TOP safely land-PAST-but (ϕ i -ga) yudouro-ni hait-ta-atoni it i -SUBJ taxiway-IOBJ move onto-PAST-after soujukan-ga kikanakunat-ta . control stick-SUBJ do not work-PAST period</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head>( 5 )</head><label>5</label><figDesc>Tom i -ga infuruenza-ni natta-node , Tom-SUBJ flu-IOBJ had-since punc haha-ga kusuri-o katta . mother-SUBJ medicine-OBJ buy-PAST period Since Tom had the flu, his mother bought medicine.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" validated="false"><head>Table 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Features of subject sharing recognition 

(6) seifu i -wa 

(ϕ i -ga) sono isetsu-o 

government-TOP it i -SUBJ the relocation-OBJ 

mitomeru koto-o 
kime-ta 
. 

admit 

COMP-OBJ 

decide-PAST period 

The government i decided that (it i ) admits the 
relocation. 

(7) sono fune-wa (ϕ i -ga) hayaku 

the ship-TOP 
it i -SUBJ fast 

hashiru nouryoku-o motteiru . 

run 
ability-OBJ 
have 
period 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3" validated="true"><head>Table 4 :</head><label>4</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Results of intra-sentential subject zero anaphora resolution (Steps 1 to 5 vs. Step 5) 

Recall Precision F-score 
Baseline (Step 5) 
0.345 
0.344 
0.344 
DEP with SSPN 
0.131 
0.744 
0.223 
ADJ with SSPN 
0.089 
0.561 
0.154 
PNP with SSPN 
0.015 
0.780 
0.030 
DEP+ADJ with SSPN 
0.164 
0.604 
0.258 
DEP+PNP with SSPN 
0.150 
0.749 
0.250 
ADJ+PNP with SSPN 
0.094 
0.566 
0.161 
DEP+ADJ+PNP with SSPN 0.169 
0.607 
0.264 

</table></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="4"> A bunsetsu-unit is a Japanese base phrase consisting of at least one content word optionally followed by functional words.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="6"> The significance was tested using McNemar&apos;s testing (p &lt; 0.01).</note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Coreference semantics from web features</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mohit</forename><surname>Bansal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dan</forename><surname>Klein</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 50th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the 50th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="389" to="398" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Unsupervised learning of contextual role knowledge for coreference resolution</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Bean</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ellen</forename><surname>Riloff</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Human Language Technology Conference of the North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the Human Language Technology Conference of the North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="297" to="304" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Chinese zero pronoun resolution: Some recent advances</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chen</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Vincent</forename><surname>Ng</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2013 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</title>
		<meeting>the 2013 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1360" to="1365" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Centering: A framework for modeling the local coherence of discourse</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Barbara</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Grosz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Scott</forename><surname>Weinstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Aravind</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Joshi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Computational Linguistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">21</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="203" to="225" />
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Japanese zero reference resolution considering exophora and author/reader mentions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Masatsugu</forename><surname>Hangyo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Daisuke</forename><surname>Kawahara</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sadao</forename><surname>Kurohashi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2013 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</title>
		<meeting>the 2013 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="924" to="934" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Zellig</forename><surname>Harris</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Distributional structure. Word</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1954" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="146" to="162" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Toward future scenario generation: Extracting event causality exploiting semantic relation, context, and association features</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chikara</forename><surname>Hashimoto</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kentaro</forename><surname>Torisawa</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Julien</forename><surname>Kloetzer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Motoki</forename><surname>Sano</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">István</forename><surname>Varga</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jong-Hoon</forename><surname>Oh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yutaka</forename><surname>Kidawara</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 52nd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the 52nd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="987" to="997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Japanese predicate argument structure analysis exploiting argument position and type</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yuta</forename><surname>Hayashibe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mamoru</forename><surname>Komachi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yuji</forename><surname>Matsumoto</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of 5th International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing</title>
		<meeting>5th International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="201" to="209" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Probabilistic latent semantic indexing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Thomas</forename><surname>Hofmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Processing of the 22nd Annual International ACM SIGIR Conference on Research and Development in Information Retrieval</title>
		<meeting>essing of the 22nd Annual International ACM SIGIR Conference on Research and Development in Information Retrieval</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="50" to="57" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A cross-lingual ILP solution to zero anaphora resolution</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ryu</forename><surname>Iida</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Massimo</forename><surname>Poesio</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 49th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics: Human Language Technologies</title>
		<meeting>the 49th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics: Human Language Technologies</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="804" to="813" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Zero-anaphora resolution by learning rich syntactic pattern features</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ryu</forename><surname>Iida</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kentaro</forename><surname>Inui</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yuji</forename><surname>Matsumoto</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">ACM Transactions on Asian Language Information Processing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Issue 4, Article 12</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Annotating a Japanese text corpus with predicate-argument and coreference relations</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ryu</forename><surname>Iida</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mamoru</forename><surname>Komachi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kentaro</forename><surname>Inui</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yuji</forename><surname>Matsumoto</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the ACL Workshop: &apos;Linguistic Annotation Workshop</title>
		<meeting>the ACL Workshop: &apos;Linguistic Annotation Workshop</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="132" to="139" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Discriminative approach to predicateargument structure analysis with zero-anaphora resolution</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kenji</forename><surname>Imamura</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kuniko</forename><surname>Saito</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tomoko</forename><surname>Izumi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the ACL-IJCNLP</title>
		<meeting>the ACL-IJCNLP</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Conference Short Papers</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="85" to="88" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Japanese zero pronoun resolution based on ranking rules and machine learning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hideki</forename><surname>Isozaki</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tsutomu</forename><surname>Hirao</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2003 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</title>
		<meeting>the 2003 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="184" to="191" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A property-sharing constraint in centering</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Megumi</forename><surname>Kameyama</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 24th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the 24th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1986" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="200" to="206" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Inducing gazetteers for named entity recognition by large-scale clustering of dependency relations</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kentaro</forename><surname>Jun&amp;apos;ichi Kazama</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Torisawa</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 46th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics: Human Language Technologies</title>
		<meeting>the 46th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics: Human Language Technologies</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="407" to="415" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Anaphora resolution of Japanese zero pronouns with deictic reference</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hiromi</forename><surname>Nakaiwa</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Satoshi</forename><surname>Shirai</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 16th International Conference on Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the 16th International Conference on Computational Linguistics</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="812" to="817" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Zero pronoun resolution in Japanese discourse based on Centering Theory</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Manabu</forename><surname>Okumura</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kouji</forename><surname>Tamura</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 16th International Conference on Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the 16th International Conference on Computational Linguistics</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="871" to="876" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Million-scale derivation of semantic relations from a manually constructed predicate taxonomy</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Motoki</forename><surname>Sano</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kentaro</forename><surname>Torisawa</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Julien</forename><surname>Kloetzer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chikara</forename><surname>Hashimoto</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">István</forename><surname>Varga</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jong-Hoon</forename><surname>Oh</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 25th International Conference on Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the 25th International Conference on Computational Linguistics</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1423" to="1434" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A fully-lexicalized probabilistic model for Japanese zero anaphora resolution</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ryohei</forename><surname>Sasano</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Daisuke</forename><surname>Kawahara</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sadao</forename><surname>Kurohashi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 22nd International Conference on Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the 22nd International Conference on Computational Linguistics</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="769" to="776" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The effect of corpus size on case frame acquisition for discourse analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ryohei</forename><surname>Sasano</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Daisuke</forename><surname>Kawahara</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sadao</forename><surname>Kurohashi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of Human Language Technologies: The 2009 Annual Conference of the North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>Human Language Technologies: The 2009 Annual Conference of the North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="521" to="529" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">A probabilistic method for analyzing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kazuhiro</forename><surname>Seki</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Atsushi</forename><surname>Fujii</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tetsuya</forename><surname>Ishikawa</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Japanese anaphora integrating zero pronoun detection and resolution</title>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 19th International Conference on Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the 19th International Conference on Computational Linguistics</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="911" to="917" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A Japanese predicate argument structure analysis using decision lists</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hirotoshi</forename><surname>Taira</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sanae</forename><surname>Fujita</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Masaaki</forename><surname>Nagata</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2008 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</title>
		<meeting>the 2008 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="523" to="532" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Adaptive and Learning Systems for Signal Processing, Communications, and Control</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Vladimir</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Vapnik</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
			<publisher>John Wiley &amp; Sons</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Statistical Learning Theory</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Japanese discourse and the process of centering</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marilyn</forename><surname>Walker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sharon</forename><surname>Cote</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Masayo</forename><surname>Iida</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Computational Linguistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="193" to="233" />
			<date type="published" when="1994" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A structured model for joint learning of argument roles and predicate senses</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yotaro</forename><surname>Watanabe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Masayuki</forename><surname>Asahara</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yuji</forename><surname>Matsumoto</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the ACL 2010 Conference Short Papers</title>
		<meeting>the ACL 2010 Conference Short Papers</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="98" to="102" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Improving pronoun resolution using statistics-based semantic compatibility information</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xiaofeng</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jian</forename><surname>Su</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chew Lim</forename><surname>Tan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 43rd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the 43rd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="165" to="172" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Jointly extracting Japanese predicate-argument relation with Markov logic</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Katsumasa</forename><surname>Yoshikawa</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Masayuki</forename><surname>Asahara</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yuji</forename><surname>Matsumoto</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of 5th International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing</title>
		<meeting>5th International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1125" to="1133" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Polynomial to linear: Efficient classification with conjunctive features</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Naoki</forename><surname>Yoshinaga</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Masaru</forename><surname>Kitsuregawa</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2009 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</title>
		<meeting>the 2009 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1542" to="1551" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Predicate argument structure analysis using partially annotated corpora</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Koichiro</forename><surname>Yoshino</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Shinsuke</forename><surname>Mori</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tatsuya</forename><surname>Kawahara</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 6th International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing</title>
		<meeting>the 6th International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="957" to="961" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Identification and resolution of Chinese zero pronouns: A machine learning approach</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Shanheng</forename><surname>Zhao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hwee Tou</forename><surname>Ng</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the</title>
		<meeting>the</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<monogr>
				<title level="m">Natural Language Processing and Computational Natural Language Learning</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="541" to="550" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
