<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T10:50+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Detecting Risks in the Banking System by Sentiment Analysis</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
				<availability status="unknown"><p>Copyright Association for Computational Linguistics</p>
				</availability>
				<date type="published" when="2015-09">September 2015. 2015</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Clemens</forename><surname>Nopp</surname></persName>
							<email>clemens.nopp@alumni.tuwien.ac.at</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Institute of Software Technology and Interactive Systems TU Wien</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">TU Wien</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Allan</forename><surname>Hanbury</surname></persName>
							<email>hanbury@ifs.tuwien.ac.at</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Institute of Software Technology and Interactive Systems TU Wien</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">TU Wien</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Detecting Risks in the Banking System by Sentiment Analysis</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2015 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</title>
						<meeting>the 2015 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing <address><addrLine>Lisbon, Portugal</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="17" to="21"/>
							<date type="published" when="2015-09">September 2015. 2015</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>In November 2014, the European Central Bank (ECB) started to directly supervise the largest banks in the Euro-zone via the Single Supervisory Mechanism (SSM). While supervisory risk assessments are usually based on quantitative data and surveys, this work explores whether sentiment analysis is capable of measuring a bank&apos;s attitude and opinions towards risk by analyzing text data. For realizing this study, a collection consisting of more than 500 CEO letters and outlook sections extracted from bank annual reports is built up. Based on these data, two distinct experiments are conducted. The evaluations find promising opportunities, but also limitations for risk sentiment analysis in banking supervision. At the level of individual banks, predictions are relatively inaccurate. In contrast, the analysis of ag-gregated figures revealed strong and significant correlations between uncertainty or negativity in textual disclosures and the quantitative risk indicator&apos;s future evolution. Risk sentiment analysis should therefore rather be used for macroprudential analyses than for assessments of individual banks.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>From 2007 on, a global crisis struck the financial markets and led to a severe slow-down of the real economy. It was triggered by the collapsing US subprime mortgage sector, where loans had been issued to borrowers with poor credit ratings. Due to the tight interconnectedness of the financial sys- tem, problems quickly propagated in the global banking system. Governments had to bail out im- portant institutions like Northern Rock, but such solutions could not be provided for every troubled bank. In September 2008, the large investment bank Lehman Brothers had to file bankruptcy. In the aftermath of this event, further banks had to be rescued in order to stabilize the financial system. This deep financial crisis highlighted the necessity of better financial regulation as well as more ef- fective financial supervision in the future <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Hodson and Quaglia, 2009)</ref>.</p><p>As a reaction to the crisis and its severe eco- nomic consequences, EU institutions decided to build up an European Banking Union (EBU). The EBU consists of three pillars, one of them being a new system of financial supervision, the Sin- gle Supervisory Mechanism (SSM). Its goal is to "promote long-term safety and soundness of credit institutions and the stability of the financial sys- tem within the Union and each Member State <ref type="bibr">[...]</ref>" (Council of the EU, 2013, p. 72).</p><p>For supervising over 120 of the largest banks in the Eurozone, the SSM utilizes a range of in- formation sources in order to detect vulnerabilities and risks. The sources include mainly backward- looking quantitative Key Risk Indicators (KRIs), which are complemented with surveys in order to include forward-looking information as well <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(European Banking Authority, 2014)</ref>. However, an- other source of information seems to be largely untapped, namely textual data published by the banks. Publications like periodic reports, press re- leases, and news published for investors also con- tain forward-looking information. Analyzing this readily available data would be more cost-efficient in comparison to traditional approaches like sur- veys. It could provide answers to questions like: what does official communication by banks re- veal about their expectations and attitudes towards risk?</p><p>In this paper, we present a novel applica- tion of sentiment analysis for exploring attitudes and opinions about risk in textual disclosures by banks. In particular, this work (1) finds suitable data sources, (2) identifies appropriate techniques for risk sentiment analysis, and (3) analyzes risk sentiment within the last decade in order to cover the financial crisis of 2007-08 adequately. The de- rived sentiment scores quantify uncertainty, nega- tivity, and positivity in the analyzed documents. All of them are interesting with regards to risk sentiment analysis: uncertainty relates to risk in a direct way since the latter are "uncertainties re- sulting in adverse variations of profitability or in losses" <ref type="bibr">(Bessis, 2002, p. 11)</ref>. Highly negative sen- timent refers to current or future problems, and too positive sentiment could represent overconfi- dence. We find that sentiment scores reflect not only the financial crisis, but also other major eco- nomic events within the last decade.</p><p>In addition, we test for correlations between the sentiment scores and a popular quantitative risk in- dicator. It turns out that aggregated risk sentiment in forward-looking documents is a leading indica- tor for the actual risk figures, so it can be used within predictive models.</p><p>The remainder of this paper, which is based on the Master's thesis of one of the authors <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(Nopp, 2015)</ref>, is organized as follows: first, we give an overview on related work in the field of risk sen- timent analysis. The following section introduces the chosen sources for text data and quantitative figures. Afterwards, we give an overview on the chosen methodologies and evaluate the experi- mental results. The last section concludes.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Related Work</head><p>Sentiment analysis in general and its application in the financial domain in particular gained a lot of interest within the last decade. There is a num- ber of studies which aim to identify risks by means of text mining. A common question tackled by researchers is whether corporate disclosures drive stock price volatilities or future earnings of the re- spective firm ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Groth and Muntermann, 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Kogan et al., 2009;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Tsai and Wang, 2013)</ref>. Hence, they focus on the risk an investor takes if he or she buys stocks of a company. Generally spo- ken, these studies find significant correlations be- tween sentiment extracted from corporate disclo- sures and future volatilities. Other papers deal with financial distress prediction, for example <ref type="bibr">Hajek and Olej (2013)</ref>. As a baseline, they classify companies based on financial indicators. It turned out that the inclusion of sentiment indicators im- proved financial distress prediction.</p><p>Among the text data sources for these studies are mainly annual reports, but also news stories or earning calls transcripts <ref type="bibr">1</ref> . <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Kogan et al. (2009)</ref> exclude irrelevant information from the annual re- ports by focusing on a section which contains im- portant forward-looking content.</p><p>In the related studies, authors work with simi- lar approaches for extracting sentiment from texts. Linguistic preprocessing generally involves to- kenization, lemmatization, and removing non- essential items like tables, exhibits, or digit se- quences. In almost every study, the authors also make use of term weighting schemes. With the selected features and additional quantitative data, the studies either employ machine learning algo- rithms, or use the data for regression analyses.</p><p>Although none of the mentioned papers focuses on risk sentiment analysis in the banking industry, parts of their processing pipelines and approaches can be reused for this work. With regards to the se- lection of appropriate data sources, it can be con- cluded that analyzing annual reports is very pop- ular in this field of research. Hence, these data should also be considered for the experiments of this study. In contrast to the majority of the related papers, we only use specific sections of the annual reports, namely CEO letters and outlook sections (see Section 3).</p><p>Regarding the machine learning algorithms and the incorporation of quantitative indicators, the ap- proaches of <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Groth and Muntermann (2011)</ref>, <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Kogan et al. (2009)</ref>, and Hajek and Olej (2013) are a good basis for the experiments of this study. All of them define the document labels based on suitable quantitative indicators. For labeling, the related studies consider the fact that text data are forward- looking, but quantitative indicators reflect the past. Hence, the indicators are taken from one period after publication of the text data. The labeled data are then used for training machine learning algo- rithms. Since the focus of our work lies on banks, we make use of a specific quantitative risk indica- tor which is not employed by related studies. In the following section, we introduce this indicator and the selected text data sources.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Data Sources</head><p>Among this work's aims is to test for relations be- tween textual risk sentiment and quantitative risk indicators. A careful selection of sources for both types of data is crucial since irrelevant ones would lead to biased conclusions.</p><p>Quantitative Risk Indicator. The selected quantitative risk indicator has to represent fi- nancial health and the general risk exposure of a bank within a specific period or at a specific point in time. Furthermore, the data have to be (1) publicly accessible, (2) available for each analyzed bank, (3) published at least annually, and (4) comparable among the different banks.</p><p>A comparison of several quantitative risk in- dicators based on expert interviews revealed that only the Tier 1 Capital Ratio (T1) fulfills all cri- teria. The T1 is one of the most important ratios based on risk-weighted amount of the bank's as- sets. In particular, it refers to the bank's Tier 1 capital as a percentage of its risk-weighted assets:</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">Tier 1 Capital Ratio = Tier 1 Capital Risk-Weighted Assets</formula><p>(1) Tier 1 capital is considered as the best form of bank capital and has to fulfill several criteria mak- ing it relatively secure. As <ref type="bibr">Cannata et al. (2012, p. 12</ref>) put it, this ratio "measures the ability of the bank to absorb losses". If the T1 is high, the bank acts conservatively and with a high risk buffer. A high ratio can be achieved by either increasing the Tier 1 capital or by reducing the amount of risk- weighted assets, i.e. reducing the amount of total assets or replacing them with safer ones.</p><p>The T1 also played a major role during the 2014 EU-wide banking stress test, which was an impor- tant part of the preparation phase for the Single Supervisory Mechanism. The stress test had the purpose to assess the resilience of large EU banks in different macroeconomic scenarios, measured by the impact on the T1.</p><p>Text Data Sources. In order to minimize noise and to enhance the sentiment analysis validity, it is crucial to work with the documents well adapted to the task of risk sentiment analysis. Like the quan- titative risk indicators, they need to be (1) publicly accessible, (2) available for every analyzed bank, and (3) published at least annually. In addition, for this study, the documents need to be (4) written in the English language, (5) directly published by the bank, and (6) contain forward-looking and subjec- tive information about the bank's attitude and ex- pectations towards risk.</p><p>These criteria are best fulfilled by two types of document published in the banks' annual reports, namely CEO letters and outlook sections. The for- mer are carefully crafted documents which con- tain valuable information about the management's opinions about risk. <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Amernic et al. (2010)</ref> recog- nize in their study from 2010 that the word choice of managers strongly influences companies, and CEO letters are a way for communicating their at- titudes and values.</p><p>Outlook sections are usually a part of the man- agement report, which is a textual summary of the bank's results, its business environment, and regu- latory as well as internal developments. In their outlook on the next year, banks write about the expected macroeconomic environment, manage- ment guidelines, and priorities for the next period. These documents might be less subjective com- pared to CEO letters, but they are usually more comprehensive and contain interesting forward- looking information.</p><p>Collection of Data. The annual reports for this work were collected via a Bloomberg Terminal, supplemented by direct downloads from bank websites. In total, over 500 documents from 27 banks which published them between 2001 and 2013 were collected. The sample contains banks from all 12 countries which have belonged to the Eurozone at least since 2002. This promotes com- parability of the data because the banks operated in similar economic circumstances and with the same currency.</p><p>Further data were retrieved from the online database Bankscope: the bank's country of resi- dence, its full name, its size measured by total as- sets, and its Tier 1 capital ratio at the end of each year between 2001 and 2013. 31 % of the Tier 1 capital ratios could not be directly retrieved from the database, so they had to be manually extracted from the respective annual reports.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Methodologies</head><p>Two independent approaches are employed for the risk sentiment analysis. First, a lexicon-based ap- proach derives and analyzes negativity, positivity, and uncertainty in publications by banks. The second approach aims to predict the evolution of quantitative risk indicators by means of supervised classification. The aim of both approaches is to assess the potential of risk sentiment analysis in banking supervision.</p><p>Creation of the Document Collection. The original documents are provided as PDF files. For building up the collection, they have to be parsed in order to acquire plain text files containing the required sections. One method for extracting the relevant sections is to split the original PDF files according to their bookmarks and to convert them into plain text files afterwards. Another way is to convert the PDF files already in the first step and to extract the relevant sections by making use of specific tokens. For example, a typical CEO let- ter is delimited by the tokens Dear Shareholders and Sincerely. If neither of these semi-automated approaches is applicable, the extraction has to be done manually 2 .  <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>: An overview of the document collection.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">Lexicon-based Approach</head><p>The first experiment is about analyzing sentiment scores derived from the documents by incorpo-rating finance-specific word lists. The objective of this experiment is to show how the language of forward-looking disclosures by European banks evolved within the last decade. The workflow con- sists of the following steps: (1) pre-processing the collected data, (2) the actual sentiment analysis which derives the scores, (3) data consolidation, and (4) data evaluation.</p><p>Sentiment Tagging. In the first step of the anal- ysis, sentiment words in the textual data are tagged. In particular, this study works with neg- ative words (Fin-Neg), positive words (Fin-Pos), and words related to uncertainty (Fin-Unc). All of these word lists are provided by <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Loughran and McDonald (2011)</ref>. Such topic-specific word lists are necessary because many words bear a different sentiment if used in a financial context: according to <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Loughran and McDonald (2011)</ref>, almost three quarters (73.8 %) of typically negative words can- not be considered as negative when they appear in financial texts. <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Kearney and Liu (2014)</ref> give the examples tax and liability. These words appear in the Harvard IV Negative Word List (H4N), but are neutral when used in a financial context, e.g. in an annual report.  <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Table 2</ref>: Examples for opinion words in the finan- cial context ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Loughran and McDonald, 2011</ref>).</p><p>Term Weighting. All terms in a document are normalized by</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">N j = 1 m i=0 (G i L i,j ) 2 .<label>(2)</label></formula><p>This equation is based on Salton and Buck- ley (1988) and accounts for documents of differ- ent lengths. G i is the global weight of term i and L i,j the local weight of term i in document j. An established method for the latter is given by the following formula (Manning and Schütze, 1999, p. 543):</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">L i,j = 1 + log(tf i,j ) if tf i,j ≥ 1 0 otherwise (3)</formula><p>The term frequency is denoted as tf i,j . The most popular global weight is the inverse document fre- quency (IDF). In</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">G i = log N df i ,<label>(4)</label></formula><p>the total number of documents is denoted by N , and df i is the number of documents where term i occurs at least once ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Salton and Buckley, 1988)</ref>.</p><p>Valence Shifting. In order to account for negated sentiment words, the simple negation han- dling algorithm proposed by Polanyi and Zae- nen <ref type="formula" target="#formula_1">(2006)</ref> is implemented. If one of the three di- rect predecessors of a sentiment word is a negation word 3 , its sentiment score will be negated. This is done by assigning −1 to the valence shifter vari- able v i of term i. If there is no negation word among the predecessors, v i is set to 1.</p><p>Calculating Sentiment Scores. The document- level sentiment scores are calculated for three sen- timent classes, namely uncertainty, positivity, and negativity. In</p><formula xml:id="formula_4">s c,j = i∈c L i,j G i N j v i ,<label>(5)</label></formula><p>the term-level sentiment score is represented by the product of the term weights L i,j and G i , the normalization factor N j , and the valence shifter v i . The document sentiment score s c,j is the sum of the term sentiment scores which belong to the document j and the sentiment class c.</p><p>Data Consolidation and Evaluation. After cal- culating the sentiment scores, the data are filtered and grouped in order to prepare them for the evalu- ations. In particular, the data are filtered according to specific countries and grouped by year respec- tively by bank.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">Supervised Classification</head><p>For the second experiment, the documents are la- beled based on a quantitative risk measure, namely the T1 dating to the end of the period referred to in the CEO letters and outlook sections. These data are then used for training supervised classi- fication algorithms which aim to predict the indi- cator's evolution.</p><p>The experiment consists of three steps: (1) read- ing and parsing the collected data as well as as- signing the class labels, (2) linguistic preprocess- ing and feature selection, and (3) classifying the data with Na¨ıveNa¨ıve Bayes (NB) and Support Vector Machine (SVM).</p><p>Assigning the Class Labels. The Tier 1 capital ratio is published by banks at least once a year. Since it is actually a continuous measure, it al- ways strongly depends on the previous year's ra- tio. Banking supervisors like the ECB are inter- ested in the future evolution of the ratio: if it in- creases, the bank acts in a less risky way, and vice versa. Hence, appropriate labels for the supervised classification task are UP for an increasing T1, and DOWN for a decreasing one. We assume that the T1 did not change notably if the difference to the previous year is less than 0.2 percent points 4 . In this case, no class label is assigned.</p><p>Preprocessing and Feature Selection. Linguis- tic preprocessing comprises the removal of punc- tuation, numbers, single characters, and stop words. The remaining words are converted to lower case. Furthermore, the terms are weighted according to the term weighting strategy presented in Section 4.1.</p><p>For feature selection, two approaches are fol- lowed. The first one assumes that the sentiment words used in the lexicon-based analysis are the relevant features for this experiment. Hence, all words which do not appear in the first experi- ment's dictionaries are removed. The second ap- proach utilizes a Snowball Stemmer to ensure that different versions of the same word are treated as equal. Its feature selection strategy is based on the concepts of document frequency (DF) and in- formation gain (IG). For DF, tests showed that a lower bound of 20 documents yields the best re- sults. The objective of the IG measure is to iden- tify those features which have the highest discrim- inatory power in a classification problem. It mea- sures the impurity of a dataset, i.e. its entropy. If a feature is able to reduce the entropy in a data set by a large amount, its information gain is high. Such features have a relatively high ability to pre- dict the corresponding class. For calculating the information gain, one has to compute the entropies given the presence or absence of a feature in a data set and subtract the results from the entropy of the original data set <ref type="bibr">(Aggarwal and Zhai, 2012, p. 169)</ref>.</p><p>Classification. The outcome of the previous steps is a set of document vectors with associated class labels. With these data, the classification al- gorithms Na¨ıveNa¨ıve Bayes (NB) and Support Vector Machine (SVM) are trained. The latter is used in its basic version, i.e. with a linear kernel. The performance measures are determined by employ- ing 10-fold cross validation, which helps to avoid problems like overfitting.</p><p>While Na¨ıveNa¨ıve Bayes works without parameters, the linear SVM depends on the parameter C. Its optimal value of 111 was determined by conduct- ing an automated grid search.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Evaluation of the Experiments</head><p>Both experiments aim to capture attitudes and opinions about risk by analyzing CEO letters and outlook sections of Eurozone banks. In this sec- tion, conclusions are drawn from the results of the experiments.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.1">Evaluation of the Lexicon-based Approach</head><p>The outcome of the lexicon-based approach con- sists of sentiment scores for each document repre- senting the degrees of uncertainty, negativity, and positivity.</p><p>Evolution of Sentiment Over Time. <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref> shows how sentiment in CEO letters has been evolving since 2002. The evolution of sentiment in outlook sections is not depicted, but is very similar to that of CEO letters. The individual data points represent the arithmetic mean of the document- level sentiment scores for each year. In 2002 and 2003, CEO letters contained more negative sen- timent than in the following years. Banks might have emphasized that the recession following the burst of the dot-com bubble was still not over and that recovery had not yet arrived. <ref type="bibr">Between 2003 and</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b14">2006</ref>, the letters became more positive and less negative from year to year. The turn- ing point was in 2006-from that time on, nega- tivity in CEO letters rose and quadrupled within three years. During the same period, positive sen- timent scores decreased continuously. The summit of these evolutions was in 2009, in the midst of the financial crisis. The letters in 2010 had been already much more optimistic, but negativity in- creased in 2011 and 2012 again when CEOs rec- ognized that the crisis was still not over. The evolution of the uncertainty scores is simi- lar to the negative sentiment scores. This observa- tion is supported by a high correlation coefficient of 0.93 between uncertainty and negativity scores. Since 2012, uncertainty has been decreasing quite sharply. This can potentially be attributed to an important and often-cited speech by ECB presi- dent Mario Draghi, who calmed the financial mar- kets with the announcement to do "whatever it takes to preserve the Euro. And believe me, it will be enough" <ref type="bibr">5</ref> .</p><p>Another observation is that the average uncer- tainty scores are much lower than the average pos- itivity and negativity scores. A plausible interpre- tation thereof is that CEOs rather use clear state- ments than uncertain language.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Do Sentiment Scores Predict Quantitative Risk</head><p>Measures? A comparison of the T1 average evolution and the corresponding sentiment scores reveals interesting relations, see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 2</ref>. The correlation coefficients in <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">Table 3</ref> indicate that a higher degree of uncertainty or negativity in the documents is commonly followed by a higher in- crease of the T1, and vice versa.</p><p>It is interesting to analyze the data by a regres- sion model for predicting the T1 evolution. <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table  4</ref> shows such a model with negativity as the only explaining variable. The coefficients can be inter- preted as follows: if the average negativity score rises by one unit, the T1 evolution increases by 0.9963 pp. If negativity is zero, the Tier 1 capital ratio would decrease by the computed intercept, which is -0.502 pp. Both coefficients are statisti- cally significant if a 95 % confidence level is as- sumed.</p><p>About 76 % of the average T1 evolution's vari- ation can be explained by the negativity score. A model of similar quality could be constructed by analyzing uncertainty in outlook sections. Hence, sentiment scores can be considered as an addi- tional leading indicator for the future evolution of the Tier 1 capital ratio.</p><p>Limitations. A drawback of this regression model is that it cannot model external shocks which influence the T1 evolution, but are not ad- <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref>: Evolution of positivity, negativity, and uncertainty in CEO letters over time.    equately covered in the text data. Examples for such shocks would be new regulations concern- ing the minimum capital ratio or monetary pol- icy actions by the ECB. A further limitation is in- duced by the fact that our methodology makes use of the bag of words (BoW) model, which ignores the documents internal structure. Hence, it is not possible to utilize information like word order and grammar, although this definitely plays a role in carefully crafted documents like CEO letters. It should also be emphasized that the model is based on figures aggregated by year. Applying it on the data of individual banks could lead to in- correct conclusions. This assumption is supported by <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 3</ref>, which compares negativity scores of individual outlook sections with the associated T1 evolutions. Although it is still possible to identify a positive relationship between the variables, the variance is too big for satisfactory representation by a regression model <ref type="bibr">6</ref> . This observation is in line with the relatively high standard deviations if the figures are aggregated by year, see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 2</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.2">Evaluation of the Supervised Classification Approach</head><p>The supervised classification experiment aims to assess whether this approach works better than the lexicon-based approach in terms of predicting the T1 evolution for individual banks based on their CEO letters or outlook sections. The class la- bels UP and DOWN have been assigned accord- ing to the direction of the T1 evolution. <ref type="table" target="#tab_5">Table  5</ref> gives an overview of the experiments and lists the respective performance measures. An analy- sis of the data in the table reveals interesting re- sults. First, feature selection based on document frequency and information gain works better than the approach based on word lists. Second, the clas- sifiers trained with CEO letters yield better results than the ones trained with outlook sections. Fi- nally, three out of the four SVM results are not meaningful due to the following reason: the pa- rameter optimization of C suggests to choose a very low value, which indeed maximizes the clas- sifier accuracy-but these SVMs simply assign the class UP to every instance. These classifiers can be seen as a baseline for comparisons. However, the remaining SVM clearly yields the best results among the employed algorithms.</p><p>None of the classifiers based on the feature se- lection method (1) is able to outperform the base- line (assigning every instance to the UP class). Both SVMs simply classify every instance as UP, and the Na¨ıveNa¨ıve Bayes classifiers also deliver unsat- isfactory results. Feature selection based on docu- ment frequency and information gain achieves bet- ter results than the first one, but only when the classifiers are trained with the CEO letter collec- tion. Most likely, this can be explained with the fact that outlook sections provide less terms with discriminatory power than CEO letters. Na¨ıveNa¨ıve Bayes correctly classifies 75 % of the instances, and the optimized SVM yields 79.2 %. The other SVM performance measures can be interpreted as follows: 81 % of the instances classified as UP were indeed instances where the Tier 1 capital ratio increased (= precision U). Furthermore, the SVM correctly identified almost 92 % of the in- stances which belong to the class UP (= recall U).</p><p>These results are better than the baseline and demonstrate a noticeable potential for supervised classification even at the level of individual bank disclosures. Nevertheless, they are not good enough for reliable predictions. However, the aggregated classification data accurately predict whether the majority of banks will increase or de- crease their Tier 1 capital ratio in the following year: for 12 out of 13 years, the algorithm cor- rectly predicts the direction of the T1 evolution. This finding is in line with the lexicon-based ap- proach, where the aggregated data yielded much better results than the individual ones.   </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Conclusion</head><p>This study explored how banking supervisors could utilize sentiment analysis for risk assess- ments. The analysis of potential document types revealed that two sections in a bank's annual re- port are particularly well suited for this work, namely CEO letters and outlook sections. The for- mer represent the tone from the top and provide subjective information about the bank's current and future situation. Outlook sections are exclu- sively forward-looking and reveal opinions about the near future. Furthermore, the Tier 1 capital ratio (T1) is the best suited quantitative risk indi- cator. The T1 sets the most secure forms of bank capital in relation to its risk-weighted assets and is widely used in banking supervision, e.g. as a key ratio for the ECB's stress test in fall 2014.</p><p>The lexicon-based analysis showed that senti- ment scores reflect major economic events be- tween 2002 and 2014 very well. In addition, there is a strong correlation between uncertainty, neg- ativity, and the Tier 1 capital ratio evolution over time. Hence, the sentiment scores could be used in regression models for predicting the T1 evolution. However, the results are only meaningful if the fig- ures are aggregated by year. Applying the model on data of individual banks leads to inaccurate re- sults. It should also be noted that this method is not meant to be used as a stand-alone estimator for the T1 evolution. Instead, it should be combined with other estimation methods.</p><p>The supervised risk classification approach cor- rectly classifies 79.2 % of the CEO letters. This is not good if one considers that it is possible to yield an accuracy of 70 % simply by assigning the class UP to every instance. However, if the results of the best SVM classifier are aggregated by year, the data correctly predict for 12 out of 13 years whether the majority of banks will increase or de- crease their Tier 1 capital ratio.</p><p>The described systems have the potential to pro- vide valuable insights for banking supervisors, in particular because of the strong correlation be- tween sentiment scores derived from textual data and the T1. Because of the mentioned limitations, these techniques should only be used for macro- prudential analyses, i.e. the promotion of stability in the whole financial system. Examples are pre- dictions for the average Tier 1 capital ratio's evolu- tion in the whole Eurozone or in groups of coun- tries. Another option is to improve existing risk prediction frameworks.</p><p>For future research, it would be interesting to validate the results by conducting the study on a larger scale. One could incorporate data from all European banks, or from other regions. The approach could also be used for other docu- ment types, for example analyst reports or inter- nal memos, or in other industries. Regarding the methodology, it would be interesting to see how alternative algorithms or word lists would affect the results.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2: Evolution of the Tier 1 capital ratio compared to negativity in outlook sections. The error bars represent the standard deviation of the negativity scores.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Figure 3: Individual negativity scores in outlook sections compared to the T1 evolution.</figDesc><graphic url="image-2.png" coords="8,90.43,62.81,181.41,154.50" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Feature</head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" validated="true"><head>Table 4 gives</head><label>4</label><figDesc>an overview of the number of doc- uments in the created collection. It shows that the number of published outlook sections constantly increased between 2002 and 2008. From 2009 on, the number was quite stable. The number of CEO letters also increased over time, but only un- til 2008, when some CEOs stopped writing letters in the course of the financial crisis.</figDesc><table>Year # of CEO letters # of outlooks 
2002 15 
14 
2003 19 
19 
2004 17 
20 
2005 19 
20 
2006 19 
21 
2007 23 
22 
2008 25 
23 
2009 21 
23 
2010 20 
23 
2011 21 
23 
2012 20 
23 
2013 22 
24 
2014 22 
23 
Total 263 
278 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" validated="false"><head>Table 2 lists</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>some examples for 
sentiment words in the financial context. 

Positive 
efficient, stabilized, vibrant 
Negative 
closure, postpone, threat 
Uncertainty approximately, might, volatility 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" validated="false"><head>Table 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Correlation coefficients between T1 evolution and sentiment scores. 

Variable 
Coeff. Std. Err. t-value 
P&gt;t 
Mean(Negativity score) 0.9963 
0.1647 
6.0478 0.0001 
Intercept 
-0.5020 0.1883 -2.6651 0.0237 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3" validated="false"><head>Table 4 : Regression model based on negativity in outlook sections.</head><label>4</label><figDesc></figDesc><table></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4" validated="false"><head>selection</head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Document type Classifier Accuracy Precision U Recall U Precision D Recall D 

(1) based on topic-
specific sentiment 
words 

CEO letters 
NB 
0.703 
0.741 
0.889 
0.500 
0.263 
SVM 
0.703 
0.703 
1.000 
n.a. 
0.000 

Outlook sections 
NB 
0.563 
0.685 
0.703 
0.246 
0.230 
SVM 
0.703 
0.703 
1.000 
n.a. 
0.000 
(2) based on doc-
ument frequency 
and 
information 
gain 

CEO letters 
NB 
0.750 
0.774 
0.911 
0.636 
0.368 
SVM 
0.792 
0.810 
0.919 
0.718 
0.491 

Outlook sections 
NB 
0.704 
0.704 
1.000 
n.a. 
0.000 
SVM 
0.704 
0.704 
1.000 
n.a. 
0.000 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_5" validated="false"><head>Table 5 :</head><label>5</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Overview of the results of the supervised classification experiment. Bold numbers indicate the 
best results, U class UP, and D class DOWN. 

</table></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> Earning calls are regular events where managers report about the company&apos;s current situation and answer questions from business analysts.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="2"> This was the case for around 20 % of the documents.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="3"> The considered negation words are no, not, don&apos;t, never, none, and neither.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="4"> This affected 17 % of the data points in the sample.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="5"> A transcript of this speech is available at https://www.ecb.europa.eu/press/key/ date/2012/html/sp120726.en.html, accessed April 20th, 2015.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="6"> If the regression model is built with non-aggregated data, it explains only 6.6 % of the variation.</note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A Survey of Text Classification Algorithms</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Charu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Cheng Xiang</forename><surname>Aggarwal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Zhai</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Mining Text Data</title>
		<editor>Charu C. Aggarwal and Cheng Xiang Zhai</editor>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer Science+Business Media</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="163" to="222" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Measuring and Assessing Tone at the Top Using Annual Report CEO Letters. Institute of Chartered Accountants of Scotland</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Joel</forename><surname>Amernic</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Russel</forename><surname>Craig</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dennis</forename><surname>Tourish</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://eprints.port.ac.uk/12648" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010-03-28" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Risk Management in Banking</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Joël</forename><surname>Bessis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
			<publisher>John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Chichester, United Kingdom</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>2nd edition</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Inside the labyrinth of Basel riskweighted assets: how not to get lost</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Francesco</forename><surname>Cannata</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Simone</forename><surname>Casellina</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gregorio</forename><surname>Guidi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://www.bancaditalia.it/pubblicazioni/qef/2012-0132/QEF_132.pdf" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Number 132 in Questioni di Economia e Finanza. Banca d&apos;Italia</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012-09-20" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Council Regulation (EU) 1024/2013 of 15 October 2013 conferring specific tasks on the European Central Bank concerning policies relating to the prudential supervision of credit institutions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">U</forename><surname>Council Of The</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Official Journal of the European Union</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">287</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="63" to="89" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Risk Assessment of the European Banking System</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Authority</forename><surname>European Banking</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://www.eba.europa.eu/documents/10180/556730/EBA+Risk+Assessment+Report+June+2014.pdf/" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014-06" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">An intraday market risk management approach based on textual analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sven</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Groth</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jan</forename><surname>Muntermann</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Decision Support Systems</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">50</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="680" to="691" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Evaluating Sentiment in Annual Reports for Financial Distress Prediction Using Neural Networks and Support Vector Machines</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Petr</forename><surname>Hájek</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Vladimír</forename><surname>Olej</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Lazaros Iliadis, Harris Papadopoulos, and Chrisina Jayne</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Berlin Heidelberg</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">384</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="10" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Engineering Applications of Neural Networks</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">European Perspectives on the Global Financial Crisis: Introduction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dermot</forename><surname>Hodson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lucia</forename><surname>Quaglia</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Common Market Studies</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">47</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="939" to="953" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Textual sentiment in finance: A survey of methods and models</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Colm</forename><surname>Kearney</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sha</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2213801" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">International Review of Financial Analysis</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">33</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="171" to="185" />
			<date type="published" when="2014-05-26" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Retrieved</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Predicting Risk from Financial Reports with Regression</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Shimon</forename><surname>Kogan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dimitry</forename><surname>Levin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bryan</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Routledge</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jacob</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Sagi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Noah</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Smith</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of Human Language Technologies: The 2009 Annual Conference of the North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>Human Language Technologies: The 2009 Annual Conference of the North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="272" to="280" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Association for Computational Linguistics</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">When Is a Liability Not a Liability? Textual Analysis, Dictionaries, and 10-Ks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tim</forename><surname>Loughran</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bill</forename><surname>Mcdonald</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Finance</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">66</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">2</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Foundations of Statistical Natural Language Processing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Christopher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hinrich</forename><surname>Manning</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Schütze</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
			<publisher>MIT Press</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Cambridge, MA, USA</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Risk Sentiment Analysis in Banking Supervision</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Clemens</forename><surname>Nopp</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>Vienna University of Technology</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
	<note>Master&apos;s thesis</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Contextual valence shifters</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Livia</forename><surname>Polanyi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Annie</forename><surname>Zaenen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Computing Attitude and Affect in Text: Theory and Applications</title>
		<editor>JamesG. Shanahan, Yan Qu, and Janyce Wiebe</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Netherlands</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="10" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gerard</forename><surname>Salton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christopher</forename><surname>Buckley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1988" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<monogr>
				<title level="m">Term-weighting Approaches in Automatic Text Retrieval. Information Processing and Management</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="513" to="523" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Risk Ranking from Financial Reports</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ming-Feng</forename><surname>Tsai</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chuan-Ju</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 35th European Conference on Advances in Information Retrieval</title>
		<meeting>the 35th European Conference on Advances in Information Retrieval</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer-Verlag</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="804" to="807" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
