<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T11:47+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Identifying Political Sentiment between Nation States with Social Media</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
				<availability status="unknown"><p>Copyright Association for Computational Linguistics</p>
				</availability>
				<date type="published" when="2015-09">September 2015. 2015</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nathanael</forename><surname>Chambers</surname></persName>
							<email>nchamber@usna.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Naval Academy</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Victor</forename><surname>Bowen</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Naval Academy</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ethan</forename><surname>Genco</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Naval Academy</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xisen</forename><surname>Tian</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Naval Academy</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Eric</forename><surname>Young</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Naval Academy</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ganesh</forename><surname>Harihara</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Naval Academy</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Eugene</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Naval Academy</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Identifying Political Sentiment between Nation States with Social Media</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2015 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</title>
						<meeting>the 2015 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing <address><addrLine>Lisbon, Portugal</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="17" to="21"/>
							<date type="published" when="2015-09">September 2015. 2015</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>This paper describes an approach to large-scale modeling of sentiment analysis for the social sciences. The goal is to model relations between nation states through social media. Many cross-disciplinary applications of NLP involve making predictions (such as predicting political elections), but this paper instead focuses on a model that is applicable to broader analysis. Do citizens express opinions in line with their home country&apos;s formal relations? When opinions diverge over time, what is the cause and can social media serve to detect these changes? We describe several learning algorithms to study how the populace of a country discusses foreign nations on Twitter, ranging from state-of-the-art contextual sentiment analysis to some required practical learners that filter irrelevant tweets. We evaluate on standard sentiment evaluations, but we also show strong correlations with two public opinion polls and current international alliance relationships. We conclude with some political science use cases.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>The volume of text available on social media pro- vides a new opportunity for public policy and po- litical science. Specifically in the area of interna- tional relations, advances in natural language un- derstanding and sentiment analysis may offer new insights into the sentiment of one nation toward another. This paper processes 17 months of Twit- ter data to identify discussions about sovereign states, and it aggregates opinions toward these states from foreign nations. We present a novel application of contextual sentiment with this task, and identify several semi-supervised learning al- gorithms that are needed to address the reference resolution challenge inherent to country names. We present intrinsic evaluations of our learners on labeled datasets as well as four extrinsic politi- cal science evaluations that show strong alignment with our large-scale sentiment extraction.</p><p>An open question for international policy mak- ers is the extent to which public opinion drives de- cision making. How do military conflicts affect a neutral nation's relationship? Does public opin- ion shift toward a country after a formal alliance is created, or must popular opinion shift first? These questions are difficult to address due to the lack of measurable data. While polling data can be col- lected, collection beyond a handful of countries is cost prohibitive. This paper hypothesizes that sentiment analysis can be used as a proxy to track international relations between nation states. We describe the largest attempt (over 2 billion tweets) to measure nation state sentiment across hundreds of country pairs.</p><p>The core challenge to measuring public opin- ion between countries is an accurate algorithm to judge the sentiment of a text toward another na- tion. Unlike traditional sentiment analysis, the general sentiment of the text is not adequate. Let the following serve as an example.</p><p>I miss Pakistan. I am in full sad mode right about now.</p><p>@RachOrange <ref type="bibr">(California)</ref> This tweet is a positive example from the USA to- ward Pakistan. However, a typical sentiment clas- sifier misclassifies this as negative because miss and sad express sadness. A contextual sentiment classification is needed to identify that the predi- cate miss is positive toward its argument. Several recent competitions included contextual classifi- cation tasks, and this paper builds on the best of those algorithms for a unique nation-nation sen- timent classifier. We describe a multi-classifier model that aggregates tweets into counts of pos- itive and negative sentiment from one country to- ward another. Several unique filters are required to resolve textual references toward country names.</p><p>We first present standard NLP sentiment exper- iments that show the classifiers achieve good per- formance on individual tweets. To evaluate the complete nation-nation system, we present four novel evaluations, including two public opinion polls. Correlation with the polls is high at ρ = .8, and our nation-nation sentiment is 84% accurate with NATO and EU relations. We then discuss the implications for both NLP as a technical science and political science as a social science.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Previous Work</head><p>Sentiment analysis is a large field applicable to many genres. This paper focuses on social me- dia and contextual polarity, so we only address the closest work in those areas. For a broader perspec- tive, several survey papers are available <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">(Pang and Lee, 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b28">Tang et al., 2009;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Liu and Zhang, 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b30">Tsytsarau and Palpanas, 2012)</ref>.</p><p>Several sources for microblogs have been used to measure a large population's mood and opin- ion. O' <ref type="bibr">Connor et al. (2010)</ref> used Twitter data to compute a ratio of positive and negative words to measure consumer confidence and presidential ap- proval. <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Kramer (2010)</ref> counted lexicon words on Facebook for a general 'happiness' measure, and Thelwall (2011) built a general sentiment model on MySpace user comments. These are early gen- eral sentiment algorithms for social media.</p><p>Other microblog research focused on finding noisy training data with distant supervision. Many of these algorithms use emoticons as semantic in- dicators of polarity. For instance, a tweet that con- tains a sad face likely contains a negative polar- ity <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">(Read, 2005;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Go et al., 2009;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Bifet and Frank, 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b21">Pak and Paroubek, 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Davidov et al., 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Kouloumpis et al., 2011</ref>). In a similar vein, hashtags can serve as noisy labels ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Davidov et al., 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Kouloumpis et al., 2011</ref>). Our bootstrap learner is similar in its selection of seed tokens.</p><p>Supervised learning for contextual polarity has received more attention recently.  is an early approach. Work on product reviews sought the sentiment toward particular product features. These systems used rule based models based on parts of speech and surface fea- tures ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">Nasukawa and Yi, 2003;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Hu and Liu, 2004;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Ding and Liu, 2007)</ref>. Most notably, recent Se- meval competitions addressed contextual polarity <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">(Nakov et al., 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b25">Rosenthal et al., 2014</ref>). The top performing systems learned their own lexicons custom to the domain ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Mohammad et al., 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b32">Zhu et al., 2014</ref>). Our proposed system includes many of their features, but several fail to help on nation-nation sentiment.</p><p>Early approaches to topic detection on social media were straightforward, selecting a keyword (e.g., "Obama") to represent the topic (e.g., "US President") and retrieving tweets containing the word <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">(O'Connor et al., 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b31">Tumasjan et al., 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b27">Tan et al., 2011</ref>). These systems classify the polarity of the entire tweet, but ignore the ques- tion of polarity toward the particular topic. This paper focuses on identifying tweets with nation mentions, and identifying the sentiment toward the mention, not the overall sentiment of the text.</p><p>Event detection on Twitter is also relevant ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">Sakaki et al., 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Becker et al., 2011</ref>). In fact, O' <ref type="bibr">Connor et al. (2013)</ref> modeled events to detect international relations, but our goal is to model long term relation trends, not isolated events.</p><p>Large-scale computational studies of social me- dia are relatively new to the international relations community. <ref type="bibr">Barbera and Rivero (2014)</ref> is a no- table example for election analysis. Some studied online discussion about Palestine <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">(Lynch, 2014)</ref> and the role of Twitter in the Arab Spring <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(Howard et al., 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Howard, 2013)</ref>. However, they sim- ply counted the volume of tweets containing key- words. This paper applies a deeper NLP analysis and we show that frequency alone fails at detecting nation-nation relations.</p><p>Most relevant to this paper is a study of Ara- bic tweets into anti-American sentiment. <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Jamal et al. (2015)</ref> used a supervised sentiment classifier on Arabic tweets to measure sentiment toward the USA. Our paper differs by taking a broader view. We investigate with state-of-the-art sentiment al- gorithms, and we we study practical problems that arise within when measuring nation-nation senti- ment across all country pairs. To our knowledge, this paper is the largest computational approach (17 months with 2 billion tweets) to measuring in- ternational relations on social media.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Microblog Datasets</head><p>The main dataset for this study is 17 months of tweets obtained through the keyword Twitter API that mention one of 187 unique countries. The dataset spans from Sep. 3, 2013 to Jan 10, 2015 with 3-5 million tweets per day. Each tweet in- cludes the profile location and geolocation data (if available) of the user who posted the tweet. Col- lection was not limited to a specific location in or- der to retrieve samples from across the world. This dataset is used in all political science experiments (Sections 6.2 and 6.3).</p><p>A smaller labeled dataset is used for supervised classification. We randomly sampled the data to create a dataset of 4250 tweets. The authors ini- tially labeled each tweet with one of four senti- ment labels: positive, negative, objective, or ir- relevant. Text was only labeled as positive if it is positive toward the nation's mention. Text that contains a nation's mention, but does not contain sentiment toward the mention is labeled objective. Text with a mention that is not referent to a phys- ical country is labeled irrelevant despite presence of sentiment. This irrelevant distinction is a depar- ture from sentiment competitions. A second label- ing added a fifth label to the irrelevant tweets to split off dining topics.</p><p>Usernames (e.g., @user) and URLs are replaced with placeholder tokens. Multiple whitespace characters are condensed and the text is split on it. Punctuation attached to tokens is removed (but saved) and used in later punctuation features. Punctuation is not treated as separate tokens in the n-gram features. We prepend occurrences of "not" to their subsequent tokens, merging the two into a new token (e.g., "not happy" becomes "not- happy"). Once the raw text of the tweet is tok- enized as above, non-English tweets are filtered out. English filtering is performed by LingPipe 1 . We manually evaluated this filter and found it 86.2% accurate over 400 tweets. Accuracy is lost due to slang and the short nature of the text.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Classifying Nation-Nation Sentiment</head><p>Given a tweet containing a country's name, our goal is to identify the sentiment of the text toward that nation. Unlike most work on contextual polar- ity, this requires reference resolution of the target phrase (e.g., the country name). Previous Semeval competitions evaluate the sentiment of a text to- ward a phrase, but the semantics of the phrase is largely ignored. For instance, the following exam- ple would make an excellent Semeval test item, but its classification is irrelevant to the goal of measur- ing nation sentiment:</p><p>My daughter and I have been to Angelo's several times when in Little Italy. Love love it!</p><p>The author is obviously positively inclined to- ward Little Italy, however, Little Italy does not refer to the country of Italy. We found that most tweets referring to dining or visiting foreign- themed restaurants are not relevant to determining nation to nation sentiment. It became necessary to research new classifiers that perform basic refer- ence resolution.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">Reference Resolution: Irrelevant Detection</head><p>This paper defines reference resolution in the tra- ditional linguistic sense: determine the real-world referent of a text mention. Most NLP tasks use coreference resolution: determine the text an- tecedent of a text mention. This paper requires ref- erence resolution because the target phrase often does not refer to an actual geolocated country. Af- ter collecting months of tweets that include coun- try name mentions, data analysis revealed several types of these non-references. We treat reference resolution as a classification problem. Below are a variety of supervised and semi-supervised learn- ers that identify different types of errant country references, and ultimately serve to filter out these irrelevant tweets.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1.1">Dining Classifier</head><p>One of our early observations was that mentions of nations are often in the context of eating and dining, as evidenced here:</p><p>This is the first turkey sandwich I've had in awhile... It's great turkey.</p><p>Taste of China For chinese food lover's. For more info Please visit</p><p>This class of tweet is problematic to our study of international politics. While microblogs about dining can contain heavy emotion, a link to the writer's opinion about the foreign nation itself is ambiguous. We thus filter out dining text through supervised classification. Using the la- beled dataset in Section 3, we annotated a dine la- bel for all dining tweets. Tweets without a dine</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Dine Rel</head><p>All unigrams in text 1-3grams that include the country Bigram and Trigram country pattern Four Square app pattern Named Entity 2-3grams w/ country Emoticon happy or sad Ending text punctuation Binary: contains exclamation point <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>: Dining and Relevant features. label are considered not-dine. We ran a logistic regression for two labels, dine and not-dine. Text features are shown in <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1.2">Irrelevancy Classifier</head><p>Beyond dining, a broader class of irrelevant tweets refer to non-nation entities. These microblogs contain country names, but the mentions do not reference the physical country. The following ex- amples illustrate this class of irrelevant tweets (na- tion tokens in bold):</p><p>Yesterday was chilly out and now today's going to be 80. New England weather is so bipolar I hate it so much</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Bank Of America Upgrades ConocoPhillips On More Favorable Outlook</head><p>Several types of irrelevancy can be found, but the most common is a non-nation geolocation like New England. Proper nouns like Bank of Amer- ica are frequent as well. A named entity recog- nizer (NER) identified some of these, but we ulti- mately turned to supervised classification for bet- ter accuracy (space constraints prevent discussion of NER performance). We trained a logistic re- gression classifier on the relevant tweets in the Section 3 dataset, and mapped all other labels to irrelevant. Features used are shown in <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1.3">Bootstrap Learner</head><p>After filtering non-referent tweets, we observed that many positive and negative tweets reference countries in the context of sporting events and mu- sic/concerts. These are correctly labeled relevant by the above binary classifiers (and possibly anno- tated as positive or negative), but the topic (sports or music) does not contain a strong semantic con- nection to the author's actual opinion about the country. A couple of sport examples are given here:</p><p>@SpecialKBrook Wow -the Brittish judge scored the fight a draw -lucky England's fighters are better than their judges.</p><p>Congo LFC now someone give me that goalie's jersey :p</p><p>The sport topic has a less diverse vocabulary than other topics. We hypothesized that a boot- strap learning framework ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Riloff and Jones, 1999</ref>) could quickly learn its unique language without the need for supervised learning. Beginning with a short list of sport keywords (football, basket- ball, baseball, cricket, soccer, golf, hockey, rugby, game, vs), we ran two iterations of a bootstrapped learner. The first step retrieves tweets containing one of the keywords. The second counts token oc- currences in this set and computes pointwise mu- tual information (PMI) scores for each unigram by comparing with the unigram counts over the entire corpus. The learner processed˜190processed˜190 million tweets (a couple months of data). The PMI scores from this process then form the basis of a simple topic classifier.</p><p>A tweet is classified as a topic (e.g., sports) if its average token PMI score is above a learned thresh- old for that topic:</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">score T (text) = 1 N w∈text pmi T (w)<label>(1)</label></formula><p>where N is the number of tokens in the text and T ∈ {sports, concerts}. The text is classified as in topic if score T (text) &gt; λ t . The threshold λ T was determined by visual inspection of a held out 1000 tweets to maximize accuracy. The initial seed words and λ T thresholds for each topic are given here:</p><p>Seed Words λ football, basketball, baseball, cricket, soccer, golf, hockey, rugby, game, vs 0.08 concert, music, album, song, playlist, stage, drum 0.15</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">Contextual Sentiment Analysis</head><p>The above classifiers identify relevant tweets with references to geolocated nations. Approximately 21% are filtered out, leaving 79% for the remain- ing component of this paper: contextual sentiment analysis. Contextual sentiment analysis focuses on the disposition of text toward a word or phrase (in this case, a country's name). Most data-driven ap- proaches rely on labeled corpora to drive the learn- ing process, and this paper is no different. Assigning polarity to a word/phrase requires features that capture the surrounding context. The following tweets are examples of context with strong polarity toward the country in bold.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>RT @ChrissyCostanza: Happiest girl ever. I LOVE YOU SINGAPORE</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>there's no Singapore Got Talent cus the only tal- ent we have is stomping complaining &amp; staring</head><p>Singapore is the target country here. The first tweet is overtly positive toward it, but the second requires a more subtle interpretation. The nega- tive context is toward us, referencing the people of the Singapore anaphor. It seems reasonable to in- fer that they are negative toward the country as a whole, but a deeper reasoning is required to make the connection. These difficult decisions require a wide-range of lexical features. We build on the top performing features from contextual polarity sys- tems in <ref type="bibr">Semeval 2013</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(Mohammad et al., 2013</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b32">Zhu et al., 2014</ref>). We used the following set of features to capture these different contexts:</p><p>Token Features: All unigrams and bigrams.</p><p>Target Patterns: This feature creates patterns from n-grams that include the target word. The target is replaced with a variable to capture gen- eralized patterns. For instance, "to France last" becomes "to X last". Bigram and trigram patterns are created. Nation-Nation Learned Dictionary: Following the success of <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">Zhu et al. (2014)</ref>, we learn a mood dictionary from our domain-specific nation dataset. We count unigrams (bigrams did not improve performance) in one year of unfiltered tweets with nation mentions that contain an emoti- con. Using these counts, each unigram computes its PMI scores toward happy and sad contexts. We construct features based on these PMI scores: (1) the highest happy PMI score of all unigrams in a tweet, (2) the highest sad PMI score, (3) the num- ber of positive tokens, (4) the number of negative tokens, and (5) the sum of the token PMI differ- ences between happy-sad.</p><p>General Learned Dictionary: We computed the same features as in the above learned dictionary, but instead counted tokens in all tweets of the gen- eral emoticon corpus of <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Go et al. (2009)</ref>.</p><p>The contextual sentiment learner is trained on the labeled dataset (Section 3). Only tweets with positive, negative, or objective labels are included (irrelevant and dining are ignored). Stanford's CoreNLP (nlp.stanford.edu/software) is used to train a MaxEnt classifier with its default settings.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Nation to Nation Pipeline</head><p>The complete system to determine the nation- nation sentiment of a tweet consists of 3 steps: (1) identify the country origin of the tweet, (2) fil- ter out tweets without references to geolocated na- tions and filter out irrelevant topics, and (3) iden- tify the sentiment toward the country. We pro- cessed 17 months of tweets (Section 3).</p><p>The first step identifies the origin of the tweet with either its GPS coordinates or the profile lo- cation of the Twitter user. Profile locations are mapped to countries with an exhaustive list of country names, major cities, and patterns that match US city/states (e.g., Pensacola,FL maps to USA). Non-english tweets are removed with ling- pipe. The second step filters non-referent, irrel- evant, dining, and concert tweets with the clas- sifiers from Section 4.1 (about 21% of tweets at this stage). The final step is the contextual sen- timent classifier (Section 4.2). Tweets that make it through receive 1 of 3 possible labels: positive, negative, objective.</p><p>The aggregate counts of the three labels are col- lected for each day. This was around 1.2 million nation labels per day over 17 months. The counts are used for evaluation in the experiments.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Experiments</head><p>Our goal is to first prove the accuracy of our senti- ment classifiers, then show the broader pipeline's correlation with known nation-nation politics.We thus conducted three types of experiments. The first is an intrinsic evaluation of the classifiers with common frameworks from the NLP community. The second is an extrinsic evaluation from multi- ple political science datasets. The third is a set of use case proposals for application of this analysis.  <ref type="table">Table 2</ref>: Classifier performance. Precision/Recall is calculated for each label separately. Accuracy is over all labels: # correct/total.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.1">Classifier Experiments</head><p>The dining, irrelevant, and sentiment classifiers are supervised systems trained on a labeled dataset of 4,250 tweets. We split the dataset into training, dev, and test sets. The dev set contains 200 tweets, the test set has 750 tweets, and the training set size varied based on the available labels. The features in this paper were developed solely on the training and dev datasets. Reported results are on the un- seen test set of 750 tweets. The bootstrapped clas- sifiers for sports and concerts were learned with- out labeled data, so we ran the sports and concerts classifiers on an unseen portion of our data, and manually evaluated the first 200 tweets that were labeled by each classifier.</p><p>Precision and recall are calculated individually for each class label: P = #correct/#guessed and R = #correct/#gold. Where #guessed is how many times the classifier predicted the target label, and #gold is how many times the target la- bel appears in the dataset. Accuracy is also shown, calculated as a single score over all labels together: Accuracy = #correct/N . The first table in <ref type="table">Ta- ble 2</ref> shows the dining classifier's performance. The majority class baseline is high at 93% because only 7% of the data is about dining. The clas- sifier achieves a 29% decrease in accuracy error (2% absolute increase). The second table shows the more general irrelevant classifier. The majority class baseline is much lower than dining at 58.7%. Many tweets that contain a country name are not relevant nor references to the geolocated country itself. Our trained classifier does well on this task achieving 84% accuracy, a 26% absolute increase over baseline. It is 84% precise with 90% recall on detecting irrelevant tweets. The third table in <ref type="table">Ta- ble 2</ref> shows sentiment classifier results. Accuracy is almost 10% absolute above the majority class.</p><p>Finally, the bootstrapped classifiers perform at 98% accuracy for sports and 90% for concerts.  <ref type="table">Table 3</ref>: Positive/Negative ratios for the US to- ward its top 10 frequently mentioned nations.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.2">Nation-Nation Sentiment Experiments</head><p>Nation opinions are represented as directed edges: each edge (X,Y) represents the opinion of nation X toward nation Y. The weight of an edge is the ratio of positive to negative counts:</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">R(X, Y ) = C(X, Y, positive)/C(X, Y, negative)</formula><p>where C(X,Y,L) is the number of tweets by nation X users about nation Y with sentiment L. Only tweets that make it through the Nation to Nation Pipeline of Section 5 receive sentiment labels. If a nation pair (X,Y) was observed less than 1000 times, it is not included in the evaluations. We provide experiments later to evaluate this cutoff's affect. The dataset (Section 3) spans 17 months from 2013-2015. All tweets are classified or filtered out, and R(X,Y) is computed for all pairs. <ref type="table">Table  3</ref> shows the top 10 nation pair ratios (with over 500k tweets between them) for the U.S.</p><p>We present four formal evaluations to answer the central question of this paper: can sentiment from social media be used to help approximate in- ternational opinions? The first two experiments use public opinion polls of national sentiment to- ward other nations. The third uses military con- flicts as a proxy for negative relations, and the fourth uses current formal alliances as a proxy for positive relations. None of these can provide a complete picture of the connection between pop- ular sentiment and international relations, but the four together provide a strong case that sentiment contains a useful signal.   <ref type="table">Table 4</ref>: Polling Data: ranking of a nation's "posi- tive contribution" to the world, compared to auto- matically identified nation-nation sentiment.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Correlation: Public Opinion Polls</head><p>Each year, GlobeScan/PIPA releases polling data of 16 nations in a ranked ordering based on how 26,000 people view their "positive contribu- tion" to the world 3 . This poll helps to determine whether or not this paper's sentiment pipeline matches human polling. We created our own rank- ing by assigning a world score to each nation n: the average sentiment ratio of all other na- tions toward n. Since the polling data also ranks the EU, we average the EU member nation world scores for an EU world score. <ref type="table">Table 4</ref> shows the PIPA poll (Human Poll) and our world ranking (Sentiment). Using Spearman's rank correlation coefficient to measure agreement, our ranking is strongly correlated at ρ = 0.8 (perfect is 1.0). The main mistake in our ranking is Germany. We also compare against a Frequency Baseline to elim- inate the possibility that it's simply a matter of topic popularity. Poll rankings could simply be correlated with who people choose to discuss, or vice versa. The frequency baseline is the aver- age number of twitter mentions per nation (i.e., the most discussed). This baseline shows no correla- tion at ρ = −.06.</p><p>We then evaluated against a US-centric polling agency, Gallup. They asked Americans to rate other nations as 'favorable' or 'unfavorable' in a 2014 poll <ref type="bibr">4</ref> . The result is a ranking of favora- bility. In contrast to the PIPA poll which evalu-ates many nations looking in, Gallup evaluates a single nation looking out. Space constraints pre- vent us from visually showing the US ranking, but again the sentiment ratios have a strong cor- relation at ρ = .81. The frequency baseline is ρ = .23. The nation-nation sentiment extraction strongly correlates with both world views (PIPA) and US-specific views (Gallup).</p><p>The third evaluation uses a political science dataset from the Correlates of War Project, the Militarized Interstate Disputes v4.01 (MID) ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Ghosn et al., 2004</ref>). This dataset is used in the field of international relations, listing conflicts since 1816. We limit the evaluation to conflicts after 1990 to keep relations current. The dataset ends at 2001, so while not a completely current evaluation, it stands as a proxy for negative rela- tions. Each conflict in MID is labeled with a con- flict severity. We convert severity labels between nations to a pair score MID(X,Y):</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">M ID(X, Y ) = d∈Disputes(X,Y ) score(d)<label>(2)</label></formula><p>where Disputes(X,Y) is the set of conflicts be- tween the two nations X and Y, and score(d) is a severity score for the type of dispute d. War is -5, use of force is -4, displays of force is -3, threaten- ing use of force is -2, and no militarized action is -1. We take the sum of severity scores and save all nation pairs (X,Y) such that M ID(X, Y ) &lt; −10. This score indicates multiple conflicts and are thus considered as nations with true negative relations. We then compare our sentiment ratios R(X,Y) against these gold negative pairs. Each continuous R(X,Y) is discretized into sentiment categories for ease of comparison. Since the mean across all R(X,Y) is 1.25, we consider an interval around 1.25 as neutral and create positive and negative la- bels above and below that neutral center:</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">ratiolabel(Z) =              positive, if Z ≥ 2.4 slightpos, if 2.4 &gt; Z ≥ 1.4 neutral, if 1.4 &gt; Z ≥ 1.1 slightneg, if 1.1 &gt; Z ≥ 0.8 negative, if 0.8 &gt; Z</formula><p>The bottom table in <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">Table 5</ref> shows the number of nation pairs that align with the negative labels of the MID dataset. Only pairs that have at least 1000 tweets are evaluated. Of the resulting 90 pairs, 61 are correctly identified by our system as neg- ative or slight negative for an accuracy of 68%.  labels are between nations with a smaller Twit- ter presence, so performance likely suffers due to lack of data. For robustness testing, we shifted the thresholds that discretize the nation ratios and MID scores into postive and negative categories. The accuracy result shows little change. We also reran the experiment with a higher cutoff of 10,000 instead of 1,000. The negative disputes accuracy increases from 68% to 81%, but the recall obvi- ously drops as less countries are included. This suggests the sentiment ratios might be used on a sliding confidence scale based on frequency of mention.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Positive: Formal Alliances</head><p>To evaluate positive relations, we use current alliances as a fourth evaluation. NATO and the EU are the main global alliances with elements of mutual defense. We do not include trade-only alliances as trade is not always an indication of allegiance and approval (Russia and Ukraine is a current example of this disparity). This evaluation considers pairs of nations within NATO and within the EU as gold positive relations. We compare our sentiment ratios to these pairs in the top of <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">Table 5</ref>. This evaluation is broader than the conflict evalu- ation because NATO and EU nations have more of a Twitter presence. Of the 482 country pairs, our positive/slightpos accuracy is 84.2%.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.3">Application Experiments</head><p>We now briefly discuss how these positive results for nation-nation sentiment relates to political sci- ence analysis.</p><p>One core area of study is how national sen- timent shifts over time, and why. Computing R(X,Y) on a bi-weekly basis, <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 1</ref> graphs the sentiment ratio from the USA toward India and Is- rael. The timeline shows significant favorability toward India during their extended election sea-  son, but afterward the opinion is similar to before the election. In contrast, the 2014 Israel-Gaza con- flict shows a very different effect. US opinion of Israel is initially steady (slightly positive) until the conflict causes a large dip. Unlike India's spike, US opinion stays depressed even after the conflict concludes. It appears to have only risen to 'nor- mal' levels months later. We do note that the wa- ter is slightly muddied because our algorithm may not distinguish well between sentiment toward the war, Israel itself, or even sympathy toward casu- alties. However, it's clear that nation-nation sen- timent is captured, and future work is needed to identify finer grained sentiment as needed.</p><p>Another application is inter-alliance relations. For instance, <ref type="table" target="#tab_7">Table 6</ref> shows how NATO member nations view other alliances. The table shows the average of all R(X,Y) edges for each nation within an alliance to a nation in the other. According to our ratios, NATO countries have stark differences between how they view themselves versus how they view African Union/Arab League nations. Further, our pipeline enables analysis of outside nations looking in. For instance, the nations with the most positive view of the EU are Uruguay, Lithuania (EU member), Belarus, Moldova, and Slovakia (EU member). Almost all (not Uruguay) are eastern european nations. Moldova is currently seeking EU membership and Belarus had closer ties until recently. Our results might point to po- tential future alliances. Future work is needed to explore this implied connection.</p><p>Finally, the R(X,Y) ratios can also represent a nation's opinion profile. Represent each nation X by a vector of its R(X,Y) ratios. This represents its entire international view based on social me-   dia sentiment. Space prohibits more detail, but we clustered opinion profiles with k-means (k=12) and cosine similarity. Typical alliances, such as European and African clusters, are learned.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.4">Ablation Tests</head><p>The sentiment pipeline includes two practical fil- ters to remove tweets about dining and sports. We added these during training and developement solely based on our interpretation and analysis of the data. We did not evaluate on the test datasets until the very end. <ref type="table" target="#tab_8">Table 7</ref> shows results from the MID evaluation with the dining and sports filters removed in sequence. The number of correctly identified negative na- tion pairs is mostly unchanged, but the number of incorrect decisions increases dramatically. This occurs because a greater number of tweets make it through the pipeline. Further, this shows that the filters effectively remove tweets that cause mis- classification errors.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7">Discussion</head><p>This work is an important first step toward auto- matic means to broadly detect international rela- tions from social media. We use sentiment analy- sis as a proxy for extracting at least one aspect of the large set of factors involved in such relations. This paper is the largest application of sentiment analysis across a diverse set of nation-nation pairs (hundreds of country pairs over 17 months), and we showed that this sentiment is strongly corre- lated (ρ = 0.8) with two independent public opin- ion polls. These correlations more importantly suggest that we are not simply identifying a bi- nary positive or negative relation, but that the rela- tive sentiment scores are useful. The failure of fre- quency baselines on this ranking further suggests that this is not a side effect of topic frequency.</p><p>One argument against using public opinion polls for an evaluation is that the same people who are polled by PIPA might be the same peo- ple who tend to voice opinions on Twitter. The Twitter dataset is not independent from the polls, so the strong correlation we found could simply be a matter of sampling the same population. This is not possible to know, but whether or not it is the case, this paper's pipeline could be quite valuable in automating expensive and time consuming hu- man polls.</p><p>The results that focused on positive sentiment (polls and alliances) are quite high. Negative sen- timent revealed a lower 68% accuracy on the MID dataset, but it is due to the fact that nation-nation conflicts often occur between smaller nations that are not represented well on Twitter. Requiring a higher observed count improves accuracy to 81%.</p><p>While we are cautious not to make broad claims about discovering international relations on Twit- ter, we are encouraged by the experimental align- ment with current alliances and historical conflict data. The sentiment timeline for Israel and India <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">(Figure 1</ref>) is also intriguing. Tracking nation rela- tions over a longer time period presents an oppor- tunity for future study. This continual tracking of sentiment is one of the most obvious benefits of an automated approach.</p><p>Finally, an interactive world map is available to browse this paper's data at www.usna.edu/Users/cs/nchamber/nations. Each nation can be selected to visually color the map with its positive/negative lens, and timelines showing sentiment shifts between nations are vis- ible. All code, data, and results are also available on this page. We hope this work encourages even further connections between NLP and political science.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Punctuation:</head><label></label><figDesc>End of sentence punctuation and punctuation attached to target words. Prefix and postfix punctuation are separate features. Emoticons: Two binary features for the pres- ence/absence of smiley and sad face emoticons. Hand-Built Dictionary: Two binary features, postivemood and negativemood, indicate if a token appears in a sentiment lexicon's positive or nega- tive list. We use Bing Liu's Opinion Lexicon 2 .</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Human</head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: USA opinion of India/Israel over 2-week intervals from Sep-2013 to Feb-2015.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4" validated="false"><head>Table 5 :</head><label>5</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Top: The number of NATO/EU nation 
pairs with automatic sentiment labels. Bottom: 
The number of pairs with military disputes (MID 
dataset) and automatic sentiment labels. 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_6" validated="false"><head>Inter -Alliance Opinion Ratios</head><label>Inter</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Source 
Target 
Average R(X,Y) 
NATO 
African Union 
0.45 
NATO 
Arab League 
0.48 
NATO 
European Union 
1.51 
NATO 
NATO 
1.55 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_7" validated="false"><head>Table 6 :</head><label>6</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Average pos/neg ratio of NATO nations 
toward the nations in other formal alliances. 

MID Accuracy with Filters 
Filters 
Correct Incorrect Acc. 
Dining+Sports 
61 
29 
68% 
Sports only 
61 
37 
62% 
None 
56 
51 
52% 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_8" validated="false"><head>Table 7 : Filtering effects on the MID results.</head><label>7</label><figDesc></figDesc><table></table></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> alias-i.com/lingpipe/#lingpipe</note>

			<note place="foot" n="2"> http://www.cs.uic.edu/˜liub/FBS/sentiment-analysis.html</note>

			<note place="foot" n="3"> http://www.worldpublicopinion.org/pipa/2013CountryRatingPoll.pdf 4 http://www.gallup.com/poll/1624/perceptions-foreign-countries.aspx</note>

			<note place="foot" n="19"> positive pairs are incorrectly aligned with MIDnegative. Error analysis shows that many incorrect</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>This work was supported in part by the DoD HPC Modernization Program. It also would not have been possible without the infrastructure support and help from the accommodating staff at the Maui HPCC. Special thanks to the reviewers and area chair for their parts in an exciting and fulfill-ing review process.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Understanding the political representativeness of twitter users</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Pablo</forename><surname>Barberá</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gonzalo</forename><surname>Rivero</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Social Science Computer Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014-12" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Beyond trending topics: Real-world event identification on twitter</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hila</forename><surname>Becker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mor</forename><surname>Naaman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Luis</forename><surname>Gravano</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">ICWSM</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="438" to="441" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Sentiment knowledge discovery in twitter streaming data</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Albert</forename><surname>Bifet</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Eibe</forename><surname>Frank</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Lecture Notes in Computer Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">6332</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="15" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Enhanced sentiment learning using twitter hashtags and smileys</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dmitry</forename><surname>Davidov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Oren</forename><surname>Tsur</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ari</forename><surname>Rappoport</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 23rd International Conference on Computational Linguistics (COLING</title>
		<meeting>the 23rd International Conference on Computational Linguistics (COLING</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The utility of linguistic rules in opinion mining</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xiaowen</forename><surname>Ding</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bing</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of SIGIR-2007</title>
		<meeting>SIGIR-2007</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="23" to="27" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The mid3 data set</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Faten</forename><surname>Ghosn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Glenn</forename><surname>Palmer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Stuart</forename><surname>Bremer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Procedures, coding rules, and description</title>
		<meeting>edures, coding rules, and description</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">21</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="133" to="154" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Conflict Management and Peace Science</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Twitter sentiment classification using distant supervision</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alec</forename><surname>Go</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Richa</forename><surname>Bhayani</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lei</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
<note type="report_type">Technical report</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Opening closed regimes: What was the role of social media during the arab spring? Technical</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Philip</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Howard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Aiden</forename><surname>Duffy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Deen</forename><surname>Freelon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011-09" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Muzammil Hussain, Will Mari, and Marwa Mazaid. Report working paper 2011.1, University of Washington</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Democracy&apos;s Fourth Wave? Digital Media and the Arab Spring</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Philip</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Howard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<publisher>Oxford University Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Mining and summarizing customer reviews</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Minqing</forename><surname>Hu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bing</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the ACM SIGKDD International Conference on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining</title>
		<meeting>the ACM SIGKDD International Conference on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Anti-americanism and anti-interventionism in arabic twitter discourses</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Amaney</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Robert</forename><forename type="middle">O</forename><surname>Jamal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Keohane</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dustin</forename><surname>Romney</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Tingley</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Perspectives on Politics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="55" to="73" />
			<date type="published" when="2015-03" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Target-dependent twitter sentiment classification</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Long</forename><surname>Jiang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mo</forename><surname>Yu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ming</forename><surname>Zhou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xiaohua</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tiejun</forename><surname>Zhao</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL-2011)</title>
		<meeting>the Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL-2011)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Twitter sentiment analysis: The good the bad and the omg!</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Efthymios</forename><surname>Kouloumpis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Theresa</forename><surname>Wilson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Johanna</forename><surname>Moore</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Fifth International AAAI Conference on Weblogs and Social Media</title>
		<meeting>the Fifth International AAAI Conference on Weblogs and Social Media</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">An unobtrusive behavioral model of &apos;gross national happiness</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">I</forename><surname>Adam</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Kramer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 28th International Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems</title>
		<meeting>the 28th International Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">A survey of opinion mining and sentiment analysis. Mining Text Data</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bing</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lei</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="415" to="463" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Arabs do care about gaza</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marc</forename><surname>Lynch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="www.washingtonpost.com/blogs/monkey-cage/wp/2014/07/14/arabs-do-care-about-gaza" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Nrc-canada: Building the stateof-the-art in sentiment analysis of tweets</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Saif</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Svetlana</forename><surname>Mohammad</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xiaodan</forename><surname>Kiritchenko</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Zhu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the seventh international workshop on Semantic Evaluation Exercises</title>
		<meeting>the seventh international workshop on Semantic Evaluation Exercises</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>SemEval-2013</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Semeval-2013 task 2: Sentiment analysis in twitter</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Preslav</forename><surname>Nakov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Zornitsa</forename><surname>Kozareva</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alan</forename><surname>Ritter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sara</forename><surname>Rosenthal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Veselin</forename><surname>Stoyanov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Theresa</forename><surname>Wilson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 7th International Workshop on Semantic Evaluation</title>
		<meeting>the 7th International Workshop on Semantic Evaluation</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Sentiment analysis: capturing favorability using natural language processing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tetsuya</forename><surname>Nasukawa</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jeonghee</forename><surname>Yi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of K-CAP</title>
		<meeting>K-CAP</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">From tweets to polls: Linking text sentiment to public opinion time series</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O&amp;apos;</forename><surname>Brendan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ramnath</forename><surname>Connor</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bryan</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Balasubramanyan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Noah</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Routledge</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Smith</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the AAAI Conference on Weblogs and Social Media</title>
		<meeting>the AAAI Conference on Weblogs and Social Media</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Learning to extract international relations from political context</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O&amp;apos;</forename><surname>Brendan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Connor</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Brandon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Noah A</forename><surname>Stewart</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Smith</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ACL (1)</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1094" to="1104" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Twitter as a corpus for sentiment analysis and opinion mining</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alexander</forename><surname>Pak</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Patrick</forename><surname>Paroubek</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Seventh International Conference On Language Resources and Evaluation (LREC)</title>
		<meeting>the Seventh International Conference On Language Resources and Evaluation (LREC)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Opinion mining and sentiment analysis. Foundations and Trends in Information Retrieval</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Pang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Using emoticons to reduce dependency in machine learning techniques for sentiment classification</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jonathon</forename><surname>Read</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the ACL Student Research Workshop (ACL-2005)</title>
		<meeting>the ACL Student Research Workshop (ACL-2005)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Learning dictionaries for information extraction by multi-level bootstrapping</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ellen</forename><surname>Riloff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rosie</forename><surname>Jones</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 16th National Conference on Artificial Intelligence (AAAI99)</title>
		<meeting>the 16th National Conference on Artificial Intelligence (AAAI99)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="474" to="479" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sara</forename><surname>Rosenthal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Preslav</forename><surname>Nakov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alan</forename><surname>Ritter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Veselin</forename><surname>Stoyanov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Sentiment analysis in twitter. Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Semeval-2014 task</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Earthquake shakes twitter users: real-time event detection by social sensors</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Takeshi</forename><surname>Sakaki</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Makoto</forename><surname>Okazaki</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yutaka</forename><surname>Matsuo</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 19th international conference on World wide web</title>
		<meeting>the 19th international conference on World wide web</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="851" to="860" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">User-level sentiment analysis incorporating social networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chenhao</forename><surname>Tan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lillian</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jie</forename><surname>Tang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Long</forename><surname>Jiang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ming</forename><surname>Zhou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ping</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 17th ACM SIGKDD Conference on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining</title>
		<meeting>the 17th ACM SIGKDD Conference on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A survey on sentiment detection of reviews</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Tang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Tan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Cheng</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Expert Systems with Applications</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Sentiment in twitter events</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mike</forename><surname>Thelwall</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kevan</forename><surname>Buckley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Georgios</forename><surname>Paltoglou</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of the American Society for Information Science and Technology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">62</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="406" to="418" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Survey on mining subjective data on the web</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Tsytsarau</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Palpanas</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Data Mining and Knowledge Discovery Journal</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="478" to="514" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Election forecasts with twitter: How 140 characters reflect the political landscape</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Andranik</forename><surname>Tumasjan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Timm</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Philipp</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Sprenger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Isabell</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Sandner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Welpe</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Social Science Computer Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Nrc-canada-2014: Recent improvements in the sentiment analysis of tweets</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xiaodan</forename><surname>Zhu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Svetlana</forename><surname>Kiritchenko</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Saif</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Mohammad</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the seventh international workshop on Semantic Evaluation Exercises</title>
		<meeting>the seventh international workshop on Semantic Evaluation Exercises</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>SemEval-2013</note>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
