<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T13:01+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Natural Language Model Re-usability for Scaling to Different Domains</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date>November 1-5, 2016</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Young-Bum</forename><surname>Kim</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Microsoft Corporation</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Redmond</settlement>
									<region>WA</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alexandre</forename><surname>Rochette</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Microsoft Corporation</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Redmond</settlement>
									<region>WA</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ruhi</forename><surname>Sarikaya</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Microsoft Corporation</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Redmond</settlement>
									<region>WA</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Natural Language Model Re-usability for Scaling to Different Domains</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2016 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</title>
						<meeting>the 2016 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing <address><addrLine>Austin, Texas</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="2071" to="2076"/>
							<date type="published">November 1-5, 2016</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Natural language understanding is the core of the human computer interactions. However , building new domains and tasks that need a separate set of models is a bottleneck for scaling to a large number of domains and experiences. In this paper, we propose a practical technique that addresses this issue in a web-scale language understanding system: Microsoft&apos;s personal digital assistant Cortana. The proposed technique uses a constrained decoding method with a universal slot tagging model sharing the same schema as the collection of slot taggers built for each domain. The proposed approach allows reusing of slots across different domains and tasks while achieving virtually the same performance as those slot taggers trained per domain fashion.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Recently there has been tremendous investment into the personal digital assistants by big technology companies <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">(Sarikaya, 2015;</ref>). Apple's SIRI, Google Now, Microsoft's Cortana and Amazon's Alexa are examples of such systems. Nat- ural language understanding ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Gupta et al., 2006;</ref><ref type="bibr">Tur and De Mori, 2011</ref>)is at the core of these systems providing natural communication between the user and the agent. These systems support a number of scenarios including creating reminders, setting up alarms, note taking, scheduling meetings, finding and consuming entertainment (i.e. movie, music, games), finding places of interest and getting driv- ing directions to them. The domains supported by these systems are on the order of tens (not in hun- dreds) and adding new domains and experiences is a scaling problem that has not been solved yet <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(Tur, 2006;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Jeong and Lee, 2009;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b3">El-Kahky et al., 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Kim et al., 2015d</ref>).</p><p>The primary reason behind this is that each do- main requires potentially a new schema, intents and slots extracted from the natural language query. That, in turn requires collecting and annotating new data, which is the most expensive step in terms of time and money, and building a new set of domain specific models to support the new domains and sce- narios. Slot modeling in particular is the most de- manding component in terms of the difficulty of an- notation and modeling.</p><p>In this study, we propose a new approach that re- duces the cost of scaling natural language under- standing to a large number of domains and expe- riences without significantly sacrificing the accu- racy. The approach consists of a universal slot tag- ging method and a runtime technique called con- strained decoding that performs the decoding ac- cording a specific schema. The proposed approach, heavily enables reusing existing slot modeling data that are collected and annotated for potentially dif- ferent domains and applications, for building new domains and applications. The new domains can be expressed in terms of existing semantic schema.</p><p>The rest of the paper is organized as follows. In the next section, we talk about universal slot mod- eling. In section 3, we present the constrained de- coding technique. We describe the experimental set up, results and analysis in section 4 followed by the conclusions and future directions in section 5.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Universal Slot Tagging</head><p>The first step is to build a universal slot tagger, a sin- gle model that can handle all the domains an agent (e.g. Cortana) can support. In <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">Table 1</ref>, we show a subset of the domains that are supported by Cortana for experimentation purposes.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">Universal Slot Tagger Training</head><p>To train the universal slot tagger, we consider two simple and intuitive approaches: Binary and All-in- one.</p><p>Suppose we have a combined k slots across do- mains and also have access to the labeled data, Bi- nary approach trains k binary classifier one for each slot type. For each binary slot tagger targeting a spe- cific slot type, the labeled data is programatically mapped to create a new labeled data set, where only the target label is kept while all the other labels are mapped "other" label. All-in-one approach simply trains a single model by aggregating queries across all domains.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">Slot Tagging Ambiguity</head><p>Universal slot tagging model has an advantage, which can share schema across all domains used for training time. In spite of the advantage, there are ambiguity problems caused by combining all do- mains (and the underlying data) into a single model. The problems can be grouped into two categories:</p><p>• Imbalanced training data distribution: The amount of training data varies across domains. Universal slot model may have bias towards predicting the slots in domains with larger training data. For example, slots with less train- ing data (e.g. app name in MEDIACONTROL domain could be overwhelmed by slots with large training data (e.g. place name in PLACES domain).</p><p>• Domain-specific schema: In practice, the do- mains the system handles are not constructed at the same time. They are designed for dif- ferent application back-ends, requirements and scenarios at different points in time. In other words, the semantic schema for a domain is de- signed without considering other domains. In ALARM domain, the slot indicating time is sub- divided into sub-slots such as start time repre- senting starting time, duration representing du- ration for an alarm. In contrast, in PLACES do- main, there is only a single slot indicating time (time).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Constrained Decoding</head><p>Slot tagging is considered as a sequence learning problem <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Deoras and Sarikaya, 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Li et al., 2009;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Xu and Sarikaya, 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Celikyilmaz et al., 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Kim et al., 2015b;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Kim et al., 2015c;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Kim et al., 2015a</ref>). In sequence learning, given a sam- ple query x 1 . . . x n , the decoding problem is to find the most likely slot sequence among all the possible sequences, y 1 . . . y n :</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">f (x 1 . . . x n ) = arg max y 1 ...yn p(x 1 . . . x n , y 1 . . . y n )</formula><p>Here, we assume that output space in training is same as those in test time.</p><p>However, in our problem, output (slot) space in test time can be different from those in training time. At test time, we may observe different slot se- quences than what is observed in the training time. This is not an issue for the Binary approach, since we can use the output of the selected taggers needed for the new domain. We simply use general decod- ing approach with each of the selected taggers. Note that a given query is run as many times as the num- bers of slot types covered in a given domain.</p><p>For All-in-One technique, we consider two possi- ble approaches: Post-Filter and Constrained Decod- ing. With Post-Filter, we simply provide the best hypothesis generated by the slot tagger that meets the domain schema constraints, by computing the full n-best of slots and filtering out the slot types</p><note type="other">that do not meet the target domain schema. With Constrained Decoding, given a schemã y ⊂ y for the target domain, we first define a constrained lat- tice lattice Y(x, ˜ y)</note><formula xml:id="formula_1">= Y(x 1 , ˜ y) × . . . × Y(x n , ˜ y)</formula><p>, as shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref>. Then, we perform the decoding in the constrained lattice:</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">f (x 1 . . . x n , ˜ y) = arg max Y(x,˜ y) p(x 1 . . . x n , y 1 . . . y n )</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Experiments</head><p>In this section, we conducted a series of experiments to evaluate the proposed techniques on datasets ob- tained from real usage.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">Experimental Setup</head><p>To test the effectiveness of the proposed approach, we apply it to a suite of 16 Cortana domains for slot tagging tasks. The data statistics and short descriptions are shown in <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">Table 1</ref>. As the ta- ble indicates, the domains have different granu- larity and diverse semantics. Note that we keep domain-specific slots such as alarm state, but there are enough shared labels across domains. For exam- ple, ALARM domain, there are 6 shared slots among 8 slots. There are 62 slots appearing more than one domain. Especially, some basic slots such as time, date,place name,person name,location and product appear in most domains.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">Slot Taggers</head><p>In all our experiments, we trained Conditional Ran- dom Fields (CRFs)( <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Lafferty et al., 2001</ref>) and used n-gram features up to n = 3, regular expression, lexicon features, and Brown Clusters ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Brown et al., 1992)</ref>. With these features, we compare the follow- ing methods for slot tagging 1 :</p><p>• In-domain: Train a domain specific model us- ing the domain specific data covering the slots supported in that domain.</p><p>• Binary: Train a binary classifier for each slot type, combine the slots needed for a given do- main schema.</p><p>• Post: Train a single model with all domain data, take the one-best parse of the tagger and filter- out slots outside the domain schema.</p><p>• Const: Train a single model with all domain data and then perform constrained decoding us- ing a domain specific schema.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3">Results</head><p>For the first scenario, we assume that test domain semantic schema is a subset of training domain schema. The results of this scenario are shown in For the second scenario, we consider a new set of test domains not covered in the training set, as shown in <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">Table 3</ref>. The amount of training data for the test domains are limited (&lt; 5K). These domains lack training data for the location and app name slots. When we use universal slot tagger with con- strained decoding Const yields 94.30%. On average, Const increases F1-score by <ref type="bibr">1</ref>     corresponding a 20% decrease in relative error. We believe that universal slot tagger learns to tag these slots from data available in PLACES and ENTER- TAINMENT domains. For the last scenario shown in <ref type="table" target="#tab_5">Table 4</ref>, we assume that we do not have training data for the test do- mains. The Const performs reasonably well, yield- ing 94.48% on average. Interestingly, for the TRAN- SIT domain, we can get almost perfect tagging per- formance of 99.5%. Note that all tags in TRANSIT and TAXI domains are fully covered by our universal models, but the MEDIACONTROL domain is par- tially covered.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.4">Discussion</head><p>By using the proposed technique, we maximize the reuse of existing data labeled for different do- mains and applications. The proposed technique allows mixing and matching of slots across differ- ent domains to create new domains. For exam- ple, we can tag the slots in the SHOWTIMES do- main, which involves finding a movie to watch by using movie titles, actor names from the ENTER- TAINMENT domain, and the location of the the- ater by using location, place name slots from the PLACES domain. If the new domain needs some new slots that are not covered by the universal tag- ger, then some examples queries could be annotated and added to the universal slot tagger training data to retrain the models. Instead of maintaining a separate slot tagger for each domain, one needs to maintain a single slot tagger. The new slots added can be used by future domains and applications.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Conclusions</head><p>We proposed a solution for scaling domains and ex- periences potentially to a large number of use cases by reusing existing data labeled for different do- mains and applications. The universal slot tagging coupled with constrained decoding achieves almost as good a performance as those slot taggers built in a domain specific fashion. This approach enables creation of virtual domains through any combina- tion of slot types covered in the universal slot tagger schema, reducing the need to collect and annotate the same slot types multiple times for different do- mains. One of the future directions of research is to extend the same idea to the intent modeling, where we can re-use intent data built for different applica- tions and domains for a new domain. Also, we plan to extend the constrained decoding idea to slot tag- ging with neural networks ( , which achieved gains over CRFs.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: Constrained Lattice: Disabling nodes and transition while decoding the lattice to honor given constraints of domain schema.</figDesc><graphic url="image-1.png" coords="2,313.20,57.83,226.80,180.41" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" validated="false"><head>Table 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>We consider In-domain as a plausible up-
per bound on the performance, yielding 94.16% of 
F1 on average. First, Binary has the lowest perfor-
mance of 75.85%. We believe that when we train 
a binary classifier for each slot type, the other slots 
that provide valuable contextual information for the 
slot sequence are ignored. This leads to degradation 
in tagging accuracy. Post improves F1 scores across 
domains, resulting into 86.50% F1 on average. Note 
that this technique does not handle ambiguities and 
data distribution mismatch due to combining mul-
tiple domain specific data with different data sizes. 
Finally, Const lead to consistent gains across all do-
mains, achieving 93.36%, which almost matches the 
In-domain performance. The reason why Const per-
forms better than Binary is that Const constrains the 
best path search to the target domain schema. It does 
not consider the schema elements that are outside 
the target domain schema. By doing so, it addresses 
the training data distribution issue as well as overlap 
on various schema elements. 
</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" validated="true"><head>Table 1 : The overview of data we used and descriptions.</head><label>1</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Domain 
In-domain Binary Post Const 
ALARM 
96.24 
76.49 91.86 95.33 
CALENDAR 
91.79 
75.62 80.58 90.19 
COMM. 
95.06 
84.17 88.19 94.76 
ENTER. 
96.05 
85.39 90.42 95.84 
MYSTUFF 
88.34 
51.3 
80.6 87.51 
ONDEVICE 
97.65 
70.16 
77.8 96.43 
PLACES 
92.39 
75.27 87.63 91.36 
REMIND 
91.53 
72.67 88.98 91.1 
WEATHER 
98.37 
91.56 92.45 97.73 
Average 
94.16 
75.85 86.50 93.36 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3" validated="true"><head>Table 2 : Performance for universal models.</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Domain 
In-domain Const 
ORDERFOOD 
93.62 
95.63 
RESERVATIONS 
93.03 
94.58 
EVENTS 
92.82 
94.28 
SHOWTIMES 
92.07 
92.69 
Average 
92.89 
94.30 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4" validated="false"><head>Table 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Performance for prototype domains. 

TAXI TRANSIT MEDIAC. AVG. 
Const 90.86 
99.5 
93.08 
94.48 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_5" validated="false"><head>Table 4 : Results across new domains.</head><label>4</label><figDesc></figDesc><table></table></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> For parameter estimation, we used L-BFGS (Liu and Nocedal, 1989) with 100 as the maximum iteration count and 1.0 for the L2 regularization parameter.</note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Classbased n-gram models of natural language</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Peter F Brown</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Peter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Robert</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Desouza</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Vincent J Della</forename><surname>Mercer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jenifer C</forename><surname>Pietra</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Lai</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Computational linguistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">18</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="467" to="479" />
			<date type="published" when="1992" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Enriching word embeddings using knowledge graph for semantic tagging in conversational dialog systems. AAAI-Association for the Advancement of Artificial Intelligence</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Asli</forename><surname>Celikyilmaz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dilek</forename><surname>Hakkani-Tur</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Panupong</forename><surname>Pasupat</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ruhi</forename><surname>Sarikaya</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015-01" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Deep belief network markov model sequence classification spoken language understanding</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Anoop</forename><surname>Deoras</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ruhi</forename><surname>Sarikaya</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Interspeech</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Extending domain coverage of language understanding systems via intent transfer between domains using knowledge graphs and search query click logs</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ali</forename><surname>El-Kahky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xiaohu</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ruhi</forename><surname>Sarikaya</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gokhan</forename><surname>Tur</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dilek</forename><surname>Hakkani-Tur</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Larry</forename><surname>Heck</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">2014 IEEE International Conference on Acoustics, Speech and Signal Processing (ICASSP)</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>IEEE</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="4067" to="4071" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The at&amp;t spoken language understanding system</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Narendra</forename><surname>Gupta</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gokhan</forename><surname>Tur</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dilek</forename><surname>Hakkani-Tur</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Srinivas</forename><surname>Bangalore</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Giuseppe</forename><surname>Riccardi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mazin</forename><surname>Gilbert</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE Transactions on Audio, Speech, and Language Processing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="213" to="222" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Multidomain spoken language understanding with transfer learning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Minwoo</forename><surname>Jeong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gary Geunbae</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Speech Communication</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">51</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="412" to="424" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Weakly supervised slot tagging with partially labeled sequences from web search click logs</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Young-Bum</forename><surname>Kim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Minwoo</forename><surname>Jeong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Karl</forename><surname>Stratos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ruhi</forename><surname>Sarikaya</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Conference of the North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics: Human Language Technologies (NAACLHLT)</title>
		<meeting>the Conference of the North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics: Human Language Technologies (NAACLHLT)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="84" to="92" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Compact lexicon selection with spectral methods</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Young-Bum</forename><surname>Kim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Karl</forename><surname>Stratos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xiaohu</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ruhi</forename><surname>Sarikaya</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL)</title>
		<meeting>Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="806" to="811" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Pre-training of hidden-unit crfs</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Young-Bum</forename><surname>Kim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Karl</forename><surname>Stratos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ruhi</forename><surname>Sarikaya</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL)</title>
		<meeting>the Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="192" to="198" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">New transfer learning techniques for disparate label sets</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Young-Bum</forename><surname>Kim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Karl</forename><surname>Stratos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ruhi</forename><surname>Sarikaya</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Minwoo</forename><surname>Jeong</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ACL. Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Domainless adaptation by constrained decoding on a schema lattice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Young-Bum</forename><surname>Kim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Karl</forename><surname>Stratos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Minjoon</forename><surname>Seo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ruhi</forename><surname>Sarikaya</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the International Conference on Computational Linguistics (Coling). Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the International Conference on Computational Linguistics (Coling). Association for Computational Linguistics</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Conditional random fields: Probabilistic models for segmenting and labeling sequence data</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">John</forename><surname>Lafferty</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Andrew</forename><surname>Mccallum</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Fernando Cn</forename><surname>Pereira</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ICML</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="282" to="289" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Extracting structured information from user queries with semisupervised conditional random fields</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xiao</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ye-Yi</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alex</forename><surname>Acero</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 32nd international ACM SIGIR conference on Research and development in information retrieval</title>
		<meeting>the 32nd international ACM SIGIR conference on Research and development in information retrieval</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">On the limited memory bfgs method for large scale optimization</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Dong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jorge</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Nocedal</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Mathematical programming</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">45</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1-3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="503" to="528" />
			<date type="published" when="1989" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">An overview of end-to-end language understanding and dialog management for personal digital 2075 assistants</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ruhi</forename><surname>Sarikaya</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Paul</forename><surname>Crook</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alex</forename><surname>Marin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Minwoo</forename><surname>Jeong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jean-Philippe</forename><surname>Robichaud</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Asli</forename><surname>Celikyilmaz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Youngbum</forename><surname>Kim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alexandre</forename><surname>Rochette</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Omar</forename><forename type="middle">Zia</forename><surname>Khan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xiuahu</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Daniel</forename><surname>Boies</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tasos</forename><surname>Anastasakos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Zhalleh</forename><surname>Feizollahi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nikhil</forename><surname>Ramesh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hisami</forename><surname>Suzuki</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Roman</forename><surname>Holenstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Elizabeth</forename><surname>Krawczyk</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Vasiliy</forename><surname>Radoste</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">IEEE Workshop on Spoken Language Technology</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Keynote at Interspeech, Dresden, Germany. Gokhan Tur and Renato De Mori. 2011. Spoken language understanding: Systems for extracting semantic information from speech</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ruhi</forename><surname>Sarikaya</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
			<publisher>John Wiley &amp; Sons</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>The technology powering personal digital assistants</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Multitask learning for spoken language understanding</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gokhan</forename><surname>Tur</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the ICASSP</title>
		<meeting>the ICASSP<address><addrLine>Toulouse, France</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Targeted feature dropout for robust slot filling in natural language understanding</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Puyang</forename><surname>Xu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ruhi</forename><surname>Sarikaya</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ISCA-International Speech Communication Association</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014-09" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
