<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T10:56+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Beyond Canonical Texts: A Computational Analysis of Fanfiction</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date>November 1-5, 2016</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Smitha</forename><surname>Milli</surname></persName>
							<email>smilli@berkeley.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Computer Science Division</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">School of Information</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of California</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Berkeley</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Bamman</surname></persName>
							<email>dbamman@berkeley.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">University of California</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Berkeley</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Beyond Canonical Texts: A Computational Analysis of Fanfiction</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2016 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</title>
						<meeting>the 2016 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing <address><addrLine>Austin, Texas</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="2048" to="2053"/>
							<date type="published">November 1-5, 2016</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>While much computational work on fiction has focused on works in the literary canon, user-created fanfiction presents a unique opportunity to study an ecosystem of literary production and consumption, embodying qualities both of large-scale literary data (55 billion tokens) and also a social network (with over 2 million users). We present several empirical analyses of this data in order to illustrate the range of affordances it presents to research in NLP, computational social science and the digital humanities. We find that fan-fiction deprioritizes main protagonists in comparison to canonical texts, has a statistically significant difference in attention allocated to female characters, and offers a framework for developing models of reader reactions to stories .</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>The development of large-scale book collections- such as Project Gutenberg, Google Books, and the HathiTrust-has given rise to serious effort in the analysis and computational modeling of fiction ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Mohammad, 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Elsner, 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Bamman et al., 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Jockers, 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Chaturvedi et al., 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b19">Vala et al., 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Iyyer et al., 2016)</ref>. Of necessity, this work often reasons over historical texts that have been in print for decades, and where the only relationship between the author and the readers is mediated by the text itself. In this work, we present a computa- tional analysis of a genre that defines an alternative relationship, blending aspects of literary production, consumption, and communication in a single, vi- brant ecosystem: fanfiction.</p><p>Fanfiction is fan-created fiction based on a previ- ously existing, original work of literature. For clarity we will use the term CANON to refer to the original work on which a fanfiction story is based (e.g. Harry Potter) and the term STORY to refer to a single fan- authored story for some canon.</p><p>Although stories are based on an original canoni- cal work and feature characters from the canon, fans frequently alter and reinterpret the canon-changing its setting, playing out an alternative ending, adding an original character, exploring a minor character more deeply, or modifying the relationships between characters ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Barnes, 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Van Steenhuyse, 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b18">Thomas, 2011)</ref>.</p><p>In this work, we present an empirical analysis of this genre, and highlight several unique affordances this data presents for contemporary research in NLP, computational social science, and the digital human- ities. Our work is the first to apply computational methods to fanfiction; in presenting this analysis, we hope to excite other work in this area.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Fanfiction data</head><p>Our data, collected between March-April 2016, originates from fanfiction.net. 1 In this data, AUTHORS publish stories serially (one chapter at a time); REVIEWERS comment on those chapters.</p><p>A summary of data is presented in table 1. The scale of this data is large for text; at 55 billion to- kens, it is over 50 times larger than the BookCorpus ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Zhu et al., 2015)</ref> and over 10% the size of Google Books (at 468B tokens).</p><p>The dataset is predominantly written in English (88%), but also includes 317,011 stories in Span- ish, 148,475 in French, 102,439 in Indonesian, and 73,575 in Portuguese. In total, 44 different lan- guages are represented.  The systematic ways in which fanfiction stories dif- fer from their canonical works can give insight into the characteristics of a story that are desired by fans but may be missing from the mainstream canon. We investigate two questions: 1.) Is there a differ- ence between the characters emphasized in fanfic- tion compared to the original canon? And 2.) Is gender presented differently in these two sources?</p><p>Character differences. In order to explore the differing attention to character, we consider fanfic- tion from ten canons whose original texts appear in Project Gutenberg; we selected the ten canons from unique authors with the most fanfiction stories as- sociated with them. <ref type="bibr">2</ref> To extract and compare char- acters, we run BookNLP ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Bamman et al., 2014</ref>) on both the canonical work and the top 100 stories (by number of reviews) from each canon, and pair char- acters across canon/fanfiction with the same name.</p><p>To measure how the importance of individual characters varies between canon and fanfiction, we calculate the change in the percent of all character mentions a character has in the canon to the aver- age percent of character mentions that same charac- ter has in fanfiction.</p><p>Across all canons we find that the most prominent character in the canon had at most a small increase in percent character mentions, while less prominent characters received large increases. The results for two illustrative examples, Pride and Prejudice and Sherlock Holmes, are shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref>. The per- cent of character mentions for the main protagonists (Elizabeth and Holmes) decreases in fanfiction, but the secondary characters of Mr. Darcy and Watson Labels Terms Author encouragement read story one reading chapters time best ever review long update please love soon story amazing really hope continue writing chapter great good keep really work story job forward awesome ca wait next chapter see na happens gon great read like well really story love chapter way one see interesting Requests for story would like know get think going could something really even Emotional reactions wow better beautiful getting fight adorable keeps team birthday tears oh god yes man yay damn hell dear yeah got poor lol cute howl evil bad hate baby feel lord xd loved funny love haha sweet lol ah cute aww Gender differences. Fanfiction has a predom- inantly female authorship and readership base <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Barnes, 2015)</ref>; these stories often oppose tradi- tional gender norms present in the canon and show- case stronger female characters <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Handley, 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Scodari and Felder, 2000;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Leow, 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Busse, 2009)</ref>. In order to test whether fanfiction allocates more attention to female characters than canonical stories, we compare the percent of mentions of male and fe- male characters using the same collection of stories from Gutenberg canons as above. 40.1% of charac- ter mentions in the canons are to women; in fanfic- tion, this ratio increases to 42.4%. This effect size is small (2.3% absolute difference), but in a bootstrap hypothesis test of the difference (using 10 6 boot- strapped samples), the difference is highly signifi- cant (p &lt; 0.001), suggesting that fanfiction does in- deed devote more attention to female characters.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Interaction between users</head><p>A unique characteristic of this data is the chapter-by- chapter reader reviews; any user can leave a review for a chapter of a story. Authors are also frequently reviewers of other stories <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">(Thomas, 2011)</ref>, forming an ecosystem with qualities of a social network.</p><p>709,849 authors in this data (52%) are also re- viewers; if we define a network node to be a user and edge to be a reviewing relationship (a directed edge exists from A ! B if A reviews one of B's works), this network contains 9.3M such directed edges, with an average outdegree of 13.2 and inde- gree of 15.6 (each author on average reviews for 13 other authors, and is reviewed by 16).</p><p>To explore the content of these reviews computa- tionally, we sampled one story with more than 500 reviews from 500 different canons and ran Latent Dirichlet Allocation ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Blei et al., 2003</ref>) with 10 topics on the text of the reviews (excluding names as stop- words). This is an exploratory analysis, but can give insight into the broad functions of reader responses in this domain. <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">Table 2</ref> presents the results, grouping the topics into three exploratory categories: positive encour- agement and pleas for updates, requests to the author about the progression of the story, and emotional re- actions to the story. Prior studies that have examined the role of reviews as a form of interaction between the reader and the author have documented the first two categories extensively ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Campbell et al., 2016;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Magnifico et al., 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Lammers and Marsh, 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Black, 2006</ref>). However, despite a significant portion of the reviews consisting of the reader's emotional responses to the story, the way in which readers use reviews as a means of emotional engagement with the story itself has yet to be examined in such detail.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3">Predicting reader responses to character</head><p>The presence of reader reviews accompanying each fanfiction chapter presents a unique opportunity to develop a predictive model of how readers respond to text-given the text of a chapter, can we predict how readers will react? To test the feasibility of this task, we focus on reader responses to character. A RESPONSE to a character is operationalized as a sentence from a reader review mentioning that character and no other characters. We create an annotated dataset by ran- domly sampling a single character with at least 10 reader responses from each of the 500 stories de- scribed in §3.2. From this set, we randomly select exactly 10 responses for each character, to yield a total of 5,000 reader responses.</p><p>We then present these 5,000 responses to annota- tors on Amazon Mechanical Turk, and ask them to judge the sentiment toward the character expressed in the response as either positive, negative, neutral, or not applicable (in the case of character recog- nition errors). The overall agreement rate among annotators for this classification task is moderate (Fleiss'  = 0.438), in part due to the difficulty of assessing the responders' attitudes from short text; while some responses wear their sentiment on their sleeve (I knew I hated Brandon!), others require more contextual knowledge to judge (Ah Link or Akira appears!).</p><p>In order to create a higher-precision subset we se- lect responses with only unanimous positive or neg- ative votes from 3 different annotators, yielding a total dataset of 1,069 response labels. We divide the dataset into 80% training/development and 20% for a held-out test (with no overlap in stories between training and test).</p><p>We also bootstrap additional semi-supervised data by training a sentiment classifier on the unigrams of the reader responses in the training data (with a 3- class accuracy of 75%; compared to majority base- line of 49.7%), predicting the sentiment label for all responses in the dataset, and selecting examples that a.) have 95% prediction confidence and b.) whose stories do not appear in the training or test data. We sample selected examples to respect the label dis- tribution in the training data, yielding an additional 25,000 data points to supplement learning.</p><p>Our core task is to use only the text of the story (and not the reader response) to predict the corre- sponding response sentiment label in order to un- derstand what aspects of the story (and a character's role within it) readers are reacting to. We experiment with several features to represent the characters:</p><p>• AGENT, PATIENT, PREDICATIVE, POSSESSIVE relations for each character (as output by BookNLP), both in the specific chapter and in the book overall (under the rationale that read- ers are responding to the actions that characters take).</p><p>• Unigrams spoken by the character, both in the chapter and in the book overall.</p><p>• Character gender.</p><p>• Character's frequency in the book (binary indi- cators of the decile of their frequency of men- tion).</p><p>• Skip-gram representations trained on 4.1B words of fanfiction text (200-dimensional, grouped into 1000 clusters using k-means clus- tering); these cluster identities form additional binary features by replacing the lexical indica- tors for the text features above.</p><p>We perform model selection using tenfold cross- validation on the training data alone, training`2training`training`2 - regularized logistic regression on one partition of the data, tuning thè 2 regularization parameter on another, and assessing performance on a third (note none of the test data described above is seen during this stage).</p><p>A majority class (all-positive) baseline on the training data results in an accuracy rate of 75.6%; only syntactic features yield a significant improve- ment, achieving an accuracy rate of 80.5%. <ref type="table" target="#tab_5">Table 3</ref> lists the most informative features for pre- dicting negatively-assessed characters. While these characteristic features have face validity and offer promise for understanding character in more depth, we do not see similar improvements in accuracy on the truly held-out test data (run once before sub- mission); this same feature set achieves an accuracy rate of 70.4% (compared to a majority baseline on the test data of 71.4%). Part of this may be due to the sample size of the test data (n = 199); a boot- strap 95% confidence interval <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Berg-Kirkpatrick et al., 2012</ref>) places the accuracy in the range <ref type="bibr">[0.648, 0.754]</ref>. However, this more likely constitutes a neg- ative result that reflects the inherent difficulty of the task; while syntactic features point to a real sig- nal that readers are reacting to when writing their responses, literary character is of course far more complex, and more sophisticated representations of character-and of the readers who react to them- are likely warranted for real predictive performance on this task.  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Conclusion</head><p>In blending aspects of large-scale literary data and social network structure, fanfiction publication con- stitutes a vibrant ecosystem with ample textual ev- idence for the production and consumption of liter- ary texts. In this work, we have briefly illustrated three aspects of this data that have the potential to yield interesting insight-the relationship between fanfiction stories and their original source material, the social network structure of authors and their re- spondents, and the possibility of predicting reader responses from serially published text. Many ques- tions remain; in providing a quantitative description of this dataset, we hope to highlight its potential for analysis, and encourage other work in this domain.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: Difference in percent character mentions between fanfiction and canon for Pride and Prejudice (left) and Sherlock Holmes (right).</figDesc><graphic url="image-1.png" coords="2,92.67,57.83,187.20,187.20" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" validated="false"><head>Table 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Summary of the fanfiction.net corpus 

3 Analysis of fanfiction 

3.1 Differences between canons and fanfiction 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" validated="false"><head>Table 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Top 10 terms in the 10 manually grouped LDA topics. 

show a large increase. These findings confirm the 
results of Xu et al. (2011), who find a greater in-
crease in mentions of Mr. Darcy relative to Elizabeth 
in a different corpus of Pride and Prejudice fanfic-
tion, and supports claims that fanfiction authors may 
delve deeper into characters that receive less atten-
tion in the canon (Jwa, 2012; Thomas, 2011). 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3" validated="false"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>I hate Mr. Darcy! … Mr. Darcy walked off; and Elizabeth remained with no very cordial feelings toward him …</figDesc><table>Fiction text 

Reader response 
Response label 

negative 

Figure 2: Illustration of data for predicting reader 
responses. Here we are using features derived only 
from FICTION TEXT to predict the RESPONSE LA-

BEL. 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_5" validated="false"><head>Table 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Syntactic features most predictive of a 
negatively-assessed character. 

</table></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> While terms of service prohibit our release of this data, tools to collect and process it can be found here: http: //github.com/smilli/fanfiction.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="2"> Les Miserables (3996 fanfiction stories), Sherlock Holmes (3283), Pride and Prejudice (3084), Peter Pan (2431), Alice in Wonderland (1446), Anne of Green Gables (620), Jane Eyre (331), Little Women (286), The Scarlet Pimpernel (255), and the Secret Garden (222).</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>We thank Cecilia Aragon and our anonymous re-viewers for their helpful comments. This work is made possible by the use of computing resources from Berkeley Research Computing.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A Bayesian mixed effects model of literary character</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Bamman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ted</forename><surname>Underwood</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Noah</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Smith</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 52nd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the 52nd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics<address><addrLine>Baltimore, Maryland</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Long Papers</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2014-06" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="370" to="379" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Association for Computational Linguistics</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Fanfiction as imaginary play: What fan-written stories can tell us about the cognitive science of fiction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Jennifer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Barnes</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Poetics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">48</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="69" to="82" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">An empirical investigation of statistical significance in NLP</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Taylor</forename><surname>Berg-Kirkpatrick</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Burkett</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dan</forename><surname>Klein</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2012 Joint Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing and Computational Natural Language Learning</title>
		<meeting>the 2012 Joint Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing and Computational Natural Language Learning<address><addrLine>Stroudsburg, PA, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="995" to="1005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Association for Computational Linguistics</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Not just the OMG standard: reader feedback and language, literacy, and culture in online fanfiction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Black</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Annual Meeting of The American Educational Research Association</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>San Francisco</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
			<biblScope unit="page">10</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Blei</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Andrew</forename><surname>Ng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Jordan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Latent dirichlet allocation. JMLR</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="993" to="1022" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">In focus: Fandom and feminism: gender and the politics of fan production</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kristina</forename><surname>Busse</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cinema Journal</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">48</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="104" to="108" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Thousands of positive reviews: Distributed mentoring in online fan communities</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Julie</forename><surname>Campbell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Cecilia</forename><surname>Aragon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Katie</forename><surname>Davis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sarah</forename><surname>Evans</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Abigail</forename><surname>Evans</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Randall</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 19th ACM Conference on Computer-Supported Cooperative Work &amp; Social Computing, CSCW &apos;16</title>
		<meeting>the 19th ACM Conference on Computer-Supported Cooperative Work &amp; Social Computing, CSCW &apos;16<address><addrLine>New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="691" to="704" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Modeling dynamic relationships between characters in literary novels</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Snigdha</forename><surname>Chaturvedi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Shashank</forename><surname>Srivastava</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hal</forename><surname>Daume</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chris</forename><surname>Dyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Character-based kernels for novelistic plot structure</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Micha</forename><surname>Elsner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>In EACL</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Distressing damsels: narrative critique and reinterpretation in star wars fanfiction. Fan Culture: Theory/Practice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christine</forename><surname>Handley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<publisher>Cambridge Scholars Publishing</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="97" to="118" />
			<pubPlace>Newcastle upon Tyne</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Feuding families and former friends: Unsupervised learning for dynamic fictional relationships</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mohit</forename><surname>Iyyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Anupam</forename><surname>Guha</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Snigdha</forename><surname>Chaturvedi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jordan</forename><surname>Boyd-Graber</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hal</forename><surname>Daumé</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Iii</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">North American Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Revealing sentiment and plot arcs with the syuzhet package</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Matthew</forename><surname>Jockers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://www.matthewjockers.net/2015/02/02/syuzhet/" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Modeling L2 writer voice: Discoursal positioning in fanfiction writing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Soomin</forename><surname>Jwa</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Computers and Composition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">29</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="323" to="340" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Going public: An adolescent&apos;s networked writing on fanfiction.net</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Jayne</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Valerie L</forename><surname>Lammers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Marsh</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Adolescent &amp; Adult Literacy</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">59</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="277" to="285" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Subverting the canon in feminist fan fiction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hui Min Annabeth</forename><surname>Leow</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Transformative Works and Cultures</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Words on the screen: broadening analyses of interactions among fanfiction writers and reviewers</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alecia</forename><forename type="middle">Marie</forename><surname>Magnifico</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jen</forename><forename type="middle">Scott</forename><surname>Curwood</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jayne</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Lammers</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Literacy</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">49</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="158" to="166" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">From once upon a time to happily ever after: Tracking emotions in novels and fairy tales</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Saif</forename><surname>Mohammad</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>abs/1309.5909</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<publisher>CoRR</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Creating a pocket universe: Shippers, fan fiction, and the X-Files online</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christine</forename><surname>Scodari</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jenna</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Felder</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Communication Studies</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">51</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="238" to="257" />
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">What is fanfiction and why are people saying such nice things about it?</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bronwen</forename><surname>Thomas</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Storyworlds: A Journal of Narrative Studies</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="24" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Mr. Bennet, his coachman, and the Archbishop walk into a bar but only one of them gets recognized: On the difficulty of detecting characters in literary texts</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hardik</forename><surname>Vala</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Jurgens</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Andrew</forename><surname>Piper</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Derek</forename><surname>Ruths</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2015 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</title>
		<meeting>the 2015 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing<address><addrLine>Lisbon, Portugal</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2015-09" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="769" to="774" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The writing and reading of fan fiction and transformation theory</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Veerle</forename><surname>Van Steenhuyse</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">CLCWeb: Comparative Literature and Culture</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">4</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Austen&apos;s fans and fans&apos; Austen</title>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Literary Semantics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">40</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="81" to="97" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Aligning books and movies: Towards story-like visual explanations by watching movies and reading books</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yukun</forename><surname>Zhu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ryan</forename><surname>Kiros</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Richard</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Zemel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ruslan</forename><surname>Salakhutdinov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Raquel</forename><surname>Urtasun</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Antonio</forename><surname>Torralba</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sanja</forename><surname>Fidler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>abs/1506.06724</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
			<publisher>CoRR</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
