<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T12:19+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Cultural Shift or Linguistic Drift? Comparing Two Computational Measures of Semantic Change</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date>November 1-5, 2016</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">William</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Hamilton</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Stanford University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>94305</postCode>
									<settlement>Stanford</settlement>
									<region>CA</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jure</forename><surname>Leskovec</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Stanford University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>94305</postCode>
									<settlement>Stanford</settlement>
									<region>CA</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dan</forename><surname>Jurafsky</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Stanford University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>94305</postCode>
									<settlement>Stanford</settlement>
									<region>CA</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Cultural Shift or Linguistic Drift? Comparing Two Computational Measures of Semantic Change</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2016 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</title>
						<meeting>the 2016 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing <address><addrLine>Austin, Texas</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="2116" to="2121"/>
							<date type="published">November 1-5, 2016</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Words shift in meaning for many reasons, including cultural factors like new technologies and regular linguistic processes like sub-jectification. Understanding the evolution of language and culture requires disentangling these underlying causes. Here we show how two different distributional measures can be used to detect two different types of semantic change. The first measure, which has been used in many previous works, analyzes global shifts in a word&apos;s distributional semantics; it is sensitive to changes due to regular processes of linguistic drift, such as the semantic generalization of promise (&quot;I promise.&quot;→&quot;It promised to be exciting.&quot;). The second measure , which we develop here, focuses on local changes to a word&apos;s nearest semantic neighbors ; it is more sensitive to cultural shifts, such as the change in the meaning of cell (&quot;prison cell&quot; → &quot;cell phone&quot;). Comparing measurements made by these two methods allows researchers to determine whether changes are more cultural or linguistic in nature, a distinction that is essential for work in the digital humanities and historical linguistics.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Distributional methods of embedding words in vec- tor spaces according to their co-occurrence statis- tics are a promising new tool for diachronic seman- tics ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Gulordava and Baroni, 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Jatowt and Duh, 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Kulkarni et al., 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b18">Xu and Kemp, 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Hamilton et al., 2016)</ref>. Previous work, however, does not consider the underlying causes of seman- tic change or how to distentangle different types of change.</p><p>We show how two computational measures can be used to distinguish between semantic changes caused by cultural shifts (e.g., technological ad- vancements) and those caused by more regular pro- cesses of semantic change (e.g., grammaticalization or subjectification). This distinction is essential for research on linguistic and cultural evolution. Detect- ing cultural shifts in language use is crucial to com- putational studies of history and other digital hu- manities projects. By contrast, for advancing histor- ical linguistics, cultural shifts amount to noise and only the more regular shifts matter.</p><p>Our work builds on two intuitions: that dis- tributional models can highlight syntagmatic ver- sus paradigmatic relations with neighboring words ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Schutze and Pedersen, 1993)</ref> and that nouns are more likely to undergo changes due to irregular cul- tural shifts while verbs more readily participate in regular processes of semantic change <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Gentner and France, 1988;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Traugott and Dasher, 2001</ref>). We use this noun vs. verb mapping as a proxy to compare our two measures' sensitivities to cultural vs. lin- guistic shifts. Sensitivity to nominal shifts indi- cates a propensity to capture irregular cultural shifts in language, such as those due to technological ad- vancements <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(Traugott and Dasher, 2001</ref>). Sensitiv- ity to shifts in verbs (and other predicates) indicates a propensity to capture regular processes of linguis- tic drift <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Gentner and France, 1988;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Kintsch, 2000;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Traugott and Dasher, 2001</ref> </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Global measure of change</head><p>Local neighborhood measure of change <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref>: Two different measures of semantic change. With the global measure of change, we measure how far a word has moved in semantic space between two time-periods. This measure is sensitive to subtle shifts in usage and also global effects due to the entire semantic space shifting. For example, this captures how actually underwent subjectification during the 20th century, shifting from uses in objective statements about the world ("actually did try") to subjective statements of attitude ("I actually agree"; see <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Traugott and Dasher, 2001</ref> for details). In contrast, with the local neighborhood measure of change, we measure changes in a word's nearest neighbors, which captures drastic shifts in core meaning, such as gay's shift in meaning over the 20th century.</p><p>we show that it is more sensitive to changes in the nominal domain and captures changes due to unpre- dictable cultural shifts. Our second measure relies on a more traditional global notion of change; we show that it better captures changes, like those in verbs, that are the result of regular linguistic drift. Our analysis relies on a large-scale statistical study of six historical corpora in multiple lan- guages, along with case-studies that illustrate the fine-grained differences between the two measures.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Methods</head><p>We use the diachronic word2vec embeddings con- structed in our previous work <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Hamilton et al., 2016)</ref> to measure how word meanings change between consecutive decades. 1 In these representations each word w i has a vector representation w (t) (Turney and Pantel, 2010) at each time point, which captures its co-occurrence statistics for that time period. The vectors are constructed using the skip-gram with negative sampling (SGNS) algorithm <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(Mikolov et al., 2013</ref>) and post-processed to align the semantic spaces between years. Measuring the distance be- tween word vectors for consecutive decades allows us to compute the rate at which the different words change in meaning ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Gulordava and Baroni, 2011</ref>).</p><p>We analyzed the decades from 1800 to 1990 using vectors derived from the Google N-gram datasets ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Lin et al., 2012</ref>) that have large amounts of his- torical text (English, French, German, and English Fiction). We also used vectors derived from the Cor- pus of Historical American English (COHA), which is smaller than Google N-grams but was carefully constructed to be genre balanced and contains word lemmas as well as surface forms <ref type="bibr">(Davies, 2010)</ref>. We examined all decades from 1850 through 2000 using the COHA dataset and used the part-of-speech tags provided with the corpora.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">Measuring semantic change</head><p>We examine two different ways to measure semantic change ( <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref>).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Global measure</head><p>The first measure analyzes global shifts in a word's vector semantics and is identical to the mea- sure used in most previous works ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Gulordava and Baroni, 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Jatowt and Duh, 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Kim et al., 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Hamilton et al., 2016)</ref>. We simply take a word's vectors for two consecutive decades and measure the cosine distance between them, i.e.</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">d G (w (t) i , w (t+1) i ) = cos-dist(w (t) i , w (t+1) i ). (1) English (All) English (Fic.) German French COHA (word) COHA (lemma) −0.4 −0.3 −0.2 −0.1 0.0 0.1 0.2 (Verb -noun) change</formula><p>Global measure Local measure <ref type="figure">Figure 2</ref>: The global measure is more sensitive to semantic changes in verbs while the local neighborhood measure is more sensitive to noun changes. Examining how much nouns change relative to verbs (using coefficients from mixed-model regressions) reveals that the two measures are sensitive to different types of semantic change. Across all languages, the local neighborhood measure always assigns relatively higher rates of change to nouns (i.e., the right/green bars are lower than the left/blue bars for all pairs), though the results vary by language (e.g., French has high noun change-rates overall). 95% confidence intervals are shown.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Local neighborhood measure</head><p>The second measure is based on the intuition that only a word's nearest semantic neighbors are rele- vant. For this measure, we first find word w i 's set of k nearest-neighbors (according to cosine-similarity) within each decade, which we denote by the ordered set N k (w (t) i ). Next, to measure the change between decades t and t + 1, we compute a "second-order" similarity vector for w (t) i from these neighbor sets with entries defined as</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">s (t) (j) = cos-sim(w (t) i , w (t) j ) ∀w j ∈ N k (w (t) i ) ∪ N k (w (t+1) i ),<label>(2)</label></formula><p>and we compute an analogous vector for w i , contains the cosine similarity of w i and the vectors of all w i 's near- est semantic neighbors in the the time-periods t and t + 1. Working with variants of these second-order vectors has been a popular approach in many recent works, though most of these works define these vec- tors against the full vocabulary and not just a word's nearest neighbors (del Prado <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Martin and Brendel, 2016;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Eger and Mehler, 2016;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Rodda et al., 2016)</ref>.</p><p>Finally, we compute the local neighborhood change as</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">d L (w (t) i , w (t+1) i ) = cos-dist(s (t) i , s (t+1) i ).<label>(3)</label></formula><p>This measures the extent to which w i 's similarity with its nearest neighbors has changed. The local neighborhood measure defined in (3) captures strong shifts in a word's paradigmatic re- lations but is less sensitive to global shifts in syntag- matic contexts ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Schutze and Pedersen, 1993</ref> used k = 25 in all experiments (though we found the results to be consistent for k ∈ [10, 50]).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">Statistical methodology</head><p>To test whether nouns or verbs change more accord- ing to our two measures of change, we build on our previous work and used a linear mixed model approach ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Hamilton et al., 2016)</ref>. This approach amounts to a linear regression where the model also includes "random" effects to account for the fact that the measurements for individual words will be cor- related across time <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(McCulloch and Neuhaus, 2001</ref>). We ran two regressions per datatset: one with the global d G values as the dependent variables (DVs) and one with the local neighborhood d L values. In both cases we examined the change between all con- secutive decades and normalized the DVs to zero- mean and unit variance. We examined nouns/verbs within the top-10000 words by frequency rank and removed all words that occurred &lt;500 times in the smaller COHA dataset. The independent vari- ables are word frequency, the decade of the change (represented categorically), and variable indicating Word 1850s context 1990s context actually "...dinners which you have actually eaten." "With that, I actually agree." must "O, George, we must have faith." "Which you must have heard ten years ago..." promise "I promise to pay you...' "...the day promised to be lovely."</p><p>gay "Gay bridals and other merry-makings of men." "...the result of gay rights demonstrations." virus "This young man is...infected with the virus." "...a rapidly spreading computer virus." cell "The door of a gloomy cell..." "They really need their cell phones." <ref type="table">Table 2</ref>: Example case-studies of semantic change. The first three words are examples of regular linguistic shifts, while the latter three are examples of words that shifted due to exogenous cultural factors. Contexts are from the COHA data <ref type="bibr">(Davies, 2010)</ref>. Examining the semantic distance between the 1850s and 1990s shows that the global measure is more sensitive to regular shifts (and vice-versa for the local measure). The plot shows the difference between the measurements made by the two methods.</p><p>whether a word is a noun or a verb (proper nouns are excluded, as in Hamilton et al., 2016). <ref type="bibr">2</ref> </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Results</head><p>Our results show that the two seemingly related measures actually result in drastically different no- tions of semantic change.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Nouns vs. verbs</head><p>The local neighborhood measure assigns far higher rates of semantic change to nouns across all lan- guages and datasets while the opposite is true for the global distance measure, which tends to assign higher rates of change to verbs <ref type="figure">(Figure 2</ref>). We focused on verbs vs. nouns since they are the two major parts-of-speech and previous research has shown that verbs are more semantically mutable than nouns and thus more likely to undergo linguis- tic drift <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Gentner and France, 1988)</ref>, while nouns are far more likely to change due to cultural shifts like new technologies <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(Traugott and Dasher, 2001</ref>). However, some well-known regular linguistic shifts include rarer parts of speech like adverbs (included in our case studies below). Thus we also confirmed 2 Frequency was included since it is known to strongly influ- ence the distributional measures ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Hamilton et al., 2016)</ref>. that the differences shown in <ref type="figure">Figure 2</ref> also hold when adverbs and adjectives are included along with the verbs. This modified analysis showed analogous significant trends, which fits with previous research arguing that adverbial and adjectival modifiers are also often the target of regular linguistic changes <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(Traugott and Dasher, 2001)</ref>.</p><p>The results of this large-scale regression analy- sis show that the local measure is more sensitive to changes in the nominal domain, a domain in which change is known to be driven by cultural factors. In contrast, the global measure is more sensitive to changes in verbs, along with adjectives and adverbs, which are known to be the targets of many regular processes of linguistic change <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(Traugott and Dasher, 2001;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Hopper and Traugott, 2003)</ref> </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Case studies</head><p>We examined six case-study words grouped into two sets. These case studies show that three examples of well-attested regular linguistic shifts (set A) changed more according to the global measure, while three well-known examples of cultural changes (set B) change more according to the local neighborhood measure. <ref type="table">Table 2</ref> lists these words with some rep- resentative historical contexts <ref type="bibr">(Davies, 2010)</ref>. Set A contains three words that underwent at- tested regular linguistic shifts detailed in <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Traugott and Dasher (2001)</ref>: actually, must, and promise. These three words represent three different types of regular linguistic shifts: actually is a case of subjec- tification (detailed in <ref type="figure">Figure 1)</ref>; must shifted from a deontic/obligation usage ("you must do X") to a epistemic one ("X must be the case"), exemplifying a regular pattern of change common to many modal verbs; and promise represents the class of shift- ing "performative speech acts" that undergo rich changes due to their pragmatic uses and subjectifi- cation <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(Traugott and Dasher, 2001</ref>). The contexts listed in <ref type="table">Table 2</ref> exemplify these shifts.</p><p>Set B contains three words that were selected because they underwent well-known cultural shifts over the last 150 years: gay, virus, and cell. These words gained new meanings due to uses in community-specific vernacular (gay) or technolog- ical advances (virus, cell). The cultural shifts un- derlying these changes in usage -e.g., the devel- opment of the mobile "cell phone" -were unpre- dictable in the sense that they were not the result of regularities in human linguistic systems. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 3</ref> shows how much the meaning of these word changed from the 1850s to the 1990s according to the two different measures on the English Google data. We see that the words in set A changed more when measurements were made using the global measure, while the opposite holds for set B.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Discussion</head><p>Our results show that our novel local neighborhood measure of semantic change is more sensitive to changes in nouns, while the global measure is more sensitive to changes in verbs. This mapping aligns with the traditional distinction between irregular cul- tural shifts in nominals and more regular cases of linguistic drift <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(Traugott and Dasher, 2001</ref>) and is further reinforced by our six case studies.</p><p>This finding emphasizes that researchers must de- velop and use measures of semantic change that are tuned to specific tasks. For example, a cul- tural change-point detection framework would be more successful using our local neighborhood mea- sure, while an empirical study of grammaticalization would be better off using the traditional global dis- tance approach. Comparing measurements made by these two approaches also allows researchers to as- sess the extent to which semantic changes are lin- guistic or cultural in nature.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Figure 3: The global measure captures classic examples of linguistic drift while the local measure captures example cultural shifts. Examining the semantic distance between the 1850s and 1990s shows that the global measure is more sensitive to regular shifts (and vice-versa for the local measure). The plot shows the difference between the measurements made by the two methods.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" validated="false"><head>) .</head><label>.</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>The first measure we analyze is based upon 
changes to a word's local semantic neighborhood; lesbian 

homosexual 

heterosexual 
queer 

woman 

gay 
(1990s) 

hispanic 

daft 

witty 

brilliant 

merry 

gay 
(1900s) 

frolicsome 

joyous 

</table></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> http://nlp.stanford.edu/projects/histwords/. This URL also links to detailed dataset descriptions and the code needed to replicate the experiments in this paper.</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgements</head><p>The authors thank C. Manning, V. Prabhakaran, S. Kumar, and our anonymous reviewers for their helpful comments. This research has been sup-ported in part by NSF CNS-1010921, IIS-1149837, IIS-1514268 NIH BD2K, ARO MURI, DARPA XDATA, DARPA SIMPLEX, Stanford Data Sci-ence Initiative, SAP Stanford Graduate Fellowship, NSERC PGS-D, Boeing, Lightspeed, and Volkswa-gen.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">400 million words</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">American</forename><surname>English</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://corpus.byu.edu/coha/" />
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1810" to="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Case and Cause in Icelandic: Reconstructing Causal Networks of Cascaded Language Changes</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Fermin Moscoso Del Prado</forename><surname>Martin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christian</forename><surname>Brendel</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. ACL</title>
		<meeting>ACL</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">On the Linearity of Semantic Change: Investigating Meaning Variation via Dynamic Graph Models</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Steffen</forename><surname>Eger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alexander</forename><surname>Mehler</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. ACL</title>
		<meeting>ACL</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The verb mutability effect: Studies of the combinatorial semantics of nouns and verbs</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dedre</forename><surname>Gentner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ilene</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>France</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Lexical ambiguity resolution: Perspectives from psycholinguistics, neuropsychology, and artificial intelligence</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1988" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="343" to="382" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A distributional similarity approach to the detection of semantic change in the Google Books Ngram corpus</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kristina</forename><surname>Gulordava</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marco</forename><surname>Baroni</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. GEMS 2011 Workshop on Geometrical Models of Natural Language Semantics</title>
		<meeting>GEMS 2011 Workshop on Geometrical Models of Natural Language Semantics</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="67" to="71" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Diachronic Word Embeddings Reveal Statistical Laws of Semantic Change</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">William</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Hamilton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jure</forename><surname>Leskovec</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dan</forename><surname>Jurafsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. ACL</title>
		<meeting>ACL</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Grammaticalization</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Paul</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Elizabeth</forename><forename type="middle">Closs</forename><surname>Hopper</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Traugott</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
			<publisher>Cambridge University Press</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Cambridge, UK</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A framework for analyzing semantic change of words across time</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Adam</forename><surname>Jatowt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kevin</forename><surname>Duh</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. 14th ACM/IEEE-CS Conf. on Digital Libraries</title>
		<meeting>14th ACM/IEEE-CS Conf. on Digital Libraries</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>IEEE Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="229" to="238" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yoon</forename><surname>Kim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">-</forename><forename type="middle">I</forename><surname>Yi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kentaro</forename><surname>Chiu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Darshan</forename><surname>Hanaki</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Slav</forename><surname>Hegde</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Petrov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:1405.3515</idno>
		<title level="m">Temporal analysis of language through neural language models</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
<note type="report_type">arXiv preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Metaphor comprehension: A computational theory</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Walter</forename><surname>Kintsch</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychon. Bull. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="257" to="266" />
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Statistically significant detection of linguistic change</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Vivek</forename><surname>Kulkarni</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rami</forename><surname>Al-Rfou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bryan</forename><surname>Perozzi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Steven</forename><surname>Skiena</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. 24th WWW Conf</title>
		<meeting>24th WWW Conf</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="625" to="635" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Syntactic annotations for the google books ngram corpus</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yuri</forename><surname>Lin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jean-Baptiste</forename><surname>Michel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Erez</forename><surname>Lieberman Aiden</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jon</forename><surname>Orwant</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Will</forename><surname>Brockman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Slav</forename><surname>Petrov</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. ACL System Demonstrations</title>
		<meeting>ACL System Demonstrations</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Generalized linear mixed models</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Charles</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">John M</forename><surname>Mcculloch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Neuhaus</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
			<publisher>Wiley-Interscience</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Hoboken, NJ</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Distributed representations of words and phrases and their compositionality</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tomas</forename><surname>Mikolov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ilya</forename><surname>Sutskever</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kai</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Greg</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Corrado</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jeff</forename><surname>Dean</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">NIPS</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Panta rei: Tracking Semantic Change with Distributional Semantics in Ancient Greek</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Martina</forename><surname>Rodda</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marco</forename><surname>Senaldi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alessandro</forename><surname>Lenci</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Italian Conference of Computational Linguistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A vector model for syntagmatic and paradigmatic relatedness</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hinrich</forename><surname>Schutze</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jan</forename><surname>Pedersen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. 9th Annu. Conf. of the UW Centre for the New OED and Text Research</title>
		<meeting>9th Annu. Conf. of the UW Centre for the New OED and Text Research</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Citeseer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="104" to="113" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Regularity in Semantic Change</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Elizabeth</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Closs</forename><surname>Traugott</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Richard B</forename><surname>Dasher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
			<publisher>Cambridge University Press</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Cambridge, UK</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">From frequency to meaning: Vector space models of semantics</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Peter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Patrick</forename><surname>Turney</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Pantel</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Artif. Intell. Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">37</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="141" to="188" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A computational evaluation of two laws of semantic change</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yang</forename><surname>Xu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Charles</forename><surname>Kemp</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. 37th Annu. Conf</title>
		<meeting>37th Annu. Conf</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
