<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T11:36+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Learning to Generate Compositional Color Descriptions</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date>November 1-5, 2016</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Will</forename><surname>Monroe</surname></persName>
							<email>wmonroe4@cs.stanford.edu,</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Noah</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Goodman</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<address>
									<settlement>Psychology</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christopher</forename><surname>Potts</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="institution">Linguistics Stanford University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>94305</postCode>
									<settlement>Stanford</settlement>
									<region>CA</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Departments of 1 Computer Science</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Learning to Generate Compositional Color Descriptions</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2016 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</title>
						<meeting>the 2016 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing <address><addrLine>Austin, Texas</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="2243" to="2248"/>
							<date type="published">November 1-5, 2016</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>The production of color language is essential for grounded language generation. Color descriptions have many challenging properties: they can be vague, compositionally complex, and denotationally rich. We present an effective approach to generating color descriptions using recurrent neural networks and a Fourier-transformed color representation. Our model outperforms previous work on a conditional language modeling task over a large corpus of naturalistic color descriptions. In addition, probing the model&apos;s output reveals that it can accurately produce not only basic color terms but also descriptors with non-convex denota-tions (&quot;greenish&quot;), bare modifiers (&quot;bright&quot;, &quot;dull&quot;), and compositional phrases (&quot;faded teal&quot;) not seen in training.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Color descriptions represent a microcosm of grounded language semantics. Basic color terms like "red" and "blue" provide a rich set of seman- tic building blocks in a continuous meaning space; in addition, people employ compositional color de- scriptions to express meanings not covered by ba- sic terms, such as "greenish blue" or "the color of the rust on my aunt's old Chevrolet" <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Berlin and Kay, 1991)</ref>. The production of color language is essential for referring expression generation <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Krahmer and Van Deemter, 2012</ref>) and image captioning <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(Kulkarni et al., 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Mitchell et al., 2012</ref>), among other grounded language generation problems.</p><p>We consider color description generation as a grounded language modeling problem. We present</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Color</head><p>Top-1 Sample (83, 80, 28) "green" "very green" (232, 43, 37) "blue" "royal indigo" (63, 44, 60) "olive" "pale army green" (39, 83, 52) "orange" "macaroni" <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>: A selection of color descriptions sampled from our model that were not seen in training. Color triples are in HSL. Top-1 shows the model's highest-probability prediction. an effective new model for this task that uses a long short-term memory (LSTM) recurrent neural net- work <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Hochreiter and Schmidhuber, 1997;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Graves, 2013</ref>) and a Fourier-basis color representation in- spired by feature representations in computer vision.</p><p>We compare our model with LUX <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">(McMahan and Stone, 2015)</ref>, a Bayesian generative model of color semantics. Our model improves on their approach in several respects, which we demonstrate by exam- ining the meanings it assigns to various unusual de- scriptions: (1) it can generate compositional color descriptions not observed in training <ref type="figure">(Fig. 3)</ref>; (2) it learns correct denotations for underspecified modi- fiers, which name a variety of colors ("dark", "dull" <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">;  Fig. 2)</ref>; and (3) it can model non-convex denota- tions, such as that of "greenish", which includes both greenish yellows and blues <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">(Fig. 4)</ref>. As a result, our model also produces significant improvements on several grounded language modeling metrics.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Model formulation</head><p>Formally, a model of color description generation is a probability distribution S(d | c) over sequences of  Architecture Our main model is a recurrent neu- ral network sequence decoder <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">(Fig. 1, left panel)</ref>. An input color c = (h, s, v) is mapped to a rep- resentation f (see Color features, below). At each time step, the model takes in a concatenation of f and an embedding for the previous output token d i , starting with the start token d 0 = &lt;s&gt;. This con- catenated vector is passed through an LSTM layer, using the formulation of <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Graves (2013)</ref>. The out- put of the LSTM at each step is passed through a fully-connected layer, and a softmax nonlinearity is applied to produce a probability distribution for the following token. <ref type="bibr">2</ref> The probability of a sequence is the product of probabilities of the output tokens up to and including the end token &lt;/s&gt;. We also implemented a simple feed-forward neu- ral network, to demonstrate the value gained by modeling descriptions as sequences. This architec- ture (atomic; <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Fig. 1</ref>, right panel) consists of two fully-connected hidden layers, with a ReLU nonlin- earity after the first and a softmax output over all full color descriptions seen in training. This model therefore treats the descriptions as atomic symbols rather than sequences.</p><p>Color features We compare three representations:</p><p>• Raw: The original 3-dimensional color vectors, in HSV space.</p><p>• Buckets: A discretized representation, dividing HSV space into rectangular regions at three res- olutions (90×10×10, 45×5×5, 1×1×1) and assigning a separate embedding to each region.</p><p>• Fourier: Transformation of HSV vectors into a Fourier basis representation. Specifically, the representation f of a color (h, s, v) is given byˆf</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">byˆ byˆf jk = exp [−2πi (jh * + ks * + v * )] f = Re{ˆfRe{ˆ Re{ˆf } Im{ˆfIm{ˆ Im{ˆf } j, k, = 0..2 where (h * , s * , v * ) = (h/360, s/200, v/200).</formula><p>The Fourier representation is inspired by the use of Fourier feature descriptors in computer vision appli- cations ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">Zhang and Lu, 2002</ref>). It is a nonlinear trans- formation that maps the 3-dimensional HSV space to a 54-dimensional vector space. This representa- tion has the property that most regions of color space denoted by some description are extreme along a single direction in Fourier space, thus largely avoid- ing the need for the model to learn non-monotonic functions of the color representation.</p><p>Training We train using Adagrad <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Duchi et al., 2011</ref>) with initial learning rate η = 0.1, hidden layer size and cell size 20, and dropout (Hinton et al., 2012) with a rate of 0.2 on the output of the LSTM and each fully-connected layer. We identified these hyperparameters with random search, evaluating on a held-out subset of the training data. We use random normally-distributed initialization for embeddings (σ = 0.01) and LSTM weights (σ = 0.1), except for forget gates, which are initialized to a constant value of 5. Dense weights use normalized uniform initialization <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Glorot and Bengio, 2010)</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Experiments</head><p>We demonstrate the effectiveness of our model us- ing the same data and statistical modeling metrics as <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">McMahan and Stone (2015)</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Data</head><p>The dataset used to train and evaluate our model consists of pairs of colors and descriptions collected in an open online survey <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">(Munroe, 2010</ref>  Metrics We quantify model effectiveness with the following evaluation metrics:</p><p>• Perplexity: The geometric mean of the recip- rocal probability assigned by the model to the descriptions in the dataset, conditioned on the respective colors. This expresses the same ob- jective as log conditional likelihood. We follow <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">McMahan and Stone (2015)</ref> in reporting per- plexity per-description, not per-token as in the language modeling literature.</p><p>• AIC: The Akaike information criterion <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Akaike, 1974)</ref> is given by AIC = 2 + 2k, where is log likelihood and k is the total number of real-valued parameters of the model (e.g., weights and biases, or bucket proba- bilities). This quantifies a tradeoff between accurate modeling and model complexity.</p><p>• Accuracy: The percentage of most-likely de- scriptions predicted by the model that exactly match the description in the dataset (recall@1).</p><p>Results The top section of <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Table 2</ref> shows devel- opment set results comparing modeling effective- ness for atomic and sequence model architectures and different features. The Fourier feature transfor- mation generally improves on raw HSV vectors and discretized embeddings. The value of modeling de- scriptions as sequences can also be observed in these results; the LSTM models consistently outperform their atomic counterparts. Additional development set experiments (not shown in <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Table 2</ref>) confirmed smaller design choices for the recurrent architecture. We evaluated a model with two LSTM layers, but we found that the model with only one layer yielded better perplexity. We also compared the LSTM with GRU and vanilla re- current cells; we saw no significant difference be- tween LSTM and GRU, while using a vanilla recur- rent unit resulted in unstable training. Also note that the color representation f is input to the model at ev- ery time step in decoding. In our experiments, this yielded a small but significant improvement in per- plexity versus using the color representation as the initial state.</p><p>Test set results appear in the bottom section. Our best model outperforms both the histogram baseline (HM) and the improved LUX model of <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">McMahan and Stone (2015)</ref>, obtaining state-of-the-art results on this task. Improvements are highly significant on all metrics (p &lt; 0.001, approximate permutation test, R = 10,000 samples; <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">Padó, 2006</ref>).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Analysis</head><p>Given the general success of LSTM-based mod- els at generation tasks, it is perhaps not surprising that they yield good raw performance when applied to color description. The color domain, however, has the advantage of admitting faithful visualiza- tion of descriptions' semantics: colors exist in a 3- dimensional space, so a two-dimensional visualiza- tion can show an acceptably complete picture of an entire distribution over the space. We exploit this to highlight three specific improvements our model realizes over previous ones.</p><p>We construct visualizations by querying the model for the probability S(d | c) of the same de- scription for each color in a uniform grid, summing the probabilities over the hue dimension (left cross- section) and the saturation dimension (right cross- section), normalizing them to sum to 1, and plotting the log of the resulting values as a grayscale image. Formally, each visualization is a pair of functions (L, R), where</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">L(s, ) = log dh S(d | c = (h, s, )) dc S(d | c ) R(h, ) = log ds S(d | c = (h, s, )) dc S(d | c )</formula><p>The maximum value of each function is plotted as white, the minimum value is black, and intermediate values linearly interpolated.</p><p>Learning modifiers Our model learns accurate meanings of adjectival modifiers apart from the full descriptions that contain them. We examine this in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Fig. 2</ref>, by plotting the probabilities assigned to the bare modifiers "light", "bright", "dark", and "dull". "Light" and "dark" unsurprisingly denote high and low lightness, respectively. Less obviously, they also exclude high-saturation colors. "Bright", on the other hand, features both high-lightness colors and saturated colors-"bright yellow" can refer to the prototypical yellow, whereas "light yellow" cannot. Finally, "dull" denotes unsaturated colors in a vari- ety of lightnesses.</p><p>Compositionality Our model generalizes to com- positional descriptions not found in the training set. <ref type="figure">Fig. 3</ref> visualizes the probability assigned to the Hue "faded teal"</p><p>Figure 3: Conditional likelihood of "faded", "teal", and "faded teal". The two meaning components can be seen in the two cross-sections: "faded" denotes a low saturation value, and "teal" denotes hues near the center of the spectrum. novel utterance "faded teal", along with "faded" and "teal" individually. The meaning of "faded teal" is intersective: "faded" colors are lower in saturation, excluding the colors of the rainbow (the V on the right side of the left panel); and "teal" denotes col- ors with a hue near 180° (center of the right panel).</p><p>Non-convex denotations The Fourier feature transformation and the nonlinearities in the model allow it to capture a rich set of denotations. In partic- ular, our model addresses the shortcoming identified by <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">McMahan and Stone (2015)</ref> that their model can- not capture non-convex denotations. The description</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Color</head><p>Top-1 Sample (36, 86, 63) "orange" "ugly" (177, 85, 26) "teal" "robin's" (29, 45, 71) "tan" "reddish green" <ref type="bibr">(196,</ref><ref type="bibr">27,</ref><ref type="bibr">71)</ref> "grey" "baby royal" <ref type="table">Table 3</ref>: Error analysis: some color descriptions sampled from our model that are incorrect or incomplete.</p><p>"greenish" <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">(Fig. 4)</ref> has such a denotation: "green- ish" specifies a region of color space surrounding, but not including, true greens.</p><p>Error analysis <ref type="table">Table 3</ref> shows some examples of errors found in samples taken from the model. The main type of error the system makes is ungrammati- cal descriptions, particularly fragments lacking a ba- sic color term (e.g., "robin's"). Rarer are grammati- cal but meaningless compositions ("reddish green") and false descriptions. When queried for its single most likely prediction, arg max d S(d | c), the result is nearly always an acceptable, "safe" description- manual inspection of 200 such top-1 predictions did not identify any errors.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Conclusion and future work</head><p>We presented a model for generating composi- tional color descriptions that is capable of produc- ing novel descriptions not seen in training and sig- nificantly outperforms prior work at conditional lan- guage modeling. <ref type="bibr">3</ref> One natural extension is the use of character-level sequence modeling to capture complex morphology (e.g., "-ish" in "greenish"). <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Kawakami et al. (2016)</ref> build character-level mod- els for predicting colors given descriptions in addi- tion to describing colors. Their model uses a Lab- space color representation and uses the color to ini- tialize the LSTM instead of feeding it in at each time step; they also focus on visualizing point predictions of their description-to-color model, whereas we ex- amine the full distributions implied by our color-to- description model. Another extension we plan to investigate is mod- eling of context, to capture how people describe col- ors differently to contrast them with other colors via</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: Left: sequence model architecture; right: atomicdescription baseline. FC denotes fully connected layers.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2: Conditional likelihood of bare modifiers according to our generation model as a function of color. White represents regions of high likelihood. We omit the hue dimension, as these modifiers do not express hue constraints.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head>Figure 4 :</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Figure 4: Conditional likelihood of "greenish" as a function of color. The distribution is bimodal, including greenish yellows and blues but not true greens. Top: LUX; bottom: our model.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" validated="false"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>). Participants were shown a square of color and asked to write a free-form description of the color in a text box. McMahan and Stone filtered the re- sponses to normalize spelling differences and ex- clude spam responses and descriptions that occurred Model Feats.</figDesc><table>Perp. 
AIC 
Acc. 

atomic raw 
28.31 1.08×10 6 28.75% 
atomic buckets 16.01 1.31×10 6 38.59% 
atomic Fourier 15.05 8.86×10 5 38.97% 
RNN 
raw 
13.27 8.40×10 5 40.11% 
RNN 
buckets 13.03 1.26×10 6 39.94% 
RNN 
Fourier 12.35 8.33×10 5 40.40% 

HM 
buckets 14.41 4.82×10 6 39.40% 
LUX 
raw 
13.61 4.13×10 6 39.55% 
RNN 
Fourier 12.58 4.03×10 6 40.22% 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" validated="false"><head>Table 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Experimental results. Top: development set; bottom: 
test set. AIC is not comparable between the two splits. HM and 
LUX are from McMahan and Stone (2015). We reimplemented 
HM and re-ran LUX from publicly available code, confirming 
all results to the reported precision except perplexity of LUX, 
for which we obtained a figure of 13.72. 

very rarely. The resulting dataset contains 2,176,417 
pairs divided into training (1,523,108), development 
(108,545), and test (544,764) sets. 

</table></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> HSV: hue-saturation-value. The visualizations and tables in this paper instead use HSL (hue-saturation-lightness), which yields somewhat more intuitive diagrams and differs from HSV by a trivial reparameterization. 2 Our implementation uses Lasagne (Dieleman et al., 2015), a neural network library based on Theano (Al-Rfou et al., 2016).</note>

			<note place="foot" n="3"> We release our code at https://github.com/ stanfordnlp/color-describer. pragmatic reasoning (DeVault and Stone, 2007; Golland et al., 2010; Monroe and Potts, 2015).</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>We thank Jiwei Li, Jian Zhang, Anusha Balakrish-nan, and Daniel Ritchie for valuable advice and discussions. This research was supported in part by the Stanford Data Science Initiative, NSF BCS 1456077, and NSF IIS 1159679.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A new look at the statistical model identification</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hirotugu</forename><surname>Akaike</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE Transactions on Automatic Control</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="716" to="723" />
			<date type="published" when="1974" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Theano: A Python framework for fast computation of mathematical expressions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rami</forename><surname>Al-Rfou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Guillaume</forename><surname>Alain</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Amjad</forename><surname>Almahairi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christof</forename><surname>Angermueller</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dzmitry</forename><surname>Bahdanau</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nicolas</forename><surname>Ballas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:1605.02688</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
<note type="report_type">arXiv preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Basic color terms: Their universality and evolution</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Brent</forename><surname>Berlin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Paul</forename><surname>Kay</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1991" />
			<publisher>University of California Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Managing ambiguities across utterances in dialogue</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Devault</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Matthew</forename><surname>Stone</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of DECALOG 2007: Workshop on the Semantics and Pragmatics of Dialogue</title>
		<editor>Ron Artstein and Laure Vieu</editor>
		<meeting>DECALOG 2007: Workshop on the Semantics and Pragmatics of Dialogue</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jan</forename><surname>Sander Dieleman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Colin</forename><surname>Schlüter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Eben</forename><surname>Raffel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Olson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Søren Kaae</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Daniel</forename><surname>Sønderby</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Nouri</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Lasagne: First release</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Adaptive subgradient methods for online learning and stochastic optimization</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">John</forename><surname>Duchi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Elad</forename><surname>Hazan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yoram</forename><surname>Singer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The Journal of Machine Learning Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2121" to="2159" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Understanding the difficulty of training deep feedforward neural networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xavier</forename><surname>Glorot</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yoshua</forename><surname>Bengio</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>In AISTATS</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">A game-theoretic approach to generating spatial descriptions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dave</forename><surname>Golland</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Percy</forename><surname>Liang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dan</forename><surname>Klein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>In EMNLP</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Generating sequences with recurrent neural networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alex</forename><surname>Graves</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:1308.0850</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
<note type="report_type">arXiv preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Improving neural networks by preventing co-adaptation of feature detectors</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Geoffrey</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Hinton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nitish</forename><surname>Srivastava</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alex</forename><surname>Krizhevsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ilya</forename><surname>Sutskever</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ruslan</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Salakhutdinov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:1207.0580</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
<note type="report_type">arXiv preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Long short-term memory</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sepp</forename><surname>Hochreiter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jürgen</forename><surname>Schmidhuber</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Neural computation</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1735" to="1780" />
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Character sequence models for colorful words</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kazuya</forename><surname>Kawakami</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chris</forename><surname>Dyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bryan</forename><surname>Routledge</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Noah</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Smith</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">EMNLP</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Computational generation of referring expressions: A survey</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Emiel</forename><surname>Krahmer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kees</forename><surname>Van Deemter</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Computational Linguistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">38</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="173" to="218" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Baby talk: Understanding and generating image descriptions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Girish</forename><surname>Kulkarni</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Visruth</forename><surname>Premraj</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sagnik</forename><surname>Dhar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Siming</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yejin</forename><surname>Choi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alexander</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Berg</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">CVPR</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A Bayesian model of grounded color semantics</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Brian</forename><surname>Mcmahan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Matthew</forename><surname>Stone</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Transactions of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="103" to="115" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Midge: Generating image descriptions from computer vision detections</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Margaret</forename><surname>Mitchell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xufeng</forename><surname>Han</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jesse</forename><surname>Dodge</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alyssa</forename><surname>Mensch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Amit</forename><surname>Goyal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alex</forename><surname>Berg</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">EACL</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Learning in the Rational Speech Acts model</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Will</forename><surname>Monroe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christopher</forename><surname>Potts</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 20th Amsterdam Colloquium</title>
		<meeting>the 20th Amsterdam Colloquium</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Color survey results</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Randall</forename><surname>Munroe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://blog.xkcd.com/2010/05/03/color-surveyresults" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">User&apos;s guide to sigf: Significance testing by approximate randomisation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sebastian</forename><surname>Padó</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://www.nlpado.de/~sebastian/software/sigf.shtml" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Shape-based image retrieval using generic Fourier descriptor. Signal Processing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dengsheng</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Guojun</forename><surname>Lu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Image Communication</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="825" to="848" />
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
