<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T10:29+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Creating a Large Benchmark for Open Information Extraction</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
				<availability status="unknown"><p>Copyright Association for Computational Linguistics</p>
				</availability>
				<date>November 1-5, 2016. 2016</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gabriel</forename><surname>Stanovsky</surname></persName>
							<email>gabriel.satanovsky@gmail.com</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Computer Science Department</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Bar-Ilan University</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Ramat Gan</settlement>
									<country key="IL">Israel</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ido</forename><surname>Dagan</surname></persName>
							<email>dagan@cs.biu.ac.il</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Computer Science Department</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Bar-Ilan University</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Ramat Gan</settlement>
									<country key="IL">Israel</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Creating a Large Benchmark for Open Information Extraction</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2016 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</title>
						<meeting>the 2016 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing <address><addrLine>Austin, Texas</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="2300" to="2305"/>
							<date type="published">November 1-5, 2016. 2016</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Open information extraction (Open IE) was presented as an unrestricted variant of traditional information extraction. It has been gaining substantial attention, manifested by a large number of automatic Open IE extractors and downstream applications. In spite of this broad attention, the Open IE task definition has been lacking-there are no formal guidelines and no large scale gold standard annotation. Subsequently, the various implementations of Open IE resorted to small scale post-hoc evaluations, inhibiting an objective and reproducible cross-system comparison. In this work, we develop a methodology that leverages the recent QA-SRL annotation to create a first independent and large scale Open IE annotation , 1 and use it to automatically compare the most prominent Open IE systems.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Open Information Extraction (Open IE) was origi- nally formulated as a function from a document to a set of tuples indicating a semantic relation between a predicate phrase and its arguments ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Banko et al., 2007)</ref>. <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">Wu and Weld (2008)</ref> further defined that an Open IE extractor should "produce one triple for ev- ery relation stated explicitly in the text, but is not required to infer implicit facts". For example, given the sentence "John managed to open the door" an Open IE extractor should produce the tuple (John; managed to open; the door) but is not required to pro- duce the extraction (John; opened; the door).</p><p>Following this initial presentation of the task, Open IE has gained substantial and consistent atten- tion. Many automatic extractors were created (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Fader et al., 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Mausam et al., 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Del Corro and Gemulla, 2013)</ref>) and were put to use in various downstream applications.</p><p>In spite of this wide attention, Open IE's for- mal definition is lacking. There are no clear guide- lines as to what constitutes a valid proposition to be extracted, and subsequently there is no large scale benchmark annotation. Open IE evaluations there- fore usually consist of a post-hoc manual evaluation of a small output sample.</p><p>This evaluation practice lacks in several respects: (1) Most works provide a precision oriented metric, whereas recall is often not measured, (2) the num- bers are not comparable across systems, as they use different guidelines and datasets, and (3) the experi- ments are hard to replicate.</p><p>In this work, we aim to contribute to the standard- ization of Open IE evaluation by providing a large gold benchmark corpus. For that end, we first iden- tify consensual guiding principles across prominent Open IE systems, resulting in a clearer formulation of the Open IE task. Following, we find that the re- cent formulation of QA-SRL ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">He et al., 2015</ref>) in fact subsumes these requirements for Open IE. This en- ables us to automatically convert the annotations of QA-SRL to a high-quality Open IE corpus of more than 10K extractions, 13 times larger than the previ- ous largest Open IE annotation.</p><p>Finally, we automatically evaluate the perfor- mance of various Open IE systems against our cor- pus, using a soft matching criterion. This is the first time such a comparative evaluation is performed on a large scale gold corpus.</p><p>Future Open IE systems (and its applicative users) can use this large benchmark, along with the auto- matic evaluation measure, to easily compare their performance against previous baselines, alleviating the current need for ad-hoc evaluation.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Background</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">Open IE</head><p>Open Information Extraction (Open IE) was intro- duced as an open variant of traditional Information Extraction ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Etzioni et al., 2008)</ref>. As mentioned in the Introduction, its primary goal is to extract coher- ent propositions from a sentence, each comprising of a relation phrase and two or more argument phrases (e.g., (Barack Obama, born in, Hawaii)). Since its inception, Open IE has gained consistent attention, mostly used as a component within larger frame- works ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Christensen et al., 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Balasubramanian et al., 2013)</ref>.</p><p>In parallel, many Open IE extractors were de- veloped. TextRunner ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Banko et al., 2007)</ref> and WOE ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Wu and Weld, 2010</ref>) take a self-supervised approach over automatically produced dependency parses. Perhaps more dominant is the rule based ap- proach taken by <ref type="bibr">ReVerb (Fader et al., 2011</ref>), OLLIE ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Mausam et al., 2012)</ref>, <ref type="bibr">KrakeN (Akbik and Löser, 2012)</ref> and ClausIE <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(Del Corro and Gemulla, 2013)</ref>.</p><p>Two recent systems take a semantically-oriented approach. Open IE-4 2 uses semantic role labeling to extract tuples, while Stanford Open Information Ex- traction ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Angeli et al., 2015</ref>) uses natural logic infer- ence to arrive at shorter, more salient, arguments.</p><p>Recently, Stanovsky et al. (2016b) presented PropS, a proposition oriented representation, ob- tained via conversion rules from dependency trees. Performing Open IE extraction over PropS struc- tures is straightforward -follow the clearly marked predicated nodes to their direct arguments.</p><p>Contrary to the vast interest in Open IE, its task formulation has been largely overlooked. There are currently no common guidelines defining a valid ex- traction, which consequently hinders the creation of an evaluation benchmark for the task. Most Open IE extractors 3 evaluate performance by manually ex- amining a small sample of their output. <ref type="table">Table 1</ref> sum- marizes the evaluations taken by the most prominent Open IE systems.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">QA-SRL</head><p>Semantic Role Labeling (SRL) <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Carreras and M` arquez, 2005</ref>) is typically perceived as answer- ing argument role questions, such as who, what, to whom, when, or where, regarding a target predicate. For instance, PropBank's ARG0 for the predicate say answers the question "who said something?".</p><p>QA-SRL ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">He et al., 2015)</ref> suggests that answering explicit role questions is an intuitive means to solicit predicate-argument structures from non-expert an- notators. Annotators are presented with a sentence in which a target predicate 4 was marked, and are re- quested to annotate argument role questions and cor- responding answers.</p><p>Consider the sentence "Giles Pearman, Mi- crosoft's director of marketing, left his job" and the target predicate left. The QA-SRL annotation con- sists of the following pairs: (1) Who left something? {Giles Pearman; Microsoft's director of market- ing} and <ref type="formula">(2)</ref> what did someone leave? his job. <ref type="bibr">5</ref> He et al. assessed the validity of QA-SRL by annotating 3200 sentences from PropBank and Wikipedia, showing high agreement with the Prop- Bank annotations. In the following section we au- tomatically derive an Open IE benchmark from this QA-SRL annotation.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Creating an Open IE Benchmark</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Open IE Guidelines</head><p>Before creating a generic benchmark for evaluat- ing Open IE systems, it is first needed to obtain a clearer specification of the common task that they address. Despite some nuances, we identified the following core aspects of the Open IE task as con- sensual across all systems mentioned in Section 2: Minimal propositions Open IE systems aim to "break down" a sentence into a set of small isolated propositions. Accordingly, the span of each individ- ual proposition, and hence the span of each of its predicate and argument slots, should be as minimal as possible, as long as the original information (truth conditions) is preserved. For example, this leads to splitting distributive coordination in the sentence "Bell distributes electronic and building products", for which ClausIE produces: (Bell, distributes, elec- tronic products) and (Bell, distributes, building prod- ucts). Having shorter entities as Open IE arguments was further found to be useful in several semantic tasks <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Angeli et al., 2015;</ref>.</p><p>Completeness and open lexicon Open IE systems aim to extract all asserted propositions from a sen- tence. In practice, most current Open IE systems limit their scope to extracting verbal predicates, but consider all possible verbs without being bound to a pre-specified lexicon.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">From QA-SRL to Open IE</head><p>SRL and Open IE have been defined with differ- ent objectives. Particularly, SRL identifies argument role labels, which is not addressed in Open IE. Yet, the two tasks overlap as they both need to recover predicate-argument structures in sentences. We now examine the above Open IE requirements and sug- gest that while they are only partly embedded within SRL structures, they can be fully recovered from QA-SRL.</p><p>Asserted (matrix) propositions appear in SRL as non-embedded predicates (e.g., succeeded in the "Sam succeeded to convince John"). However, SRL's predicates are grounded to a lexicon such as PropBank ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Palmer et al., 2005</ref>) or FrameNet ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Baker et al., 1998)</ref>, which violates the completeness and open lexicon principle. Further, in contrast to the minimal propositions principle, arguments in SRL annotations are inclusive, each marked as full sub- trees in a syntactic parse.</p><p>Yet, QA-SRL seems to bridge this gap between traditional SRL structures and Open IE require- ments. Its predicate vocabulary is open, and its question-answer format solicits minimal proposi- tions, as was found in a recent study by <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">(Stanovsky et al., 2016a</ref>). This correlation suggests that the QA- SRL methodology is in fact also an attractive means for soliciting Open IE extractions from non-experts annotators. Evidently, it enables automatically de- riving high quality Open IE annotations from (cur- rent or future) QA-SRL gold annotations, as de- scribed in the following section</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3">Generating Open-IE Extractions</head><p>Formally, we extract an Open-IE dataset from the QA-SRL dataset by the following algorithm, which is illustrated in more detail further below:</p><p>1. Given:</p><p>• s -a sentence from the QA-SRL dataset.</p><p>• p -a predicate in s.</p><p>• tq 1 , ..., q n u -a list of questions over p.</p><p>• tta 1,1 , ..., a 1,l 1 u, ...ta n,1 , ..., a n,ln uu -a list of sets of corresponding answers, where question q i has l i answers.</p><p>2. If p is a non-embedded (matrix) verb:</p><p>(a) Remove answers which are composed only of pronouns, as these are not ex- pected to be extracted by Open-IE (and ac- cordingly adjust the l i 's). (b) Return extractions composed of p and every combination of answers in tta 1,1 , ..., a 1,l 1 u ˆ ... ˆ ta n,1 , ..., a n,ln uu (the Cartesian product of the answers). This process results in a list of</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">l 1 ¨ l 2 ¨ ... ¨ l n Open IE extractions.</formula><p>For example, consider the sentence: "Barack Obama, the U.S. president, was determined to win the majority vote in Washington and Arizona". The questions corresponding to the predicate determine are: {who was determined?, what was someone de- termined to do?}, and the corresponding answer sets are: {{"Barack Obama", "the U.S president"}, {"win the majority vote in Washington", "win the majority vote in Arizona"}}.</p><p>Following, our algorithm will produce these Open IE extractions: (Barack Obama; was determined; to win the majority vote in Washington), (the U.S. presi- dent; was determined; to win the majority vote in Wash- ington), (Barack Obama; was determined; to win the majority vote in Arizona), and (the U.S. president; was determined; to win the majority vote in Arizona).</p><p>Note that we do not produce extractions for em- bedded predicates (e.g., win) to conform with the assertedness principle, as discussed earlier.</p><p>With respect to pronoun removal (step 2(a)), we would remove the pronoun "he" as the answer to the question who was tired? in "John went home, he was   tired". Notice that in this sentence "John" would be a second answer for the above question, yielding the extraction (John; was tired). When the only answer to a question is a pronoun this question will be ignored in the extraction process, since the QA-SRL corpus does not address cross-sentence co-references. This issue may be addressed in future work.</p><p>Applying this process to the QA-SRL corpus yielded a total of 10,359 Open IE extractions over 3200 sentences from 2 domains (see <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">Ta- ble 2</ref>). This corpus is about 13 times larger than the previous largest annotated Open IE cor- pus <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Fader et al., 2011</ref>). The corpus is avail- able at: http://www.cs.biu.ac.il/nlp/ resources/downloads.</p><p>Corpus validation We assess the validity of our dataset by performing expert annotation 6 of Open IE extractions, following the principles discussed in Section 3.1, for 100 random sentences. We find that our benchmark extractions, derived automati- cally from QA-SRL, highly agree with the expert annotation, reaching 95.8 F1 by the head-agreement criterion defined in the next section. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Comparative Evaluation</head><p>In this section, we illustrate the utility of our new corpus by testing the performance of 6 promi- nent Open IE systems: OpenIE-4, ClausIE, OLLIE, PropS, Stanford, and ReVerb (see Section 2). <ref type="bibr">7</ref> In order to evaluate these systems in terms of pre- cision and recall, we need to match between their au- tomated extractions and the benchmark extractions. To allow some flexibility (e.g., omissions of preposi- tions or auxiliaries), we follow ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">He et al., 2015)</ref> and match an automated extraction with a gold proposi- tion if both agree on the grammatical head of all of their elements (predicate and arguments). We then analyze the recall and precision of Open IE systems on different confidence thresholds <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">(Figure 1)</ref>. Fur- thermore, we calculate the area under the PR curve for each of the different corpora <ref type="figure">(Figure 2</ref>) and the explicit yield per system <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">(Table 3)</ref>.</p><p>To the best of our knowledge, this is the first ob- jective comparative evaluation of prominent Open- IE systems, over a large and independently created dataset. This comparison gives rise to several ob- servations; which can be useful for future research and for choosing a preferred system for a particular application setting, such as: <ref type="figure">Figure 2</ref>: Area Under the PR Curve (AUC) measure for the evaluated systems.</p><p>1. Open IE-4 achieves best precision above 3% re- call (ě 78.67) and best AUC score (54.02),</p><p>2. ClausIE is best at recall (81.38), and 3. Stanford Open IE assigns confidence of 1 to 94% of its extractions, explaining its low pre- cision.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Conclusions</head><p>We presented the first independent and large scale Open IE benchmark annotation, and tested the most prominent systems against it. We hope that future Open IE systems can make use of this new resource to easily and objectively measure and compare their performance.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: Precision-recall curve for the different Open IE systems on our corpus (see discussion in Section 4).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" validated="true"><head>Table 2 : Corpus statistics.</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>System 
#Extractions 
WSJ WIKI ALL 
Stanford 
6423 14104 20527 
ClausIE 
5295 
8265 13560 
Open IE4 3634 
5113 
8747 
OLLIE 
2976 
5250 
8226 
PropS 
2852 
4990 
7842 
ReVerb 
1624 
2552 
4716 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3" validated="false"><head>Table 3 : The yield of the different Open IE systems.</head><label>3</label><figDesc></figDesc><table></table></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> Publicly available at http://www.cs.biu.ac.il/ nlp/resources/downloads</note>

			<note place="foot" n="2"> https://github.com/knowitall/openie</note>

			<note place="foot" n="3"> Except for (Wu and Weld, 2010) who evaluated recall. 4 Currently consisting of automatically annotated verbs. 5 Three cases give rise to multiple answers for the same question: appositives (as illustrated in this example), co-reference (&quot;Jimmy Hendrix played the guitar, he was really good at it&quot;), and distributive coordinations (&quot;Bob and Mary were born in America&quot;).</note>

			<note place="foot" n="6"> Carried by the first author. 7 Currently, we test only the common case of verbal predicates.</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>We would like to thank Mausam for fruitful discus-sions, and the anonymous reviewers for their helpful comments.</p><p>This work was supported in part by grants from the MAGNET program of the Israeli Office of the Chief Scientist (OCS), the Israel Science Founda-tion grant 880/12, and the German Research Foun-dation through the German-Israeli Project Coopera-tion (DIP, grant DA 1600/1-1).</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Kraken: N-ary facts in open information extraction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alan</forename><surname>Akbik</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alexander</forename><surname>Löser</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">NAACL-HLT 2012: Proceedings of the The Knowledge Extraction Workshop</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Leveraging linguistic structure for open domain information extraction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gabor</forename><surname>Angeli</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Melvin</forename><forename type="middle">Johnson</forename><surname>Premkumar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christopher</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Manning</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 53rd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL</title>
		<meeting>the 53rd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The berkeley framenet project</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Collin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Charles</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Baker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">John B</forename><surname>Fillmore</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Lowe</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of ACL</title>
		<meeting>ACL</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="86" to="90" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Generating coherent event schemas at scale</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Niranjan</forename><surname>Balasubramanian</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Stephen</forename><surname>Soderland</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Oren</forename><forename type="middle">Etzioni</forename><surname>Mausam</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Oren</forename><surname>Etzioni</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">EMNLP</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1721" to="1731" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Open information extraction from the web</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michele</forename><surname>Banko</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michael</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Cafarella</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Stephen</forename><surname>Soderland</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Matthew</forename><surname>Broadhead</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Oren</forename><surname>Etzioni</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">IJCAI 2007, Proceedings of the 20th International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Hyderabad, India</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007-01-06" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2670" to="2676" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Introduction to the conll-2005 shared task: Semantic role labeling</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xavier</forename><surname>Carreras</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Lluís</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of CONLL</title>
		<meeting>CONLL</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="152" to="164" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Towards coherent multi-document summarization</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Janara</forename><surname>Christensen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Stephen</forename><forename type="middle">Soderland</forename><surname>Mausam</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Stephen</forename><surname>Soderland</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Oren</forename><surname>Etzioni</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">HLT-NAACL</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Citeseer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1163" to="1173" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Clausie: clause-based open information extraction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Luciano</forename><surname>Del Corro</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rainer</forename><surname>Gemulla</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 22nd international conference on World Wide Web</title>
		<meeting>the 22nd international conference on World Wide Web</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="355" to="366" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>International World Wide Web Conferences Steering Committee</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Open information extraction from the Web</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Oren</forename><surname>Etzioni</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michele</forename><surname>Banko</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Stephen</forename><surname>Soderland</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Weld</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Communications of the ACM</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">51</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="68" to="74" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Identifying relations for open information extraction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Anthony</forename><surname>Fader</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Stephen</forename><surname>Soderland</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Oren</forename><surname>Etzioni</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</title>
		<meeting>the Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1535" to="1545" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Association for Computational Linguistics</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Question-answer driven semantic role labeling: Using natural language to annotate natural language</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Luheng</forename><surname>He</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mike</forename><surname>Lewis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Luke</forename><surname>Zettlemoyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">the Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>EMNLP</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Open language learning for information extraction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Mausam</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Stephen</forename><surname>Schmitz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Robert</forename><surname>Soderland</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Oren</forename><surname>Bart</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Etzioni</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2012 Joint Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing and Computational Natural Language Learning</title>
		<meeting>the 2012 Joint Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing and Computational Natural Language Learning<address><addrLine>Jeju Island, Korea</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2012-07" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="523" to="534" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The proposition bank: An annotated corpus of semantic roles</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Martha</forename><surname>Palmer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Daniel</forename><surname>Gildea</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Paul</forename><surname>Kingsbury</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Computational linguistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">31</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="71" to="106" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Open IE as an intermediate structure for semantic tasks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gabriel</forename><surname>Stanovsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ido</forename><surname>Dagan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mausam</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 53rd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the 53rd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Specifying and annotating reduced argument span via qa-srl</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gabriel</forename><surname>Stanovsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ido</forename><surname>Dagan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Meni</forename><surname>Adler</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 54rd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the 54rd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Getting more out of syntax with props</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gabriel</forename><surname>Stanovsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jessica</forename><surname>Ficler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ido</forename><surname>Dagan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yoav</forename><surname>Goldberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
<note type="report_type">arXiv preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Open information extraction using wikipedia</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Fei</forename><surname>Wu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Daniel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Weld</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 48th</title>
		<meeting>the 48th</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<monogr>
				<title level="m">Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Uppsala, Sweden</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="118" to="127" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Information extraction from wikipedia: Moving down the long tail</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Fei</forename><surname>Wu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Raphael</forename><surname>Hoffmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Weld</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 14th ACM SIGKDD international conference on Knowledge discovery and data mining</title>
		<meeting>the 14th ACM SIGKDD international conference on Knowledge discovery and data mining</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="731" to="739" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
