<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T11:30+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Nested Propositions in Open Information Extraction</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
				<availability status="unknown"><p>Copyright Association for Computational Linguistics</p>
				</availability>
				<date>November 1-5, 2016. 2016</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nikita</forename><surname>Bhutani</surname></persName>
							<email>nbhutani@umich.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Department of EECS</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Department of EECS</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep3">Department of EECS</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">University of Michigan</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">University of Michigan</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit3">University of Michigan</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ann</forename><surname>Arbor</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Department of EECS</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Department of EECS</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep3">Department of EECS</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">University of Michigan</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">University of Michigan</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit3">University of Michigan</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">V</forename><surname>Jagadish</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Department of EECS</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Department of EECS</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep3">Department of EECS</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">University of Michigan</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">University of Michigan</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit3">University of Michigan</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ann</forename><surname>Arbor</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Department of EECS</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Department of EECS</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep3">Department of EECS</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">University of Michigan</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">University of Michigan</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit3">University of Michigan</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dragomir</forename><surname>Radev</surname></persName>
							<email>radev@umich.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Department of EECS</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Department of EECS</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep3">Department of EECS</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">University of Michigan</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">University of Michigan</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit3">University of Michigan</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ann</forename><surname>Arbor</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Department of EECS</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Department of EECS</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep3">Department of EECS</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">University of Michigan</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">University of Michigan</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit3">University of Michigan</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Nested Propositions in Open Information Extraction</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2016 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</title>
						<meeting>the 2016 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing <address><addrLine>Austin, Texas</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="55" to="64"/>
							<date type="published">November 1-5, 2016. 2016</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>The challenges of Machine Reading and Knowledge Extraction at a web scale require a system capable of extracting diverse information from large, heterogeneous corpora. The Open Information Extraction (OIE) paradigm aims at extracting assertions from large corpora without requiring a vocabulary or relation-specific training data. Most systems built on this paradigm extract binary relations from arbitrary sentences, ignoring the context under which the assertions are correct and complete. They lack the expres-siveness needed to properly represent and extract complex assertions commonly found in the text. To address the lack of representation power, we propose NESTIE, which uses a nested representation to extract higher-order relations, and complex, interdependent assertions. Nesting the extracted propositions allows NESTIE to more accurately reflect the meaning of the original sentence. Our experimental study on real-world datasets suggests that NESTIE obtains comparable precision with better minimality and informative-ness than existing approaches. NESTIE produces 1.7-1.8 times more minimal extractions and achieves 1.1-1.2 times higher informative-ness than CLAUSIE.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Syntactic analyses produced by syntactic parsers are a long way from representing the full meaning of the sentences parsed. In particular, they cannot support questions like "Who did what to whom?", "Where did what happen?". Owing to the large, hetero- geneous corpora available at web scale, traditional approaches to information extraction <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Brin, 1998;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Agichtein and Gravano, 2000</ref>) fail to scale to the millions of relations found on the web. As a re- sponse, the paradigm of Open Information Extrac- tion (OIE) (  has seen a rise in interest as it eliminates the need for domain knowl- edge or relation-specific annotated data. OIE sys- tems use a collection of patterns over the surface form or dependency tree of a sentence to extract propositions of the form (arg1,rel,arg2).</p><p>However, state-of-the-art OIE systems, REVERB <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">(Fader et al., 2011</ref>) and OLLIE ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">Schmitz et al., 2012</ref>) focus on extracting binary assertions and suffer from three key drawbacks. First, lack of expressivity of representation leads to significant information loss for higher-order relations and complex assertions. This results in incomplete, uniformative and inco- herent prepositions. Consider Example 1 in Fig- ure 1. Important contextual information is either ignored or is subsumed in over-specified argument and relation phrases. It is not possible to fix such nuances by post-processing the propositions. This affects downstream applications like Question An- swering <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">(Fader et al., 2014</ref>) which rely on correct- ness and completeness of the propositions.</p><p>Second, natural language frequently includes re- lations presented in a non-canonical form that can- not be captured by a small set of extraction pat- terns that only extract relation mediated by verbs or a subset of verbal patterns. Consider Ex- ample 2 in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref> that asserts, "Rozsa Hill is the third hill near the river", "Rozsa Hill is Rose Hill" and "Rozsa Hill lies north of Cas- tle Hill". A verb-mediated pattern would extract</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>N:</head><p>P1: (body, appeared to have been thrown, ∅) P2: (P1, from, vehicle) P3: (A senior official in Iraq, said, P2) P4: (U.S. military police, found, body) a triple, (the third hill, lies north of, Castle Hill) that is less informative than a triple, (Rozsa, lies, north of Castle Hill) which is not mediated by a verb in the original sentence. Furthermore, these propositions are not complete. Specifically, queries of the form 'What is the other name of Rozsa Hill?", "Where is Rozsa Hill located?", "Which is the third hill near the river?" will either return no answer or return an uninformative answer with these propositions. Since information is encoded at various granularity levels, there is a need for a representation rich enough to ex- press such complex relations and sentence construc- tions.</p><p>Third, OIE systems tend to extract propositions with long argument phrases that are not minimal and are difficult to disambiguate or aggregate for downstream applications. For instance, the argu- ment phrase, body which was found by U.S. military police, is less likely to be useful than the argument phrase, body in Example 3 in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref>.</p><p>In this paper we present NESTIE, which over- comes these limitations by 1) expanding the propo- sition representation to nested expressions so addi- tional contextual information can be captured, 2) expanding the syntactic scope of relation phrases to allow relations mediated by other syntactic en- tities like nouns, adjectives and nominal modifiers. NESTIE bootstraps a small set of extraction pat- terns that cover simple sentences and learns broad- coverage relation-independent patterns. We believe that it is possible to adapt OIE systems that extract verb-based relations to process assertions denoting events with many arguments, and learn other non- clausal relations found in the text. With weakly- supervised learning techniques, patterns encoding these relations can be learned from a limited amount of data containing sentence equivalence pairs. This article is organized as follows. We pro- vide background on OIE in Sec. 2 followed by an overview of our proposed solution in Sec. 3. We then discuss how the extraction patterns for nested representations are learned in Sec. 4. In Sec. 5, we compare NESTIE against alternative methods on two datasets: Wikipedia and News. In Sec. 6, we discuss related work on pattern-based information extraction.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Background</head><p>The key goal of OIE is to obtain a shallow seman- tic representation of the text in the form of tuples consisting of argument phrases and a phrase that expresses the relation between the arguments. The phrases are identified automatically using domain- independent syntactic and lexical constraints. Some OIE systems are:</p><p>TextRunner (Yates et al., 2007) WOE (Wu and Weld, 2010): They use a sequence-labeling graph- ical model on extractions labeled automatically us- ing heuristics or distant supervision. Consequently, long-range dependencies, holistic and lexical as- pects of relations tend to get ignored.</p><p>ReVerb <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">(Fader et al., 2011</ref>): Trained with shallow syntactic features, REVERB uses a logistic regres- sion classifier to extract relations that begin with a verb and occur between argument phrases.</p><p>Ollie ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">Schmitz et al., 2012)</ref>: Bootstrapping from REVERB extractions, OLLIE learns syntactic and lexical dependency parse-tree patterns for extrac- tion. Some patterns reduce higher order relations to ReVerb-style relation phrases. Also, representa- tion is extended optionally to capture contextual in- formation about conditional truth and attribution for extractions.</p><p>ClausIE (Del Corro and Gemulla, 2013): Us- ing linguistic knowledge and a small set of domain- independent lexica, CLAUSIE identifies and classi- fies clauses into clause types, and then generates ex- tractions based on the clause type. It relies on a pre- defined set of rules on how to extract assertions in- stead of learning extraction patterns. Also, it doesn't capture the relations between the clauses.</p><p>There has been some work in open-domain in- formation extraction to extract higher-order rela- tions. <ref type="bibr">KRAKEN (Akbik and Löser, 2012</ref>) uses a predefined set of rules based on dependency parse to identify fact phrases and argument heads within fact phrases. But unlike alternative approaches, it doesn't canonicalize the fact phrases. There is another body of work in natural language under- standing that shares tasks with OIE. AMR parsing ( <ref type="bibr">Banarescu et al., )</ref>, semantic role labeling (SRL) ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">Toutanova et al., 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Punyakanok et al., 2008)</ref> and frame-semantic parsing ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Das et al., 2014</ref>). In these tasks, verbs or nouns are analyzed to identify their arguments. The verb or noun is then mapped to a semantic frame and roles of each argument in the frame are identified. These techniques have gained interest with the advent of hand-constructed seman- tic resources like <ref type="bibr">PropBank and FrameNet (Kingsbury and Palmer, 2002;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Baker et al., 1998</ref>). Gener- ally, the verb/noun and the semantically labeled ar- guments correspond to OIE propositions and, there- fore, the two tasks are considered similar. Systems like SRL-IE ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Christensen et al., 2010</ref>) explore if these techniques can be used for OIE. However, while OIE aims to identify the relation/predicate be- tween a pair of arguments, frame-based techniques aim to identify arguments and their roles with re- spect to a predicate. Hence, the frames won't corre- spond to propositions when both the arguments can- not be identified for a binary relation or when the correct argument is buried in long argument phrases. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Task Definition and NestIE Overview</head><p>Task: We focus on the task of OIE, where the sys- tem takes a natural language statement and extracts the supported assertions. This is achieved by us- ing an extractor that uses nested representations to extract propositions and a linker that connects ex- tracted propositions to capture context.</p><p>Proposition-based Extractor: We propose a framework to extend open-domain binary-relation extractors to extract n-ary and complex rela- tions. As not all assertions can be expressed as (arg1,rel,arg2), we learn syntactic patterns for relations that are expressed as nested templates like, (arg1,rel,(arg2,rel2,arg3)), ((arg1,rel,arg2),rel2,arg3).</p><p>Proposition Linking: In practice, it is infeasible to enumerate simple syntactic pattern templates that capture the entire meaning of a sentence. Also, in- creasing the complexity of templates would lead to sparsity issues while bootstrapping. We assume that there is a finite set of inter-proposition relations that can be captured using a small set of rules which take into account the structural properties of the propo- sitions and syntactic dependencies between the rela- tion phrases of the propositions.</p><p>System Evaluation: To compare NESTIE to other alternative methods, we conduct an experi- mental study on two real-world datasets: Wikipedia and News. Propositions from each system are eval- uated for correctness, minimality, and informative- ness.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Template</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Example</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Pattern:</head><p>A body has been found by police. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Proposition Extraction</head><p>Figure 2 illustrates the system architecture of NESTIE. First, a set of high-precision seed tem- plates is used to extract propositions. A template maps a dependency parse-tree pattern to a triple representation such as (arg1,rel,arg2) for bi- nary relations, or a nested triple representation such as ((arg1,rel,arg2),rel2,arg3) for n- ary relations. Furthermore, an argument is allowed to be a sequence of words, "arg2 rel2 arg3" to capture its nominal modifiers. Then, using a RTE dataset that contains syntactic paraphrases, NESTIE learns equivalent parse-tree patterns for each tem- plate in the seed set. These patterns are used to ex- tract propositions which are then linked.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">Constructing Seed Set</head><p>We use a set of 13 hand-written templates. Each template maps an extraction pattern for a simple sentence to corresponding representation. A sub- set of these templates is shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 3</ref>. To create a seed set of propositions, we use the RTE dataset which is comprised of statements and their entailed hypotheses. We observed that most of the hypotheses were syntactic variants of the facts in their corresponding statements. These hypotheses were also short with a single, independent clause. These shared sentence constructions could be cap- tured with a small set of templates. We iteratively create templates until at least one proposition could be extracted for each hypothesis. The propositions from the hypotheses form the set for bootstrapping.</p><p>For each seed proposition extracted from a hy- pothesis, the statement entailing the hypothesis con- tains all the content words of the proposition and expresses the same information as the proposition. However, there is a closed class of words, such as prepositions, a subset of adverbs, determiners, verbs etc. that does not modify the underlying meaning of the hypothesis or the statement and can be consid- ered auxiliary. These were ignored while construct- ing the seed set.</p><p>Example 1 Consider a statement-hypothesis pair, Statement: Paul Bremer, the top U.S. civilian admin- istrator in Iraq, and Iraq's new president, Ghazi al- Yawar, visited the northern Iraqi city of Kirkuk. Hypothesis: Ghazi al-Yawar is the president of Iraq. The hypothesis is entailed in the statement. The seed templates extract propositions from the hypothesis: (al-Yawar,is,president, (al-Yawar,is,president of Iraq), and (al-Yawar,is president of,Iraq).</p><p>Bootstrapping is a popular technique to gener- ate positive training data for information extraction <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Collins and Singer, 1999;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Hoffmann et al., 2011</ref>). We extend the bootstrapping techniques employed in OLLIE and RENOUN, for n-ary and complex re- lations. First, instead of learning dependency parse- tree patterns connecting the heads of the argument phrases and the relation phrase connecting them, we learn the dependency parse-tree patterns connect- ing the heads of all argument and relation phrases in the template. This allows greater coverage of context for the propositions and prevents the argu- ments/relations from being over-specified and/or un- informative. Second, some of the relations in the representation are derived from the type of depen- dency, e.g. type of nominal modifier. As these relations are implicit, and might not be present in the paraphrase, they are ignored for learning. In- tuitively, with such constraints, paraphrases "Mary gave John a car" and "Mary gave a car to John" can map to the same representation.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">Extraction Pattern Learning</head><p>The biggest challenge in information extraction is the multitude of ways in which information can be expressed. Since it is not possible to enumerate all the different syntactic variations of an assertion, there is a need to learn general patterns that encode the various ways of expressing the assertion. In par- ticular, we learn the various syntactic patterns that can encode the same information as the seed patterns and hence can be mapped to same representation. NESTIE tries to learn the different ways in which the content words of a seed proposition from a hy- pothesis can be expressed in the statement that en- tails this hypothesis. We use the Stanford depen- dency parser <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(De Marneffe et al., 2006</ref>) to parse the statement and identify the path connecting the content words in the parse tree. If such a path ex- ists, we retain the syntactic constraints on the nodes and edges in the path and ignore the surface forms of the nodes in the path. This helps generalize the learned patterns to unseen relations and arguments. NESTIE could learn 183 templates from the 13 seed templates. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">Figure 4</ref> shows a subset of these patterns.  arg1, be, arg2), returning proposition, (al-Yawar,is,president of Iraq). With bootstrapping, the syntactic pattern from the statement is mapped to the same representation.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3">Pattern Matching</head><p>Once the extraction patterns are learned, we use these patterns to extract propositions from new un- seen sentences. We first parse a new sentence and match the patterns against the parse tree. As the pat- terns only capture the heads of the arguments and relations, we expand the extracted propositions to increase the coverage of context of the arguments as in the original sentence.</p><p>Example 3 In the statement from Example 1, the extraction patterns capture the dependency path con- necting the head words: Iraq, administrator and Paul Bremer. However, to capture the con- textual information, further qualification of the argu- ment node, administrator, is required.</p><p>Following this observation, we expand the arguments on nmod, amod, compound, nummod, det, neg edges. We expand the relations on advmod, neg, aux, auxpass, cop, nmod edges. Only the dependency edges not captured in the pattern are considered for expansion. Also, the order of words from the original sentence is retained in the argument phrases.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.4">Proposition Linking</head><p>NESTIE uses a nested representation to capture the context of extracted propositions. The context could include condition, attribution, belief, order, reason and more. Since it is not possible to generate or learn patterns that can express these complex assertions as a whole, NESTIE links the various propositions from the previous step to generate nested proposi- tions that are complete and closer in meaning to the original statement.</p><p>The proposition linking module is based on the assumption that the inter-proposition relation can be inferred from the dependency parse of the sentence from which propositions were extracted. Some of the rules employed to link the propositions are:</p><p>• The relation of proposition P1 has a relation- ship to the relation of proposition P2.  Consider the statement, "The accident happened af- ter the chief guest had left the event." and propo- sitions, P1: (accident, happen, φ) and P2: (chief guest, had left, event). Us- ing dependency edge, nmod:after, the linking re- turns (P1,after,P2).</p><p>• Proposition P1 is argument in proposition P2.</p><p>Consider the statement, "A senior offi- cial said the body appeared to have been thrown from a vehicle." and propositions, P1:</p><p>(body,appeared to have been thrown from,vehicle) and P2: (senior official,said,φ). The linking updates P2 to (senior official,said,P1).</p><p>• An inner nested proposition is replaced with a more descriptive alternative proposition.</p><p>We use dependency parse patterns to link proposi- tions. We find correspondences between: a ccomp edge and a clausal complement, an advcl edge and a conditional, a nmod edge and a relation modi- fier. For clausal complements, a null argument in the source proposition is updated with the target propo- sition. For conditionals and nominal modifiers, a new proposition is created with the source and target propositions as arguments. The relation of the new proposition is derived from the target of the mark edge from the relation head of target proposition.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.5">Comparison with Ollie</head><p>NESTIE uses an approach similar to OLLIE and WOE to learn dependency parse based syntactic pat- terns. However, there are significant differences. First, OLLIE and WOE rely on extractions from REVERB and Wikipedia info-boxes respectively for bootstrapping. Most of these relations are binary. On the contrary, our algorithm is based on high- confidence seed templates that are more expressive and hence learn patterns expressing different ways in which the proposition as a whole can be expressed. Though the arguments in OLLIE can be expanded to include the n-ary arguments, NESTIE encodes them in the seed templates and learns different ways of expressing these arguments. Also, similar to OL- LIE, NESTIE can extract propositions that are not just mediated by verbs.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Experiments</head><p>We conducted an experimental study to compare NESTIE to other state-of-the-art extractors. We found that it achieves higher informativeness and produces more correct and minimal propositions than other extractors.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.1">Experimental Setup</head><p>We used two datasets released by <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(Del Corro and Gemulla, 2013</ref>) in our experiments: 200 random sentences from Wikipedia, and 200 random sen- tences from New York Times (NYT). We compared  NESTIE against three OIE systems: REVERB, OL- LIE and CLAUSIE. Since the source code for each of the extractors was available, we independently ran the extractors on the two datasets. Next, to make the extractions comparable, we configured the extrac- tors to generate triple propositions. REVERB and CLAUSIE extractions were available as triples by default. OLLIE extends its triple proposition repre- sentation. So, we generated an additional extraction for each of the possible extensions of a proposition. NESTIE uses a nested representation. So, we simply extracted the innermost proposition in a nested rep- resentation as a triple and allowed the subject and the object in the outer proposition to contain a ref- erence to the inner triple. By preserving references the context of a proposition is retained while allow- ing for queries at various granularity levels.</p><p>We manually labeled the extractions obtained from all extractors to 1) maintain consistency, 2) additionally, assess if extracted triples were infor- mative and minimal. Some extractors use heuris- tics to identify arguments and/or relation phrase boundaries, which leads to over-specific arguments that render the extractions unusable for other down- stream applications. To assess the usability of ex- tractions, we evaluated them for minimality <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Bast and Haussmann, 2013)</ref>. Furthermore, the goal of our system is to extract as many propositions as pos- sible and lose as little information as possible. We measure this as informativeness of the set of the ex- tractions for a sentence. Since computing informa- tiveness as a percentage of text contained in at least one extraction could be biased towards long extrac- tions, we used an explicit rating scale to measure informativeness.</p><p>Two CS graduate student labeled each extraction for correctness (0 or 1) and minimality (0 or 1). For each sentence, they label the set of extractions for in- formativeness (0-5). An extraction is marked correct if it is asserted in the text and correctly captures the contextual information. An extraction is considered minimal if the arguments are not over-specified i.e. they don't subsume another extraction or have con- junctions or are excessively long. Lastly, they rank the set of extractions on a scale of 0-5 (0 for bad, 5 for good) based on the coverage of information in the original sentence. The agreement between label- ers was measured in terms of Cohens Kappa.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.2">Comparative Results</head><p>The results of our experimental study are summa- rized in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">Figure 5</ref> which shows the number of cor- rect and minimal extractions, as well as the total number of extractions for each extractor and dataset. For each dataset, we also report the macro-average of informativeness reported by the labelers. We found moderate inter-annotator agreement: 0.59 on correctness and 0.53 on minimality for both the datasets. Each extractor also includes a confidence score for the propositions. But since each extractor has its unique method to find confidence, we com- pare the precision over all the extractions instead of a subset of high-confidence extractions.</p><p>NESTIE produced many more extractions, and more informative extractions than other systems. There appears to be a trade-off between informa- tiveness and correctness (which are akin to recall and precision, respectively). CLAUSEIE is the sys- tem with results closer to NESTIE than other sys- tems. However, the nested representation and propo- sition linking used by NESTIE produce substantially more (1.7-1.8 times more) minimal extractions than CLAUSEIE, which generates propositions from the constituents of the clause. Learning non-verb medi-ated extraction patterns and proposition linking also increase the syntactic scope of relation expressions and context. This is also reflected in the average informativeness score of the extractions. NESTIE achieves 1.1-1.9 times higher informativeness score than the other systems.</p><p>We believe that nested representation directly im- proves minimality, independent of other aspects of extractor design. To explore this idea, we conducted experiments on OLLIE, which does not expand the context of the arguments heuristically unlike other extractors. Of the extractions labeled correct but not minimal by the annotators on the Wikipedia dataset, we identified extractions that satisfy one of: 1) has an argument for which there is an equivalent extrac- tion (nested extractions), 2) shares the same subject with another extraction whose relation phrase con- tains the relation and object of this extraction (n- ary extractions), 3) has an object with conjunction. Any such extractions can be made minimal and in- formative with a nested representation. 73.75% of the non-minimal correct extractions met at least one of these conditions, so by a post-processing step, we could raise the minimality score of OLLIE by 17.65%, from 76.1% to 93.75%.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.3">Error Analysis of NestIE</head><p>We did a preliminary analysis of the errors made by NESTIE. We found that in most of the cases (about 33%-35%), extraction errors were due to in- correct dependency parsing. This is not surprising as NESTIE relies heavily on the parser for learning ex- traction patterns and linking propositions. An incor- rect parse affects NESTIE more than other systems which are not focused on extracting finer grained in- formation and can trade-off minimality for correct- ness. An incorrect parse not only affects the pattern matching but also proposition linking which either fails to link two propositions or produces an incor- rect proposition.</p><p>Example 4 Consider the statement, "A day after strong winds stirred up the Hauraki Gulf and broke the mast of Team New Zealand, a lack of wind caused Race 5 of the America's Cup to be aban- doned today.". The statement entails following as- sertions: A1: "strong winds stirred up the Hauraki Gulf" A2: "strong winds broke the mast of Team New Zealand" A3: "a lack of wind caused Race 5 of the America's Cup to be abandoned" A1 and A2 are parsed correctly. A3 is parsed incorrectly with Race 5 as object of the verb caused. Some extractors either don't capture A3 or return an over-specified extraction, (a lack of wind, caused, Race 5 of the America 's Cup to be abandoned today). Such an extraction is correct but not minimal.</p><p>To maintain minimality, NESTIE aims to extract propositions, P1: (Race 5 of the America 's Cup, be abandoned, φ) and P2: (a lack of wind, caused, P1). However, it fails because of parser errors. It extracts incorrect proposition, P3: (a lack of wind, caused, Race 5) corresponding to A3 and links it to propo- sitions for A1 and A2. Linking an incorrect propo- sition generates more incorrect propositions which hurt the system performance.</p><p>However, we hope this problem can be allevi- ated to some extent as parsers become more robust. Another approach could be to use clause segmenta- tion to first identify clause boundaries and then use NESTIE on reduced clauses. As the problem be- comes more severe for longer sentences, we wish to explore clause processing for complex sentences in future.</p><p>Another source of errors was under-specified propositions. Since our nested representation al- lows null arguments for intransitive verb phrases and for linking propositions, failure to find an ar- gument/proposition results in an under-specified ex- traction. We found that 27% of the errors were be- cause of null arguments. However, by ignoring ex- tractions with null arguments we found that preci- sion increases by only 4%-6% (on Wikipedia). This explains that many of the extractions with empty ar- guments were correct, and need special handling. Other sources of errors were: aggressive general- ization of an extraction pattern to unseen relations (24%), unidentified dependency types while parsing long, complex sentences (21%), and errors in ex- panding the scope of arguments and linking extrac- tions (20%).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>62</head><p>As OIE has gained popularity to extract propositions from large corpora of unstructured text, the problem of the extractions being uninformative and incom- plete has surfaced. A recent paper <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(Bast and Haussmann, 2014</ref>) pointed out that a significant fraction of the extracted propositions is not informative. A simple inference algorithm was proposed that uses generic rules for each semantic class of predicate to derive new triples from extracted triples. Though it improved the informativeness of extracted triples, it did not alleviate the problem of lost context in com- plex sentences. We, therefore, create our own ex- tractions.</p><p>Some recent works ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Bast and Haussmann, 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Angeli et al., 2015</ref>) have tried to address the prob- lem of long and uninformative extractions in open- domain information extraction by finding short en- tailment or clusters of semantically related con- stituents from a longer utterance. These clusters are reduced to triples using schema mapping to known relation types or using a set of hand-crafted rules. NESTIE shares similar objectives but uses boot- strapping to learn extraction patterns.</p><p>Bootstrapping and pattern learning has a long his- tory in traditional information extraction. Systems like DIPRE <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Brin, 1998)</ref>, SNOWBALL <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Agichtein and Gravano, 2000</ref>), NELL <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">(Mitchell, 2010)</ref>, and OLLIE bootstrap based on seed instances of a rela- tion and then learn patterns for extraction. We fol- low a similar bootstrapping algorithm to learn ex- traction patterns for n-ary and nested propositions.</p><p>Using a nested representation to express com- plex and n-ary assertions has been studied in closed- domain or ontology-aided information extraction. <ref type="bibr">Yago (Suchanek et al., 2008)</ref> and <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">(Nakashole and Mitchell, 2015)</ref> extend binary relations to capture temporal, geospatial and prepositional context infor- mation. We study such a representation for open- domain information extraction.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7">Conclusions</head><p>We presented NESTIE, a novel open information ex- tractor that uses nested representation for expressing complex propositions and inter-propositional rela- tions. It extends the bootstrapping techniques of pre- vious approaches to learn syntactic extraction pat- terns for the nested representation. This allows it to obtain higher informativeness and minimality scores for extractions at comparable precision. It produces 1.7-1.8 times more minimal extractions and achieves 1.1-1.2 times higher informativeness than CLAU- SEIE. Thus far, we have tested our bootstrap learn- ing and proposition linking approaches only on a small dataset. We believe that its performance will improve with larger datasets. NESTIE can be seen as a step towards a system that has a greater aware- ness of the context of each extraction and provides informative extractions to downstream applications.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: Example propositions from OIE systems: REVERB (R), OLLIE (O) and NESTIE(N).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2: System Architecture of NESTIE.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Figure 3: Seed templates and corresponding representation.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>Example 2</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Consider dependency parse-subtree of the statement and hypothesis from Example 1, Statement: Iraq poss −→ president appos −→ al − Y awar Hypothesis: al −Y awar nsubj ←− president of −→ Iraq A seed extraction pattern maps the parse- tree of the hypothesis to the representation,</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head>(</head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><head>Figure 4 :</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Figure 4: Syntactic Patterns learned using bootstrapping.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_6"><head>Figure 5 :</head><label>5</label><figDesc>Figure 5: Informativeness and number of correct and minimal extractions as fraction of total extractions.</figDesc></figure>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>This research was supported in part by NSF grants IIS 1250880 and IIS 1017296.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Snowball: Extracting relations from large plain-text collections</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Eugene</forename><surname>Agichtein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Luis</forename><surname>Gravano</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the fifth ACM conference on Digital libraries</title>
		<meeting>the fifth ACM conference on Digital libraries</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="85" to="94" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Kraken: N-ary facts in open information extraction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alan</forename><surname>Akbik</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alexander</forename><surname>Löser</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the AKBC-WEKEX</title>
		<meeting>the AKBC-WEKEX</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="52" to="56" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Leveraging linguistic structure for open domain information extraction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gabor</forename><surname>Angeli</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Melvin</forename><forename type="middle">Johnson</forename><surname>Premkumar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christopher D</forename><surname>Manning</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of ACL</title>
		<meeting>ACL</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="26" to="31" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The berkeley framenet project</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Collin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Charles</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Baker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">John B</forename><surname>Fillmore</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Lowe</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 17th international conference on Computational linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the 17th international conference on Computational linguistics</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="86" to="90" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Laura</forename><surname>Banarescu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Claire</forename><surname>Bonial</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Shu</forename><surname>Cai</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Madalina</forename><surname>Georgescu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kira</forename><surname>Griffitt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ulf</forename><surname>Hermjakob</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<pubPlace>Kevin Knight, Philipp Koehn, Martha Palmer, and Nathan Schneider</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Abstract meaning representation (amr) 1.0 specification</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Open information extraction for the web</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michele</forename><surname>Banko</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Michael</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Stephen</forename><surname>Cafarella</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Matthew</forename><surname>Soderland</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Oren</forename><surname>Broadhead</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Etzioni</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">In IJCAI</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2670" to="2676" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Open information extraction via contextual sentence decomposition</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hannah</forename><surname>Bast</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Elmar</forename><surname>Haussmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">IEEE-ICSC 2013</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="154" to="159" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">More informative open information extraction via simple inference</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hannah</forename><surname>Bast</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Elmar</forename><surname>Haussmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Advances in information retrieval</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="585" to="590" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Extracting patterns and relations from the world wide web</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Sergey Brin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">The World Wide Web and Databases</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="172" to="183" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Semantic role labeling for open information extraction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Janara</forename><surname>Christensen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Stephen</forename><surname>Soderland</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Oren</forename><surname>Etzioni</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the NAACL-HLT 2010</title>
		<meeting>the NAACL-HLT 2010</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="52" to="60" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Unsupervised models for named entity classification</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Collins</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yoram</forename><surname>Singer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the joint SIGDAT conference on empirical methods in natural language processing and very large corpora</title>
		<meeting>the joint SIGDAT conference on empirical methods in natural language processing and very large corpora</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Citeseer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="100" to="110" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Frame-semantic parsing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dipanjan</forename><surname>Das</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Desai</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>André</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nathan</forename><surname>Martins</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Noah A</forename><surname>Schneider</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Smith</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Computational linguistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">40</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="9" to="56" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Generating typed dependency parses from phrase structure parses</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marie-Catherine De</forename><surname>Marneffe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bill</forename><surname>Maccartney</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christopher</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Manning</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of LREC</title>
		<meeting>LREC</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="449" to="454" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Clausie: clause-based open information extraction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Luciano</forename><surname>Del Corro</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rainer</forename><surname>Gemulla</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the IW3C2</title>
		<meeting>the IW3C2</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="355" to="366" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Identifying relations for open information extraction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Anthony</forename><surname>Fader</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Stephen</forename><surname>Soderland</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Oren</forename><surname>Etzioni</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of EMNLP</title>
		<meeting>EMNLP</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1535" to="1545" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Open question answering over curated and extracted knowledge bases</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Anthony</forename><surname>Fader</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Luke</forename><surname>Zettlemoyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Oren</forename><surname>Etzioni</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of ACMSIGKDD</title>
		<meeting>ACMSIGKDD</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1156" to="1165" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Knowledgebased weak supervision for information extraction of overlapping relations</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Raphael</forename><surname>Hoffmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Congle</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xiao</forename><surname>Ling</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Luke</forename><surname>Zettlemoyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Weld</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of ACL-HLT</title>
		<meeting>ACL-HLT</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="541" to="550" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">From treebank to propbank</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Paul</forename><surname>Kingsbury</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Martha</forename><surname>Palmer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">LREC</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Never-ending learning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tom</forename><surname>Mitchell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>DTIC Document, Carnegie Mellon University</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
<note type="report_type">Technical report</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A knowledge-intensive model for prepositional phrase attachment</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ndapandula</forename><surname>Nakashole</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Tom</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Mitchell</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of ACL</title>
		<meeting>ACL</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="365" to="375" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The importance of syntactic parsing and inference in semantic role labeling</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Punyakanok</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Roth</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Yih</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Computational Linguistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">34</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Open language learning for information extraction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Schmitz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Robert</forename><surname>Bart</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Stephen</forename><surname>Soderland</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Oren</forename><surname>Etzioni</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of EMNLP-CoNLL 2012</title>
		<meeting>EMNLP-CoNLL 2012</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="523" to="534" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Yago: A large ontology from wikipedia and wordnet</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gjergji</forename><surname>Fabian M Suchanek</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gerhard</forename><surname>Kasneci</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Weikum</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Web Semantics: Science, Services and Agents on the World Wide Web</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="203" to="217" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A global joint model for semantic role labeling</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kristina</forename><surname>Toutanova</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Aria</forename><surname>Haghighi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christopher D</forename><surname>Manning</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Computational Linguistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">34</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="161" to="191" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Open information extraction using wikipedia</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Fei</forename><surname>Wu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Daniel S Weld</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the ACL</title>
		<meeting>the ACL</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="118" to="127" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Textrunner: open information extraction on the web</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alexander</forename><surname>Yates</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Cafarella</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michele</forename><surname>Banko</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Oren</forename><surname>Etzioni</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Matthew</forename><surname>Broadhead</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Stephen</forename><surname>Soderland</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of NAACL-HLT: Demonstrations</title>
		<meeting>NAACL-HLT: Demonstrations</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="25" to="26" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
