<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T11:04+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Identifying Dogmatism in Social Media: Signals and Models</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
				<availability status="unknown"><p>Copyright Association for Computational Linguistics</p>
				</availability>
				<date>November 1-5, 2016. 2016</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ethan</forename><surname>Fast</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Eric</forename><surname>Horvitz</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Identifying Dogmatism in Social Media: Signals and Models</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2016 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</title>
						<meeting>the 2016 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing <address><addrLine>Austin, Texas</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="690" to="699"/>
							<date type="published">November 1-5, 2016. 2016</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>We explore linguistic and behavioral features of dogmatism in social media and construct statistical models that can identify dogmatic comments. Our model is based on a corpus of Reddit posts, collected across a diverse set of conversational topics and annotated via paid crowdsourcing. We operationalize key aspects of dogmatism described by existing psychology theories (such as over-confidence), finding they have predictive power. We also find evidence for new signals of dogmatism, such as the tendency of dogmatic posts to refrain from signaling cognitive processes. When we use our predictive model to analyze millions of other Reddit posts, we find evidence that suggests dogmatism is a deeper personality trait, present for dogmatic users across many different domains, and that users who engage on dogmatic comments tend to show increases in dogmatic posts themselves.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>"I'm supposed to trust the opinion of a MS min- ion? The people that produced Windows ME, Vista and 8? They don't even understand people, yet they think they can predict the behavior of new, self- guiding AI?" -anonymous "I think an AI would make it easier for Patients to confide their information because by nature, a robot cannot judge them. Win-win? :D"' -anonymous Dogmatism describes the tendency to lay down opinions as incontrovertibly true, without respect for conflicting evidence or the opinions of others <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">(Oxford Dictionary, 2016)</ref>. Which user is more dog- matic in the examples above? This question is sim- ple for humans. Phrases like "they think" and "they don't even understand," suggest an intractability of opinion, while "I think" and "win-win?" suggest the opposite. Can we train computers to draw sim- ilar distinctions? Work in psychology has called out many aspects of dogmatism that can be modeled computationally via natural language, such as over- confidence and strong emotions <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">(Rokeach, 1954)</ref>.</p><p>We present a statistical model of dogmatism that addresses two complementary goals. First, we val- idate psychological theories by examining the pre- dictive power of feature sets that guide the model's predictions. For example, do linguistic signals of certainty help to predict a post is dogmatic, as the- ory would suggest? Second, we apply our model to answer four questions:</p><p>R1: What kinds of topics (e.g., guns, LGBT) at- tract the highest levels of dogmatism? R2: How do dogmatic beliefs cluster? R3: How does dogmatism influence a conversa- tion on social media? R4: How do other user behaviors (e.g., frequency and breadth of posts) relate to dogmatism?</p><p>We train a predictive model to classify dogmatic posts from Reddit, one of the most popular discus- sion communities on the web. <ref type="bibr">1</ref> Posts on Reddit cap- ture discussion and debate across a diverse set of do- mains and topics -users talk about everything from climate change and abortion, to world news and re- lationship advice, to the future of artificial intelli- gence. As a prerequisite to training our model, we have created a corpus of 5,000 Reddit posts anno- tated with levels of dogmatism, which we are releas- ing to share with other researchers. Using the model, we operationalize key domain- independent aspects of psychological theories of dogmatism drawn from the literature. We find these features have predictive power that largely supports the underlying theory. For example, posts that use less confident language tend to be less dogmatic. We also discover evidence for new attributes of dog- matism. For example, dogmatic posts tend not to verbalize cognition, through terms such as "I think," "possibly," or "might be."</p><p>Our model is trained on only 5,000 annotated posts, but once trained, we use it to analyze millions of other Reddit posts to answer our research ques- tions. We find a diverse set of topics are colored by dogmatic language (e.g., people are dogmatic about religion, but also about LGBT issues). Further, we find some evidence for dogmatism as a deeper per- sonality trait -people who are strongly dogmatic about one topic are more likely to express dogmatic views about others as well. Finally, in conversation, we discover that one user's dogmatism tends to bring out dogmatism in their conversational partner, form- ing a vicious cycle.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Dogmatism data</head><p>Posts on Reddit capture debate and discussion across a diverse set of topics, making them a natural start- ing point for untangling domain-independent lin- guistic features of dogmatism.</p><p>Data collection. Subreddits are sub-communities on Reddit oriented around specific interests or top- ics, such as technology or politics. Sampling from Reddit as a whole would bias the model towards the most commonly discussed content. But by sampling posts from individual subreddits, we can control the kinds of posts we use to train our model. To collect a diverse training dataset, we have randomly sampled 1000 posts each from the subreddits politics, busi- ness, science, and AskReddit, and 1000 additional posts from the Reddit frontpage. All posts in our sample appeared between January 2007 and March 2015, and to control for length effects, contain be- tween 300 and 400 characters. This results in a total training dataset of 5000 posts.</p><p>Dogmatism annotations. Building a useful com- putational model requires labeled training data. We labeled the Reddit dataset using crowdworkers on Amazon Mechanical Turk (AMT), creating the first public corpus annotated with levels of dogmatism. We asked crowdworkers to rate levels of dogmatism on a 5-point Likert scale, as supported by similar annotation tasks in prior work <ref type="bibr">(Danescu-NiculescuMizil et al., 2013</ref>). Concretely, we gave crowdwork- ers the following task:</p><p>Given a comment, imagine you hold a well- informed, different opinion from the com- menter in question. We'd like you to tell us how likely that commenter would be to engage you in a constructive conversation about your disagreement, where you each are able to ex- plore the other's beliefs. The options are: (5): It's unlikely you'll be able to engage in any substantive conversation. When you re- spectfully express your disagreement, they are likely to ignore you or insult you or otherwise lower the level of discourse. (4): They are deeply rooted in their opinion, but you are able to exchange your views with- out the conversation degenerating too much. (3): It's not likely you'll be able to change their mind, but you're easily able to talk and understand each other's point of view.</p><p>(2): They may have a clear opinion about the subject, but would likely be open to discussing alternative viewpoints.</p><p>(1): They are not set in their opinion, and it's possible you might change their mind. If the comment does not convey an opinion of any kind, you may also select this option.</p><p>To ensure quality work, we restricted the task to Masters workers and provided examples corre- sponding to each point on the scale. Including ex- amples in a task has been shown to significantly increase the agreement and quality of crowdwork ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Doroudi et al., 2016)</ref>. For instance, here is an ex- ample of a highly dogmatic (5) comment: I won't be happy until I see the executive suite of BofA, Wells, and all the others, frog- marched into waiting squad cars. It's AL- READY BEEN ESTABLISHED that...</p><p>And a minimally dogmatic (1) comment:</p><p>I agree. I would like to compile a playlist for us trance yogi's, even if you just would like to experiment with it. Is there any preference on which platform to use?</p><p>Each comment has been annotated by three indepen- dent workers on AMT, which is enough to produce reliable results in most labeling tasks ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">Sheng et al., 2008)</ref>. To compute an aggregate measure of dogma- tism for each comment, we summed the scores of all three workers. We show the resulting distribution of annotations in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref>.</p><p>Inter-annotator agreement. To evaluate the reli- ability of annotations we compute Krippendorff's α, a measure of agreement designed for variable levels of measurement such as a Likert scale <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Hayes and Krippendorff, 2007</ref>). An α of 0 indicates agreement indistinguishable from chance, while an α of 1 indi- cates perfect agreement. Across all annotations we find α = 0.44. While workers agree much more than chance, clearly dogmatism is also subjective. In fact, when we examine only the middle two quar- tiles of the dogmatism annotations, we find agree- ment is no better than chance. Alternatively, when we measure agreement only among the top and bot- tom quartiles of annotations, we find agreement of α = 0.69. This suggests comments with scores that are only slightly dogmatic are unreliable and often subject to human disagreement. For this reason, we use only the top and bottom quartiles of comments when training our model.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Approaches to Identifying Dogmatism</head><p>We now consider strategies for identifying dog- matism based on prior work in psychology. We start with the Linguistic Inquiry and Word Count (LIWC), a lexicon popular in the social sciences ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">Pennebaker et al., 2001</ref>). LIWC provides human validated lists of words that correspond to high- level psychological categories such as certainty or perception. In other studies, LIWC has uncovered linguistic signals relating to politeness <ref type="bibr">(DanescuNiculescu-Mizil et al., 2013)</ref>, deception <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">(Yoo and Gretzel, 2009)</ref>, or authority in texts <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(Gilbert, 2012)</ref>. Here, we examine how dogmatism relates to 17 of LIWC's categories <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">(Table 1)</ref>.</p><p>To compute the relationships between LIWC cat- egories and dogmatism, we first count the relevant category terms that appear in each annotated Reddit comment, normalized by its word count. We then calculate odds ratios on the aggregate counts of each LIWC category over the top and bottom quartiles of dogmatic comments. As we have discussed, using the top and bottom quartiles of comments provides a more reliable signal of dogmatism. We check for significant differences in categories between dog- matic and non-dogmatic comments using the Mann- Whitney U test and apply Holmes method for cor- rection. All odds we report in this section are signif- icant after correction.</p><p>Dogmatic statements tend to express a high de- gree of certainty <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">(Rokeach, 1954)</ref>. Here we consider LIWC categories that express certainty both posi- tively (certainty) and negatively (tentativeness). For example, the word "always" is certain, while "possi- bly" is tentative. Conforming to existing theory, cer- tainty is more associated with dogmatic comments (1.52 odds), while tentativeness is more associated with the absence of dogmatism (0.88 odds).</p><p>Terms used to verbalize cognition can act as a hedge that often characterizes non-dogmatic lan- guage. LIWC's insight category captures this effect through words such as "think," "know," or "believe." These words add nuance to a statement <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">(Pennebaker and Francis, 1996)</ref>, signaling it is the product of someone's mind ("I think you should give this paper a good review") and not meant to be interpreted as an objective truth. Along these lines, we find the use of terms in the insight category is associated with non-dogmatic comments (0.83 odds).</p><p>Sensory language, with its focus on description and detail, often signals a lack of any kind of opin- ion, dogmatic or otherwise. LIWC's perception cat- egory captures this idea through words associated with hearing, feeling, or seeing. For example, these words might occur when recounting a personal ex- perience ("I saw his incoming fist"), which even if emotionally charged or negative, is less likely to be dogmatic. We find perception is associated with</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Strategy</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Odds</head><p>Example Certainty 1.33* Be a hate monger all you want... Your life will never truly be happy though, and you will never know peace. Tentativeness 0.88* Most are likely to be more technically advanced and, if still using radio, might very well be emitting signals we could detect Insight 0.83* I think stating the obvious is a necessary function. Information like this is important to consider... Perception 0.77* I saw four crows on that same branch, staring at the deceased. The silence of the crows was deafening. Relativity 0.82* I've known a number to go into shock during the procedure Comparison 0.91 This may be more than a coincidence. I (pronouns) 0.68* Like I said, I want to believe the former. I'm glad it worked out. You (pronouns) 2.18* I don't give a fuck what you do. You can get drink yourself to death, you can get yourself pregnant... We (pronouns) 0.96 We need a bigger, better, colder fridge. We have worked hard...  Strategy describes the psychological category. Odds describes the likelihood that a category will appear more often in a dogmatic comment (e.g., dogmatic comments are 2.18 times more likely to mention you-oriented phrases). Example illustrates a comment that matches the category. * indicates significance (p &lt; 0.05) after correction with Holmes method.</p><p>non-dogmatic comments at 0.77 odds. Drawing comparisons or qualifying something as relative to something else conveys a nuance that is absent from traditionally dogmatic language. The LIWC categories comparison and relativity capture these effects through comparison words such as "than" or "as" and qualifying words such as "dur- ing" or "when." For example, the statement "I hate politicians" is more dogmatic than "I hate politicians when they can't get anything done.' Relativity is as- sociated with non-dogmatic comments at 0.80 odds, but comparison does not reach significance.</p><p>Pronouns can be surprisingly revealing indicators of language: for example, signaling one's gender or hierarchical status in a conversation <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">(Pennebaker, 2011)</ref>. We find first person singular pronouns are a useful negative signal for dogmatism (0.46 odds), while second person singular pronouns (2.18 odds) and third person plural (1.63 odds) are a useful pos- itive signal. Looking across the corpus, we see I of- ten used with a hedge ("I think" or "I know"), while you and they tend to characterize the beliefs of oth-ers, often in a strongly opinionated way ("you are a moron" or "they are keeping us down"). Other pro- noun types do not show significant relationships.</p><p>Like pronouns, verb tense can reveal subtle sig- nals in language use, such as the tendency of medi- cal inpatients to focus on the past ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">Wolf et al., 2007</ref>). On social media, comments written in the present tense are more likely to be oriented towards a user's current interaction ("this is all so stupid"), creating opportunities to signal dogmatism. Alternatively, comments in the past tense are more likely to re- fer to outside experiences ("it was an awful party"), speaking less to a user's stance towards an ongoing discussion. We find present tense is a positive sig- nal for dogmatism (1.11 odds) and past tense is a negative signal (0.69 odds).</p><p>Dogmatic language can be either positively or negatively charged in sentiment: for example, con- sider the positive statement "Trump is the SAVIOR of this country!!!" or the negative statement "Are you REALLY that stupid?? Education is the only way out of this horrible mess. It's hard to imagine how anyone could be so deluded." In diverse com- munities, where people hold many different kinds of opinions, dogmatic opinions will often tend to come into conflict with one another <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(McCluskey and Hmielowski, 2012)</ref>, producing a greater likelihood of negative sentiment. Perhaps for this reason, neg- ative emotion (2.09 odds) is a useful positive signal of dogmatism, while positive emotion shows no sig- nificant relationship.</p><p>Finally, we find that interrogative language (1.12 odds) and negation (1.35 odds) are two additional positive signals of dogmatism. While interrogative words like "how" or "what" have many benign uses, they disproportionately appear in our data in the form of rhetorical or emotionally charged questions, such as "how can anyone be that dumb?" Many of these linguistic signals are correlated with each other, suggesting that dogmatism is the cumulative effect of many component relationships. For example, consider the relatively non-dogmatic statement: "I think the reviewers are wrong in this instance." Removing signals of insight, we have: "the reviewers are wrong in this instance," which is slightly more dogmatic. Then removing relativ- ity, we have: "the reviewers are wrong." And fi- nally, adding certainty, we have a dogmatic state-</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Classifier</head><p>In-domain Cross-domain   Prediction task. Our goal is (1) to understand how well we can use the strategies in Section 3 to predict dogmatism, and (2) to test the domain- independence of these strategies. First, we test the performance of our model under cross-validation within the Reddit comment dataset. We then eval- uate the Reddit-based model on a held out corpus of New York Times comments annotated using the technique in Section 2. We did not refer to this sec- ond dataset during feature construction.</p><p>For classification, we consider two classes of comments: dogmatic and non-dogmatic. As in the prior analysis, we draw these comments from the top and bottom quartiles of the dogmatism distribution. This means the classes are balanced, with 2,500 total comments in the Reddit training data and 500 total comments in the New York Times testing data.</p><p>We compare the predictions of logistic regression models based on unigram bag-of-words features (BOW), sentiment signals 2 (SENT), the linguistic features from our earlier analyses (LING), and com- binations of these features. BOW and SENT provide baselines for the task. We compute BOW features using term frequency-inverse document frequency (TF-IDF) and category-based features by normaliz- ing counts for each category by the number of words in each document. The BOW classifiers are trained with regularization (L2 penalties of 1.5).</p><p>Classification results. We present classification accuracy in <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">Table 2</ref>. BOW shows an AUC of 0.853 within Reddit and 0.776 on the held out New York Times comments. The linguistic features boost clas- sification results within Reddit (0.881) and on the held out New York Times comments (0.791). While linguistic signals by themselves provide strong pre- dictive power (0.801 AUC within domain), senti- ment signals are much less predictive.</p><p>These results suggest that linguistic features in- spired by prior efforts in psychology are useful for predicting dogmatism in practice and generalize across new domains.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Dogmatism in the Reddit Community</head><p>We now apply our dogmatism classifier to a larger dataset of posts, examining how dogmatic language shapes the Reddit community. Concretely, we ap- ply the BOW+LING model trained on the full Red- dit dataset to millions of new unannotated posts, la- beling these posts with a probability of dogmatism according to the classifier (0=non-dogmatic, 1=dog- matic). We then use these dogmatism annotations to address four research questions.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.1">What subreddits have the highest and lowest levels of dogmatism? (R1)</head><p>A natural starting point for analyzing dogmatism on Reddit is to examine how it characterizes the site's sub-communities. For example, we might expect to see that subreddits oriented around topics such as abortion or climate change are more dogmatic, and subreddits about cooking are less so.</p><p>To answer this question, we randomly sample 1.6 million posts from the entire Reddit community be- tween 2007 and 2015. We then annotate each of these posts with dogmatism using our classifier, and compute the average dogmatism level for each sub- reddit in the sample with at least 100 posts.   We present the results of this analysis in <ref type="table" target="#tab_5">Table 3</ref>. The subreddits with the highest levels of dogmatism tend to be oriented around politics and religion (De- bateAChristian or ukpolitics), while those with the lowest levels tend to focus on hobbies (photogra- phy or homebrewing). The subreddit with the high- est average dogmatism level, cringepics, is a place to make fun of socially awkward messages, often from would-be romantic partners. Dogmatism here tends to take the form of "how could someone be that stupid" and is directed at the subject of the post, as opposed to other members of the community.</p><p>Similarly, SubredditDrama is a community where people come to talk about fights on the internet or social media. These fights are often then extended in discussion, for example: "If the best you can come up with is that something you did was legal, it's probably time to own up to being an ass." The presence of this subreddit in our analysis provides a further sanity check that our model is capturing a robust signal of dogmatism.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.2">How do dogmatic beliefs cluster? (R2)</head><p>Dogmatism is widely considered to be a domain- specific attitude (for example, oriented towards re- ligion or politics) as opposed to a deeper personality trait <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">(Rokeach, 1954)</ref>. Here we use Reddit as a lens to examine this idea more closely. Are users who are dogmatic about one topic likely to be dogmatic about others? Do clusters of dogmatism exist around particular topics? To find out, we examine the re-  <ref type="table">conspiracy  science  Christianity  lgbt  Anarcho Capitalism  Bitcoin  Republican  Christianity  DebateAChristian  feminisms  Bitcoin  economy  conspiritard  relationship advice  DebateReligion  Equality  ronpaul  entertainment  ronpaul  worldpolitics  science  SubredditDrama  Conservative  TrueReddit  collapse  MensRights  videos  TwoXChromosomes  Android  socialism  guns  IAmA  news  MensRights  ukpolitics  bestof  worldpolitics  TwoXChromosomes  Libertarianism  offbeat  Equality  philosophy  occupywallstreet  WTF  atheism  fffffffuuuuuuuuuuuu   Table 4</ref>: Clusters of subreddits that share dogmatic users. For example, users who are dogmatic on the conspiracy subreddit (a place to discuss conspiracy theories) are also likely to be dogmatic on guns or occupywallstreet.</p><p>lationships between subreddits over which individ- ual users are dogmatic. For example, if many users often post dogmatic comments on both the politics and Christianity subreddits, but less often on world- news, that would suggest politics and Christianity are linked per a boost in likelihood of individuals being dogmatic in both.</p><p>We sample 1000 Reddit users who posted at least once a year between 2007 and 2015 to construct a corpus of 10 million posts that constitute their entire post history. We then annotate these posts using the classifier and compute the average dogmatism score per subreddit per user. For example, one user might have an average dogmatism level of 0.55 for the pol- itics subreddit and 0.45 for the economics subred- dit. Most users do not post in all subreddits, so we track only subreddits for which a user had posted at least 10 times. Any subreddits with an average dog- matism score higher than 0.50 we consider to be a user's dogmatic subreddits. We then count all pairs of these dogmatic subreddits. For example, 45 users have politics and technology among their dogmatic subreddits, so we consider politics and technology as linked 45 times. We compute the mutual informa- tion <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Church and Hanks, 1990</ref>) between these links, which gives us a measure of the subreddits that are most related through dogmatism.</p><p>We present the results of this analysis in <ref type="table">Table 4</ref>, choosing clusters that represent a diverse set of top- ics. For example, Libertarianism is linked through dogmatism to other political communities like An- archo Capitalism, ronpaul, or ukpolitics, as well as other topical subreddits like guns or economy. Sim- ilarly, people who are dogmatic in the business sub- reddit also tend to be dogmatic in subreddits for Bit- coin, socialism, and technology. Notably, when we apply the same mutual information analysis to links defined by subreddits posted in by the same user, we see dramatically different results. For example, the subreddits most linked to science through user posts are UpliftingNews, photoshopbattles, and firstworl- danarchist, and millionairemakers. Finally, we see less obvious connections between subreddits that suggest some people may be dog- matic by nature. For example, among the users who are dogmatic on politics, they are also disproportion- ately dogmatic on unrelated subreddits such as sci- ence (p &lt; 0.001), technology (p &lt; 0.001), IAmA (p &lt; 0.001), and AskReddit (p &lt; 0.05), with p- values computed under a binomial test.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.3">What user behaviors are predictive of dogmatism? (R3)</head><p>We have shown dogmatism is captured by many lin- guistic features, but can we discover other high-level user behaviors that are similarly predictive? To find out, we compute metrics of user behavior using the data sample of 1000 users and 10 million posts described in Section 5.2. Specifically, we cal- culate (1) activity: a user's total number of posts, (2) breadth: the number of subreddits a user has posted in, (3) focus: the proportion of a user's posts that appear in the subreddit where they are most active, and (4) engagement: the average number of posts a user contributes to each discussion they engage in.</p><p>We then fit these behavioral features to a linear re- gression model where we predict each user's average dogmatism level. Positive coefficients in this model are positively predictive of dogmatism, while nega- tive coefficients are negatively predictive.</p><p>We find this model is significantly predicitive of dogmatism (R 2 = 0.1, p &lt; 0.001), with all features reaching statistical significance (p &lt; 0.001). Activ- ity and focus are positively associated with dogma- tism, while breadth and engagement are negatively associated <ref type="table">(Table 5)</ref>. Together, these results suggest dogmatic users tend to post frequently and in spe- cific communities, but are not as inclined to continue to engage with a discussion, once it has begun.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.4">How does dogmatism impact a conversation? (R4)</head><p>How does interacting with a dogmatic comment im- pact a conversation? Are users able to shrug it off? Or do otherwise non-dogmatic users become more dogmatic themselves?</p><p>To answer this question, we sample 600,000 con- versations triples from Reddit. These conversations consist of two people (A and B) talking, with the structure: A1 → B → A2. This allows us to mea- sure the impact of B's dogmatism on A's response, while also controlling for the dogmatism level ini- tially set by A. Concretely, we model the impact of dogmatism on these conversations through a linear regression. This model takes two features, the dog- matism levels of A1 and B, and predicts the dogma- tism response of A2. If B's dogmatism has no effect on A's response, the coefficient that corresponds to B will not be significant in the model. Alternatively, if B's dogmatism does have some effect, it will be captured by the model's coefficient.</p><p>We find the coefficient of the B feature in the model is positively associated with dogmatism (p &lt; 0.001). In other words, engagement with a dog- matic comment tends to make a user more dogmatic themselves. This effect holds when we run the same model on data subsets consisting only of dogmatic or non-dogmatic users, and also when we conserva- tively remove all words used by B from A's response (i.e., controlling for quoting effects).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Related Work</head><p>In contrast to the computational models we have pre- sented, dogmatism is usually measured in psychol- ogy through survey scales, in which study partic- ipants answer questions designed to reveal under- lying personality attributes <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">(Rokeach, 1954)</ref>. Over time, these surveys have been updated <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">(Shearman and Levine, 2006</ref>) and improved to meet standards of psychometric validity <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Crowson, 2009)</ref>.</p><p>These surveys are often used to study the rela- tionship between dogmatism and other psychologi- cal phenomena. For example, dogmatic people tend to show an increased tendency for confrontation <ref type="bibr">(ElNawawy and Powers, 2010)</ref> or moral conviction and religiosity <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">(Swink, 2011)</ref>, and less likelihood of cog- nitive flexibility <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Martin et al., 2011</ref>), even among stereotypically non-dogmatic groups like atheists <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Gurney et al., 2013)</ref>. From a behavioral standpoint, dogmatic people solve problems differently, spend- ing less time framing a problem and expressing more certainty in their solution <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(Lohman, 2010)</ref>. Here we similarly examine how user behaviors on Reddit re- late to a language model of dogmatism.</p><p>Ertel sought to capture dogmatism linguistically, though a small lexicon of words that correspond with high-level concepts like certainty and compro- mise <ref type="bibr">(1985)</ref>. McKenny then used this dictionary to relate dogmatism to argument quality in student es- says <ref type="bibr">(2005)</ref>. Our work expands on this approach, applying supervised models based on a broader set of linguistic categories to identify dogmatism in text.</p><p>Other researchers have studied topics similar to dogmatism, such as signals of cognitive style in right-wing political thought <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">(Van Hiel et al., 2010</ref>), the language used by trolls on social media ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Cheng et al., 2015)</ref>, or what makes for impartial language on twitter ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">Zafar et al., 2016)</ref>. A similar flavor of work has examined linguistic models that capture politeness (Danescu-Niculescu-Mizil et al., 2013), deception <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">(Ott et al., 2011)</ref>, and authority <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(Gilbert, 2012)</ref>. We took inspiration from these models when constructing the feature sets in our work.</p><p>Finally, while we examine what makes an opin- ion dogmatic, other work has pushed further into the structure of arguments, for example classifying their justifications <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Hasan and Ng, 2014)</ref>, or what makes an argument likely to win <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">(Tan et al., 2016)</ref>. Our model may allow future researchers to probe these questions more deeply.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7">Conclusion</head><p>We have constructed the first corpus of social me- dia posts annotated with dogmatism scores, allowing us to explore linguistic features of dogmatism and build a predictive model that analyzes new content. We apply this model to Reddit, where we discover behavioral predictors of dogmatism and topical pat- terns in the comments of dogmatic users.</p><p>Could we use this computational model to help users shed their dogmatic beliefs? Looking forward, our work makes possible new avenues for encourag- ing pro-social behavior in online communities.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: We crowdsourced dogmatism labels for 5000 comments. The distribution is slightly skewed towards higher levels of dogmatism. For example, crowdworkers unanimously labeled 206 comments as highly dogmatic (5 × 3 = 15), but only 47 as minimally dogmatic (1 × 3 = 3).</figDesc><graphic url="image-1.png" coords="2,72.00,57.83,226.80,106.27" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>BOW</head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Highest</head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Feature Direction total user posts ↑ proportion of posts in most active subreddit ↑ number of subreddits posted in ↓ average number of posts in active articles ↓ Table 5: User behavioral features that are positively and nega- tively associated with dogmatism. ↑ means the feature is pos- itively predictive with dogmatism, and ↓ means the feature is negatively predictive. For example, the more subreddits a user posts in, the less likely they are to be dogmatic. All features are statistically significant (p &lt; 0.001).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" validated="false"><head>Table 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Linguistic features that capture high level psychological categories and their relationship with dogmatic comments.</figDesc><table></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3" validated="false"><head>Table 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>The AUC scores for dogmatism classifiers within and 

across domains. BOW (bag-of-words) and SENT (sentiment 

signals) are baselines, and LING uses the linguistic features 

from Table 1. We compute in-domain accuracy using 15-fold 

cross-validation on the Reddit dataset, and cross-domain accu-

racy by training on Reddit and evaluating on comments on arti-

cles from the New York Times. Chance AUC is 0.5. 

ment: "the reviewers are always wrong." 

4 Predicting dogmatism 

We now show how we can use the linguistic feature 
sets we have described to build a classifier that pre-
dicts dogmatism in comments. A predictive model 
further validates our feature sets, and also allows us 
to analyze dogmatism in millions of other Reddit 
comments in a scalable way, with multiple uses in 
ongoing, downstream analyses. 
</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_5" validated="false"><head>Table 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Subreddits with the highest and lowest dogmatism 

scores. Politics and religion are common themes among the 

most dogmatic subreddits, while hobbies (e.g., photography, 

homebrewing, buildapc) show the least dogmatism. 

</table></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> http://www.reddit.com</note>

			<note place="foot" n="2"> For SENT, we use normalized word counts from LIWC&apos;s positive and negative emotional categories.</note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Justin</forename><surname>Cheng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Cristian</forename><surname>Danescu-Niculescu-Mizil</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jure</forename><surname>Leskovec</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:1504.00680</idno>
		<title level="m">Antisocial behavior in online discussion communities</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
<note type="report_type">arXiv preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Word association norms, mutual information, and lexicography</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kenneth</forename><forename type="middle">Ward</forename><surname>Church</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Patrick</forename><surname>Hanks</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Computational linguistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">16</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="22" to="29" />
			<date type="published" when="1990" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Does the dog scale measure dogmatism? another look at construct validity</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Michael Crowson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The Journal of social psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">149</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="365" to="383" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">A computational approach to politeness with application to social factors</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Cristian</forename><surname>Danescu-Niculescu-Mizil</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Moritz</forename><surname>Sudhof</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dan</forename><surname>Jurafsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jure</forename><surname>Leskovec</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christopher</forename><surname>Potts</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:1306.6078</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
<note type="report_type">arXiv preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Toward a learning science for complex crowdsourcing tasks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Shayan</forename><surname>Doroudi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ece</forename><surname>Kamar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Emma</forename><surname>Brunskill</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Eric</forename><surname>Horvitz</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2016 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems</title>
		<meeting>the 2016 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2623" to="2634" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Aljazeera english a conciliatory medium in a conflictdriven environment?</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mohammed</forename><surname>El</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">-Nawawy</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Shawn</forename><surname>Powers</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Global Media and Communication</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="61" to="84" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Content analysis: An alternative approach to open and closed minds</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Ertel</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The High School Journal</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">68</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="229" to="240" />
			<date type="published" when="1985" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Phrases that signal workplace hierarchy</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Eric</forename><surname>Gilbert</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the ACM 2012 conference on Computer Supported Cooperative Work</title>
		<meeting>the ACM 2012 conference on Computer Supported Cooperative Work</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1037" to="1046" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Believe it or not: Exploring the relationship between dogmatism and openness within non-religious samples. Personality and Individual Differences</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Daniel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Shelley</forename><surname>Gurney</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jamie</forename><surname>Mckeown</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Neil</forename><surname>Churchyard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Howlett</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">55</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="936" to="940" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Why are you taking this stance? identifying and classifying reasons in ideological debates</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Saidul</forename><surname>Kazi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Vincent</forename><surname>Hasan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Ng</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">EMNLP</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="751" to="762" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Answering the call for a standard reliability measure for coding data</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Andrew</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Klaus</forename><surname>Hayes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Krippendorff</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Communication methods and measures</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="77" to="89" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">An unexamined triumvirate: dogmatism, problem solving, and hrd. Human Resource Development Review</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Margaret C Lohman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The relationships between cognitive flexibility with dogmatism, intellectual flexibility, preference for consistency, and self-compassion</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sydney</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Matthew M Martin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Carolyn M</forename><surname>Staggers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Anderson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Communication Research Reports</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">28</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="275" to="280" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Opinion expression during social conflict: Comparing online reader comments and letters to the editor</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Mccluskey</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jay</forename><surname>Hmielowski</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journalism</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="303" to="319" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Content analysis of dogmatism compared with corpus analysis of epistemic stance in student essays</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">John</forename><surname>Mckenny</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Information Design Journal &amp; Document Design</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">13</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Finding deceptive opinion spam by any stretch of the imagination</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Myle</forename><surname>Ott</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yejin</forename><surname>Choi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Claire</forename><surname>Cardie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jeffrey T</forename><surname>Hancock</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 49th</title>
		<meeting>the 49th</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<monogr>
				<title level="m">Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics: Human Language Technologies</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="309" to="319" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Association for Computational Linguistics</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Definition of dogmatism</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>English Oxford Dictionary</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Cognitive, emotional, and language processes in disclosure</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>James</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Martha</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Pennebaker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Francis</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognition &amp; Emotion</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="601" to="626" />
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Linguistic inquiry and word count: Liwc</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Martha</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>James W Pennebaker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Roger J</forename><surname>Francis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Booth</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Mahway</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">71</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
			<publisher>Lawrence Erlbaum Associates</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The secret life of pronouns</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>James W Pennebaker</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">New Scientist</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">211</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="42" to="45" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The nature and meaning of dogmatism</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Milton</forename><surname>Rokeach</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1954" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dogmatism updated: A scale revision and validation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Sachiyo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Timothy</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Shearman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Levine</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Communication Quarterly</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">54</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="275" to="291" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Get another label? improving data quality and data mining using multiple, noisy labelers</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Victor</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Foster</forename><surname>Sheng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Panagiotis G</forename><surname>Provost</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Ipeirotis</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 14th ACM SIGKDD international conference on Knowledge discovery and data mining</title>
		<meeting>the 14th ACM SIGKDD international conference on Knowledge discovery and data mining</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="614" to="622" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Dogmatism and moral conviction in individuals: Injustice for all</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nathan</forename><surname>Swink</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Winning arguments: Interaction dynamics and persuasion strategies in good-faith online discussions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chenhao</forename><surname>Tan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Vlad</forename><surname>Niculae</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Cristian</forename><surname>Danescuniculescu-Mizil</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lillian</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of WWW</title>
		<meeting>WWW</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The relationship between social-cultural attitudes and behavioral measures of cognitive style: A meta-analytic integration of studies</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alain</forename><surname>Van Hiel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Emma</forename><surname>Onraet</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sarah</forename><forename type="middle">De</forename><surname>Pauw</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of personality</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">78</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1765" to="1800" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Linguistic analyses of natural written language: Unobtrusive assessment of cognitive style in eating disorders</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Markus</forename><surname>Wolf</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jan</forename><surname>Sedway</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Cynthia</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Bulik</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hans</forename><surname>Kordy</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">International Journal of Eating Disorders</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">40</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="711" to="717" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Comparison of deceptive and truthful travel reviews. Information and communication technologies in tourism</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kyung-Hyan</forename><surname>Yoo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ulrike</forename><surname>Gretzel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="37" to="47" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Message impartiality in social media discussions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Muhammad</forename><surname>Bilal Zafar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Krishna</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Gummadi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Cristian</forename><surname>Danescu-Niculescu-Mizil</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Tenth International AAAI Conference on Web and Social Media</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
