<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T12:22+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Tense Manages to Predict Implicative Behavior in Verbs</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date>November 1-5, 2016</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ellie</forename><surname>Pavlick</surname></persName>
							<email>epavlick@seas.upenn.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">University of Pennsylvania</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">University of Pennsylvania</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chris</forename><surname>Callison-Burch</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">University of Pennsylvania</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">University of Pennsylvania</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Tense Manages to Predict Implicative Behavior in Verbs</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2016 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</title>
						<meeting>the 2016 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing <address><addrLine>Austin, Texas</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="2225" to="2229"/>
							<date type="published">November 1-5, 2016</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Implicative verbs (e.g. manage) entail their complement clauses, while non-implicative verbs (e.g. want) do not. For example, while managing to solve the problem entails solving the problem, no such inference follows from wanting to solve the problem. Differentiating between implicative and non-implicative verbs is therefore an essential component of natural language understanding, relevant to applications such as textual entailment and summarization. We present a simple method for predicting implicativeness which exploits known constraints on the tense of implicative verbs and their complements. We show that this yields an effective, data-driven way of capturing this nuanced property in verbs.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Overview</head><p>Understanding language requires the ability to per- form basic inference-to make conclusions about what is likely true or false based on what is said. For example, given the sentence She fixed the bug, we should almost certainly infer that the bug is fixed. However, rather than stating plainly that She fixed the bug, one might instead say: (1a) She managed to fix the bug before midnight.</p><p>(1b) She happened to fix the bug while refactoring.</p><p>In either case, the hearer should still infer that the bug is fixed. But it is not as easy as always inferring that embedded clauses are true. By changing only one word, these sentence no longer give a clear indi- cation as to whether or not the bug has been fixed: Implicative verbs, like those in (1), give rise to en- tailments, while non-implicative verbs, like those in (2), do not. It is therefore vital to natural language understanding to differentiate between clauses that are embedded under implicatives, which we can of- ten infer to be either true or false, and those which are embedded under non-implicatives, for which such inferences cannot be made. In this paper, we exploit a known linguistic property of implicative verbs-that their complement clause is constrained to be in the same tense as the main clause-in or- der to predict the tendency of verbs to behave im- plicatively. We show that our method almost per- fectly separates non-implicatives from implicatives in a small hand-labeled dataset, and that it provides strong signal for predicting entailments in sentences involving implicative verbs.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Implicative Verbs</head><p>Some English verbs can take infinitival comple- ments, meaning they can appear in constructions of the form VB * 1 to VB 2 , where VB * 1 is the "main" verb (which can be conjugated 1 ) and VB 2 is the "com- plement" verb (which is in infinitive form). Exam- ples (1a)-(2b) illustrate verbs taking infinitive com- plements.</p><p>Implicative verbs are a special subclass 2 of such verbs which give rise to entailments involving their <ref type="bibr">1</ref> Here, * indicates that VB1 can match any verb form, e.g. VB, VBD, VBP, etc. VB2 can only match the base form VB. <ref type="bibr">2</ref> We note that factive verbs represent another special class of verbs which can take infinitival complements. Unlike implica-Is the main verb Is the complement Example negated? entailed? Implicative − Yes I managed to solve the problem. ⇒ I solved the problem. Implicative + No I did not manage to solve the problem. ⇒ I did not solve the problem. Implicative − No I failed to solve the problem. ⇒ I did not solve the problem. Implicative + Yes I did not fail to solve the problem. ⇒ I solved the problem. Non-Impl.</p><p>− Unknown I wanted to solve the problem. ⇒ I solved the problem. Non-Impl.</p><p>+ Unknown I did not want to solve the problem. ⇒ I did not solve the problem. <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>: Implicative verbs give rise to entailments involving their complement clauses. Non-implicatives entail neither the truth nor the falsity of their complements, and thus the truth/falsity of the complement is unaffected by negation of the main clause.</p><p>complement clauses. Individual implicatives can differ in the entailments they generate: e.g. while manage entails the truth of its complement, fail en- tails the falsity of its complement (failed to solve the problem ⇒ didn't solve the problem). Despite these differences, however, implicatives represent a coher- ent class of verbs in that they permit some inference to be made about their complements, and this infer- ence is sensitive to the context (positive/negated) of the main clause. This contrasts with non-implicative verbs, like want, which do not permit any inference regarding their complements, and for which the truth of the complement is unaffected by negation in the main clause <ref type="table">(Table 1)</ref>. The method described in this paper aims to sep- arate implicatives from non-implicatives (manage vs. want), rather than to differentiate between types implicatives (manage vs. fail). Making this implicative/non-implicative distinction is a neces- sary first step toward handling inferences involving embedded clauses, and one that, to date, has only been performed using manually-constructed word lists <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(MacCartney, 2009;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Recasens et al., 2013</ref>).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">Tense Constraints on Complement Clauses</head><p>Karttunen <ref type="bibr">(1971)</ref> observed that, in sentences in- volving implicatives, the tense of the main verb must necessarily match the tense of the complement clause. For example, (3), in which the main clause and the complement are both in the past tense, is ac- ceptable but (4), in which the complement is in the future, is clearly not. For non-implicatives, however, tives, factives presuppose, rather than entail, their complements. E.g. both I was/was not glad to solve the problem entail I solved the problem. We do not address factives here, as factives rarely take infinitival complements: more often, they take "that" com- plements (e.g. know that, realize that). Factives that do take infinitival complements are mostly phrasal (e.g. be glad to). no such constraint exists: (6) is perfectly felicitous.</p><p>(3) I managed to solve the problem last night.</p><p>(4) #I managed to solve the problem tomorrow.</p><p>(5) I planned to solve the problem last night.</p><p>(6) I planned to solve the problem tomorrow.</p><p>We exploit this property to predict implicativeness- whether the truth of a verb's complement can be inferred-by observing the verb's usage in practice.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Method</head><p>We hypothesize that, given a large corpus, we should be able to distinguish implicative verbs from non- implicative verbs by observing how often the main verb tense agrees/disagrees with the tense of the complement clause. Unfortunately, verbs in infini- tival complement clauses are not conjugated, and so are not necessarily marked for tense. We therefore use the Stanford Temporal Tagger (TT) <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Chang and Manning, 2012</ref>) in order to identify time-referring expressions (e.g. tomorrow or last night) and resolve them to either past, present, or future tense.</p><p>We find all sentences containing VB * 1 to VB 2 constructions in the Annotated Gigaword corpus ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Napoles et al., 2012</ref>). We run the the TT over all of the sentences in order to identify time-referring expressions. We only consider sentences in which a time-referring expression appears and is in a di- rect dependency relationship with the complement verb (VB 2 ). We provide the TT with the document publication dates, 3 which are used to resolve each time mention to a specific calendar date and time. We then map these time expressions coarsely to ei- ther past, present, or future tense by comparing the resolved time to the document creation time. Be- cause of the fact that days were often not resolved correctly, or at all, we eventually throw away sen- tences in which the complement clause is labeled as present tense, as these are rarely true references to the present, and rather the result of incorrect time resolution, or implicit future references (e.g. I am going to solve the problem today implies the future as in later today, but this is not captured by the TT). We also assign the main clause to past, present, or future tense by using the fine-grained POS tag and a set of heuristics (for example, to check for modals). <ref type="bibr">4</ref> We assign a tense agreement score to each verb v as follows. Let S be the set of all VB * 1 to VB 2 constructions in which VB * 1 = v. Then tense agreement is simply 1 |S| × |{s ∈ S | complement tense = main tense}|, i.e. the fraction of constructions in S in which the tenses of the main and complement clauses agree. We expect implica- tive verbs to occur mostly in agreeing constructions, and thus have high tense agreement, while non- implicatives may occur in both agreeing and non- agreeing constructions, and thus should have lower tense agreement. Note that while in theory, implica- tives should never appear in non-agreeing construc- tions, the time annotation process is very imprecise, and thus we do not expect perfect results.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Evaluation</head><p>Recreating list from <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Karttunen (1971)</ref>. <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Karttunen (1971)</ref> provides a short illustrative list of 7 known implicatives 5 and 8 non-implicatives (shown in <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Table 2</ref>). As a first evaluation, we test whether tense agreement can accurately separate the verbs in this list, such that the implicatives are assigned higher agreement scores than the non-implicatives. <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Table 2</ref> shows that this is indeed the case. Tense agreement almost perfectly divides the list, with implicative verbs appearing above non-implicative verbs in all cases. The one exception is decide (reportedly non-implicative), which appears above dare (reportedly implicative). This error, however, seems understandable: while decide is not strictly implicative in the way manage is, it is often used as an implicative. E.g. the sentence I decided to leave would likely be taken to mean I left.  and non-implicatives listed in <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Karttunen (1971)</ref>. Ranking by tense agreement almost perfectly divides the two classes.</p><p>Predicting Entailment. Our interest is not in dis- tinguishing implicatives from non-implicatives for its own sake, but rather to predict, based on the main verb, whether the truth of the complement can be in- ferred. We therefore conduct a second evaluation to assess how well tense agreement predicts this entail- ment property. We design our evaluation following the recognizing textual entailment (RTE) task <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Dagan et al., 2006</ref>), in which two sentences are given, a premise p and a hypothesis h, and the goal is to determine whether p reasonably entails h. To con- struct our p/h pairs, we take all the verbs extracted in Section 3 which appear in at least 50 tense-labeled sentences. For each of these verbs, we choose 3 ran- dom sentences in which the verb appears as VB * 1 in a VB * 1 to VB 2 construction. <ref type="bibr">6</ref> From each sentence, we extract the complement clause by deleting VB * 1 to from the sentence, and conjugating VB 2 to match the tense of VB * 1 . We then use the original sentence as p and the extracted complement as h: e.g. a p/h pair might look like I get to interact with fellow profes- sors/I interact with fellow professors. We ask 5 in- dependent annotators on Amazon Mechanical Turk to read each p and then determine whether h is true, false, or unclear given p. <ref type="bibr">7</ref> We take the majority an- swer as the true label. We expect that implicative verbs should lead to judgements which are decid- edly true or false while non-implicatives should lead <ref type="bibr">(0.14</ref></p><note type="other">) UFJ wants to merge with Mitsubishi, a combination that'd surpass Citigroup as the world's biggest bank.</note><p>⇒ The merger of Japanese Banks creates the world's biggest bank. (0.55) After graduating, Gallager chose to accept a full scholarship to play football for Temple University.</p><p>⇒ Gallager attended Temple University. (0.68) Wilkins was allowed to leave in 1987 to join French outfit Paris Saint-Germain.</p><p>⇒ Wilkins departed Milan in 1987. <ref type="table">Table 3</ref>: Examples from the RTE3 dataset ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Giampiccolo et al., 2007</ref>) which require recognizing implicative behavior, even in verbs that are not implicative by definition. The tendency of certain verbs (e.g. be allowed) to behave as de facto implicatives is captured surprisingly well by the tense agreement score (shown in parentheses).</p><p>to mostly judgements of unclear. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 1</ref> shows that these expectations hold. When a verb with low tense agreement appeared as the main verb of a sentence, the truth of the comple- ment could only be inferred 30% of the time. When a verb with high tense agreement appeared as the main verb, the truth of the complement could be in- ferred 91% of the time. This difference is significant at p &lt; 0.01. That is, tense agreement provides a strong signal for identifying non-implicative verbs, and thus can help systems avoid false-positive en- tailment judgements, e.g. incorrectly inferring that wanting to merge ⇒ merging <ref type="table">(Table 3</ref>). Interestingly, tense agreement accurately mod- els verbs that are not implicative by definition, but which nonetheless tend to behave implicatively in practice. For example, our method finds high tense agreement for choose to and be allowed to, which are often used to communicate, albeit indirectly, that their complements did in fact happen. To convince ourselves that treating such verbs as implicatives makes sense in practice, we manually look through the RTE3 dataset ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Giampiccolo et al., 2007</ref>) for ex- amples containing high-scoring verbs according to our method. <ref type="table">Table 3</ref> shows some example inferences that hinge precisely on recognizing these types of de facto implicatives.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Discussion and Related Work</head><p>Language understanding tasks such as RTE <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Clark et al., 2007;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b7">MacCartney, 2009)</ref> and bias detection ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Recasens et al., 2013</ref>) have been shown to require knowledge of implicative verbs, but such knowledge has previously come from manually-built word lists rather than from data. <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Nairn et al. (2006) and</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Martin et al. (2009)</ref> describe automatic systems to han- dle implicatives, but require hand-crafted rules for each unique verb that is handled. The tense agree- ment method we present offers a starting point for acquiring such rules from data, and is well-suited for incorporating into statistical systems. The clear next step is to explore similar data-driven means for learning the specific behaviors of individual implica- tive verbs, which has been well-studied from a the- oretical perspective <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Karttunen, 1971;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Nairn et al., 2006;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Amaral et al., 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Karttunen, 2012</ref>). An- other interesting extension concerns the role of tense in word representations. While currently, tense is rarely built directly into distributional representa- tions of words ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Mikolov et al., 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Pennington et al., 2014)</ref>, our results suggest it may offer important insights into the semantics of individual words. We leave this question as a direction for future work.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Conclusion</head><p>Differentiating between implicative and non- implicative verbs is important for discriminating inferences that can and cannot be made in natural language. We have presented a data-driven method that captures the implicative tendencies of verbs by exploiting the tense relationship between the verb and its complement clauses. This method effectively separates known implicatives from known non-implicatives, and, more importantly, provides good predictive signal in an entailment recognition task.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>(</head><label></label><figDesc>2a) She wanted to fix the bug before midnight. (2b) She planned to fix the bug while refactoring.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: Whether or not complement is entailed for main verbs with varying levels of tense agreement. Verbs with high tense agreement yield more definitive judgments (true/false). Each bar represents aggregated judgements over approx. 20 verbs.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" validated="false"><head>Table 2 : Tense agreement scores for known implicatives (bold)</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table></table></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="3"> Provided as metadata in the Annotated Gigaword.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="4"> Full set of heuristics in supplementary material. 5 The original list had 8 implicatives, but we omit remember since, in our data, it occurred almost exclusively with recurring time expressions, which we were not able to map to a specific date/time and thus tense, e.g. consumers must remember to make payments every 14 days.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="6"> These sentences can come from anywhere in the Gigaword corpus, they are not required to contain time expressions. 7 Full annotation guidelines in supplementary material.</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>We would like to thank Florian Schwartz for valu-able discussions. This research was supported by a Facebook Fellowship, and by gifts from the Al-fred P. Sloan Foundation, Google, and Facebook. This material is based in part on research sponsored by the NSF grant under IIS-1249516 and DARPA under number FA8750-13-2-0017 (the DEFT pro-gram). The U.S. Government is authorized to repro-duce and distribute reprints for Governmental pur-poses. The views and conclusions contained in this publication are those of the authors and should not be interpreted as representing official policies or en-dorsements of DARPA and the U.S. Government.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Where&apos;s the meeting that was cancelled? existential implications of transitive verbs</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Patricia</forename><surname>Amaral</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Cleo</forename><surname>Valeria De Paiva</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Annie</forename><surname>Condoravdi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Zaenen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 3rd Workshop on Cognitive Aspects of the Lexicon</title>
		<meeting>the 3rd Workshop on Cognitive Aspects of the Lexicon<address><addrLine>Mumbai, India, December</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="183" to="194" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>The COLING 2012 Organizing Committee</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Sutime: A library for recognizing and normalizing time expressions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Angel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christopher D</forename><surname>Chang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Manning</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">LREC</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3735" to="3740" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">On the role of lexical and world knowledge in rte3</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Peter</forename><surname>Clark</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Phil</forename><surname>Harrison</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">John</forename><surname>Thompson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">William</forename><surname>Murray</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jerry</forename><surname>Hobbs</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christiane</forename><surname>Fellbaum</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the ACL-PASCAL Workshop on Textual Entailment and Paraphrasing</title>
		<meeting>the ACL-PASCAL Workshop on Textual Entailment and Paraphrasing<address><addrLine>Prague</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2007-06" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="54" to="59" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The PASCAL recognizing textual entailment challenge</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Oren</forename><surname>Ido Dagan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bernardo</forename><surname>Glickman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Magnini</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Machine Learning Challenges. Evaluating Predictive Uncertainty, Visual Object Classification, and Recognising Tectual Entailment</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="177" to="190" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The third PASCAL recognising textual entailment challenge</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Danilo</forename><surname>Giampiccolo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bernardo</forename><surname>Magnini</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ido</forename><surname>Dagan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bill</forename><surname>Dolan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the ACLPASCAL workshop on textual entailment and paraphrasing</title>
		<meeting>the ACLPASCAL workshop on textual entailment and paraphrasing</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="9" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lauri</forename><surname>Karttunen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Implicative verbs. Language</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1971" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="340" to="358" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Simple and phrasal implicatives</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lauri</forename><surname>Karttunen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">*SEM 2012: The First Joint Conference on Lexical and Computational Semantics</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Montréal, Canada</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="7" to="8" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>June. Association for Computational Linguistics</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Natural language inference</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bill</forename><surname>Maccartney</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Ph.D. thesis, Citeseer</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Disambiguation of polysemous verbs for rule-based inferencing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Fabienne</forename><surname>Martin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dennis</forename><surname>Spohr</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Achim</forename><surname>Stein</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Eight International Conference on Computational Semantics</title>
		<meeting>the Eight International Conference on Computational Semantics<address><addrLine>Tilburg, The Netherlands</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2009-01" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="222" to="234" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Efficient estimation of word representations in vector space</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tomas</forename><surname>Mikolov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kai</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Greg</forename><surname>Corrado</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jeffrey</forename><surname>Dean</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:1301.3781</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
<note type="report_type">arXiv preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Computing relative polarity for textual inference</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rowan</forename><surname>Nairn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Cleo</forename><surname>Condoravdi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lauri</forename><surname>Karttunen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Inference in Computational Semantics (ICoS-5)</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="20" to="21" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Annotated gigaword</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Courtney</forename><surname>Napoles</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Matthew</forename><surname>Gormley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Benjamin</forename><surname>Van Durme</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Joint Workshop on Automatic Knowledge Base Construction and Web-scale Knowledge Extraction (AKBC-WEKEX)</title>
		<meeting>the Joint Workshop on Automatic Knowledge Base Construction and Web-scale Knowledge Extraction (AKBC-WEKEX)<address><addrLine>Montréal, Canada</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012-06" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="95" to="100" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Association for Computational Linguistics</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Glove: Global vectors for word representation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jeffrey</forename><surname>Pennington</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Richard</forename><surname>Socher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christopher</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Manning</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP)</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1532" to="1543" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Linguistic models for analyzing and detecting biased language</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marta</forename><surname>Recasens</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Cristian</forename><surname>Danescu-Niculescu-Mizil</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dan</forename><surname>Jurafsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 51st Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the 51st Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics<address><addrLine>Sofia, Bulgaria</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2013-08" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1650" to="1659" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
