<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T10:36+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Capturing Argument Relationships for Chinese Semantic Role Labeling</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date>November 1-5, 2016</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lei</forename><surname>Sha</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Ministry of Education School of Electronics Engineering and Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">Key Laboratory of Computational Linguistics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Peking University Collaborative Innovation Center for Language Ability</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>221009</postCode>
									<settlement>Xuzhou</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tingsong</forename><surname>Jiang</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Ministry of Education School of Electronics Engineering and Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">Key Laboratory of Computational Linguistics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Peking University Collaborative Innovation Center for Language Ability</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>221009</postCode>
									<settlement>Xuzhou</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sujian</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Ministry of Education School of Electronics Engineering and Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">Key Laboratory of Computational Linguistics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Peking University Collaborative Innovation Center for Language Ability</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>221009</postCode>
									<settlement>Xuzhou</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Baobao</forename><surname>Chang</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Ministry of Education School of Electronics Engineering and Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">Key Laboratory of Computational Linguistics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Peking University Collaborative Innovation Center for Language Ability</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>221009</postCode>
									<settlement>Xuzhou</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Zhifang</forename><surname>Sui</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Ministry of Education School of Electronics Engineering and Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">Key Laboratory of Computational Linguistics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Peking University Collaborative Innovation Center for Language Ability</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>221009</postCode>
									<settlement>Xuzhou</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Capturing Argument Relationships for Chinese Semantic Role Labeling</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2016 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</title>
						<meeting>the 2016 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing <address><addrLine>Austin, Texas</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="2011" to="2016"/>
							<date type="published">November 1-5, 2016</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>In this paper, we capture the argument relationships for Chinese semantic role labeling task, and improve the task&apos;s performance with the help of argument relationships. We split the relationship between two candidate arguments into two categories: (1) Compatible arguments: if one candidate argument belongs to a given predicate, then the other is more likely to belong to the same predicate; (2) Incompatible arguments: if one candidate argument belongs to a given predicate, then the other is less likely to belong to the same predicate. However, previous works did not explicitly model argument relationships. We use a simple maximum entropy classifier to capture the two categories of argument relationships and test its performance on the Chinese Proposition Bank (CPB). The experiments show that argument relationships is effective in Chinese semantic role labeling task.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Semantic Role Labeling (SRL) is defined as the task to recognize arguments for a given predicate and as- sign semantic role labels to them. Because of it- s ability to encode semantic information, there has been an increasing interest in SRL on many lan- guages ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Gildea and Jurafsky, 2002;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Sun and Jurafsky, 2004</ref>). <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 1</ref> shows an example in Chinese Proposition Bank (CPB) <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(Xue and Palmer, 2003)</ref>, which is a Chinese corpus annotated with semantic role labels.</p><p>Previous works of Chinese SRL include feature- based approaches and neural network based ap- proaches. Feature-based approaches often extract a large number of handcrafted features from the sen- tence, and feed these features to statistical classifiers such as CRF, MaxEnt and SVM ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Sun and Jurafsky, 2004;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Xue, 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Ding and Chang, 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Ding and Chang, 2009;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Sun, 2010)</ref>. Neural network based approaches usually take Chinese SRL as sequence labeling task and use bidirectional recurrent neural network (RNN) with long-short-term memory (LST- M) to solve the problem ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Wang et al., 2015</ref>).</p><p>However, both of the above two kinds of ap- proaches identify each candidate argument separate- ly without considering the relationship between ar- guments. We define two categories of argument re- lationships here: (1) Compatible arguments: if one candidate argument belongs to a given predicate, then the other is more likely to belong to the same predicate; (2) Incompatible arguments: if one can- didate argument belongs to a given predicate, then the other is less likely to belong to the same pred- icate. For example, in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 1</ref>, the word " û"(foreign businessman) and "è'"(entrepreneur) tend to be compatible arguments when the predi- cate word is "Ý]"(invest). On the other hand, "è '"(entrepreneur) and " 5½"(rule) are not likely to belong to the same predicate "Ý]"(invest).</p><p>In this paper, we propose to use a quadratic opti- mization method to explicitly model the relationship between candidate arguments to improve the perfor- mance of Chinese SRL. We train a maximum en- tropy classifier, and then use the classifier to predict argument relationships between any two candidate arguments in a sentence. Experiments show that ar- gument relationships can greatly improve the perfor- mance of Chinese SRL.  <ref type="table">投资  企业  合法  权益  六  项  规定  protect foreign businessman invest  entrepreneur legal  profit  six  item  rule   POS:  VV  NN  VV  NN  JJ  NN  CD  M  NN</ref> SRL: </p><formula xml:id="formula_0">O S-ARG0 rel S-arg1 O O O O O Word:</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Related Work</head><p>Semantic Role Labeling (SRL) task was first pro- posed by <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Gildea and Jurafsky (2002)</ref>. Previous ap- proaches on Chinese SRL can be classified into two categories: (1) feature-based approaches (2) neural network based approaches. Among feature-based approaches, Sun and Juraf- sky (2004) did the preliminary work on Chinese SR- L without any large semantically annotated corpus and produced promising results. <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Xue and Palmer (2003)</ref> proposed Chinese Proposition Bank (CPB), which leads to more complete and systematic re- search on Chinese SRL ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Xue and Palmer, 2005;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Xue, 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Ding and Chang, 2009)</ref>. <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Sun et al. (2009)</ref> extended the work of <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Chen et al. (2006)</ref>, per- formed Chinese SRL with shallow parsing, which took partial parses as inputs. <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Yang and Zong (2014)</ref> proposed multi-predicate SRL, which showed im- provements both on English and Chinese Proposi- tion Bank.</p><p>Neural network based approaches are free of handcrafted features, <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Collobert and Weston (2008)</ref> proposed a convolutional neural network for SRL. Their approach achieved competitive performance on English SRL without requiring task specific fea- ture. <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Wang et al. (2015)</ref> proposed a bidirectional LSTM-RNN for Chinese SRL.</p><p>However, most of the aforementioned approaches did not take the compatible arguments and incom- patible arguments into account. Inspired by <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Sha et al. (2016)</ref>, our approach model the two argumen- t relationships explicitly to achieve a better perfor- mance on Chinese SRL.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Capturing the Relationship Between Arguments</head><p>We found that there are two typical relationships be- tween candidate arguments: (1) Compatible argu- ments: if one candidate argument belongs to one event, then the other is more likely to belong to the same event; (2) incompatible arguments: if one can- didate argument belongs to one event, then the other is less likely to belong to the same event.</p><p>We trained a maximum entropy classifier to pre- dict the relationship between two candidate argu- ments. We choose the following features:  The chinese sentences should be segmented to chinese words first. For a sentence with n + 1 word- s, we denote C ∈ R n×n as the argument relation- ship matrix. In the testing procedure, the maximum entropy classifier is used to predict the relationship between argument i and argument j as C ij .</p><p>When the output of the maximum entropy clas- sifier is around 0.5, it is not easy to figure out whether it is the first relationship or the second, we call this kind of information "uncertain infor- mation"(unclear relationship). For a better perfor- mance, we strengthen the certain information and weaken the uncertain information. We transform the result of maximum entropy classifier as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">C(i, j) =    1 0.8 &lt; M axEnt(i, j) ≤ 1.0 0 0.2 ≤ M axEnt(i, j) ≤ 0.8 −1 0.0 ≤ M axEnt(i, j) &lt; 0.2<label>(1)</label></formula><p>We set two thresholds, if the output of the maximum entropy classifier is larger than 0.8, we set C i,j = 1 (compatible arguments), if the output is lower than 0.2, we set C i,j = −1 (incompatible arguments), otherwise, we set C i,j = 0 (unclear relationship). The threshold 0.8 and 0.2 are tuned by development set.   Each dimension of the output vector L i ∈ R n L , i = 1 · · · n corresponds to the score of a cer- tain semantic role label. n L represents the number of semantic role labels. Then we normalize L i over semantic roles as Eq 2 shows.</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">L i = N ormalize(L i )<label>(2)</label></formula><p>Each dimension of L i represents the probability of a certain semantic role label.</p><p>Let P Arg ∈ R n be a probability vector, each di- mension of which represents the probability that the current word has a semantic role as is shown in Eq 3. P Role ∈ R n is another probability vector, each di- mension represents the probability of the most likely semantic role the current word may be labeled as is shown in Eq 4.</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">P Arg (i) = j L i (j)[label(j) = '0']<label>(3)</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_4">P Role (i) = max j L i (j)<label>(4)</label></formula><p>where [·] equals to 1 if the inner statement is true and 0 otherwise. label(j) = '0' means the j-th word is not labeled with semantic role.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">Quadratic Optimization</head><p>We use a n-dim vector X to represent the identifica- tion result of candidate arguments. Each entry of X is 0 or 1, 0 represents "noArg", 1 represents "arg". X can be assigned by maximizing E(X) as defined by Eq 5.</p><formula xml:id="formula_5">X = argmax X E(X) E(X) = λ 1 X T CX + λ 2 X T P arg + (1 − λ 1 − λ 2 )X T P role<label>(5)</label></formula><p>Here, X T CX means to add up all the relationship value if the two arguments are identified. Hence, the more the identified arguments are related, the larger the value X T CX is. X T P arg is the sum of all cho- sen arguments probability. X T P role is the sum of all the classified roles' probability. Eq 5 means that, while we should select the se- mantic role with a larger probability, the argument relationship evaluation should also as large as possi- ble.</p><p>We use Beam Search method (Algorithm 1) to search for the optimal assignment X. The hyper- parameters λ 1 and λ 2 can be chosen according to development set. </p><formula xml:id="formula_6">for i ← 1 · · · n do buf← {z • l|z ∈ B, l ∈ {0, 1}}; B ← [] ; while j ← 1 · · · K do x best = argmax x∈buf E(x); B ← B ∪ {x best }; buf←buf−{x best }; end end Sort B descendingly according to E(X); return B[0];</formula><p>Algorithm 1: Beam Search decoding algorithm for SRL.</p><p>• means to concatenate an element to the end of a vector.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Experiment</head><p>We conduct experiments to compare our model with previous landmark methods on the benchmark dataset CPB for Chinese SRL. We use <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Wang et al. (2015)</ref>'s model as baseline. The result reveals that our quadratic optimization method can further im- prove the result of bidirectional LSTM-RNN.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.1">Experiment Settings</head><p>We conduct experiments on the standard benchmark dataset CPB 1.0 2 . We follow the same data set- ting as previous work <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(Xue, 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Sun et al., 2009)</ref>, which divided the dataset into three parts: 648 files (from chtb 081.fid to chtb 899.fid) are used as the training set. The developmen- t set includes 40 files, from chtb 041.fid to chtb 080.fid. The test set includes 72 files, <ref type="formula" target="#formula_2">(2008)</ref> 71.90 <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Collobert and</ref><ref type="bibr">Weston (2008) 74.05 Sun et al. (2009)</ref> 74.12 <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Yang and Zong (2014)</ref> 75.31 <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Wang et al. (2015)</ref> 77.21 QOM -stengthen 76.24 QOM -feature 4,5,6</p><formula xml:id="formula_7">Method F 1 (%) Xue</formula><p>77.52 QOM 77.69 which are chtb 001.fid to chtb 040.fid, and chtb 900.fid to chtb 931.fid.</p><p>The training dataset of the argument relation- ship matrix contains 1.6M cases (736K positive and 864K negative) which are randomly generated ac- cording to the ground truth in the training docu- ments. We use Stanford Parser 3 for dependency parsing.</p><p>We tuned the coefficients λ 1 and λ 2 of Eq 5 on the development set, and finally we set λ 1 = 0.10 and λ 2 = 0.45. <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Table 1</ref> shows our SRL performance compared to previous landmark results. We can see that with quadratic optimization method as the post- processing module, our approach (QOM) outper- forms <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Wang et al. (2015)</ref> by a large margin (Wilcox- on Signed Rank Test, p &lt; 0.05). We also did some ablation test, in <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Table 1</ref>, "QOM -stengthen" is the result when we do not strengthen the argument re- lationship matrix. We can see that the uncertain in- formation is very harmful to the performance, which worsen the accuracy for about 1%. "QOM -feature 4,5,6" is the performance when we do not use the dependency features when capturing the argument relationships since <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Wang et al. (2015)</ref> didn't use any dependency feature. We can see that event without dependency feature, our method still can outperform <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Wang et al. (2015)</ref>'s result. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_7">Figure 3</ref> visualizes the candidate argument re- lationship matrix. From this graph, we captured the compatible arguments (" û foreign businessman " and "è ' entrepreneur "), incompatible arguments ("' item " and " û foreign businessman "), ("5 ½ rule " Chinese o û è' Ü{ Ã 8 ' 5½ English translation protect foreign businessman entrepreneur legal profit six item rule and " û foreign businessman ").</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.2">Chinese SRL Performance</head><p>Therefore, " û foreign businessman " and "è' entrepreneur " should be the roles of "Ý] invest " simultaneously , ("' item ", " û foreign businessman ") and ("5 ½ rule ", " û foreign businessman ") should not be the roles of "Ý ] invest " simultaneously.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Conclusion</head><p>In this paper, we propose to use a quadratic opti- mization method based on two kinds of argumen- t relationships to improve the performance of Chi- nese SRL. We first train a maximum entropy clas- sifier to capture the compatible arguments and in- compatible arguments. Then we use quadratic op- timization to improve the result of bidirectional LSTM-RNN( <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Wang et al., 2015)</ref>. The experimen- t has proved the effectiveness of our approach. This method can also be used in other probabilistic meth- ods.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: A sentence with semantic roles labeled from CPB. "rel" represents the predicate, English translation: "Six rules to protect foreign businessman's legal profits when investing entrepreneurs"</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2: The bidirectional LSTM-RNN architecture.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>4</head><label></label><figDesc>Quadratic Optimization Method (QOM) 4.1 Post-processing Module of Bidirectional LSTM-RNN Our quadratic optimization method is a post- processing module of bidirectional LSTM- RNN(Wang et al., 2015). The simplified ar- chitecture of bidirectional LSTM-RNN is shown as</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head>Figure 2</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><head>.</head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_6"><head>Input:</head><label></label><figDesc>Argument relationship matrix: C the argument probabilities required by P arg sum the role probabilities required by P role sum Data: K: Beam size n: Number of candidate arguments Output: The best assignment X Set beam B ← [] ;</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_7"><head>Figure 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Figure 3: The Visualization of argument relationship Matrix, Left is the origin matrix. Right is the strengthened matrix. In the origin matrix, we can directly see the argument relationship we captured (the darker green means stronger relationship, lighter green means weaker relationship). After strengthening, on the right, the words with strong relationship are classified as compatible arguments (the black squares), weak relationship are classified as incompatible arguments (the white squares). Others (the grey squares) are unclear relationship.</figDesc><graphic url="image-1.png" coords="5,88.75,49.91,234.99,139.56" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" validated="false"><head>Table 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Results comparison on CPB dataset. 

</table></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> an irrelevant argument is in the same sentence with the predicate, but it is not labeled as semantic role</note>

			<note place="foot" n="2"> https://catalog.ldc.upenn.edu/LDC2005T23</note>

			<note place="foot" n="3"> http://nlp.stanford.edu/software/lex-parser.shtml</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgements</head><p>We would like to thank our three anonymous re-viewers for their helpful advice on various as-pects of this work. </p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">An empirical study of chinese chunking</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wenliang</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yujie</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hitoshi</forename><surname>Isahara</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the COLING/ACL on Main conference poster sessions</title>
		<meeting>the COLING/ACL on Main conference poster sessions</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="97" to="104" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A unified architecture for natural language processing: Deep neural networks with multitask learning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ronan</forename><surname>Collobert</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jason</forename><surname>Weston</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 25th international conference on Machine learning</title>
		<meeting>the 25th international conference on Machine learning</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="160" to="167" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Improving chinese semantic role classification with hierarchical feature selection strategy</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Weiwei</forename><surname>Ding</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Baobao</forename><surname>Chang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</title>
		<meeting>the Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="324" to="333" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Association for Computational Linguistics</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Word based chinese semantic role labeling with semantic chunking</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Weiwei</forename><surname>Ding</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Baobao</forename><surname>Chang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">International Journal of Computer Processing Of Languages</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">02n03</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="133" to="154" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Automatic labeling of semantic roles</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Daniel</forename><surname>Gildea</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Daniel</forename><surname>Jurafsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Computational linguistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">28</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="245" to="288" />
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Rbpb: Regularizationbased pattern balancing method for event extraction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lei</forename><surname>Sha</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jing</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chin-Yew</forename><surname>Lin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sujian</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Baobao</forename><surname>Chang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Zhifang</forename><surname>Sui</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<monogr>
				<title level="m">Proceedings of the 54th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the 54th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics<address><addrLine>Berlin, Germany, August</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1224" to="1234" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Long Papers)</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Shallow semantic parsing of chinese</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Honglin</forename><surname>Sun</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Daniel</forename><surname>Jurafsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of NAACL-HLT</title>
		<meeting>NAACL-HLT</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Chinese semantic role labeling with shallow parsing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Weiwei</forename><surname>Sun</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Zhifang</forename><surname>Sui</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Meng</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xin</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2009 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</title>
		<meeting>the 2009 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1475" to="1483" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Improving chinese semantic role labeling with rich syntactic features</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Weiwei</forename><surname>Sun</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the ACL 2010 Conference Short Papers</title>
		<meeting>the ACL 2010 Conference Short Papers</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="168" to="172" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Chinese semantic role labeling with bidirectional recurrent neural networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Zhen</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tingsong</forename><surname>Jiang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Baobao</forename><surname>Chang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Zhifang</forename><surname>Sui</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of the 2015 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP)</title>
		<meeting>of the 2015 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language essing (EMNLP)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1626" to="1631" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Annotating the propositions in the penn chinese treebank</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nianwen</forename><surname>Xue</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Martha</forename><surname>Palmer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the second SIGHAN workshop on Chinese language processing</title>
		<meeting>the second SIGHAN workshop on Chinese language processing</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="47" to="54" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Association for Computational Linguistics</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Automatic semantic role labeling for chinese verbs</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nianwen</forename><surname>Xue</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Martha</forename><surname>Palmer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">In IJCAI</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1160" to="1165" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
			<publisher>Citeseer</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Labeling chinese predicates with semantic roles</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nianwen</forename><surname>Xue</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Computational linguistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">34</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="225" to="255" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Multipredicate semantic role labeling</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Haitong</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chengqing</forename><surname>Zong</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">EMNLP</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="363" to="373" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
