<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T10:38+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Fluency detection on communication networks</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date>November 1-5, 2016</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tom</forename><surname>Lippincott</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Human Language Technology Center of Excellence</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Johns Hopkins University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Benjamin</forename><forename type="middle">Van</forename><surname>Durme</surname></persName>
							<email>vandurme@cs.jhu.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Human Language Technology Center of Excellence</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Johns Hopkins University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Fluency detection on communication networks</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2016 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</title>
						<meeting>the 2016 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing <address><addrLine>Austin, Texas</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="1025" to="1029"/>
							<date type="published">November 1-5, 2016</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>When considering a social media corpus, we often have access to structural information about how messages are flowing between people or organizations. This information is particularly useful when the linguistic evidence is sparse, incomplete, or of dubious quality. In this paper we construct a simple model to leverage the structure of Twitter data to help determine the set of languages each user is fluent in. Our results demonstrate that imposing several intuitive constraints leads to improvements in performance and stability. We release the first annotated data set for exploring this task, and discuss how our approach may be extended to other applications.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Language identification (LID) is an important first step in many NLP pipelines since most downstream tasks need to employ language-specific resources. In many situations, LID is a trivial task that can be addressed e.g. by a simple Naive Bayes classifier trained on word and character n-gram data <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(Lui and Baldwin, 2012)</ref>: a document of significant length will be quickly disambiguated based on its vocab- ulary ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">King et al., 2014</ref>). However, social media platforms like Twitter produce data sets in which individual documents are extremely short, and lan- guage use is idiosyncratic: LID performance on such data is dramatically lower than on traditional corpora ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Bergsma et al., 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Carter et al., 2013</ref>). The widespread adoption of social media throughout the world amplifies the problem as less-studied lan- guages lack the annotated resources needed to train the most effective NLP models (e.g. treebanks for statistical parsing, tagged corpora for part-of-speech tagging, etc). All of this motivates the research com- munity's continued interest in LID ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">Zampieri et al., 2014</ref>).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Tweet #1</head><p>Êîç ýâåðèñèíã þ äó èñ ìýäaeèê Tweet #2 omg favourite day of the week! In this paper, we consider the closely-related task of determining an actor's fluencies, the set of lan- guages they are capable of speaking and understand- ing. The observed language data will be the same as for LID, but is now considered to indicate a latent property of the actor. This information has a num- ber of downstream uses, such as providing a strong prior on the language of the actor's future communi- cations, constructing monolingual data sets, and rec- ommending appropriate content for display or fur- ther processing.</p><p>This paper also focuses on the situation where a very small amount of content has been observed from the particular user. While this may seem strange considering the volume of data generated by social media, this is dominated by particularly active users: for example, 30% of Twitter users post only once per month ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Leetaru et al., 2013)</ref>. This content- starved situation is exacerbated by certain use-cases, such as responding to emergency events where sud- den focus is directed at a particular location, or fo- cusing on new users with shallow histories.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>1025</head><p>Twitter and other social media platforms are a ma- jor area of ongoing NLP research, including dedi- cated workshops <ref type="bibr">(NAA, 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr">ACL, 2014)</ref>. Previ- ous work has considered macroscopic properties of the entire Twitter network ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Gabielkov et al., 2014)</ref>, and pondered whether it is an "information" or "so- cial" network ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Myers et al., 2014</ref>). Studies have fo- cused on determining user attributes such as gender ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Li et al., 2015)</ref>, political allegiance ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">Volkova et al., 2014</ref>), brand affinity (Pennacchiotti and Popescu, 2011a), sentiment analysis ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">West et al., 2014)</ref>, and more abstract roles ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Beller et al., 2014</ref>). Such demo- graphic information is known to help downstream tasks <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Hovy, 2015)</ref>. Research involving social media communication networks has typically focused on homophily, the tendency of users to connect to oth- ers with similar properties <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Barberá, 2014)</ref>. A num- ber of papers have employed features drawn from both the content and structure of network entities in pursuit of latent user attributes <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">(Pennacchiotti and Popescu, 2011b;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Campbell et al., 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b18">Suwan et al., 2015</ref>).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Definitions</head><p>We refer to the entities that produce and consume communications as Actors, and the communications (packets of language data) as Messages. Each mes- sage occurs in a particular Language, and each actor has a set of Fluencies, representing the ability to pro- duce and consume a message in a given language. We refer to a connected graph of such entities as a Communication Network. For Twitter data, mes- sages are simply associated with a single actor, who is in turn associated with other actors via the "fol- lowing" relationship, the actor's "friends" in Twit- ter's terminology. <ref type="bibr">1</ref> We assume each message (tweet) is written in a single language, and actors are either fluent or not in each possible language.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Twitter Data Set</head><p>To build a suitable data set 2 for fluency detection, we first identified 1000 Twitter users who, accord- ing to the Twitter LID system, have tweeted in Rus- sian and at least one additional language. For each of these "seed" users, we gather a local context (a "snowflake") as follows: we choose 20 of their friends at random. For each of these friends, we choose 15 of their friends (again, at random). Fi- nally, we randomly pull 200 tweets for each identi- fied user. The data set consists of 989 seed users, 165,042 friends, and 55,019,811 tweets. We pre- serve all Twitter meta-data for the users and tweets, such as location, follower count, hashtags, etc, though for the purposes of this paper we are only interested in the friendship structure and message text. We then had an annotator determine the set of languages each of the 1000 seed users is fluent in. For each seed user, the annotator was presented with their 200 tweets, grouped by Twitter language ID, and was asked to 1) flag users that appear to be bots and 2) list the languages they believe the user is fluent in. These steps are reflected in <ref type="figure">Figure 4</ref>. Over 50% (507) of the users were flagged as pos- sible bots and not used in this study. The remaining 482 were observed employing 7 different languages: Russian, Ukrainian, German, Polish, Bulgarian, Lat- vian, and English. At most, a single user was found to be fluent in three languages. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Structure-Aware Fluency Model</head><p>Our goal was to explicitly model each actor's flu- ency in different languages, using a model with sim-ple, interpretable parameters that can be used to en- code well-motivated assumptions about the data. In particular, we want to bias the model towards the belief that actors typically speak a small number of languages, and encode the belief that all actors par- ticipating in a message are highly likely to be fluent</p><note type="other">in its language. Our basic hypothesis is that, in ad- dition to scores from traditional LID modules, such a model will benefit from considering the behavior of an actor's interlocutors. To test this, we designed a model that employs scores from an existing LID system, and compare performance with and without awareness of the communication network structure. To demonstrate the effectiveness of the model in sit- uations with sparse or unreliable linguistic content, we perform experiments where the number of mes- sages associated with each actor has been randomly down-sampled.</note><p>Linear Programming Linear Programming (LP) is a method for specifying constraints and cost func- tions in terms of linear relationships between vari- ables, and then finding the optimal solution that re- spects the constraints. The restriction to linear equa- tions ensures that the objective function is itself lin- ear, and can be efficiently solved. If some or all variables are restricted to take discrete values, re- ferred to as (Mixed) Integer Linear Programming (ILP), finding a solution becomes NP-hard, though common special cases remain efficiently solvable. We specify our model as an ILP with the hope that it provides sufficient expressiveness for the task, while remaining intuitive and tractable. Infer- ence is performed using the Gurobi modeling toolkit <ref type="bibr">(Gurobi Optimization, 2015)</ref>.</p><p>Model definition Given a communication net- work with no LID information, ideally we would like to determine the language of each message, and the set of languages each actor is fluent in. Ini- tially, we assume access to a probablistic LID sys- tem that maps unicode text to a distribution over possible languages. We use the following notation: A 1:T and M 1:U are the actors and messages, respec- tively. F (a i ) is a binary vector indicating which lan- guages we believe actor a i is fluent in. L(m i ) is a one-on binary vector indicating which language we believe message m i is written in. P (m i ) is the set of actors participating in message m i : for Twitter data, where messages are (usually) not directed at specific users, we treat a user and the users' friends as par- ticipants. LID(m i ) is a real vector representing the probability of message m i being in each language, according to the LID system.</p><p>To build our ILP model, we iterate over actors and messages, defining constraints and the objective function as we go. There are two types of structural constraints: first, we restrict each message to have a single language assignment:</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">L(m i ) = 1<label>(1)</label></formula><p>Second, we ensure that all actors participating in a given message are fluent in its language:</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">∀a ∈ P (m i ), L(m i ) × F (a) = 1<label>(2)</label></formula><p>The objective function also has two components: first, the language fit encourages the model to assign each message a language that has high probability according the the LID system:</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">LF = m∈M L(m) × LID(m)<label>(3)</label></formula><p>Second, the structure fit minimizes the cardinal- ity of the actors' fluency sets (subject to the struc- tural constraints), and thus avoids the trivial solution where each actor is fluent in all languages:</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">SF = − a∈A F (a)<label>(4)</label></formula><p>Finally, the two components of the objective func- tion are combined with an empirically-determined language weight to get the complete objective func- tion:</p><formula xml:id="formula_4">LW × LF + (1.0 − LW) × SF<label>(5)</label></formula><p>Note that these are not all linear relationships: in particular, the multiplication operator cannot be used in ILP when the operands are both variables, as in equation 2. There are however techniques that can represent these situations in a linear program by introducing helper variables and constraints <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Bisschop, 2015</ref>).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Language Identification Scores and Fluency</head><p>Baseline To get LID scores, we ran the VaLID sys- tem ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Bergsma et al., 2012</ref>) on each message, and normalize the output into distributions over 261 pos- sible languages. VaLID is trained on Wikipedia data (i.e. out-of-domain relative to Twitter), although it does employ hand-specified rules for sanitizing tweet text, such as normalizing whitespace and re- moving URLs and user tags. VaLID uses a data- compression approach that is competitive with Twit- ter's in-house LID, despite no consideration of geo- graphic or user priors. These language scores are used in the structure-aware model to compute the language fit.</p><p>Because VaLID makes no use of the communi- cation network structure, we also use its scores to create a baseline structure-unaware fluency model. To get structure-unaware baseline scores for the flu- ency identification task, we average the LID distri- butions for each actor's messages and consider them fluent in a language if its probability is above an empirically-determined threshold.</p><p>Tuning parameters We empirically determine the thresholds for the baseline model and the language weights for the structure-aware model via a simple grid search, repeated 100 times. We randomly split the data into 20%/80% tune/test sets, and evaluate filter thresholds and language weights from 0 to 1 in .01 increments, with messages per actor ranging between 1 and 10. We expected the baseline model to have a consistent optimal threshold (though with higher performance variance with fewer messages), and this was borne out with optimal performance at a threshold of 0.06, independent of the number of messages per actor. For the structure-aware model, the optimal language weight was 0.9, although the entire range from 0.1-0.9 showed similar perfor- mance. This result was surprising, as we expect the structure-aware model to rely heavily on the struc- tural fit when the number of messages is small, and on the language fit when the number is large. This trend doesn't emerge because the structural fit actu- ally relies on the language fit to make assignments for the seed actor's friends and their messages. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Results and discussion</head><p>Figure 2 compares the performance 3 of the structure-aware ILP model with the baseline model as a function of the number of messages per ac- tor, using the empirically-determined threshold and language weight. At the left extreme, the models only have a single, randomly-selected message from each actor. As this number increases, the baseline model improves as it becomes more likely to have seen enough messages to reflect the actor's full spec- trum of language use. The structure-aware model is able to make immediate use of the actor's friends, immediately reaching high performance even when the language data is very sparse. Its most frequent type of error is over-hypothesizing fluency in both Ukrainian and Russian, when the user is in fact monolingual, followed by incorrectly hypothesizing fluency in English. This is understandable given the similarity of the languages in the former case, and the popularity of English expressions, titles, and the like in the latter.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7">Conclusion</head><p>We have presented promising results from lever- aging structural information from a communica- tion network to improve performance on fluency detection in situations where direct linguistic data is sparse. In addition to defining the task itself, we release an annotated data set for training and evaluating future models. Planned future work in- cludes a more flexible decoupling of the language and structure fits (in light of Section 5), and mov- ing from pre-existing LID systems to joint models where LID scores are directly informed by structural information.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: Structure of one snowflake in the Twitter Fluency data set.</figDesc><graphic url="image-1.png" coords="2,313.20,468.05,187.19,113.18" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2: Performance of baseline and structure-aware models as a function of the number of messages per actor used as evidence. Each bar represents the average over 100 random tuning/testing splits, with whiskers showing the standard deviation.</figDesc><graphic url="image-2.png" coords="4,313.20,57.82,187.20,140.40" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" validated="false"><head>Table 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Multilingual social media users often communicate in different languages depending on their intended audience, such as with these Russian and English tweets posted by the same Twitter account</figDesc><table></table></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> Note that, confusingly, Twitter&apos;s &quot;friend&quot; relationship is not symmetric: Mary&apos;s friends are users she has decided to follow, and not necessarily vise-versa.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="2"> The full data set is available at www.university.edu/ link</note>

			<note place="foot" n="3"> F-score calculated based on correct and hypothesized fluency-assignments for each actor.</note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">ACL Joint Workshop on Social Dynamics and Personal Attributes in Social Media</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Birds of the same feather tweet together: Bayesian ideal point estimation using twitter data</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Pablo</forename><surname>Barberá</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Political Analysis</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">23</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="76" to="91" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">I&apos;m a belieber: Social roles via selfidentification and conceptual attributes</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Charley</forename><surname>Beller</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rebecca</forename><surname>Knowles</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Craig</forename><surname>Harman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Shane</forename><surname>Bergsma</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Margaret</forename><surname>Mitchell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Benjamin</forename><surname>Van Durme</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 52rd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the 52rd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics<address><addrLine>Baltimore, Maryland, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="181" to="186" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Language identification for creating language-specific Twitter collections</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Shane</forename><surname>Bergsma</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Paul</forename><surname>Mcnamee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mossaab</forename><surname>Bagdouri</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Clayton</forename><surname>Fink</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Theresa</forename><surname>Wilson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. Second Workshop on Language in Social Media</title>
		<meeting>Second Workshop on Language in Social Media</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="65" to="74" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Aimms optimization modeling</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Johannes</forename><surname>Bisschop</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">langid.py: An off-the-shelf language identification tool</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Campbell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Baseman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Greenfield</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Second Workshop on Natural Language Processing for Social Media</title>
		<meeting>the Second Workshop on Natural Language Processing for Social Media<address><addrLine>Dublin, Ireland</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="59" to="65" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Microblog language identification: Overcoming the limitations of short, unedited and idiomatic text</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Simon</forename><surname>Carter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wouter</forename><surname>Weerkamp</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Manos</forename><surname>Tsagkias</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Lang. Resour. Eval</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">47</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="195" to="215" />
			<date type="published" when="2013-03" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Studying social networks at scale: Macroscopic anatomy of the twitter social graph</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Maksym</forename><surname>Gabielkov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ashwin</forename><surname>Rao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Arnaud</forename><surname>Legout</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">SIGMETRICS &apos;14</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Austin, Texas, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Gurobi optimizer reference manual</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Inc</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Gurobi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Optimization</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Demographic factors improve classification performance</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dirk</forename><surname>Hovy</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 53rd</title>
		<meeting>the 53rd</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Experiments in sentence language identification with groups of similar languages</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">China</forename><forename type="middle">Ben</forename><surname>Beijing</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dragomir</forename><surname>King</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Steven</forename><surname>Radev</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Abney</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the First Workshop on Applying NLP Tools to Similar Languages, Varieties and Dialects</title>
		<meeting>the First Workshop on Applying NLP Tools to Similar Languages, Varieties and Dialects<address><addrLine>Dublin, Ireland</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="146" to="154" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Mapping the global twitter heartbeat: The geography of twitter</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kalev</forename><surname>Leetaru</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Shaowen</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Guofeng</forename><surname>Cao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Anand</forename><surname>Padmanabhan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Eric</forename><surname>Shook</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">First Monday</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">18</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Interactive gender inference with integer linear programming</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Shoushan</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jingjing</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Guodong</forename><surname>Zhou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hanxiao</forename><surname>Shi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 24th International Conference on Artificial Intelligence, IJCAI&apos;15</title>
		<meeting>the 24th International Conference on Artificial Intelligence, IJCAI&apos;15</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>AAAI Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2341" to="2347" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">langid.py: An off-the-shelf language identification tool</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marco</forename><surname>Lui</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Timothy</forename><surname>Baldwin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 50th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the 50th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics<address><addrLine>Jeju, Republic of Korea</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="25" to="30" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Information network or social network? the structure of the twitter follow graph</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Seth</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Myers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Aneesh</forename><surname>Sharma</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Pankaj</forename><surname>Gupta</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jimmy</forename><surname>Lin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">WWW &apos;14 Companion</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Seoul, Korea</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<monogr>
				<title level="m">NAACL International Workshop on Natural Language Processing for Social Media</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Democrats, republicans and starbucks afficionados: User classification in twitter</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marco</forename><surname>Pennacchiotti</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ana-Maria</forename><surname>Popescu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">KDD &apos;11</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>San Diego, California, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A machine learning approach to twitter user classification</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marco</forename><surname>Pennacchiotti</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ana-Maria</forename><surname>Popescu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Fifth International AAAI Conference on Weblogs and Social Media</title>
		<meeting>the Fifth International AAAI Conference on Weblogs and Social Media</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="281" to="288" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Bayesian vertex nomination using content and context</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Shakira</forename><surname>Suwan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dominic</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Carey</forename><surname>Priebe</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">WIREs Comput Stat</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="400" to="416" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Inferring user political preferences from streaming communications</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Svitlana</forename><surname>Volkova</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Glen</forename><surname>Coppersmith</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Benjamin</forename><surname>Van Durme</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 52rd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the 52rd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics<address><addrLine>Baltimore, Maryland, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="186" to="196" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Exploiting social network structure for person-to-person sentiment analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Robert</forename><surname>West</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hristo</forename><surname>Paskov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jure</forename><surname>Leskovec</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christopher</forename><surname>Potts</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Transactions of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="297" to="310" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Discriminating similar languages shared task at coling</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marcos</forename><surname>Zampieri</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Liling</forename><surname>Tang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nikola</forename><surname>Ljubeši´ljubeši´c</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jörg</forename><surname>Tiedemann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
