<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T12:01+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">An Embedding Model for Predicting Roll-Call Votes</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
				<availability status="unknown"><p>Copyright Association for Computational Linguistics</p>
				</availability>
				<date>November 1-5, 2016. 2016</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Peter</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Kraft</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">School of Engineering and Applied Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Harvard University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hirsh</forename><surname>Jain</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">School of Engineering and Applied Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Harvard University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alexander</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Rush</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">School of Engineering and Applied Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Harvard University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">An Embedding Model for Predicting Roll-Call Votes</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2016 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</title>
						<meeting>the 2016 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing <address><addrLine>Austin, Texas</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="2066" to="2070"/>
							<date type="published">November 1-5, 2016. 2016</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>We develop a novel embedding-based model for predicting legislative roll-call votes from bill text. The model introduces multidimen-sional ideal vectors for legislators as an alternative to single dimensional ideal point models for quantitatively analyzing roll-call data. These vectors are learned to correspond with pre-trained word embeddings which allows us to analyze which features in a bill text are most predictive of political support. Our model is quite simple, while at the same time allowing us to successfully predict legislator votes on specific bills with higher accuracy than past methods.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Quantitative analysis of political data can contribute to our understanding of governments. One impor- tant source of such data is roll-call votes, records of how legislators vote on bills. Analysis of roll-call data can reveal interesting information about legisla- tors (such as political leanings and ideological clus- ters) and can also allow prediction of future votes <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Clinton, 2012)</ref>.</p><p>Previous work on analyzing roll-call votes has chiefly involved positioning congresspeople on ideal point models. Ideal point models assume all legisla- tors and bills can be plotted as single points in one- dimensional "political space." The closer a particu- lar bill's position is to a particular congressperson's, the more utility the congressperson is expected to derive from the bill. Initial work on ideal point models focused on using them to test theories about legislative behavior, such as predicting that the rel- ative differences between ideal points of congress- people of different parties, and thus party polar- ization, would increase over time <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(McCarty, 2001)</ref>. Ideal point models are often created using Bayesian techniques over large amounts of roll-call data <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Clinton et al., 2004;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Jackman, 2001</ref>). However, these models are not used to make predictions. They are trained using the complete vote matrix for the bill, which indicates how each congressperson voted on each bill. Therefore, they cannot say anything about how congresspeople will vote on a new bill, as until some congresspeople have voted on the bill its ideal point is not known.</p><p>We target this vote prediction problem: given the text of a bill and a congressperson, can we indepen- dently predict how each congressperson will vote on the bill? The first prior attempt at this task was made by <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Gerrish and Blei (2011)</ref> who create an ideal point topic model which integrates a topic model similar to LDA for the bill text with an ideal point model for the congresspeople. They use variational inference to approximate the posterior distribution of the top- ics and ideal points, predicting with a linear model. <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Gerrish and Blei (2012)</ref> further extend this work with an issue-adjusted model, a similar model that modifies congressperson ideal points based on top- ics identified with labeled LDA, but which cannot be used for predictions. Further work in a similar vein includes <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Wang et al. (2013)</ref>, who introduced temporal information to a graphical model for pre- dicting Congressional votes, and <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Kim et al. (2014)</ref>, who used sparse factor analysis to estimate Senato- rial ideal points from bill text and the votes of party leadership.</p><p>In this work we revisit this task with a simple bilinear model that learns multidimensional embed- dings for both legislators and bills, combining them to make vote predictions. We represent a bill as the average of its word embeddings. We represent legislators as ideal vectors, trained end-to-end for vote prediction. These ideal vectors serve as a use- ful, easy-to-train, multidimensional representation of legislator ideology that does not rely on elaborate statistical models or any further assumptions about legislator behavior. Finally, we train our model by optimizing a cross-entropy objective instead of the posterior of a topic model. The final model achieves high accuracy at predicting roll-call votes.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Model</head><p>Our goal is to predict roll-call votes by learning from the texts of bills and from past votes. Our input con- sists of a congressperson c and the set B of unique words in a bill. Our output y is whether that the con- gressperson voted yea or nay on the bill. We train on the full set of congressional votes on a number of bills. At test time, we supply entirely new bills and predict how each congressperson will vote on each new bill.</p><p>We propose a simple bilinear model that uses low-dimensional embeddings to model each word in our dictionary and each congressperson. We rep- resent each bill using its word embeddings in or- der to capture the multivariate relationships between words and their meanings <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Collobert et al., 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Mikolov et al., 2013</ref>). The model is trained to synthesize information about each congressperson's voting record into a multidimensional ideal vector. At test time, the model combines the embedding rep- resentation of a new bill with the trained ideal vector of a congressperson and generates a prediction for how the congressperson will vote on the bill.</p><p>Let e w ∈ R d word be the pretrained embedding for a word w. We initialize to the GloVe embeddings with d word = 50 ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Pennington et al., 2014</ref>), then jointly train them with the model. To represent a bill, we average over the embeddings of the set B of words in the bill.</p><p>To represent a congressperson, we introduce an- other set of embeddings v c ∈ R d emb for each con- gressperson c. The embeddings act as the ideal vec- tor for each legislator. Unlike the word embeddings, we initialize these randomly.</p><p>The full model takes in a bill and a congressper- to map the bill representation into the space of the ideal vectors, and then uses a dot-product to provide a yea/nay score.</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">p(y = yea|B, c) = σ((W w∈B e w /|B| + b) · v c )</formula><p>The full model is simply trained to minimize the negative log-likelihood of the training set, and re- quires no additional meta-information (such as party affiliation) or additional preprocessing of the bills during training-or test-time.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Experimental Setup</head><p>Data Following past work, our dataset is derived from the Govtrack database. 1 Specifically, our dataset consists of all votes on the full-text (not amendments) of bills or resolutions from the 106th- 111th Congress, six of the most recent Congresses for which bill texts are readily available. Details of each these congresses are shown in <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>.</p><p>To create our dataset, we first find a list of all votes on the full text of bills, and create a matrix of how each congressperson voted on each bill, which will be used in training and in testing. In accordance with previous work, we only consider yes-or-no votes and omit abstentions and "present" votes (Gerrish and Blei, 2011). We then simply collect the set of words used in each bill. Overall, our dataset consists of 4067 bills and over a million unique yes-or-no votes.  <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">Table 2</ref>: Main results comparing predictive accu- racy of our model EMB with a several baselines (de- scribed in the text) on the 106th-111th Congress.</p><p>Model We tested prediction accuracy of the average-of-embeddings model, EMB, by running it for ten epochs at a learning rate of η = 0.1 and d emb set to 10. Hyperparameters were tuned on a held- out section of the 107th Congress. We ran on each of the 106th to 111th Congresses individually using five-fold cross-validation.</p><p>Baselines We compare our results to three differ- ent baselines. The first, YEA, is a majority class baseline which assumes all legislators vote yea. The second, IDP, is our model with d emb set to 1 to simulate a simple ideal point model. The third, GB, is Gerrish and Blei's reported predictive accu- racy of 89 % on average from the 106th to 111th Congresses, which is to the extent of our knowledge the best predictive accuracy on roll-call votes yet achieved in the literature. Gerrish and Blei report on the same data set using cross-validation and like us train and test on each congress individually, but do not split out results into individual congresses.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Experiments and Analysis</head><p>Predictive Results The main predictive experi- mental results are shown in  and obtained an accuracy of 89.5%, in between GB and EMB. This indicates that the word embeddings are also responsible for part, but not all, of the accu- racy improvement. We also report minority class F1 scores for EMB in <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">Table 3</ref>, finding an overall average F1 score of 0.645.</p><p>Ideal Vectors Beyond predictive accuracy, one of the most interesting features of the model is that it produces ideal vectors as its complete representa- tion of congresspeople. These vectors are much eas- ier to compute than standard ideal points, which re- quire relatively complex and computationally inten- sive statistical models <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(Jackman, 2001</ref>). Addition- ally unlike ideal point models, which tend to contain many assumptions about legislative behavior, ideal vectors arise naturally from raw data and bill text <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Clinton et al., 2004</ref>). In <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref>, we show the ideal vectors for the 111th Congress. We use PCA to project the vec- tors down to two dimensions. This graph displays several interesting patterns in agreement with theo- ries of legislative behavior. For example, political scientists theorize that the majority party in a legis- lature will display more unity in roll-call votes be- cause they decide what gets voted on and only allow a vote on a bill if they can unify behind it and pass it, while that bill may divide the other party <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Carrubba et al., 2006;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Carrubba et al., 2008)</ref>. On this graph, in accordance with that prediction, the ma- jority Democrats are more clustered than the minor- ity Republicans. We observe similar trends in the ideal vectors of the other Congresses. Moreover, the model lets us examine the positions of individual congresspeople. In the figure, the 34 Democrats who <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref>: PCA projection of the ideal vectors for 111th Congress, both House and Senate. Republi- cans shown in red, Democrats who voted for Afford- able Care Act (ACA) in blue, Democrats who voted against ACA in yellow, and independents in green.</p><p>voted against the Affordable Care Act (ACA, bet- ter known as Obamacare) are shown in yellow. The ACA was a major Democratic priority and point of difference between the two parties. The Democrats who voted against it tended to be relatively conser- vative and closer to the Republicans. The model picks up on this distinction.</p><p>Furthermore, since our model maps individual words and congresspeople to the same vector space, we can use it to determine how words (and by proxy issues) unite or divide congresspeople and parties. In <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 2</ref>, we show the scaled probabilities that congresspeople will vote for a bill containing only the word "enterprise" versus one containing only the word "science" in the 110th Congress. The word "enterprise," denoting pro-business legislation, neatly divides the parties. Both are for it, but Repub- licans favor it more. More interestingly, the word "science" creates division within the parties, as nei- ther was at the time more for science funding than the other but both contained congresspeople with varying levels of support for it. An ideal point model would likely capture the "enterprise" dimension, but not the "science" one, and would not be able to dis- tinguish between libertarians like Ron Paul (R-TX) who are against both "corporate welfare" and gov- ernment science funding, conservative budget hawks like Jeff Flake (R-AZ) who favor business but are skeptical of government funding of science, and es- tablishment Republicans like Kevin McCarthy (R- CA) who support both. Indeed, ideal point models are known to perform poorly at describing ideolog- ically idiosyncratic figures like Ron <ref type="bibr">Paul (Gerrish and Blei, 2011)</ref>. Providing the ability to explore multiple dimensions of difference between legisla- tors will be extremely helpful for political scientists analyzing the dynamics of legislatures.</p><p>Lexical Properties Finally, as with topic model- ing approaches, we can use our model to analyze the relationships between congresspeople or parties and individual words in bills. For example, Ta- ble 4 shows the ten words closest by cosine simi- larity to each party's average congressperson (stop words omitted) for the 110th Congress. The Demo- cratic list mostly contains words relating to govern- ing and regulating, such as "consumer," "state," and "educational," likely because the Democrats were at the time the majority party with the responsibil- ity for passing large governmental and regulatory bills like budgets. The Republican list is largely concerned with the military, with words like "vet- erans," "service," and "executive," probably because of the importance at the time of the wars in Iraq and Afghanistan, started by a Republican president. <ref type="table">Republicans   economic  veterans  exchange  head  state  opportunities  carrying  provided  government  promote  higher  service  congress  identified  consumer  information  educational  record  special  executive   Table 4</ref>: Top ten words by cosine similarity for each party in the 110th Congress with stop words re- moved.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Democrats</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Conclusion</head><p>We have developed a novel model for predicting Congressional roll-call votes. This new model provides a new and interesting way of analyz- ing the behavior of parties and legislatures. It achieves predictive accuracies around 90.6% on av- erage and outperforms any prior model of roll-call voting. We also introduce the idea of ideal vec- tors as a fast, simple, and multidimensional al- ternative to ideal point models for analyzing the actions of individual legislators and testing theo- ries about their behavior. Our code and datasets are available online at https://github.com/ kraftp/roll_call_predictor.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2: Relative likelihood of congresspeople in the 110th Congress voting for a bill containing only the word "Enterprise" versus only the word "Science." Coordinates are sigmoids of dot products of congressperson vectors with normalized word vectors.</figDesc><graphic url="image-2.png" coords="4,313.20,57.82,226.80,160.47" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" validated="false"><head>Table 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>We see that 
EMB performs substantially better than YEA on all 
six Congresses. It has a weighted average of 90.6% 
on an 84.5% baseline, compared to Gerrish and 
Blei's 89% on an identical dataset. IDP, however, 
actually does worse than the baseline, demonstrat-
ing that the bulk of our gain in prediction accu-
racy comes from using ideal vectors instead of ideal 
points. To further test this hypothesis, we experi-
mented with replacing word embeddings with LDA 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3" validated="false"><head>Table 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Minority class F1 Scores of our model EMB 
on the 106th-111th Congress. 

</table></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> https://www.govtrack.us/ 2 Mostly. Republicans controlled the 107th Senate for five months between the inauguration of Dick Cheney as vicepresident in January of 2001 and the defection of Jim Jeffords in June.</note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Off the record: Unrecorded legislative votes, selection bias and roll-call vote analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Clifford</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Matthew</forename><surname>Carrubba</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lacey</forename><surname>Gabel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ryan</forename><surname>Murrah</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Elizabeth</forename><surname>Clough</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rebecca</forename><surname>Montgomery</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Schambach</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">British Journal of Political Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">36</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">04</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="691" to="704" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Legislative voting behavior, seen and unseen: A theory of roll-call vote selection</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Clifford</forename><surname>Carrubba</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Matthew</forename><surname>Gabel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Simon</forename><surname>Hug</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Legislative Studies Quarterly</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">33</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="543" to="572" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The statistical analysis of roll call data</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Joshua</forename><surname>Clinton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Simon</forename><surname>Jackman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Douglas</forename><surname>Rivers</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">American Political Science Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">98</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">02</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="355" to="370" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Using roll call estimates to test models of politics</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Joshua D Clinton</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Annual Review of Political Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="79" to="99" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Natural language processing (almost) from scratch</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ronan</forename><surname>Collobert</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jason</forename><surname>Weston</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Léon</forename><surname>Bottou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Karlen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Koray</forename><surname>Kavukcuoglu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Pavel</forename><surname>Kuksa</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The Journal of Machine Learning Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2493" to="2537" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Predicting legislative roll calls from text</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sean</forename><surname>Gerrish</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>David</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Blei</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 28th international conference on machine learning (icml11)</title>
		<meeting>the 28th international conference on machine learning (icml11)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="489" to="496" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">How they vote: Issue-adjusted models of legislative behavior</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sean</forename><surname>Gerrish</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>David</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Blei</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Advances in Neural Information Processing Systems</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2753" to="2761" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Multidimensional analysis of roll call data via bayesian simulation: Identification, estimation, inference, and model checking</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Simon</forename><surname>Jackman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Political Analysis</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="227" to="241" />
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Voting, speechmaking, and the dimensions of conflict in the us senate</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">In</forename><forename type="middle">Song</forename><surname>Kim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">John</forename><surname>Londregan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marc</forename><surname>Ratkovic</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Annual Meeting of the Midwest Political Science Association</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The hunt for party discipline in congress</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nolan</forename><surname>Mccarty</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">American Political Science Association</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Cambridge Univ Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">95</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="673" to="687" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Linguistic regularities in continuous space word representations</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tomas</forename><surname>Mikolov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Geoffrey</forename><surname>Wen-Tau Yih</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Zweig</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">HLT-NAACL</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="746" to="751" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Glove: Global vectors for word representation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jeffrey</forename><surname>Pennington</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Richard</forename><surname>Socher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christopher D</forename><surname>Manning</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">EMNLP</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1532" to="1543" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Spatio-temporal modeling of legislation and votes</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Eric</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Esther</forename><surname>Salazar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Dunson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lawrence</forename><surname>Carin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Bayesian Analysis</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="233" to="268" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
