<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T11:44+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Non-Literal Text Reuse in Historical Texts: An Approach to Identify Reuse Transformations and its Application to Bible Reuse</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date>November 1-5, 2016</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Maria</forename><surname>Moritz</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Institute of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Göttingen</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Andreas</forename><surname>Wiederhold</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Institute for Educational Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Göttingen</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Barbara</forename><surname>Pavlek</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="department">Minds and Traditions Research Group</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Max Planck Institute for the Science of Human History</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Jena</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yuri</forename><surname>Bizzoni</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff3">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Department of Philosophy</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Theory of Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Gothenburg</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Linguistics</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marco</forename><forename type="middle">B ¨</forename><surname>Uchler</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Institute of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Göttingen</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Non-Literal Text Reuse in Historical Texts: An Approach to Identify Reuse Transformations and its Application to Bible Reuse</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2016 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</title>
						<meeting>the 2016 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing <address><addrLine>Austin, Texas</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="1849" to="1859"/>
							<date type="published">November 1-5, 2016</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Text reuse refers to citing, copying or alluding text excerpts from a text resource to a new context. While detecting reuse in contemporary languages is well supported-given extensive research, techniques, and corpora-automatically detecting historical text reuse is much more difficult. Corpora of historical languages are less documented and often encompass various genres, linguistic varieties, and topics. In fact, historical text reuse detection is much less understood and empirical studies are necessary to enable and improve its automation. We present a linguistic analysis of text reuse in two ancient data sets. We contribute an automated approach to analyze how an original text was transformed into its reuse, taking linguistic resources into account to understand how they help characterizing the transformation. It is complemented by a manual analysis of a subset of the reuse. Our results show the limitations of approaches focusing on literal reuse detection. Yet, linguistic resources can effectively support understanding the non-literal text reuse transformation process. Our results support practitioners and researchers working on understanding and detecting historical reuse.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>The computational detection of historical text reuse- including citations, quotations or allusions -can be applied in many respects. It can help tracing down historical content (a.k.a., lines of transmis- sion), which is essential to the field of textual crit- icism <ref type="bibr">(Büchler et al., 2012</ref>). In the context of mas- sive digitization projects, it can identify relationships between text excerpts referring to the same source. Specifically, detecting copies of the same historical text that have diverged over time (manuscript studies, a.k.a., Stemma Codicum) is an important task.</p><p>Although much work exists in the field of nat- ural language processing (NLP), many new chal- lenges arise when processing historical text. The most important challenges are the absence of support- ing tools and methods, including an agreement on a common orthography, standardization of variants, and a wide range of clean, digitized text <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">(Piotrowski, 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr">Geyken and Gloning, 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b30">Zitouni, 2014)</ref>. Typical statistical approaches from the field of NLP are difficult to apply to historically transferred texts, since these often cover a large timespan and, thus, comprise many different writing styles, text variants or even reuse styles <ref type="bibr">(Büchler, 2013)</ref>. Our long-term goal is to conceive robust text reuse detection tech- niques for historical texts. To this end, we need to improve the quantitative empirical understanding of such reuse accompanied by qualitative empirical stud- ies. However, only few such works exist.</p><p>We study less-and non-literal text reuse of Bible verses in Ancient Greek and Latin texts. Our focus is on understanding how the reuse instances are trans- formed from the original verses. We identify opera- tions that characterize how words are changed-e.g., synonymized, capitalized or part-of-speech (PoS) in- formation changed. Since our approach uses external linguistic resources, including Ancient Greek Word- Net (AGWN) ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Bizzoni et al., 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b23">Minozzi, 2009)</ref> and various lemma lists, we also show how such resources can help detecting reuse and where the lim- itations are. We complement the automated approach with a qualitative manual analysis. We contribute:</p><p>• an automated approach to characterize how text is transformed between reuse and original, • an application of the approach to two text datasets where reuse was manually identified, • empirical data based on the automated approach, complemented by a manual identification.</p><p>Our resulting datasets 1 with rich information about the reuse transformation (e.g., PoS and morphology changes, and words becoming synonyms or hyper- onyms, among others) can be used as a benchmark for future reuse detection and classification approaches.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Related Work</head><p>We first discuss why existing reuse detection ap- proaches are not applicable to historical texts, and then present works trying to address this problem. Historical Text <ref type="bibr">Reuse and Plagiarism Detection. Büchler (2013)</ref> combines state-of-the-art NLP tech- niques to address reuse detection scenarios for histor- ical texts, ranging from near copies to text excerpts with a minimum overlap. He uses the commonly used method fingerprinting, which selects n-grams from an upfront pre-segmentized corpus. While his ap- proach can discover historical and modern text reuse language-independently, it requires a minimum text similarity-typically at least two common features.</p><p>Recognizing modified reuse is difficult in general. <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Alzahrani et al. (2012)</ref> study plagiarism detection techniques: n-gram-, syntax-, and semantics-based approaches. As soon as reused text is slightly modi- fied (e.g., words changed) most systems fail. <ref type="bibr">BarrónCedeño et al. (2013)</ref> conduct experiments on para- phrasing, observing that complex paraphrasing along with a high paraphrasing density challenges plagia- rism detection, and that lexical substitution is the most frequent technique for plagiarizing. The Ara- PlagDet ( <ref type="bibr">Bensalem et al., 2015</ref>) initiative focuses on the evaluation of plagiarism detection methods for Arabic texts. Eight methods were submitted and turned out to work with a high accuracy on exter- nal plagiarism detection but did not achieve usable results for intrinsic plagiarism detection. Corpora. Huge parallel corpora of modern lan- guages are used in fields such as paraphrase gen-eration and detection, typically used to train statis- tical models ( <ref type="bibr">Zhao et al., 2009;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b19">Madnani and Dorr, 2010)</ref>. However, such corpora hardly exist for his- torical languages or are copyrighted, such as the TLG digital library <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">(Pantelia, 2014)</ref>. Especially in the field of modern reuse investigation, aligned cor- pora are often used, providing a rich source of para- phrasal sentence pairs in one, sometimes multiple languages. One of such is the Microsoft Research Paraphrase Corpus (MSRP), which contains 5801 manually evaluated, paraphrasal sentence pairs in En- glish <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(Dolan and Brockett, 2005</ref>). <ref type="bibr">Ganitkevitch et al. (2013)</ref> present a paraphrase database with over 200 million English paraphrase pairs and 196 million Spanish paraphrases. Each paraphrase pair comes with measures, such as a paraphrase probability score. In ancient literature, efforts are made to collect Bib- lical reuse. One of such is the collection of Ancinet Greek and Latin quotations based on the the Vetus Latina series and the Novum Testamentum Graecum Editio Critica Maior <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(Houghton, 2013a;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Houghton, 2013b)</ref>. It contains more than 150,000 Latin citations and about 87,000 Ancient Greek Bible references. Historical Text Processing in General. Efforts to automatically process ancient texts are made around the Perseus Digital Library project <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Crane, 1985)</ref>, among others. For example, <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Bamman (2008)</ref> presents the discovery of textual allusions in a col- lection of Classical poetry, using measures such as token similarity, n-grams or syntactic similarity. This allows finding at least the most similar candidates within a closed library. Some works have focused on text reuse in Biblical Greek text. <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">Lee (2007)</ref> investi- gate reuse among the Gospels of the New Testament, aimed at aligning similar sentences. Using source alternation patterns, among others, the approach uses cosine similarity, source verse proximity, and source verse order. Focusing on high recall, the detection of Homeric quotations in Athenaeus' Deipnosophistai' was investigated by <ref type="bibr">Büchler et al. (2012)</ref>, searching for distinctive words within reuse.</p><p>While the approaches above rely on string or fea- ture similarity, Bamman (2011b) attempts to process the semantic space using word-sense disambigua- tion ( <ref type="bibr">Patwardhan et al., 2003;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Agirre and Edmonds, 2007)</ref>. Using a bilingual sense inventory and training set, they classify up to 72 % of word senses correctly. Utilizing Linguistic Resources. Word nets support identifying word relationships. Jing (1998) investi- gates issues that come with using WordNet <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">(Miller et al., 1990</ref>) for language generation. Among others, these comprise issues arising from the adaption of a general lexicon to a specific domain. These were en- countered by using a domain corpus and an ontology to prune WordNet to a certain domain.</p><p>In our work, we are interested in using linguistic resources (word nets and lemma lists) together with PoS information to model the transformation process of reuse, specifically on an ancient language text to find limitations when applied to non-literal text reuse.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Methodology</head><p>Our study addresses two main research questions: RQ1. What is the extent of non-literal reuse in our datasets? This analysis provides a baseline for the following characterizations of the non-literal reuse. RQ2. How is the non-literally reused text modified in our datasets? We study kinds and frequencies of semantic, lexical, and morphological changes. We develop an automated approach to identify the reuse transformation, and complement it with a manual, qualitative analysis. We formulate two sub-questions: RQ2.1. How can linguistic resources support the discovery of non-literal reuse? We conjecture that non-literal reuse is difficult to capture automatically (especially due to domain-or author-specific words), but that taking linguistic resources into account helps. We analyze the coverage of words in lemma lists and a synset database, and investigate how useful they are for understanding the reuse transformations. RQ2.2. What are the limitations of an automated classification approach relying on linguistic re- sources? Our manual analysis investigates the reuse in its full richness, to understand the limitations of the automated approach and identify further charac- teristics of the reuse in our datasets.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Study Design</head><p>Our study comprises the following main steps. First (RQ1), we identify and characterize the literal and non-literal overlap in reuse instances. Second (to- wards RQ2), we define operations reflecting literal reuse, replacements (inspired by semantic relation- ships, such as synonyms and hyperonyms, supported by AGWN), and morphological changes (e.g., when mapping words contain the same cognate). Our oper- ations are based on a one-word-replacement to better quantify the results. Third (RQ2.1), we develop an algorithm that identifies operations by first looking for morphological changes between a word from the reuse and its corresponding candidate from the Bible verse and, in case of no success, by seeking for a semantic relation. We apply it to our two datasets and investigate the relationships of affected words and the literal share. We quantify occurrences of op- erations and calculate two measures sup lem (lemma support) and sup AGWN (AGWN support) to assess the resources' coverage for our approach. Fourth <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">(RQ2.2)</ref>, we manually analyze a smaller sample of our reuse datasets, using further operations, to under- stand the full richness of the reuse.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Datasets</head><p>We use the following two text sources, both reusing content from Bible verses. As a ground truth of the reuse, we use manually annotated versions of both, provided to us by <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Mellerin (2014)</ref> and the Biblindex project <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">(Mellerin, 2016;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b29">Vinzent et al., 2013)</ref>.</p><p>Our first dataset comes from the primary source text of "Salvation for the Rich" from the An- cient Greek writer Clement of Alexandria (Clément d'Alexandrie, 2011), a well-known author in Bibli- cal literature <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Cosaert, 2008)</ref>. The Biblindex team annotated 128 text passages as Bible reuse instances, adding a footnote with Bible verse pointers to each. We select a total of 95 out of these 128, following four criteria: (i) reuse should not consist of an exact literal copy of a Bible verse (skipping six instances), (ii) reuse should be recognizable by our expert (skip- ping ten instances), (iii) the reference frame should be within five Bible verses (comparable with sen- tences) to avoid too much noise in our data to ensure a comparable length to the original Bible verse (skip- ping nine instances), and (iv) reuse instances should not exceed a length of 40 tokens (1-2 sentences), again to cut the long tail and avoid too much noise (skipping eight instances). Sometimes one reuse in- stance pointed to different Bible verses or one text passage contained more than one reuse instance, thus, we come up with 199 verse-reuse-pairs. The excerpts point to a total of 15 Bible books.</p><p>Our second dataset are extracts from a total of 14 volumes of twelve works and two work collec-</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>si occultabitur vir in absconditis et ego non videbo eum dicit Dominus numquid non caelum et terram ego impleo ait Dominus (Can anyone hide himself in secret places that I will not see him? Said the lord. Do not I fill heaven and earth? Said the Lord) literal et terram ego impleo (and I fill the earth)</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Mk 10 30</head><p>Ἤρξατο λέγειν ὁ Πέτρος αὐτῷ, Ἰδοὺ ἡμεῖς ἀφήκαμεν πάντα καὶ ἠκολουθήκαμέν σοι. (Peter began to say to him: See, we left everything and followed you.) literal ἡμεῖς ἀϕήκαμεν πάντα καὶ ἠκολουθήσαμέν σοι (we left everything and followed you)  <ref type="bibr">and Aland, 1966)</ref>, and Biblia sacra juxta vulgatam versionem <ref type="bibr">(Weber R., 1969</ref><ref type="bibr">(Weber R., 1994</ref><ref type="bibr">(Weber R., 2007</ref>. <ref type="figure">Fig. 1</ref> shows reuse examples, illustrating the wide range of literalness in our data, comprising literal (all tokens overlap), less literal (important tokens over- lap), and non-literal (no content word tokens overlap) reuse. For example, Clement's reuse ranges from in- troducing the overall topic by citing multiple verses, to supporting his argumentation. Specifically, Mk 10 30 is a fully literal reuse from a passage that dis- cusses the problem of rich men in heaven. Clement uses this episode as a main point in his essay. Later he refers to 1Cor 13 13, he again refers to how hard it would be for rich men to enter heaven, explaining that salvation is independent of "external things," but depends on the "virtue of the soul," mentioning faith,</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Algorithm 1: Reuse classification algorithm</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>/ * Executed for each reuse instance and its corresponding</head><p>Bible verse. morph(x) returns the part-of-speech and/or case of x. repl case and repl pos are masked to repl morph for clarity reasons. checkm(x,y) returns NOPmorph(morph(x),morph(y)) if morph(x) equals morph(y) and repl morph(morph(x),morph(y)) otherwise. * / input : L ← set of word-lemma pairs obtained from the lemma resources input : S ← set of synsets from AGWN; each synset contains an id and a parent id input : T ← list of words of reuse instance (containing part-of-speech information) input : B ← list of words of Bible verse (containing part-of-speech information) output : OP ← list of sets containing up to 3 parameterized operations s1, s2 ← any two synsets ∈ S. tmp op ← temporary variable which presents the absence of a relation but not of a lemma.</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">for t in T do for b in B do if t=b then OP ← OP ∪ (N OP (t, b), checkm(morph(t), morph(b))) break else if lowerCase(t) = b then OP ← OP ∪ (lower(t, b), checkm(morph(t), morph(b))) break else if lowerCase(b) = t then OP ← OP ∪ (upper(t, b), checkm(morph(t), morph(b))) break else if t ∈ L and b ∈ L then / * lemma found for original (b) and reuse word (t) * / if lemma(t) = lemma(b) then OP ← OP ∪ (lem(t, b), checkm(morph(t), morph(b)))</formula><p>break else if t ∈ s1 and b ∈ s2 and s1 ∈ S and s2 ∈ S then if s1 = s2 then <ref type="figure">(hyper(t, b)</ref>) break else if parent id(s1) = parent id(s2) then / * synset of t and synset of b both have the same synset as parent</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">/ * t is synonym of b * / OP ← OP ∪ (repl syn(t, b)) break else if id(s1) = parent id(s2) then / * t is hyperonym of b * / OP ← OP ∪ (repl hypo(t, b)) break else if parent id(s1) = id(s2) then / * t is hyperonym of b * / OP ← OP ∪</formula><formula xml:id="formula_2">* / OP ← OP ∪ (repl cohypo(t, b)) break else tmp op ← (no rel f ound(t, b)) end if tmp op then OP ← OP ∪ tmp op else OP ← OP ∪ (lemma missing(t))</formula><p>end return OP hope, and love, the key words in the original verse.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3">PoS Tagging</head><p>The automated and the manual approach also take PoS information into account to understand the reuse transformation. Following the Greek morphol- ogy tagging system of Perseus (Bamman and Crane, 2011a), which maps PoS and case information to sin- gle characters 2 , we manually PoS-tag the 199 reuse instances of Ancient Greek and the 162 of Latin, as well as the original Bible verses. Since Latin and Ancinet Greek PoS-taggers lack available implemen- tations, appropriate trained models or simply accu-  <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">Greek Bible 4  3238  1906 1422 1185 1422  4776  Clement 5  739  326 231  175  231  2189  Latin Bible 4  2473  1241 905  863  905  2618  Bernard 5  1219  643 471  455  471</ref>  n/a n/a n/a n/a n/a 2618 Bernard <ref type="bibr">5,</ref><ref type="bibr">6</ref> n/a n/a n/a n/a n/a 1335   <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Crane, 1991;</ref><ref type="bibr">vor der Brück et al., 2015</ref>), we perform this step manually to assure high accuracy. We also assign cases for the classes noun, article, ad- jective, and pronoun. We introduce b to represent the Latin ablative case, which does not exist in Greek.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.4">Automated Approach</head><p>Our approach is to model the transformation process in terms of parameterized operations applied to the words in the reuse instance in order to obtain the original words. These operations use linguistic re- sources, such as lemma lists of classical Greek and Biblical Koine, and a synset database. For each trans- formation, we create the set of operations necessary to transform the reuse instance to its original.  <ref type="bibr">3</ref> and the Septuaginta (LXX), a translation of the Old Testament (Rahlfs, 1935a) 4 from the Center for Computer Analysis of Texts at UPenn. We acknowledge code-page cor- rections by M. Munson. SBLGNT&amp;LXX provide 59,510 word-lemma-pairs. We use AGWN ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Bizzoni et al., 2014</ref>), which also contains Latin WordNet <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">(Minozzi, 2009)</ref>, to identify synsets (sets of synonyms) as well as hyperonyms, hyponyms, and co-hyponyms. From the wordnets' 98,950 synsets 33,910 synsets contain Ancient Greek and 27,126 synsets contain Latin words. Coverage. <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">Table 1</ref> shows the coverage of each re- source for our datasets. In the lower part of it we merge all lemma resources into one set of word- lemma pairs. The table shows that CLTK covers the Bible data better than the Hellenistic Greek as used in Clement of Alexandria, an author from 2nd century AD, writing in an archaic style with Biblical vocabulary, while also being influenced by Classi- cal Greek. We also check the coverage of lemmata stemming from the same source (Biblindex) as our reuse. To increase the coverage for Greek, we consult SBLGNT&amp;LXX, which in fact increases it. To not miss important information, we integrate all of the resources' data into our approach. For every lemma of a word we check the semantic relations in AGWN. We experimented with different ways of looking up lemmas and found that lower-casing all Latin tokens improved the success. For Greek, it had the opposite effect, which indicates that the Greek text contains more entities that are not available in lowercase in the lemma lists, so we did not change in that case. <ref type="bibr">5</ref> Operations and Classification. We define replace- ment operations using words and PoS as parame- ters, to transform a reuse instance back into the Bible verse it originates from. <ref type="table">Table 2</ref> lists the op- erations for the computational approach. We in- troduce the operations NOPmorph, repl pos, and repl case for words having the same cognate, and lemma missing(reuse word) when a word is not 4 CATSS LXX is prepared by the Thesaurus Linguae Grae- cae project directed by T. Brunner at UC Irvine, with further verification and adaptation by CATSS towards conformity with the individual Göttingen editions which appeared since 1935. LXXM is morphologically analyzed text of CATSS LXX pre- pared by CATSS led by R. Kraft (Philadelphia team) <ref type="bibr">5</ref> Often, the decision on whether to represent a word in upper or lower case letters is made by the editor, thus, our decision is affected by the edition we use for our research. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>NOP(reuse word, orig word)</head><p>Original and reuse word are equal.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>NOP(maledictus,maledictus) upper(reuse word, orig word)</head><p>Word is lowercase in reuse and uppercase in original.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>upper(kai,Kai) -in Greek lower(reuse word, orig word)</head><p>Word is uppercase in reuse and lowercase in original.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>lower(Gloriam,gloriam) lem(reuse word, orig word)</head><p>Lemmatization leads to equality of reuse and original. lem(penetrat,penetrabit) repl syn(reuse word, orig word)</p><p>Reuse word replaced with a synonym to match original word. repl syn(magnificavit,glorificavit) repl hyper(reuse word, orig word) Word in bible verse is a hyperonym of the reused word. hyper(cupit,habens) repl hypo(reuse word, orig word) Word in bible verse is a hyponym of the reused word. hypo(dederit,tollet) repl co-hypo(reuse word, orig word)</p><p>Reused word and original have the same hyperonym. repl co-hypo(magnificavit,fecit)</p><p>NOPmorph(reuse tags, orig tags) Case or PoS did not change between reused and original word. NOPmorph(na,na) repl pos(reuse tag, orig tag)</p><p>Reuse and original contain the same cognate, but PoS changed. repl pos(n,a) repl case(reuse tag, orig tag)</p><p>Reuse and original have the same cognate, but the case changed repl case(g,d) -cases genitive, dative lemma missing(reuse word, orig word) Lemma unknown for reuse or original word lemma missing(tentari, inlectus) no rel found(reuse wword, orig word)</p><p>Relation for reuse or original word not found in AGWN no rel found(gloria,arguitur) <ref type="table">Table 2</ref>: Operation list for the automated approach known to any of our lemma resources as well as no rel found(reuse word, orig word) when the rela- tionship between a reuse word and each potential word from the original is not covered by AGWN. Algorithm 1 shows our approach to classify the reuse transformation by identifying the operations. For each reuse token, we identify the first applicable operation matching the foremost Bible verse word (it- erating the verse) in the following order: exact word match (NOP: no operation), case changed to upper or lower. Thereafter, we look up the lemma and re- turn lem if the lemma of the reused word matches the lemma of the original. For these four, we also check the morphology, in addition returning whether the original has the same PoS and case (NOPmorph) or whether PoS changed (repl pos), case changed (repl case), or both. So up to three operations can be returned per word. Finally, we check for synonyms (repl syn), hyperonyms (hyper), hyponyms (hypo), and co-hyponyms (repl co-hypo), but do not check morphology. If a Bible verse word is used as a match, it is not used again for any other word from the reuse.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.5">Qualitative Approach</head><p>To obtain a deeper understanding of the limitations of linguistic resources for our purpose, two graduate stu- dents (one Latinist, one Classical Archeologist) man- ually analyze 100 Greek and 60 Latin reuse instances with their expert knowledge, using an extended set of operations. It comprises ins(word) (insert a word) and del(word) (delete a word)-two operations we ig- nore in the automated approach where we focuse on the coverage of the resources. It also has a richer set of replacement operations: those from the upper part of <ref type="table">Table 2</ref> (without upper and lower), and instead of only using repl case when a cognate stays the same, we refine it and assign all changing morphological categories from Perseus' tag set for any "relativeness" between two words (e.g., repl case a g).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Results</head><p>We now present the results for our research questions in Sec. 4.1-4.3, which are summarized and further interpreted in Sec. 4.4.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">Literal Share of the Reuse (RQ1)</head><p>We obtain a first understanding of the reuse by look- ing at the percentage of overlapping words between reuse instance and original Bible verse. We measure the longest common substring based on word tokens. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Fig. 2</ref> shows the distributions, distinguishing between a lemmatized and non-lemmatized word comparison.</p><p>While lemmatizing words before comparison has only a small impact, we observe differences between the datasets. In our Latin dataset, the overlap is sig- nificantly higher than in the Greek dataset Sec. 3.2. 25 % (upper quartile) of Bernard's reuse instances have 50 % or more tokens overlap with their original, which is only the case for less than 25 % in Clement's Greek data. Still, large overlaps of up to 75 % (top non-lem. lem. non-lem. lem.  whisker) in our Greek and up to around 90 % in our Latin dataset exist-so a small fraction of the reuse contains literal parts Sec. 3.2.</p><p>For a more precise understanding of the literalness, we group operations into literal (NOP, upper, lower, lem), non-literal (repl syn, repl hyper, repl hypo, repl co-hypo), and unclassified (no rel found and lemma missing). Within each reuse instance, we cal- culate their relative occurrence using the results of the automated approach (explained shortly). <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Fig. 3</ref> shows the distribution of these relative occurrences for all reuse instances. It confirms <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Fig. 2</ref> by show- ing a higher rate of literalness for Latin compared to Greek. In summary, it also shows that the Latin reuse can be better classified by our approach, which takes the lemma lists and AGWN into account. <ref type="table" target="#tab_7">Table 3</ref> shows the total number of operations identi- fied for the transformation from reuse instances to the Greek and Latin originals. For 987 (45 %) out of 2189 words in the Greek instances and for 893 (67 %) out of 1335 words in the Latin instances, we were able to identify at least one operation, which already indicates to what extent the resources are helpful.    length without a particular trend in both datasets. We only encounter a frequent use of upper at the first position in Latin, which means that Bernard often starts his Biblical references with literal Bible words.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">Automated Approach (RQ2.1)</head><p>After having checked the overall coverage of the linguistic resources for all tokens (cf. Sec. 3.4), we now specifically investigate to what extent the resources support identifying the reuse transforma- tion for the non-literal reuse using our approach. We introduce the measures sup lem and sup AGWN to calculate how often looking up a lemma or subsequently a synset element was successful. This is easy based on our operations. Let Occ(o) be the number of occurrences of an operation o, obtained from <ref type="table" target="#tab_7">Table 3</ref>. The operations that successfully looked up a lemma (before consulting AGWN) are lem success={lem, syn, repl hyper, repl hypo, repl co-hypo, no rel found}. Now recall that lem missing represents the case when a reuse token was not found in the lemma resources. Then sup lem = Occ(o) o∈lem success Occ(o) o∈lem success∪{lem missing} . We obtain a sup lem of 0.65 for the Greek reuse and 0.88 for the Latin reuse. Similarly, the operations that success- fully looked up from AGWN are agwn success={syn, operation</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Greek</head><p>Latin operation Greek Latin repl syn 78 (40.6%) 91 (40.4%) repl gender 6 (3.1%) 1 (0.4%) repl ant 1 (0.5%) 0 repl mood 11 (5.7%) 12 (5.3%) repl hyper 3 (1.6%) 0 repl number 17 (8.9%) 17 (7.6%) repl hypo 11 (5.7%) 0 repl person 5 (2.6%) 14 (6.2%) lem 1 (0.5%) 2 (0.9%) repl pos 18 (9.4%) 33 (14.7%) repl co-hypo 0 1 (0.4%) repl tense 3 (1.6%) 9 (4.0%) repl case 38 (19.8%) 36 (16%) repl voice 0 8 (3.6%) These values can be interpreted as follows. The lemma resources for genre-and time-specific text work well for less-literal reuse, but the resources for semantic relationships (synset databases) show a lack of support and need further development.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3">Qualitative Approach (RQ2.2)</head><p>We manually identify the transformation operations for 60 reuse instances of the Ancient Greek data and for 100 of the Latin data. Here, NOPs cover 9.3 %, insertions 49.8 %, and deletions cover 30.5 % in the Greek data. NOPs cover 26.1 %, insertions 49.7 %, and deletions 11.9 % in the Latin data. <ref type="table" target="#tab_8">Table 4</ref> shows the ratios of the various repl oper- ations based on the remaining 10.4 % and 12.2 %. Similar to the automated approach, we observe a strong use of synonyms and other semantic-level op- erations, and also a certain portion of switching mor- phological categories, which indicates para-phrasal reuse. In the Greek data, PoS changes cover about 9%, out of which a participle became a verb (7 times) and vice-versa (5 times). In our Latin data, PoS changes represent 15% of replacements: often a pro- noun changed to a noun (6 times) and a participle became a verb (12 times). Case changes are shown in <ref type="table">Table 5</ref>. Significantly often, an ablative became an accusative, because often changing prepositions expect different cases, or an accusative was replaced by an ablative or nominative, because para-phrasal expression changed.</p><p>We encounter exceptions that prevent applying the operations. In the Greek data, one word is replaced operation Greek Latin operation Greek Latin repl case a b 0 6 repl case g a 5 2 repl case a n 9 4 repl case g n 4 2 repl case b a 0 10 repl case n a <ref type="table" target="#tab_7">7  5  repl case d a  0  2 repl case n d  3  0  repl case d g  3  0 repl case v g  0  2  repl case d n  5  0   Table 5</ref>: Numbers of case replacements with its antonym 6 ; once, a synonym also changes its PoS. Four times, more than one morphological cate- gory changes, twice an auxiliary is deleted, and five times inserted. We find one writing variance (lem), and three times a synonym is replaced by a multi- word expression. In the Latin data, in 16 cases a synonym is replaced and morphological information changed. Seven times, more than one morphological parameter changes for the same cognate. Eight times, an auxiliary is inserted or deleted, and twice, a writ- ing variance is encountered. A synonym is replaced by more than one word five times. In one case, a reuse is too paraphrasal for any word to match se- mantic relationships (e.g., judged calmly-Bernard vs. fake friend -Sal 12 18).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.4">Summary and Discussion</head><p>RQ1. The reuse is significantly non-literal and only lemmatizing words does not help discovering it. Our results show that reuse in two substantial histor- ical texts requires techniques beyond simple pre- processing (e.g., stemming or lemmatizing), which explains why plagiarism-detection systems fail when paraphrases are used ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Alzahrani et al., 2012</ref>  The manually identified exceptions show that finding a connection between original verse and reuse can be difficult when there is only a vague semantic one. RQ2.2. Our results show that the automated ap- proach cannot capture the richness of the manual approach. Especially from the exceptions, it is clear that less-literal reuse does not only need information from a word's semantic environment, but also that it needs to be identified by looser relations, such as co-hyponyms, multi-to-multi-word associations or implicit meanings, which can be hidden in structural or more broader expert knowledge.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Threats to Validity</head><p>External Validity. We enhance the external valid- ity of our work by focusing on Bible verses-one of the oldest, most conveyed, and cited sources of Ancient Greek, offering a vast amount of primary source text and also coming with a long history of scholars studying it. Clement of Alexandria is known for his retelling of biblical excerpts <ref type="bibr">(Clemens, 1905</ref><ref type="bibr">(Clemens, 1909</ref><ref type="bibr">Freppel, 1865)</ref>, providing an interesting base for reuse investigation. The french abbot <ref type="bibr">Bernard of Clairvaux (Smith, 2010</ref>) is equally known for his influence to the Cistercian order and his work in biblical studies. Furthermore, the chosen lemma re- sources are the most extensive ones existing for An- cient Greek and Latin. We chose the AGWN, since it is freely available, offering one of the largest synset database for Ancient Greek and Latin. Internal Validity. A threat is that our ground truth has mistakes, as the PoS tagging was done by one author only and relied on a manual post-correction. The selection criteria in Sec. 3.2 were chosen to en- sure quality and comparability. Extreme outliers in the length of the reuse instance or source (multiple Bible verses) are cut-off. For Greek, 33 are cut-off, as opposed to Latin, where our sample is significantly smaller than the whole population that we have. To automatically check whether the sample has similar characteristics with respect to the literal reuse, we create <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">Fig. 5</ref>. It shows the overlap of the whole 1128 instances of Bernard's extracted reuse, which when compared to <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Fig. 2</ref> (right) supports the representa- tiveness of our sample. Last, we can only derive operation replacements when a word token was cov- ered by the lemma sources, contained in AGWN, and when there actually exists a relation between two words. Also, our authors' vocabulary can differ in terms of domain knowledge, personal idiolect, and age of the Biblical vocabulary.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Conclusion</head><p>We presented a study of historical-and mostly non- literal-text reuse. We automatically and manually characterize the reuse and identify to what extent ex- isting linguistic resources are able to cover non-literal text reuse. Our results show the potential as well as the necessity to develop robust techniques and to ex- tend linguistic resources for analyzing and detecting such reuse. Our results can help to enhance para- phrase generation to model automatic ways on how small text portions can be rephrased. Considering the effects of syntactic rearrangement of reuse can also support such efforts. A smarter automated approach for deriving an original text excerpt would be learn- ing so-called edit scripts <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">(Kehrer, 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Chawathe et al., 1996)</ref>, which more precisely identify opera- tions an author performed on a text to transform it into another version. Whether learning edit scripts on such intricate transformations is possible is an open question and valuable future research. Finally, analyzing further languages and data sets helps to further complete our findings.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2: Ratios of literal overlaps between reuse instance and original (left: Greek, right: Latin)</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Figure 3: Ratios of unclassified, literal, and non-literal words in reuse instances (left: Greek, right: Latin)</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>Fig. 4</head><label>4</label><figDesc>visualizes the distribution of the frequencies (y-axis) of each operation (x-axis) together with the distribution of the operations' positions in the reuse instances (z-axis). The latter is calculated as the rela- tive position p ∈ [0..1] of an operation with respect to the length of the reuse instance. It indicates that most operation types are distributed over the whole reuse NOP upper lower lem syn hyper hypo co-hypo</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head>Figure 4 :</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Figure 4: Occurrence of operations in reuse instances. X-axis: operations; Y-axis: relative position within reuse instances. Z-axis: natural logarithm of number of operations. Values are smoothed by spline interpolation. The order of operations is arbitrary.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><head>Figure 5 :</head><label>5</label><figDesc>Figure 5: Ratios of literal overlaps in the whole Latin dataset approach, but only for about one third of the lookups. The manually identified exceptions show that finding a connection between original verse and reuse can be difficult when there is only a vague semantic one. RQ2.2. Our results show that the automated approach cannot capture the richness of the manual approach. Especially from the exceptions, it is clear that less-literal reuse does not only need information from a word's semantic environment, but also that it needs to be identified by looser relations, such as co-hyponyms, multi-to-multi-word associations or implicit meanings, which can be hidden in structural or more broader expert knowledge.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" validated="false"><head>1335</head><label>1335</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Biblindex 
Greek Bible 4 
752 
103 58 
67 
58 
4776 
Clement 5 
455 
54 
24 
33 
24 
2189 
Latin Bible 4 
2473 
1365 1057 1023 1057 
2618 
Bernard 5 
1219 
701 531 
520 
531 
1335 

SBLGNT 

&amp; LXX 

Greek Bible 4 
4718 
3385 2616 2092 2616 
4776 
Clement 5 
1297 
824 582 
421 
582 
2189 
Latin Bible 4,6 </table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4" validated="false"><head>Table 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Coverage of tokens by language resources 

racy (</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_7" validated="false"><head>Table 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Absolute numbers of operations identified 
automatically 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_8" validated="false"><head>Table 4 :</head><label>4</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Numbers of replacement operations identi-
fied for the manual reuse transformation. 

repl hyper, repl hypo, repl co-hypo}, with 
no rel found representing a failed lookup. Then: 

sup AGWN = 


Occ(o) o∈agwn success 


Occ(o) o∈agwn success∪{no rel found} . We 
obtain sup AGWN of 0.34 for Greek and 0.33 for Latin. 
</table></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> https://bitbucket.org/mariamoritz/emnlp</note>

			<note place="foot" n="2"> http://nlp.perseus.tufts.edu/syntax/ treebank/agdt/1.7/docs/README.txt</note>

			<note place="foot" n="3"> Logos Bible Software, Sbl new testament, 2014 http: //sblgnt.com/about/</note>

			<note place="foot" n="6"> Translation: &quot;the God, the good (one)&quot; (Clement) vs. &quot;none is good but the God&quot; (Bible).</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>We thank Laurence Mellerin for providing the datasets we used, and for valuable advice on its con-tent. Our work is funded by the German Federal Min-istry of Education and Research (grant 01UG1509).</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Word Sense Disambiguation-Algorithms and Applications</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Eneko</forename><surname>Edmonds2007</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Philip</forename><surname>Agirre</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Edmonds</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">The Greek New Testament. Deutsche Bibelgesellschaft-United Bible Societies</title>
		<editor>Aland and Aland1966] Kurt Aland and Barbara Aland</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Netherlands</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1966" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>27 edition</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Bamman and Crane2011a] David Bamman and Gregory Crane. 2011a. The ancient greek and latin dependency treebanks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">[</forename><surname>Alzahrani</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Eds) Language technology for cultural heritage: Selected papers from the LaTeCH Workshop Series</title>
		<editor>Caroline Sporleder, Antal van den Bosch, &amp; Kalliopi Zervanou</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Marrakech Morocco. LREC; Berlin, Germany</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer-Verlag</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">42</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="79" to="98" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>LaTeCH (Language Technology for Cultural Heritage Data)</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Measuring historical word sense variation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Crane2011b] David</forename><surname>Bamman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gregory</forename><surname>Bamman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Crane</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>Barrón-Cedeño et al.2013</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 11th ACM/IEEE-CS Joint Conference on Digital libraries (JCDL 2011)</title>
		<meeting>the 11th ACM/IEEE-CS Joint Conference on Digital libraries (JCDL 2011)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="10" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>ACM Digital Library</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Plagiarism meets paraphrasing: Insights for the next generation in automatic plagiarism detection</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marta</forename><surname>Vila</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">Antònia</forename><surname>Martí</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Paolo</forename><surname>Rosso</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">FIRE 2015 Working Notes Papers</title>
		<editor>Bensalem et al.2015] Imene Bensalem, Imene Boukhalfa, Paolo Rosso, Lahsen Abouenour, Kareem Darwish, and Salim Chikhi</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">39</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="4" to="6" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Overview of the AraPlagDet PAN@FIRE2015 Shared Task on Arabic Plagiarism Detection</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The making of ancient greek wordnet</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>December</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Gandhinagar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>India</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>December</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Bizzoni</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Ninth International Conference on Language Resources and Evaluation (LREC&apos;14)</title>
		<meeting>the Ninth International Conference on Language Resources and Evaluation (LREC&apos;14)<address><addrLine>Reykjavik, Iceland</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>European Language Resources Association (ELRA</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Increasing recall for text re-use in historical documents to support research in the humanities</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">[</forename><surname>Büchler</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Theory and Practice of Digital Libraries</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Berlin Heidelberg</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">7489</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="95" to="100" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Informationstechnische Aspekte des Historical Text Re-use (English: Computational Aspects of Historical Text Re-use</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marco</forename><surname>Büchler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Anand</forename><surname>Sudarshan S Chawathe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hector</forename><surname>Rajaraman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jennifer</forename><surname>Garcia-Molina</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Widom</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ACM SIGMOD Record</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Germany</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Titus Flavius Clemens</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1909" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">25</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1905" to="1909" />
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>Leipzig University</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
<note type="report_type">Ph.D. thesis</note>
	<note>Change detection in hierarchically structured information</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Werke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<editor>Otto Stählin, editor, Die Griechischen Christlichen Schrifteller</editor>
		<imprint>
			<pubPlace>Berlin</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>in greek. v. 12, 15, 27. Leipzig. Clément d&apos;Alexandrie2011] Clément d&apos;Alexandrie, 2011. Quel riche peut-ˆ etre sauvé. ´ editions du Cerf, Paris, sources chrtiennes 537 edition</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The Text of the Gospels in Clement of Alexandria. New Testament in the Greek Fathers. Society of Biblical Literature</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Carl</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Cosaert</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Perseus digital library</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gregory</forename><surname>Crane</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://www.perseus.tufts.edu/hopper/" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1985" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Generating and parsing classical greek. Literary and Linguistic Computing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gregory</forename><surname>Crane</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1991" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="243" to="245" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Automatically constructing a corpus of sentential paraphrases</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Brockett2005] Bill</forename><surname>Dolan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chris</forename><surname>Dolan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Brockett</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Third International Workshop on Paraphrasing (IWP2005). Asia Federation of Natural Language Processing</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Association for Computational Linguistics. [Geyken and Gloning2014] Alexander Geyken and Thomas Gloning. 2014. A living text archive of 15th-19th century german: Corpus strategies, technology, organization</title>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Corpus Linguistics and Interdisciplinary Perspectives on Language-CLIP. Narr Tbingen</title>
		<editor>Charles-Emile Freppel. 1865. Clement d&apos;Alexandrie. [Ganitkevitch et al.2013] Juri Ganitkevitch, Benjamin Van Durme, and Chris Callison-Burch</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Atlanta, Georgia</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="758" to="764" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Proceedings of NAACL-HLT</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Patristic evidence in the new edition of the vetus latina iohannes</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">A G</forename><surname>Houghton</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Biblical Quotations in Patristic Texts</title>
		<editor>L. Mellerin and H.A.G. Houghton</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Leuven</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Peeters</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">54</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="69" to="85" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The use of the latin fathers for new testament textual criticism</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">A G</forename><surname>Houghton</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">The Text of the New Testament in Contemporary Research. Essays on the Status Quaestionis second edition. NTTSD</title>
		<editor>B.D. Ehrman and M.W. Holmes</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Leiden</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Brill</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="375" to="405" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Usage of wordnet in natural language generation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hongyan</forename><surname>Jing</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Workshop on Usage of WordNet in Natural Language Processing Systems (COLING-ACL&apos;98). Columbia University Academic Commons</title>
		<meeting>the Workshop on Usage of WordNet in Natural Language Processing Systems (COLING-ACL&apos;98). Columbia University Academic Commons</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Johnson</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https" />
		<title level="m">Cltk: The classical language toolkit</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="20142016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="doi">10.5281/zen-odo.44555v0.1.32</idno>
		<ptr target="//github.com/cltk/cltk.DOI10.5281/zen-odo.44555v0.1.32" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Generierung konsistenzerhaltender editierskripte im kontext der modellversionierung</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Timo</forename><surname>Kehrer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Fachtagung des GI-Fachbereichs Softwaretechnik, 25. Februar-28. Februar</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Kiel, Deutschland</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>GI</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">227</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="57" to="58" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Wilhelm Hasselbring and Nils Christian Ehmke</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Generating phrasal and sentential paraphrases: A survey of data-driven methods</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">John</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nitin</forename><surname>Madnani</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bonnie</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Dorr</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 45th Annual Meeting of the Association of Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the 45th Annual Meeting of the Association of Computational Linguistics<address><addrLine>Prague, Czech Republic</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">36</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="341" to="387" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>A computational model of text reuse in ancient literary texts</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">New ways of searching with biblindex, the online index of biblical quotations in early christian literature</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Laurence</forename><surname>Mellerin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Digital Humanities in Biblical, Early Jewish and Early Christian Studies</title>
		<editor>Claire Clivaz, Andrew Gregory, and David Hamidovic</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Leiden</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Brill</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="175" to="192" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Laurence</forename><surname>Mellerin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://www.biblindex.mom.fr/" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Introduction to wordnet: An on-line lexical database</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">[</forename><surname>Miller</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">International Journal of Lexicography (special issue)</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="235" to="312" />
			<date type="published" when="1990" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Innsbrucker Beitrge zur Sprachwissenschaft</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Stefano</forename><surname>Minozzi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">chapter The Latin WordNet Project</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Innsbruck</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">137</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="707" to="716" />
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>Institut fr Sprachen und Literaturen der Universitt Innsbruck</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Maria</forename><surname>Pantelia</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://stephanus.tlg.uci.edu/index.php" />
		<title level="m">Computational Linguistics and Intelligent Text Processing: 4th International Conference (CICLing), chapter Using Measures of Semantic Relatedness for Word Sense Disambiguation</title>
		<editor>Siddharth Patwardhan, Satanjeev Banerjee, and Ted Pedersen</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Berlin Heidelberg; Berlin, Heidelberg</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="241" to="257" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Thesaurus linguae graecae</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Natural Language Processing for Historical Texts (Synthesis Lectures on Human Language Technologies)</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Piotrowski</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<publisher>Morgan &amp; Claypool Publishers</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<monogr>
				<title level="m">editor. 1935a. Septuaginta. Württembergische Bibelanstalt</title>
		<editor>Alfred Rahlfs</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1971" />
			<biblScope unit="page">9</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Septuaginta, id est Vetus Testamentum Graece juxta LXX interpretes</title>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Rahlfs</title>
		<editor>Alfred Rahlfs</editor>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1935" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Catholic Church Milestones: People and Events That Shaped the Institutional Church</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">William</forename><surname>Smith</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Indianapolis: Left Coast</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Lexicon-assisted tagging and lemmatization in latin: A comparison of six taggers and two lemmatization models</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Vinzent</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Joint Conference of the 47th Annual Meeting of the ACL and the 4th International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing of the AFNLP</title>
		<editor>Zhao et al.2009] Shiqi Zhao, Xiang Lan, Ting Liu, and Sheng Li</editor>
		<meeting>the Joint Conference of the 47th Annual Meeting of the ACL and the 4th International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing of the AFNLP<address><addrLine>Beijing, China; Stroudsburg, PA, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1969" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="834" to="842" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>ACL &apos;09</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Natural language processing of semitic languages</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Imed</forename><surname>Zitouni</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
