<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T12:14+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Assessing Objective Recommendation Quality through Political Forecasting</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
				<availability status="unknown"><p>Copyright Association for Computational Linguistics</p>
				</availability>
				<date>September 7-11, 2017. 2017</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Andrew Schwartz</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Stony Brook University ‡ Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">University of Pennsylvania Computer &amp; Information Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit3">University of Pennsylvania</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Masoud</forename><surname>Rouhizadeh</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Stony Brook University ‡ Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">University of Pennsylvania Computer &amp; Information Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit3">University of Pennsylvania</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Bishop</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Stony Brook University ‡ Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">University of Pennsylvania Computer &amp; Information Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit3">University of Pennsylvania</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Philip</forename><surname>Tetlock</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Stony Brook University ‡ Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">University of Pennsylvania Computer &amp; Information Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit3">University of Pennsylvania</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Barbara</forename><surname>Mellers</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Stony Brook University ‡ Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">University of Pennsylvania Computer &amp; Information Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit3">University of Pennsylvania</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lyle</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Ungar</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Stony Brook University ‡ Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">University of Pennsylvania Computer &amp; Information Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit3">University of Pennsylvania</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Assessing Objective Recommendation Quality through Political Forecasting</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Natural Language Processing</title>
						<meeting> <address><addrLine>Copenhagen, Denmark</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="2348" to="2357"/>
							<date type="published">September 7-11, 2017. 2017</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Recommendations are often rated for their subjective quality, but few researchers have studied quality in terms of objective utility. We explore quality assessment with respect to both subjective (i.e. users&apos; ratings) and objective (i.e., did it in-fluence? did it improve decisions?) met-rics in a massive online geopolitical forecasting system, ultimately comparing linguistic characteristics of each quality metric. Using a variety of features, we predict all types of quality with better accuracy than the simple yet strong baseline of recommendation length. For example, more complex sentence constructions, as evi-denced by subordinate conjunctions, are characteristic of recommendations leading to objective improvements in forecasting. Our analyses also reveal rater biases; for example, forecasters are subjectively biased in favor of recommendations mentioning business deals and material things, even though such recommendations do not indeed prove any more useful objectively.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Finding good recommendations is an integral part of a modern information-seeking life -from pur- chasing products based on reviews to finding an- swers to baffling questions. Following the tradi- tion of sentiment analysis, many have proposed methods to automatically assess the quality of rec- ommendations or comments based on subjective ratings of their usefulness ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">Liu et al., 2007;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b27">Siersdorfer et al., 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Becker et al., 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Momeni et al., 2013</ref>) or of persuasiveness ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">Wei et al., 2016)</ref>. However, information thought to be useful does not always prove so, and subjective ratings may be driven by biases. Reviews which convince you to watch a movie or buy a product do not guarantee that you will enjoy the product, and the most con- vincing or highest rated answers to questions on sites like Stack Overflow or Yahoo Answers are not always the most accurate.</p><p>We explore recommendations in a unique dataset, an online forecasting competition, which offers a rare glimpse into both subjective and ob- jective quality. In this competition, the users (forecasters) had a measurable goal -to fore- cast the outcomes of geopolitical events -and a need to effectively gather information in order to reach this goal. They viewed recommendations (or "tips") from other forecasters, rated them, and po- tentially updated their own forecast. This data not only allows us to access what information the fore- casters thought useful based on their ratings, but also what was objectively useful based on (a) the rate at which forecasters change their prediction after viewing tips and, (b) the average improve- ment (or decrease) in their prediction accuracy af- ter this change.</p><p>We seek to tease out subjective biases by dis- tinguishing the linguistic characteristics of rec- ommendations with high subjective ratings from those of objective utility. Since objectively good recommendations tend to get higher subjective assessments, detecting such differences is non- trivial. Past literature has suggested that sub- jective quality is well predicted by comment length ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Beygelzimer et al., 2015)</ref>; We seek differences beyond this. We build quality predictive models from linguistic features of recommendations -1 to 3 word sequences, parts-of-speech, and mentions of concepts from a taxonomy -comparing to surface-level features (length and readability). We then explore the lan- guage which distinguishes high quality comments from low quality, controlling for comment length, and ultimately what distinguishes high subjective quality from objective quality in order to reveal subjective biases.</p><p>Contributions. We see the key contribution of this paper, perhaps non-conventional for NLP, as presenting an evidence-based suggestion for the field to consider metrics of objective quality be- yond that of subjective ratings. To the best of our knowledge this represents the first study of objective comment quality using randomized ex- perimental data. Specific novel contributions in- clude (a) the development of automated assess- ments fit to objective outcomes, (b) the identifi- cation of linguistic features distinguishing high- from low-quality comments, (c) the use of a new, important, real-world domain for NLP -geopo- litical information, and (d), most consequentially, the identification of subjective biases manifested in the comments' text itself.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Data Set</head><p>Data were collected from the massive online geopolitical forecasting system (MOOF) de- scribed by <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">Mellers et al. (Mellers et al., 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Atanasov et al., 2016)</ref>. Forecasters completed tasks where they indicated the probability of dis- crete outcomes for specific future geopolitical events around the world. For example, forecasters might be asked to forecast the likelihood of a coup in Venezuela within the next 12 months. Respon- dents indicated a probability for the event and, af- ter the event resolved, they received a score <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Brier, 1950</ref>) based on how close their probability re- flected the outcome of the event. <ref type="bibr">1</ref> Recommendations generated from a another parallel forecasting system were presented as "tips". In the parallel system, the recommendation writers were asked "Why did you answer the way you did?" when making forecasts, and were given the option to mark their response as potentially being useful to others. Comments marked useful from the parallel system were then presented as tips within the main MOOF system, where they were evaluated for their subjective and objective usefulness. Below is an example of one such com- ment:</p><p>Predicting the foreign ministers will meet and state something along the lines of "hoping for a summit at the appropri- ate time." ... Predict this because of the cautious language here and elsewhere: http://www.china.org.cn/wap/2015- 03/13/... If wrong, will have time to redress the damage done before any possible summit.</p><p>The above forecaster identifies a reason for their decision, a source of information (a Chinese news website), and even a contingency plan if their rea- soning doesn't seem to be planning out. <ref type="figure">Fig- ure 1</ref> shows a representative screen shot from the MOOF system.</p><p>We focus on one subjective and two objective quality metrics for these recommendations: rating: subjective ratings on a 5-point scale by the forecasters in the parallel system. influence: the rate at which MOOF forecasters up- date their predictions after reading the comment. benefit: the mean change in MOOF forecaster ac- curacy resulting from updating their predictions after rating the comment. Because there were nu- merous confounding factors regarding the magni- tude of change (i.e. forecaster quality, time un- til task resolution), we simply encoded the change as a binary indicator of whether it was positive or negative.</p><p>For the purposes of this study, we consider both influence and benefit as assessments of objective utility, though they each capture different aspects of utility (behavioral influence of others in the case of influence; and specifically positive influence in the case of benefit). The MOOF forecasters did not know who wrote the tip or any other infor- mation about it; their actions were based on the comment's content and not reputation of the com- ment author. MOOF forecasters were also linked directly to the form to update their forecast from the comment to minimize outside influences be- tween the reading of the comment and prediction update. However, as the forecasters were not in a laboratory, other Web browsing behavior in other tabs could not be controlled.</p><p>In order to balance quality score reliability with quantity of recommendation data, we restricted the dataset to recommendations with at least 10 words that received at least 3 ratings. This re- sulted in 8, 498 comments with ratings and influ- ence scores. Out of those, 4, 317 comments had at <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref>: Screenshot of the forecasting system prompting users to justify their forecasts with recommen- dations. These recommendations are then passed on to the parallel MOOF system as "tips" which are rated and sometimes lead forecasters to change their predictions.</p><p>rating v rating v influence v influence benefit benefit .45* .01 .06* <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>: Correlation (Pearson product-moment coefficient) between all subjective and objective quality metrics: rating: forecaster subjective rat- ing, influence: forecaster update rate, benefit: change in forecast accuracy due to update. *sig- nificant at p &lt; .01.</p><p>least one associated change in forecast, and thus had a score for the final metric, benefit. <ref type="table">Table 1</ref> shows correlations (Pearson product- moment coefficients) between all subjective and objective quality metrics. Rating and influence are fairly predictive of each other (r = 0.45, p &lt; 0.01), and neither correlates particularly strongly with benefit. (r = 0.01, p &gt; .01 for rating v bene- fit, and r = 0.06, p &lt; .01 for influence v benefit). This implies that while comments rated for subjec- tive utility are also more likely to influence users, they are not necessary influencing them in a pos- itive way. Further, it is possible (and indeed the case) that the characteristics of comments deemed subjectively useful may differ from those that ob- jectively provide benefit. In Section 4 we consider the content that leads to these differences in the metrics.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Regression</head><p>Our goal is to predict the quality score of a com- ment from its content over each of the three qual- ity metrics: rating, influence, and benefit. These 3 types of features were chosen in order to ac- count for qualitatively different types of linguistic attributes. To capture linguistic variance at vary- ing resolutions, we use a combination of open- vocabulary and taxonomic linguistic features: ngrams: 1 to 3 word sequences. These ngrams were recorded as binary variables indicating whether each ngram appeared in each comment. We limited ngrams to those mentioned in at least 0.1% of all comments. parts-of-speech: POS frequences The Stanford Part-of-Speech tagger was used to identify parts of speech in each comment. The relative frequency of each tag (i.e., the probability of the tag, given the comment) was recorded. concepts: Nominal concepts within a hierarchy. The WordNet noun ontology <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Fellbaum, 1998)</ref> was used. For each comment, we tracked all of the hypernyms of each noun within the comment. As features per comment, we use the presence of each hypernym concept, limited to those concepts that appeared in at least 0.1% of all comments.</p><p>To control for task-specific language, features (n-grams) were restricted to those mentioned in at least 50% of forecasting tasks. The n-grams, in- tended to capture fine-grained lexical information, were also restricted to those mentioned in at least 1% of comments, while the parts-of-speech and concepts, intended to capture more coarse-grained linguistic characteristics, were restricted to those appearing in 5% of comments. These thresholds were chosen such that total number of features was within the same order of magnitude as the number of recommendations with objective scores In the end, there were 1, 202 unique n-grams, 32 unique parts-of-speech, and 155 unique concepts.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Predictive Modeling</head><p>We built predictive models of all three quality met- rics based on the linguistic features of the mes- sages. To handle covariance and avoid over-fitting with so many features, we used a series of feature selection and dimensionality reduction techniques fed into a ridge regression to create the models. Specifically, we filtered the features (which were already restricted to those present in at least 50% of the forecasting tasks) to those with a small lin- ear correlation with the outcome, defined as hav- ing a family-wise error rate &lt; 60 <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">(Toothaker, 1993)</ref>. This feature selection was run indepen- dently on each type of feature (n-grams, parts-of- speech, and concepts). Similar to correcting for multiple hypothesis tests, family-wise error pe- nalizes groups containing more features (i.e. n- grams) more stringently.</p><p>We then used randomized singular value de- composition (SVD) <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(Halko et al., 2011</ref>) to reduce the feature set to 1 / 5 the number of original fea- tures. Randomized SVD uses stochastic sampling to more efficiently calculate the principal com- ponents ).In this context, SVD functions as a type of regularization to re- duce variance by removing lesser principal com- ponents (and thus helping to avoid overfit). Fi- nally, the resulting dimensions were fit to the given quality metric using L2 penalized linear regres- sion. All feature selection, dimensionality reduc- tion, and L2 parameter tuning were done over a held-out portion of the training set.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Evaluation</head><p>To evaluate our models out-of-sample, we use 10- fold cross-validation over the subjective ratings (rating) and update rates (influence). In this pro- cess, a random selection of 1/10th of the com- ments are held-out as a test set, while the other 9/10ths are used to train (estimate) the model. This model is then used to predict the quality of the rating influence benefit baseline .59 .24 .02</p><p>our model .76* .37 .21* <ref type="table">Table 2</ref>: Predictive accuracy (out-of-sample Pear- son correlation coefficient) of our content-based models across the subjective and objective mea- sures. baseline: square-root number of words; our model: based on ngrams, parts-of-speech, and concepts. *significant reduction in error over the baseline at p &lt; .001.</p><p>comments in the 1/10th sample and compared to the true quality for those comments (using Pear- son correlation in this case). However, many of our scores for change in forecaster accuracy (ben- efit) are based simply on one change and thus quite unreliable. While it is best to include such noisy data when training, it does not provide a very ac- curate assessment. Therefore, we use dedicated training and test sets, where the test set is a ran- dom sample of 500 comments with more than 3 updates and thus a more reliable mean change in forecaster accuracy.</p><p>As a baseline, we use the square-root of the number of words in the comment. This may seem like weak measure of quality, but the his- tory of automatic quality assessment is saturated with findings that length is the best predictor of quality. This holds true for both answers to ques- tions ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">Surdeanu et al., 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Beygelzimer et al., 2015)</ref>; as well as e-commerce reviews <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(Cao et al., 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Racherla and Friske, 2012)</ref>. Of course, length is not as shallow as it may seem at first; given no strong incentive for authors to leave long comments, length is likely a proxy for thoroughness of the comment. Still, because we would like to understand the content distinguishing various metrics of quality, we view length as a baseline to move beyond. <ref type="table">Table 2</ref> compares the accuracy of models built on content (ngrams, parts-of-speech, and con- cepts) to the baseline of length. In all cases, our models, based on content, perform significantly better than those based only on length. Further in the case of benefit (change in forecaster accuracy), length has virtually no predictive power.  .23 .59</p><p>influence .08 .24 <ref type="table">Table 3</ref>: Predictive accuracy (out-of-sample Pearson correlation coefficient) of the baseline of length and the baseline of readability and their combination across the subjective and objective measures. length: square-root number of words; readability: Flesch-Kincaid Scale.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3">Relation to Readability</head><p>Some previous work used on readability measures to evaluate comment quality (e.g. ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Hsu et al., 2009)</ref>). Readability of- ten refers to the difficulty or complexity scale of a comment, determining the minimum age group able to perceive it. Various readability measures have been suggested in the past such as Flesch- Kincaid Formula ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Kincaid et al., 1975)</ref>, Gunning- Fog Index <ref type="bibr">(Gunning, 1952)</ref>, and SMOG Grading <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">(Mc Laughlin, 1969)</ref>. All methods are based on the combination of the count of syllables or words in the comment (as a representation of syntactic complexity), and the number of sentences in the comments (representing the semantic complexity). Such measures of readability are often considered naive and questionable, however, they are com- monly used and present a coarse evaluation of the comment's complexity.</p><p>We used Flesch-Kincaid scale to measure read- ability. This scale measures readability by the average number of syllables per word as well as the average number of words per sentence ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Doak et al., 1996)</ref>. We combined the baseline of length and the baseline of readability in order to measure the quality of comments. <ref type="table">Table 3</ref> shows results for readability and length plus readability. We find no significant improvement in the baseline and that our model based on content still adds significantly more predictive accuracy. <ref type="bibr">2</ref> </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Differential Analysis</head><p>The prediction results show promise for automated quality assessment, and that linguistic content can predict quality above-and-beyond length (a proxy for comprehensiveness). Next, we explore what content exactly it is that is predictive of each qual- ity metric, and what content suggests biases dis- tinguishing subjective versus objective quality.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">Method</head><p>To identify distinguishing features, we use a series of multivariate linear regressions to find the rela- tionship between each individual linguistic feature and the given quality metric, controlling for com- ment length -a process known as differential lan- guage analysis ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">Schwartz et al., 2013)</ref>. Specifi- cally, the individual linguistic feature along with the comment length (logged) are standardized and used as independent variables, and then fit to the standardized form of the given quality metric. The coefficient given is then taken as the standardized effect size of the relationship between that fea- ture and the quality metric, holding length con- stant <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Fox, 1997)</ref>. In other words, it tells us how much the feature can explain the quality score, be- yond what is explainable simply from length.</p><p>Using regression to relate variables, although rarely done in Computer Science domains, is stan- dard practice in social and political science <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Fox, 1997</ref>), though typically not over thousands of potential independent variables as we do here. Therefore, we also correct for multiple hypothe- ses by using the Benjamini-Hochberg proce- dure ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Benjamini and Hochberg, 1995</ref>) over our significance tests.</p><p>Differential language analysis allows us to ob- serve and test the unique relationship between each feature and each metric, holding length con- stant. In addition, we use the difference between standardized metric scores to find the features that distinguish high quality comments in one metric versus another. All methods were implemented within the package, dlatk ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">Schwartz et al., 2017</ref>). <ref type="figure">Figure 2</ref> shows the n-grams most highly correlated with each of our quality metrics. Size indicates correlation strength while color represents over- all frequency. Across both subjective ratings and objective update rates, we see discussion of news plays an important role (e.g. "news", "article", and "www.reuters.com"). We do not see the same from comments resulting in positive changes of forecaster accuracy (benefit), which seemed to be distinguished by negation (e.g. "no", "unlikely"). For influence, we see other features indicating probabilistic reasoning (e.g. "%"); the individual <ref type="figure">Figure 2</ref>: Top: ngrams (words and phrases) most distinguishing high quality comments based on (a) subjective ratings, (b) objective forecaster update rates, and (c) objective changes in forecaster accuracy. Bottom: ngrams (words and phrases) most distinguishing (d) subjective ratings from objective update rates and (e) objective update rates from objective changes in forecaster accuracy. All correlates are significant at p &lt; .05 after a Benjamini-Hochberg false-discovery rate correction. numbers in influence actually represent numbered lists of signal. These features are more indicative of a comment that convinces one to update their prediction rather than one that highly rated.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">Quality Comment Features</head><p>We can directly observe the differences in what the metrics capture by looking at the final two vi- sualizations in <ref type="figure">Figure 2</ref>, rating v influence and rat- ing v benefit. Rating v influence tells us which ngrams were predictive of high quality comments that were less likely to result in a forecast update. Discussion of energy topics (e.g. "oil", "prices", "cut", "production") are predictive of comments subjectively rated higher than their update rates would suggest. Further, discussion of dates (e.g. "january", "may", "days", "2015", "2013") seems to predict comments that lead forecasters to update but which do not actually result in better predic- tions (influence v benefit). Discussion of news and articles ("article", "news", "html", "question" ap- pears to predict subjectively top-rated comments from those comments that actually result in better predictions (influence v benefit). <ref type="table">Table 4</ref> shows differential language of quality based on part-of-speech. We observe that some patterns from the ngram results are generalized. Examples of these patterns include more num- bers, parentheses, and quotes in highly rated and influential comments. Other results are some- what novel, such as the use of more adverbs and subordinate conjunctions (e.g. "though", "since", "whereas") in comments leading to better forecast accuracy, and that both ratings and influence fa- vored quotes.</p><p>We notice that including explanation or af- terthought (using more parentheses) can predict subjectively high rated comments from the com- ments leading to updated ratings. The use of quotes and numbers along with mentioning proper nouns can predict influential comments that do not help in better predictions. Including explana- tion, quotes, and numbers as well as reporting past events seems to predict comment that convinces  <ref type="table">Table 4</ref>: Top: Most distinguishing parts-of-speech correlating with the three metrics of quality: sub- jective rating, forecaster updates (influence), and forecaster accuracy (benefit). Bottom: parts-of-speech most predictive of differences in quality metric scores (rating v influence and rating v benefit). All correlates are significant at p &lt; .05 after a Benjamini-Hochberg false-discovery rate correction.</p><p>one to update their prediction as opposed to help- ing better forecasting accuracy. Distinguishing concepts, in <ref type="table">Table 5</ref> offer a dif- ferent perspective. Discussions of documents and written material characterize highly rated and in- fluential comments, while changes in accuracy (benefit) were characterized by more discussion of abstract attributes or states of being. Highly rated comments were more likely to discuss concepts re- lated to transactions and materials than influential comments, but they are more likely to discuss con- cepts about creation compared to comments re- sulting in better predictions.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Related Work</head><p>While no prior work has focused on recommenda- tion quality in terms of how readers change or im- prove decisions (i.e. objective metrics), there is an extensive body of literature on the automated anal- ysis of subjective comment quality from which we build. Such work typically uses subjective assessments specific to their application domain (e.g. thumbs up/ thumbs down over YouTube com- ments, answer ratings in Yahoo Answers, or help- fulness ratings of Amazon product reviews). Be- low we discuss such work organized into three main categories of subjective comment quality: comment usefulness, the quality of answers in QA platform, and comment helpfulness.</p><p>Comment usefulness concerns the acceptance (vs. non-acceptance) of comments by a commu- nity ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">Siersdorfer et al., 2010)</ref>. Some previous work has focused on the usefulness of YouTube comments. For example, <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">Siersdorfer et. al. (Siersdorfer et al., 2010)</ref> have used support vector ma- chines to identify the acceptance of comments by the community in 6 million comments on 67,000 YouTube videos. They showed that community feedback and term weight features can be good predictors of comment acceptance. Other work such as ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Momeni et al., 2013</ref>) predicted com- ment usefulness on YouTube and Flickr, and found that comments rated as useful usually include named entities and "insight"-related terms (think, know, consider, etc.), whereas non-useful com- ments contain emotional and affective expression, and "certainty"-related (always, never, etc.).</p><p>Others working on comment quality assessment focus on user-generated answers in social media and QA platforms. ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Bian et al., 2008</ref>) present a general ranking approach for finding the answers from 1,250 TREC factoid questions containing at least one similar question from Yahoo! Answers. They found that various features including tex- tual (e.g. word overlap, length ratio), and com- munity (e.g. total points, total answers) are im- portant in retrieving factual answers, whereas sta- tistical features (e.g. length, lifetime, popularity) are not very effective. Exploring if additional fea- tures could outperform answer length in predicting the best answer, <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Beygelzimer et al. (2015)</ref> con- sidered a wide variety of features including func- tional, linguistic, questioner and answerer person- alization, and "superlative" features, but were un- able to overcome the length baseline.</p><p>Helpfulness is mainly defined in the context of online reviews and represents the number of users indicating a particular review was helpful. Us- ing structural features like sentence tokens, length, Concepts rating document, written document, papers -writ- ing that provides information (especially in- formation of an official nature).</p><p>gathering, assemblage -a group of persons together in one place. influence writing, written material, piece of writing - the work of a writer; anything expressed in letters of the alphabet (especially when con- sidered from the point of view of style and effect). benefit attribute -an abstraction belonging to or characteristic of an entity.</p><p>state -the way something is with respect to its main attributes.</p><p>rating v influence transaction, dealing, dealings -the act of transacting within or between groups (as car- rying on commercial activities).</p><p>material, stuff -the tangible substance that goes into the makeup of a physical object.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>rating v benefit</head><p>creation -an artifact that has been brought into existence by someone. <ref type="table">Table 5</ref>: Top: Select concepts correlating with the three metrics of quality: subjective rating, forecaster updates (influence), and forecaster accuracy (benefit). Bottom: concepts most predictive of differences in qualtric metric scores (rating v influence and rating v benefit). All correlates are significant at p &lt; .05 after a Benjamini-Hochberg false-discovery rate correction.</p><p>proportion of question sentences along with lex- ical and syntactic features, <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Kim et. al. (2006)</ref> could achieve rank correlations of up to 0.66 with helpfulness votes of Amazon reviews. Ghose and Ipeirotis (2011) analyzed length, readability, and subjective and objective information on Ama- zon.com reviews finding that reviews with ob- jective, and highly subjective sentences are rated more helpful. Similar findings were reported by <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">Mudambi and Schuff (2010)</ref>, finding that review extremity, review depth, and product type affect the perceived helpfulness of the review. Most studies listed thus far found length of comment to be the dominant predictor, with other features providing minimal benefit. However, a few studies (including our own) have found this baseline can be overcome. For example, Racherla and Friske (Racherla and Friske, 2012) investi- gated perceived usefulness of consumer reviews on Yelp and found that reputation and expertise were more important than total number of words on perceived usefulness.</p><p>All of these prior works focus on assessing sub- jective aspects of comments (usefulness, quality, and helpfulness); Perhaps the study coming clos- est in spirit to our own was Ghose et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Ghose et al. (2007)</ref> who quantified quality of reviews by the economic change they produced. How- ever, they still were not dealing with a randomized experiment and so conclusions were correlational and the objective was better sales of the product rather than benefit to the reader (i.e. leading to a better decision).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Conclusion</head><p>Our results suggest three key findings. First, what one writes in a comment is more important than simply how much one writes; this is true across both subjective and objective outcomes, though length had virtually no predictive ability for im- proving forecaster accuracy. Second, we found many linguistic features characteristic of quality, many of which seemingly align with attributes of strong forecasters <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">(Mellers et al., 2015)</ref>. For example, high quality comments contained sig- nals of probabilistic reasoning (e.g. "%", "un- likely", numerical parts-of-speech), inductive rea- soning (e.g. justifications with "news" and doc- uments), and cognitive flexibility (e.g. subordi- nate conjunctions which signal more complex sen- tence constructions used to relate two independent clauses or ideas).</p><p>Most importantly, our results suggest a sub- jective bias: that what people believe to be use- ful does not always turn out to be truly useful. Subjective ratings were favorably biased towards comments containing energy-related content (e.g. "oil", "production", "prices"), news articles, and nouns of creation and materials (as opposed to ab- stractions or attributes).</p><p>The implications of identifying subjective bi- ases in comment quality extend to many domains involving comment ratings. Consumers of com- ments, typically, desire information that ultimately leads to real utility benefits, and this domain is not the only one where objective quality can be obtained: For example, one could: (1) ask con- sumers of restaurant reviews to indicate if one con- vinces them to go to the restaurant and then follow up on their experience, (2) consider evaluating re- search paper quality -reviewer ratings versus ci- tation count (influence), (3) determine whether the answer to the question about how to drive to con- serve fuel lead to the reader actually using less gas? A review being convincing or being "liked" may correlate with better outcomes, but it is not equivalent.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7">Acknowledgments</head><p>Funding This research was supported by the Intelligence Advanced Research Projects Activ- ity (IARPA) via the Department of Interior Na- tional Business Center (DoI/NBC) Contract No. D11PC20061. The U.S. government is authorized to reproduce and distribute reprints for govern- ment purposes notwithstanding any copyright an- notation thereon. The views and conclusions ex- pressed herein are those of the authors and should not be interpreted as necessarily representing the official policies or endorsements, either expressed or implied, of IARPA, DoI/ NBC, or the U.S. gov- ernment. This work also supported, in part, from the Templeton Religion Trust, grant TRT-0048.</p></div>
			<note place="foot" n="1"> Data, in the form of quality ratings, POS features, and aggregate concept features is released at http://http://www3.cs.stonybrook.edu/ ˜ has/objective_quality/. Due to IRB privacy considerations we are unable to release the full data set.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="2"> Adding length and readability together to the full model had no benefit.</note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Finding high-quality content in social media</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Eugene</forename><surname>Agichtein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Carlos</forename><surname>Castillo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Debora</forename><surname>Donato</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2008 International Conference on Web Search and Data Mining</title>
		<meeting>the 2008 International Conference on Web Search and Data Mining</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="183" to="194" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Aristides Gionis, and Gilad Mishne</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Accountability and adaptive performance: The long-term view</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Atanasov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Chang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Patil</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Mellers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Tetlock</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Under Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Identifying content for planned events across social media sites</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hila</forename><surname>Becker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dan</forename><surname>Iter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mor</forename><surname>Naaman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Luis</forename><surname>Gravano</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the fifth ACM international conference on Web search and data mining</title>
		<meeting>the fifth ACM international conference on Web search and data mining</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="533" to="542" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Controlling the false discovery rate: a practical and powerful approach to multiple testing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yoav</forename><surname>Benjamini</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yosef</forename><surname>Hochberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of the Royal Statistical Society. Series B (Methodological</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="289" to="300" />
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">On yahoo answers, long answers are best</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alina</forename><surname>Beygelzimer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ruggiero</forename><surname>Cavallo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Joel</forename><surname>Tetreault</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of CrowdML: The ICML 15 Workshop on Crowdsourcing and Machine Learning</title>
		<meeting>CrowdML: The ICML 15 Workshop on Crowdsourcing and Machine Learning</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Finding the right facts in the crowd: factoid question answering over social media</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jiang</forename><surname>Bian</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yandong</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Eugene</forename><surname>Agichtein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hongyuan</forename><surname>Zha</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 17th international conference on World Wide Web</title>
		<meeting>the 17th international conference on World Wide Web</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="467" to="476" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Verification of forecasts expressed in terms of probability</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Glenn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Brier</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Monthly weather review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">78</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="3" />
			<date type="published" when="1950" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Exploring determinants of voting for the &quot;helpfulness&quot; of online user reviews: A text mining approach. Decision Support Systems</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Qing</forename><surname>Cao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wenjing</forename><surname>Duan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Qiwei</forename><surname>Gan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">50</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="511" to="521" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Teaching patients with low literacy skills</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Cecilia</forename><forename type="middle">Conrath</forename><surname>Doak</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Leonard</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Doak</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jane</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Root</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">AJN The American Journal of Nursing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">96</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">16</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christiane</forename><surname>Fellbaum</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
			<publisher>Wiley Online Library</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Applied regression analysis, linear models, and related methods</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">John</forename><surname>Fox</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
			<publisher>Sage Publications, Inc</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Estimating the helpfulness and economic impact of product reviews: Mining text and reviewer characteristics. Knowledge and Data Engineering</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Anindya</forename><surname>Ghose</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Panagiotis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Ipeirotis</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE Transactions on</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">23</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1498" to="1512" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Opinion mining using econometrics: A case study on reputation systems. In annual meeting-association for computational linguistics</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Anindya</forename><surname>Ghose</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Panagiotis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Arun</forename><surname>Ipeirotis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Sundararajan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">45</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">416</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Finding structure with randomness: Probabilistic algorithms for constructing approximate matrix decompositions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nathan</forename><surname>Halko</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Per-Gunnar Martinsson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Tropp</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">SIAM review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">53</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="217" to="288" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Ranking comments on the social web</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chiao-Fang</forename><surname>Hsu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Elham</forename><surname>Khabiri</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">James</forename><surname>Caverlee</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Computational Science and Engineering, 2009. CSE&apos;09. International Conference on. IEEE</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="90" to="97" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Automatically assessing review helpfulness</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Soo-Min</forename><surname>Kim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Patrick</forename><surname>Pantel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tim</forename><surname>Chklovski</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marco</forename><surname>Pennacchiotti</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the</title>
		<meeting>the</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Conference on empirical methods in natural language processing</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="423" to="430" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Derivation of new readability formulas (automated readability index, fog count and flesch reading ease formula) for navy enlisted personnel</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J Peter</forename><surname>Kincaid</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Robert P Fishburne</forename><surname>Jr</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Brad</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Richard L Rogers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Chissom</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1975" />
			<publisher>DTIC Document</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
<note type="report_type">Technical report</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Low-quality product review detection in opinion summarization</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jingjing</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yunbo</forename><surname>Cao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chin-Yew</forename><surname>Lin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yalou</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ming</forename><surname>Zhou</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">EMNLPCoNLL</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="334" to="342" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">A randomized algorithm for the decomposition of matrices. Applied and Computational Harmonic Analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Vladimir</forename><surname>Per-Gunnar Martinsson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mark</forename><surname>Rokhlin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Tygert</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">30</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="47" to="68" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Smog grading-a new readability formula</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G Harry Mc</forename><surname>Laughlin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of reading</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="639" to="646" />
			<date type="published" when="1969" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The psychology of intelligence analysis: Drivers of prediction accuracy in world politics</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Barbara</forename><surname>Mellers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Eric</forename><surname>Stone</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Pavel</forename><surname>Atanasov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nick</forename><surname>Rohrbaugh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>S Emlen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lyle</forename><surname>Metz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Ungar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Michael</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Bishop</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ed</forename><surname>Horowitz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Philip</forename><surname>Merkle</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Tetlock</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of experimental psychology: applied</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">21</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Properties, prediction, and prevalence of useful usergenerated comments for descriptive annotation of social media objects</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Elaheh</forename><surname>Momeni</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Claire</forename><surname>Cardie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Myle</forename><surname>Ott</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ICWSM-2013: Proceedings of the International AAAI Conference on Weblogs and Social Media</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">What makes a helpful review? a study of customer reviews on amazon</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Susan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Mudambi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Schuff</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">MIS quarterly</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">34</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="185" to="200" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Perceived &apos;usefulness&apos; of online consumer reviews: An exploratory investigation across three services categories</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Pradeep</forename><surname>Racherla</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wesley</forename><surname>Friske</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Electronic Commerce Research and Applications</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="548" to="559" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Personality, gender, and age in the language of social media: The open-vocabulary approach</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H Andrew</forename><surname>Schwartz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Johannes</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Eichstaedt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Margaret</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Kern</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lukasz</forename><surname>Dziurzynski</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Megha</forename><surname>Stephanie M Ramones</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Achal</forename><surname>Agrawal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michal</forename><surname>Shah</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Kosinski</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Stillwell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Martin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lyle</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Seligman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Ungar</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">PloS one</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">9</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">DLATK: Differential Language Analysis ToolKit</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H Andrew</forename><surname>Schwartz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Salvatore</forename><surname>Giorgi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Maarten</forename><surname>Sap</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Patrick</forename><surname>Crutchley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Johannes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lyle</forename><surname>Eichstaedt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Ungar</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2017 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</title>
		<meeting>the 2017 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">How useful are your comments?: analyzing and predicting youtube comments and comment ratings</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Stefan</forename><surname>Siersdorfer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sergiu</forename><surname>Chelaru</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wolfgang</forename><surname>Nejdl</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jose San</forename><surname>Pedro</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 19th international conference on World wide web</title>
		<meeting>the 19th international conference on World wide web</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="891" to="900" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Learning to rank answers to nonfactoid questions from web collections</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mihai</forename><surname>Surdeanu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Massimiliano</forename><surname>Ciaramita</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hugo</forename><surname>Zaragoza</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Computational Linguistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">37</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="351" to="383" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Multiple comparison procedures. 89. Sage</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Larry E Toothaker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Is this post persuasive? ranking argumentative comments in the online forum</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Zhongyu</forename><surname>Wei</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yang</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yi</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">The 54th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
			<biblScope unit="page">195</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
