<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T12:31+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">KnowYourNyms? A Game of Semantic Relationships</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
				<availability status="unknown"><p>Copyright Association for Computational Linguistics</p>
				</availability>
				<date>September 7-11, 2017. 2017</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ross</forename><surname>Mechanic</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Computer and Information Science Department</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">University of Pennsylvania * LIMSI</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">CNRS</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit3">Université Paris-Saclay</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>91403</postCode>
									<settlement>Orsay</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dean</forename><surname>Fulgoni</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Computer and Information Science Department</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">University of Pennsylvania * LIMSI</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">CNRS</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit3">Université Paris-Saclay</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>91403</postCode>
									<settlement>Orsay</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hannah</forename><surname>Cutler</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Computer and Information Science Department</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">University of Pennsylvania * LIMSI</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">CNRS</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit3">Université Paris-Saclay</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>91403</postCode>
									<settlement>Orsay</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sneha</forename><surname>Rajana</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Computer and Information Science Department</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">University of Pennsylvania * LIMSI</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">CNRS</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit3">Université Paris-Saclay</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>91403</postCode>
									<settlement>Orsay</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Zheyuan</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Computer and Information Science Department</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">University of Pennsylvania * LIMSI</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">CNRS</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit3">Université Paris-Saclay</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>91403</postCode>
									<settlement>Orsay</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bradley</forename><surname>Jackson</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Computer and Information Science Department</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">University of Pennsylvania * LIMSI</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">CNRS</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit3">Université Paris-Saclay</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>91403</postCode>
									<settlement>Orsay</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Anne</forename><surname>Cocos</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Computer and Information Science Department</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">University of Pennsylvania * LIMSI</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">CNRS</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit3">Université Paris-Saclay</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>91403</postCode>
									<settlement>Orsay</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chris</forename><surname>Callison-Burch</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Computer and Information Science Department</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">University of Pennsylvania * LIMSI</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">CNRS</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit3">Université Paris-Saclay</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>91403</postCode>
									<settlement>Orsay</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marianna</forename><surname>Apidianaki</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Computer and Information Science Department</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">University of Pennsylvania * LIMSI</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">CNRS</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit3">Université Paris-Saclay</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>91403</postCode>
									<settlement>Orsay</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">KnowYourNyms? A Game of Semantic Relationships</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="j" type="main">EMNLP System Demonstrations</title>
						<meeting> <address><addrLine>Copenhagen, Denmark</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="37" to="42"/>
							<date type="published">September 7-11, 2017. 2017</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Semantic relation knowledge is crucial for natural language understanding. We introduce KnowYourNyms?, a web-based game for learning semantic relations. While providing users with an engaging experience, the application collects large amounts of data that can be used to improve semantic relation classifiers. The data also broadly informs us of how people perceive the relationships between words, providing useful insights for research in psychology and linguistics.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Knowledge of semantic relationships can help nu- merous NLP tasks that need to infer meaning from text, such as text classification, content analysis and query answering. We apply the "games with a purpose" methodology (von <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Ahn and Dabbish, 2004</ref>) to the task of discovering semantic relation- ships between words. Our aim is to collect a large volume of accurately labeled lexical relationships through this type of crowdsourcing. Gamification offers several advantages compared to a fully au- tomatic or manual relation identification process since it enables acquiring considerable amounts of high quality data at no cost.</p><p>We have created a simple game called KnowYourNyms? with the tag line Keep your brain on its toes. It asks players to list word for a prompt in a short amount of time. As the seconds tick down, they type as many answers as they can for prompts like "What are kinds of seafood?" or "What are the parts of a volcano?" or "What's the opposite of fat?". <ref type="table">Table 1</ref> shows the hyponyms, meronyms and antonyms that our players provided in response to these questions. Their answers are useful as training data for natural language under- hyponyms of seafood: fish (54), shrimp (53), lobster (38), crab (36), clams (24), salmon (17), oysters (12), scallops (12), shellfish (10), mussels (10), cod (7), tuna (7), tilapia (5), whale (4), trout (4), octopus (4), shark (4), squid (3), prawn (3), haddock (3), flounder (2), catfish (2), swordfish (2), eel (2), sushi (2), bass (2), calamari (2), mussles (2). Words suggested once: muss-, pearls, suslhi, prawns, schrimp, seal, hadsoxk, crab", sepia, scampi, scalop, sea- weed, dolphin, fi-, seaww-, snapper, s-, pr-, seabass, jelly- fish, cra-, muscles, oy-, soup, sardine, mahi, herrin, mussells, tipica, tun-, lob-, sa-, osyter, crawdad, roe, swai-, cram-, pa-, caviar, seewee-, carp, oyste-, sw-, musse-. meronyms of volcano: lava (32), rock (12), magma (10), mountain (9), crater (9), smoke (7), eruption (7), ash (6), fire (6), vent (4), heat (4), mouth (3), steam (2), danger (2), dust (2), volcano (2), cone (2), core (2), geodes (2). Words suggested once: crust, energy, moutain, hot, village, sulfur, mount-, caldera, throat, pummice, gas, top, side, sill, stones, sparks, motlen, lawa, japan, opening, soil, head, earth, metal, op-, cliff, cond-, cr-, pl-, flow, pressure, spout, clay, pollution, sediment, rim antonyms of fat: thin (15), skinny (13), slender (5), slim (4), small (4), tiny (3), fit (3), trim (2), lean (2). Words suggested once: delgado, svelt, narrow, bare, attrac- tive, anorexic, teeny, underweight, bulemic, in shape, under-, wispy, healthy, light, smal-, little <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>: Example relationships provided by KnowYourNyms? players (with frequency counts). standing applications and may provide useful in- sights for psycholinguistics research.</p><p>Go to www.know-your-nyms.com to play KnowYourNyms?.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Related Work</head><p>Several games with a purpose (GWAPs) have been developed for gathering linguistic annota- tions for building resources and training systems ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Chamberlain et al., 2013)</ref>. <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Lafourcade (2007)</ref> and <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Fort et al. (2014)</ref> developed games for defin- ing semantic relations and dependency relations in French. <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Chamberlain et al. (2008)</ref> created Phrase Detectives to annotate and validate things like co-reference. <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Jurgens and Navigli (2014)</ref> re- cently proposed using video games to link Word- Net senses to images and perform word sense dis- ambiguation. KnowYourNyms? gathers high qual- ity semantic relationships between English words to increase the coverage of resources like Word- Net and assign a taxonomic structure to the Para- phrase Database ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Ganitkevitch et al., 2013)</ref>. Addi- tionally, it provides rich data for training relation detection systems like <ref type="bibr">LexNET (Shwartz and Dagan, 2016</ref>), up to now trained on small training datasets (BLESS ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Baroni and Lenci, 2011</ref> </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">System Overview</head><p>KnowYourNyms? is modeled after GWAPs like the ESP game or the Google Image Labeler, which use human-based computation to gather metadata to improve image recognition classifiers <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(von Ahn and Dabbish, 2004)</ref>. At a high level, the appli- cation is simple. Once a user creates an account, she may start a round of the game. For each round, the system selects a specific word (called the "base word") and asks the user to name as many seman- tic relationship pairs for that word as possible in a set time limit. After the allotted time expires, these named pairs are recorded in our database and serve as data points for possible semantic relationships. The user then sees a display of her scoring per- formance, which is primarily based on how many other users named the same relationships for the given base word. In this way, the scoring is remi- niscent of Family Feud, a popular game show that incentivizes answering questions in a way most similar to your peers. The scoring screen also shows the most popular answers to the question, in their appropriate distribution. Once completed, another round begins. The rounds are short (5-20 seconds, depending on the relation type), which makes the game fun and easy to play in short peri- ods of time.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">System Implementation</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">Architecture</head><p>The web application was built with the Django framework, using Python for all backend and database interaction and standard JavaScript, HTML, and CSS for the frontend, including the jQuery, d3.js, and Bootstrap JavaScript/CSS li- braries. We used AWS Elastic Beanstalk, which deploys our Django web application to an AWS EC2 server. The application has multiple com- ponents that are important to the user experience, which are separated into three main views.</p><p>Welcome Screen This screen gives information about the purpose of the game, what semantic re- lationships are, how to play, and a little about our team. When a user is signed in this screen dis- plays some statistics about the player, including number of completed rounds, total score, and av- erage score per round. Four checkboxes are dis- played, one for each playable semantic relation- ship type (synonyms, antonyms, hyponyms, and meronyms). These allow the user to select which relations to play. All are selected by default.</p><p>Game Play A timer begins immediately as the round starts. To answer the question prompt, the user may type as many semantic relationships as possible into text forms. Each discrete answer is known as an input word. Forms are dynamically generated upon pressing tab or enter, for however many input words are necessary during that round. At the end of 20 seconds, the round immediately ends and the user is directed to the scoring page. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref> shows what a player sees after the time elapses for a round. This scoring page displays two items to the player. The first is a table breakdown of all input words during the round, mapping each to a score for that word. It also includes the total round score. The second is a bar graph showing the top answers for that question. Here, users can observe which relations they identified or missed compared to the entire population. . The top half of the figure shows the components of the system backend. Note that the "Semantic Relationship Classifier" is faded because we trained and tested the Classifier on the players' data in an offline setting (see Section 6.2).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Scoring Page</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">Base Word Selection</head><p>Base words are those used for each round's ques- tion; they are the 'X' in a potential (X,Y) seman- tic relationship pair. Good base words are essen- tial for good questions, as there aren't necessar- ily good synonyms for 'triceratops' or many parts of a 'sphere'. To address these issues, we build four separate vocabulary lists for the base words, one for each allowed semantic relationship type extracted from WordNet. We select base words that have at least one synonym or antonym, and at least three hyponyms or meronyms in WordNet. To make sure we don't ask users about rare words, which might discourage the users from continu- ing playing, we only retain unigrams and bigrams that occur at least 1,000,000 times in the Google n-grams corpus. <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Table 2</ref> shows the number of base words retained from WordNet for each re- lation type. Finally, we have integrated a "skip" button which allows the users to skip queries for which they cannot think of any good relations.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3">Scoring</head><p>We incentivize players to generate many answers to each prompt by giving them a score at the end of each round. The score is based on the percentage of other users who named a word when they were given the same base word and relationship type.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Relation</head><p>Base  Finally, the score is also potentially augmented by a WordNet bonus, which is a simple boolean check of whether the word pair is linked by this specific relation in WordNet. The total score for each word is the sum of these values, sorted in descending order in the final score table.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.4">Data Visualization</head><p>In order for users to see the most common re- sponses for each round, a bar graph is included on the scoring page that shows the top 5 responses and the percentage of previous users who gave them. The percentages for scoring are calculated on the backend. On the frontend, we use the data visualization library d3.js, in order to dynamically create a bar graph that is scaled to the appropri- ate size for the window. This allows the graph to be seen on mobile devices, or to be dynamically resized as the user changes the size of a desktop window.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Design Decisions</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.1">User Identification</head><p>We require users to create an account. This design decision was mainly driven by quality control con- cerns. Since we don't expect all users to provide good answers, it is important that we be able to fil- ter out malicious users, so that we can gather data that has sufficiently high quality for research pur- poses. An additional benefit of user identification is that it allows to not present a user with the same query several times, since this could skew the data.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.2">Vocabulary Selection</head><p>The list of base words is traversed in a specific or- der by each user. Compared to fully random selec- tion, this has the advantage of not repeating words until all have been played by the user. Presenting the user with the same words a few rounds apart is unacceptable from a user experience standpoint. Furthermore, having different users play the same words is important since it leads to better scoring and percentage visualization. Finally, this traver- sal is beneficial for learning high confidence rela- tionships, as we collect data on fewer base words in a more concentrated way. To cover more words, we decided to allow a small amount of randomness which consists in drawing a word randomly from the whole vocabulary list every five items.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Evaluation</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.1">Crowdsourced Approach</head><p>To evaluate our game, we asked 160 crowd- workers to play KnowYourNyms? on Amazon Mechanical Turk for ten rounds each. Our intention was to seed the game with data so that normal users would receive scores based on words suggested by previous players. Al- though these workers were only asked to play ten rounds, many went on to play thirty, forty, or even a hundred rounds of the game. From these workers, we received over 15,000 user inputs. <ref type="table">Table 3</ref> gives a breakdown of the re- lations that we have collected so far. Here are some examples of the most frequently suggested word pairs for our relation types. Synonyms include pony-horse, woods-forest, woods-trees, marching-walking, electricity-power, four- quad, looking-seeing, frequent-often, woody- forest, and pester-annoy. Antonyms include sleep-awake, limited-unlimited, prefix-suffix, Users (n) Rels Rels not in <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">WordNet Rels in WordNet  all  17,603  16,813  790  n&lt;=3  15,895  15,265 (96%)  630  3&lt;n&lt;=5  724  672 (93%)  52  5&lt;n&lt;=15  794  723 (91%)  71  15&lt;n&lt;=30  153  126 (82%)  27  n&gt;30  37</ref> 27 (73%) 10 <ref type="table">Table 3</ref>: The number of relations (rels) learned at different confidence levels, where confidence is measured by the number of users (n) who named the relation. We compare this to the number of re- lations found in WordNet for the same base words.</p><p>desirable-undesirable, similarity-difference, similarity-different, hitch-unhitch, immature- mature, wake-sleep, and sterile-dirty. Meronyms include knife-handle, knife-blade, chain-link, woods-trees, book-cover, writings-words, ice-water, month-days, aquarium-fish, and chain-metal. Hyponyms include seafood-fish, seafood-shrimp, seafood-lobster, sleep-deep, similarity-same, seafood-crab, plaster-paris, Asian-Chinese, Asian-Japanese, and hitch-trailer Bold items are relations that are not present in WordNet.</p><p>We surveyed the crowd workers about their feel- ings about the game and whether or not they would play again. The first 30 crowd workers played the game before anyone else had played, so many of their scores were empty (the game relies on previ- ous players). Those workers rated the game on average 3.9/5 on experience and 3.8/5 on like- lihood of playing again. However, our second group of crowd workers was given the game with many more of the rounds already played, which improved scoring. These workers rated the ex- perience 4.46/5 on average, and 4.43/5 for likeli- hood of playing again. Moreover, many of the sec- ond round of workers left comments stating that they "loved this addicting game", that the game "is fun", "makes you think fast" and "really wakes up the brain", and made useful suggestions for im- provement. The positive reaction about playing the game (especially the shift in positivity as the scoring became more clear) is evidence that this game may work on a larger scale, and may allow us to gather important word relationship data from players for free.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.2">Classifier Evaluation</head><p>To demonstrate how this game could be used to collect training data for semantic relation classi-  <ref type="table">Table 4</ref>: Precision, Recall, and F-Score of the LexNET semantic relation classifier, when trained and evaluated on data collected by KnowYourNyms?.</p><p>fiers, we used our players' data to train and eval- uate a state-of-the-art semantic relationship clas- sifier, <ref type="bibr">LexNET (Shwartz and Dagan, 2016)</ref>. Our dataset consisted of 8613 meronym, antonym, hy- ponym and synonym pairs proposed by at least five users, and 6228 random word pairs. From these 14,841 pairs, we extracted a subset of 951 pairs for testing and used the remaining 4675 pairs whose constituent words did not overlap with the test set for training and validation. The classifier achieved an overall weighted average F-Score of 0.34 over the test set. The full results of this experiment are given in <ref type="table">Table 4</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7">Discussion</head><p>One of the challenging aspects of making this game fun to play is selecting words and relation types that are easy for people to think of answers for. Despite our attempts to filter the vocabu- lary sets drawn from WordNet to be high frequent words with several WordNet relations, we found that many players were stumped by some of our questions. Here are examples of the questions that most users pressed the "Pass" button for:</p><p>• What are kinds of geology? (71% passed)</p><p>• What are kinds of a saver? (70%)</p><p>• What is the opposite of conception? (67%)</p><p>• What is the opposite of differentiated? (67%)</p><p>• What are kinds of hormones? (67%)</p><p>• What is another word for notorious? (60%)</p><p>• What are kinds of sinking? (56%)</p><p>• What are kinds of barley? (56%)</p><p>Some prompts are clearly more difficult for users to answer than others. We hypothesized that abstract words (e.g. geology, sinking, dissolution) are more difficult to provide relations for than con- crete words. An indicator of annotation difficulty for a word is the number of times users choose to skip it: if they cannot think of any good re- lationships, users can choose to pass to the next round. We calculate the correlation between word difficulty -measured as the ratio of the number of times the word was skipped to the number of times it was seen -and concreteness scores in the dataset built by <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Brysbaert et al. (2014)</ref> (hereafter CON- CRETE) which contains ratings for 37,058 English words and 2,896 two-word expressions. Words are ranked on a 5-point rating scale going from ab- stract words (low values) to words with concrete meaning (high values). We expect abstract words to be more difficult to handle and more frequently skipped by our users compared to concrete words.</p><p>We perform the correlation calculation on 412 lemma-relation pairs extracted from KnowYourNyms?. From these, 40 correspond to specific terms and named entities (e.g. cy- tochrome, methyl, Utah, Mexico, etiology, flora, Maryland) that are not in CONCRETE (it only includes words known to 85% of the annotators and excludes proper names).</p><p>We intend to use existence in CONCRETE as a criterion for identifying words that would be too difficult for the annotators and should be excluded from our game.</p><p>The Pearson correlation results for the remain- ing 372 words indicate a negative correlation of -0.2007 between word difficulty and concreteness (p &lt; 0.001), confirming our assumption that more abstract words are more difficult to handle. Corre- lation for the 99 lemmas in CONCRETE that were seen at least 10 times by our crowdworkers is even higher, -0.3851 (p &lt; 0.001),</p><p>Finally, we intend to analyze the collected rela- tions in the light of typicality and gradual semantic category membership, as proposed in <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">(Vuli´cVuli´c et al., 2016)</ref>, to make them more useful for textual en- tailment tasks.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="8">Conclusions and Future Work</head><p>KnowYourNyms? gamifies the process of gather- ing pairs of words holding specific semantic rela- tionships that are not found in existing resources. While providing users with an entertaining expe- rience, our application enables collection of large amounts of data that can be used to improve se-mantic relation classifiers and content analysis tools. This application offers exciting possibili- ties for further development. As the number of players grow, our lexical relation dataset will keep expanding. This will provide new opportunities for evaluation in full-blown applications and will richen our understanding of how people perceive word relations.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="9">Software and Data</head><p>We release the software that underlies our game under the BSD open source license. We provide instructions on how to set up your own instance of the game and populate it with your own base words and semantic relationship types. The soft- ware is available at https://github.com/ rossmechanic/know_your_nyms/. A file containing the semantic relations collected during our initial testing of the game is also included in the repository.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: This example scoring page shows the scores for the player's words, and the top answers.</figDesc><graphic url="image-1.png" coords="2,72.00,62.81,218.27,143.74" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>), EVA- Lution (Santus et al., 2015), ROOT9 (Santus et al., 2016) and K&amp;H+N (Necsulescu et al., 2015)).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2: The application flow of the KnowYourNyms? game. The bottom half of the figure depicts the application functionality from the user's perspective (frontend). The top half of the figure shows the components of the system backend. Note that the "Semantic Relationship Classifier" is faded because we trained and tested the Classifier on the players' data in an offline setting (see Section 6.2).</figDesc><graphic url="image-2.png" coords="3,102.39,62.81,390.05,226.89" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" validated="false"><head>Table 2 : # of base words for each relation type.</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table></table></figure>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>We would like to thank Ani Nenkova and Jonathan Smith for the discussions and useful feedback on this project, and the Mechanical Turk workers who did the play testing.</p><p>This material is based in part on research spon-sored by DARPA under grant number FA8750-13-2-0017 (the DEFT program). The U.S. Gov-ernment is authorized to reproduce and distribute reprints for Governmental purposes. The views and conclusions contained in this publication are those of the authors and should not be interpreted as representing official policies or endorsements of DARPA and the U.S. Government. This work has also been supported by the French National Research Agency under project ANR-16-CE33-0013.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">How we BLESSed distributional semantic evaluation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marco</forename><surname>Baroni</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alessandro</forename><surname>Lenci</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of GEMS</title>
		<meeting>GEMS<address><addrLine>Edinburgh, UK</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="10" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Concreteness ratings for 40 thousand generally known English word lemmas</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marc</forename><surname>Brysbaert</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Amy</forename><forename type="middle">Beth</forename><surname>Warriner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Victor</forename><surname>Kuperman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Behavior Research Methods</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">46</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="904" to="911" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Using games to create language resources: Successes and limitations of the approach</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jon</forename><surname>Chamberlain</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Karën</forename><surname>Fort</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Udo</forename><surname>Kruschwitz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mathieu</forename><surname>Lafourcade</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Massimo</forename><surname>Poesio</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">The Peoples Web Meets NLP</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3" to="44" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Phrase detectives: A web-based collaborative annotation game</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jon</forename><surname>Chamberlain</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Massimo</forename><surname>Poesio</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Udo</forename><surname>Kruschwitz</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of I-Semantics 08</title>
		<meeting>I-Semantics 08</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="42" to="49" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Creating Zombilingo, a Game With A Purpose for dependency syntax annotation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Karën</forename><surname>Fort</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bruno</forename><surname>Guillaume</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hadrien</forename><surname>Chastant</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of GamifIR &apos;14</title>
		<meeting>GamifIR &apos;14<address><addrLine>Amsterdam, The Netherlands</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2" to="6" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">PPDB: The Paraphrase Database</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Juri</forename><surname>Ganitkevitch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Benjamin</forename><surname>Van Durme</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chris</forename><surname>Callison-Burch</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of NAACL/HLT</title>
		<meeting>NAACL/HLT<address><addrLine>Atlanta, Georgia</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="758" to="764" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">It&apos;s All Fun and Games until Someone Annotates: Video Games with a Purpose for Linguistic Annotation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Jurgens</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Roberto</forename><surname>Navigli</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">TACL</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="449" to="464" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Making people play for Lexical Acquisition with the JeuxDeMots prototype</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Mathieu Lafourcade</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of SNLP&apos;07</title>
		<meeting>SNLP&apos;07<address><addrLine>Pattaya, Thailand</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Reading Between the Lines: Overcoming Data Sparsity for Accurate Classification of Lexical Relationships</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Silvia</forename><surname>Necsulescu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sara</forename><surname>Mendes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Jurgens</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Núria</forename><surname>Bel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Roberto</forename><surname>Navigli</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of *SEM</title>
		<meeting>*SEM<address><addrLine>Denver, Colorado</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="182" to="192" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Nine features in a random forest to learn taxonomical semantic relations</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Enrico</forename><surname>Santus</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alessandro</forename><surname>Lenci</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tin-Shing</forename><surname>Chiu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Qin</forename><surname>Lu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chu-Ren</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of LREC</title>
		<meeting>LREC<address><addrLine>Portoroz, Slovenia</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">EVALution 1.0: an Evolving Semantic Dataset for Training and Evaluation of Distributional Semantic Models</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Enrico</forename><surname>Santus</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Frances</forename><surname>Yung</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alessandro</forename><surname>Lenci</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chu-Ren</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of Linked Data in Linguistics: Resources and Applications</title>
		<meeting>Linked Data in Linguistics: Resources and Applications<address><addrLine>Beijing, China</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="64" to="69" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">CogALex-V Shared Task: LexNET-Integrated Path-based and Distributional Method for the Identification of Semantic Relations</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Vered</forename><surname>Shwartz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ido</forename><surname>Dagan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of CogALex-V</title>
		<meeting>CogALex-V</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Japan</forename><surname>Osaka</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="80" to="85" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Labeling images with a computer game</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Laura</forename><surname>Luis Von Ahn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Dabbish</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the SIGCHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems</title>
		<meeting>the SIGCHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems<address><addrLine>Vienna, Austria</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="319" to="326" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">HyperLex: A Large-Scale Evaluation of Graded Lexical Entailment</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ivan</forename><surname>Vuli´cvuli´c</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Daniela</forename><surname>Gerz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Douwe</forename><surname>Kiela</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Felix</forename><surname>Hill</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Anna</forename><surname>Korhonen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>CoRR abs/1608.02117</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
