<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T11:08+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Fine-Grained Citation Span Detection for References in Wikipedia</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
				<availability status="unknown"><p>Copyright Association for Computational Linguistics</p>
				</availability>
				<date>September 7-11, 2017. 2017</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Besnik</forename><surname>Fetahu</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory">L3S Research Center</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Leibniz University of Hannover Hannover</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Katja</forename><surname>Markert</surname></persName>
							<email>markert@cl.uni-heidelberg.de</email>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Institute of Computational Linguistics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Heidelberg University</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Heidelberg</settlement>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Avishek</forename><surname>Anand</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory">L3S Research Center</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Leibniz University of Hannover Hannover</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Fine-Grained Citation Span Detection for References in Wikipedia</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Natural Language Processing</title>
						<meeting> <address><addrLine>Copenhagen, Denmark</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="1990" to="1999"/>
							<date type="published">September 7-11, 2017. 2017</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Verifiability is one of the core editing principles in Wikipedia, editors being encouraged to provide citations for the added content. For a Wikipedia article, determining the citation span of a citation, i.e. what content is covered by a citation, is important as it helps decide for which content citations are still missing. We are the first to address the problem of determining the citation span in Wikipedia articles. We approach this problem by classifying which textual fragments in an article are covered by a citation. We propose a sequence classification approach where for a paragraph and a citation, we determine the citation span at a fine-grained level. We provide a thorough experimental evaluation and compare our approach against baselines adopted from the scientific domain , where we show improvement for all evaluation metrics.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Citations uphold the crucial policy of verifiability in Wikipedia. This policy requires Wikipedia con- tributors to support their additions with citations from authoritative external sources (web, news, journal etc.). In particular, it states that "arti- cles should be based on reliable, third-party, pub- lished sources with a reputation for fact-checking and accuracy" 1 . Not only are citations essential in maintaining reliability, neutrality and authori- tative assessment of content in such a collabora- tively edited platform; but lack of citations are At the summit of the climb, carpet tacks <ref type="bibr">[1]</ref> were thrown onto the road causing as many as thirty riders to puncture, <ref type="bibr">[2]</ref> <ref type="bibr">[3]</ref> including Gilbert's team- mates Cadel Evans and Steve Cummings, <ref type="bibr">[39]</ref> while race leader Bradley Wiggins <ref type="bibr">[…]</ref> precaution. <ref type="bibr">[42]</ref> As a result, <ref type="bibr">[…]</ref> and eventually soloed his way to a fourth career stage victory at the Tour. <ref type="bibr">[47]</ref> Sagan led home a group of four riders almost a minute behind, <ref type="bibr">[…]</ref> behind Sánchez. <ref type="bibr">[39]</ref> Figure 1: Sub-sentence level span for citation <ref type="bibr">[1]</ref> in a citing paragraph in a Wikipedia article. essential signals for core editors for unreliability checks. However, there are two problems when it comes to citing facts in Wikipedia. First, there is a long tail of Wikipedia pages where citations are missing and hence facts might be unverified. Second, cita- tions might have different span granularities, i.e., the text encoding the fact(s), for which a citation is intended, might span less than a sentence (see <ref type="figure">Fig- ure 1</ref>) to multiple sentences. We denote the differ- ent pieces of text which contain a citation marker as fact statements or simply statements. For exam- ple, <ref type="table">Table 1</ref> shows different statements for several citations. The aim of this work is to automatically and accurately determine citation spans in order to improve coverage ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Fetahu et al., 2015b</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Fetahu et al., , 2016</ref> and to assist editors in verifying citation quality at a fine-grained level.</p><p>Earlier work on span determination is mostly concerned with scientific texts <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(O'Connor, 1982;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Kaplan et al., 2016</ref>), operates at sentence level and exploits explicit authoring cues specific to scien- tific text. Although Wikipedia has well formed text, it does not follow explicit scientific guide- lines for placing citations. Moreover, most state- ments can only be inferred from the citation text.</p><p>In this work, we operate at a sub-sentence level, loosely referred to as text fragments, and take a sequence prediction approach using a linear chain CRF ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Lafferty et al., 2001</ref>). We limit our work to citations referring to web and news sources, as they are accessible online and present the most prominent sources in <ref type="bibr">Wikipedia (Fetahu et al., 2015a)</ref>. By using recent work on moving window language models <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">(Taneva and Weikum, 2013</ref>) and the structure of the paragraph that includes a ci- tation, we classify sequences of text fragments as text that belong to a given citation. We are able to tackle all citation span cases as shown in <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>  <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>: Varying degrees of citation span granu- larity in Wikipedia text.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Problem Definition and Terminology</head><p>In this section, we describe the terminology and define the problem of determining the citation span in text in Wikipedia articles.</p><p>Terminology. We consider Wikipedia articles W = {e 1 , . . . , e n } from a Wikipedia snapshot. We distinguish citations to external references in text and denote them with ⟨p k , c i ⟩, where c i repre- sents a citation which occurs in paragraph p k with positional index k in an entity e ∈ W . We will re- fer to p k as the citing paragraph. Furthermore, with citing sentence we refer to the sentence in s ∈ p k , which contains c i . Note that p k can have more than one citation as shown in <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>.</p><p>Problem Definition. The task of determining the citation span for a citation c and a paragraph p, respectively ⟨p, c⟩ (or simply p c ), is subject to the citing paragraph and the citation content. In particular, we refer with citation span to the tex- tual fragments from p which are covered by c. The fragments correspond to the sequence of sub- sentences S(p) = ⟨δ 1 1 , δ 2 1 , . . . , δ k 1 , . . . , δ m n ⟩. We obtain the sequence of sub-sentences from p by splitting the sentences into sub-sentences or text fragments based on the following punctuation de- limiters ({, !; :?}). These delimitors do not al- ways provide a perfect semantic segmentation of sentences into facts. A more involved approach could be taken akin to work in text summarization, such as Zhou and Hovy ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Zhou and Hovy, 2006</ref>) or ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Nenkova et al., 2007</ref>) who consider summary units for a similar purpose.</p><p>Formally, we define the citation span in Equa- tion 4 as the function of finding the subset S ′ ⊆ S where the fragments in S ′ are covered by c.</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">φ(p, c) → S ′ ⊆ S, s.t. δ ∈ S ′ ∧ c ⊢ δ (1)</formula><p>where c ⊢ δ states that δ is covered in c.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Related Work</head><p>Scientific Text. One of the first attempts to deter- mine the citation span in text <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(O'Connor, 1982)</ref> was carried out in the context of document re- trieval. The citing statements from a document were used as an index to retrieve the cited docu- ment. The citing statements are extracted based on heuristics starting from the citing sentence and are expanded with sentences in a window of +/-2 sen- tences, depending on them containing cue words like 'this', 'these',. . . 'above-mentioned'. We con- sider the approach in <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(O'Connor, 1982)</ref> as a base- line. <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Kaplan et al. (2016)</ref> proposed the task of de- termining the citation block based on a set of tex- tual coherence features (e.g. grammatical or lex- ical coherence). The citation block starts from the citing sentence, with succeeding sentences classified (through SVMs or CRFs) according to whether they belong to the block. Abu-Jbara and Radev (2012) determine the citation block by first segmenting the sentences and then classifying in- dividual words as being inside/outside the citation. Finally, the segment is classified depending on the word labels (majority of words being inside, at least one, or all of them). This approach is not applicable in our case due to the fact that words in Wikipedia text are not domain or genre-specific as one expects in scientific text, and as such their classification does not work.</p><p>Citations in IR. The importance of determin- ing the citation span has been acknowledged in the field of Information Retrieval (IR). The focus is on building citation indexes <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Garfield, 1955)</ref> and im- proving the retrieval of scientific articles ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">Ritchie et al., 2008</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b19">Ritchie et al., , 2006</ref>). Citing sentences on a fixed window size are used to index documents and aid the retrieval process.</p><p>Summarization. Citations have been success- fully employed to generate summaries of scientific articles <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(Qazvinian and Radev, 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Elkiss et al., 2008)</ref>. In all cases, citing statements are either ex- tracted manually or via heuristics such as extract- ing only citing sentences. Similarly <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Nanba and Okumura, 1999</ref>) expand the summaries in addi- tion to the citing sentence based on cue words (e.g. 'In this', 'However' etc.). The work in <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">(Qazvinian and Radev, 2010</ref>) goes one step beyond and con- siders sentences which do not explicitly cite an- other article. The task is to assign a binary label to a sentence, indicating whether it contains con- text for a cited paper. We use this approach as one of our competitors. Again, the premise is that ci- tations are marked explicitly and additional citing sentences are found dependent on them.</p><p>Comparison to our work. The language style and the composition of citations in Wikipedia and in scientific text differ significantly. Citations are explicit in scientific text (e.g. author names) and are usually the first word in a sentence ( <ref type="bibr">AbuJbara and Radev, 2012)</ref>. In Wikipedia, citations are implicit (see <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>) and there are no cue words in text which link to the provided citations. Therefore, the proposed methodologies and fea- tures from the scientific domain do not perform optimally in our case.</p><p>Both <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">(Qazvinian and Radev, 2010)</ref> and <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(O'Connor, 1982)</ref> work at the sentence level. As, in Wikipedia, citation span detection needs to be performed at the sub-sentence level (see <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>), their method introduces erroneous spans as we will show in our evaluation.</p><p>Related to our problem is the work on address- ing quotation attribution. <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Pareti et al. (2013)</ref> pro- pose an approach for direct and indirect quotation attribution. The task is mostly based on lexical cues and specific reporting verbs that are the sig- nal for the majority of direct quotations. However, in the case of quotation attribution the task is to find the source, cue, and content of the quotation, whereas in our case, for a given citing paragraph and reference we simply assess which text frag- ment is covered by the reference. We also do nor- mally not have access to specific lexical links be- tween the citation and its citation span.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Citation Span Approach</head><p>We approach the problem of citation span de- tection in Wikipedia as a sequence classification problem. For a citation c and a citing paragraph p, we chunk the paragraph into textual fragments at the sub-sentence granularity, shown in Equation 4. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 2</ref> shows an overview of the sequence classification of textual fragments. We use a lin- ear chain CRF ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Lafferty et al., 2001</ref>), where for any fragment δ we predict the label corresponding to a random variable y which is either 'covered' or 'not-covered'. We opt for CRFs since we can en- code global dependencies between the text frag- ments and the actual citation, thus, ensuring the coherence and accuracy of the predicted labels. We now describe the features we compute for the factors Ψ(y i , y i−1 , δ i ) for a fragment δ i w.r.t the citation c. We determine the fitness of δ i hold- ing true or being covered by c. We denote with f k the features for the factors Ψ i (y i , y i−1 , δ i ) for sequence δ i for the linear-chain CRF in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 2</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">Structural Features</head><p>An important aspect to consider for citation span detection is the structure of the citing paragraph, and correspondingly its sentences. For a textual fragment δ, we extract the following structural fea- tures shown in <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Table 2</ref>.  which specifies the distance of δ to the fragment that cites c. The closer a fragment is to the cita- tion the higher the likelihood of it being covered in c. In Wikipedia, depending on the citation and the paragraph length, the validity of a citation is densely concentrated in its nearby sub-sentences (preceding and succeeding).</p><p>Furthermore, the features f #s and f s i (the num- ber of sentences in p together with the feature con- sidering if δ is in the same sentence as c) are strong indicators for accurate prediction of the label of δ. That is, it is more likely for a fragment δ to be cov- ered by the citation if it appears in the same sen- tence or sentences nearby to the citation marker.</p><p>However, as shown in <ref type="table">Table 1</ref> there are three main citation span groups, and as such relying only on the structure of the citing paragraph does not yield optimal results. Hence, in the next group we consider features that tie the individual frag- ments in the citing paragraph with the citation as shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 2</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">Citation Features</head><p>A core indicator as to whether a fragment δ is cov- ered by c is based on the lexical similarity between δ and the content in c. We gather such evidence by computing two similarity measures. We com- pute the features f LM i and f J i between δ and para- graphs in the citation content c.</p><p>The first measure, f LM i , corresponds to a moving language window proposed in <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">(Taneva and Weikum, 2013)</ref>. In this case, for each word in either a paragraph in the citation c or the sequence δ, we associate a language model M w i based on its context ϕ(w i ) = {w i−3 , w i−2 , w i−1 , w i , w i+1 , w i+2 , w i+3 } with a window of +/-3 words. The parameters for the model M w i are estimated as in Equation 2 for all the words in the context ϕ(w i ) and their frequen- cies denoted with tf . With M δ and M p we denote the overall models as estimated in Equation 2 for the words in the respective fragments.</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">P (w|Mw i ) = tf w,ϕ(w i ) ∑ w ′ ∈ϕ(w i ) tf w ′ ,ϕ(w i )<label>(2)</label></formula><p>Finally, we compute the similarity of each word in w ∈ δ against the language model of paragraph p ∈ c in Equation 3, which corresponds to the Kullback-Leibler divergence score.</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">f LM i = min p∈c [ − ∑ w∈δ P (w|M δ ) log P (w|M δ ) P (w|Mp) ]<label>(3)</label></formula><p>The intuition behind f LM i is that for the frag- ments δ we take into account the word similarity and the similarity in the context they appear in w.r.t a paragraph in a citation. In this way, we ensure that the similarity is not by chance but is supported by the context in which the word appears. Finally, another advantage of this model is that we localize the paragraphs in c which provide evidence for δ.</p><p>As an additional feature we compute f J i which corresponds to the maximal jaccard similarity be- tween δ i and paragraphs p ∈ c.</p><p>Finally, as we will show in our experimental evaluation in Section 5, there is a high correlation between the citation span length and the length of citation content in terms of sentences. Hence, we add as an additional feature f c the number of sen- tences in c.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3">Discourse Features</head><p>Sentences and fragments within a sentence can be tied together by discourse relations. We an- notate sentences with explicit discourse relations based on an approach proposed in <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">(Pitler and Nenkova, 2009</ref>), using discourse connectives as cues. The explicit discourse relations belong to one of the following: temporal, contingency, ex- pansion, comparison.</p><p>After extracting a discourse connective in a sen- tence, we determine by its position to which frag- ment it belongs and mark the fragment accord- ingly. We denote with f disc i the discourse feature for the fragment δ i . <ref type="bibr">2</ref> </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.4">Temporal Features</head><p>An important aspect that we consider here is the temporal difference between two consecutive frag- ments δ i and δ i−1 . If there exists a temporal date expression in δ i and δ i−1 and they point to differ- ent time-points, this presents an indicator on the transitioning between the states y i and y i−1 . That is, there is a higher likelihood of changing the state in the sequence S for the labels y i and y i−1 .</p><p>We compute the temporal feature f λ(i,i−1) i ,indicating the difference in days be- tween any two temporal expression extracted from δ i and δ i−1 . We extract the temporal expression through a set of hand-crafted regular expressions. We use the following expressions: (1) DD Month YYYY, (2) DD MM YYYY, (3) MM DD YY(YY), (4) YYYY, with delimiters (whitespace, '-', '.').</p><note type="other">type avg. |s| avg. |δ| avg 'covered' news 7.76 22.55 0.28 web 8.67 23.07 0.30</note></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Experimental Setup</head><p>We now outline the experimental setup for evalu- ating the citation span approach and the competi- tors for this task. The data and the proposed ap- proaches are made available at the paper URL 3 .</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.1">Dataset</head><p>We evaluate the citation span approaches on a ran- dom sample of Wikipedia entities (snapshot of 20/11/2016). For the sampling process, we first group entities based on the number of web or news citations. <ref type="bibr">4</ref> ). We then sample from the specific groups. This is due to the inherent differences in citation spans for entities with different num- bers of citations. For instance, entities with a high number of citations tend to have shorter spans per citation. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 3</ref> shows the distribution of entities from the different groups. From each sampled en- tity, we extract all citing paragraphs that contain either a web or news citation. Our sample consists of 509 citing paragraphs from 134 entities. Furthermore, since a paragraph may have more than one citation, in our sampled citing para- graphs, we have an average of 4.4 citations per paragraph, which finally resulted in 408 unique paragraphs. <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">Table 3</ref> shows the stats of the dataset.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.2">Ground Truth</head><p>Setup. For the ground truth, the citation span of c in paragraph p was manually determined by la- beling each fragment in p with the binary label covered or not-covered.</p><p>We set strict guidelines that help us generate re- liable ground-truth annotations. We follow two main guidelines: (i) requirement to read and com- prehend the content in c, and (ii) matching of the 3 http://l3s.de/ ˜ fetahu/emnlp17/ 4 Wikipedia has an internal categorization of citations based on the reference they point to. textual fragments from p as either being supported explicitly or implicitly in c. <ref type="bibr">5</ref> The entire dataset was carefully annotated by the first author. Later, a second annotator anno- tated a 10% sample of the dataset with an inter- rater agreement of κ = .84. We chose not to use crowd-sourcing as the task is very complex and hard to divide into small independent tasks. Since the task requires reading and comprehending the entire content in c and p, it takes on average up to 2.4 minutes to perform the evaluation for a single item. In future, it would be worthwhile to conduct more large-scale annotation exercises.</p><p>Citation Span Stats. Following the definition in Equation 4, we determine the citation span at the sub-sentence granularity level. <ref type="table">Table 4</ref> shows the distribution of citations falling into the specific spans for the citing paragraphs. We note that the majority of citations have a span between half a sentence and up to a sentence, yet, the remainder of more than 20% of citation span across multiple sentences in such paragraphs.</p><p>We define the citation span as the ratio of sub- sentences which are covered by a given citation over the total number of sub-sentences in the sentence, consequentially in the citing paragraph. That is, a citation is considered to have a span of one sentence if it covers all its sub-sentences.</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">span(c, p) = ∑ s∈p #δ s ∈ S ′ #δ s<label>(4)</label></formula><p>where δ s represents a sequence in sentence s ∈ p, which are part of the the ground-truth.</p><p>In <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Figure 4</ref>, we analyze a possible factor in the variance of the citation span. It is evident that for longer cited documents the span increases. This is total ≤ .5 (.5, 1] (1, 2] (2, 5] &gt; <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">5   news 318 35  201  54  22  6  web 191 13  121  27  25  6   Table 4</ref>: Citation span distribution based on the number of sub-sentences in the citing paragraph.</p><p>intuitive since such documents carry more infor- mation and consequentially their span in the cit- ing paragraphs can be larger. An example is the Wikipedia article 2008 US Open (tennis) which has a citing paragraph with a citation span of 7 sentences for an article of 30k characters long <ref type="bibr">6</ref> . We encoded this in the citation features f c . Additionally, within the different citation spans we analyze how many of them contain skips for two cases: (i) skip a fragment within a sentence, and (ii) skip sentences in p. The results for both cases are presented in <ref type="table">Table 5</ref>. <ref type="table">Table 5</ref>: The percentage of citations in a span with fragment skips and sentence skips.</p><formula xml:id="formula_4">span news web skip δ skip s skip δ skip s ≤ 0.5 6% - - - (0.5, 1] - - - 1% (1, 2] - 8% - 19% (2, 5] 5% 18% - 21% &gt; 5 - 20% - 67%</formula><p>From the results in <ref type="table">Table 4</ref> and 5 we see that simple heuristics on selecting complete sentences or selecting consecutive sequences do not account for the different citation span cases and skips at the sentence and paragraph level. This leads to subop- timal results and introduces erroneous spans. Fur- thermore, we find that in 3.7% of the cases in our ground-truth, the citation spans include fragments after the citation marker.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.3">Baselines</head><p>We consider the following baselines as competi- tors for our citation span approach.</p><p>Inter-Citation Text -IC. The span consists of sentences which start either at the beginning of the paragraph or at the end of a previous citation. The granularity is at the sentence level.</p><p>Citation-Sentence-Window -CSW. The span consists of sentences in a window of +/-2 sen- tences from the citing sentence <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(O'Connor, 1982)</ref>. The other sentences are included if they contain specific cue words in fixed positions.</p><p>Citing Sentence -CS. The span consists of only the citing sentence.</p><p>Markov Random Fields - MRF. MRFs ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Qazvinian and Radev, 2010</ref>) model two functions. First, compatibility, which mea- sures the similarity of sentences in p, and as such allows to extract non-citing sentences. Second, the potential, which measures the similarity between sentences in c with sentences in p. We use the provided implementation by the authors.</p><p>Citation Span Plain -CSPC. A plain clas- sification setup using the features in Section 4, where the sequences are classified in isolation. We use Random Forests <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Breiman, 2001</ref>) and evaluate them with 5-fold cross validation.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.4">Citation Span Approach Setup -CSPS</head><p>For our approach CSP S as mentioned in Sec- tion 4, we opt for linear-chain CRFs and use the implementation in <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(Okazaki, 2007)</ref>. We evaluate our models using 5-fold cross validation, and learn the optimal parameters for the CRF model through the L-BFGS approach ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Liu and Nocedal, 1989)</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.5">Evaluation Metrics</head><p>We measure the performance of the citation span approaches through the following metrics. We will denote with W ′ the sampled entities, with p = {p c , . . .} (p c refers to ⟨p, c⟩) the set of sam- pled paragraphs from e, and with |p| the total items from e.</p><p>Mean Average Precision -M AP . First, we define precision for p c as the ratio P (p c ) = |S ′ ∩ S t |/|S ′ | of fragments present in S ′ ∩ S t over S ′ . We measure MAP as in Equation 5.</p><formula xml:id="formula_5">M AP = 1 |W ′ | ∑ e∈W ′ ∑ pc∈p P (pc) |p| (5)</formula><p>Recall -R. We measure the recall for p c as the ratio S ′ ∩ S t over all fragments in S t , R(p c ) = |S ′ ∩ S t |/|S t |. We average the individual recall scores for e ∈ W ′ for the corresponding p.</p><formula xml:id="formula_6">R = 1 |W ′ | ∑ e∈W ′ ∑ pc∈p R(pc) |p| (6)</formula><p>Erroneous Span -∆. We measure the num- ber of extra words or extra sub-sentences (denoted with ∆ w and ∆ δ ) added by text fragments that are not part of the ground-truth S t . The ratio is rel- ative to the number of words or sub-sentences in the ground-truth for p c . We compute ∆ w and ∆ δ in Equation 7 and 8, respectively.</p><formula xml:id="formula_7">∆w = 1 |W ′ | ∑ e∈W ′ 1 |p| ∑ pc∈p ∑ δ∈S ′ \S t words(δ) ∑ δ∈S t words(δ)<label>(7)</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_8">∆ δ = 1 |W ′ | ∑ e∈W ′ 1 |p| ∑ pc∈p |S ′ \ S t | |S t |<label>(8)</label></formula><p>6 Results and Discussion <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">Table 6</ref> shows the results for the different ap- proaches on determining the citation span for all span cases shown in <ref type="table">Table 4</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.1">Citation Span Robustness</head><p>Accuracy. Not surprisingly, the baseline ap- proaches perform reasonably well. CS which se- lects only the citing sentence achieves a reasonable M AP = 0.86 and similar recall. A slightly dif- ferent baseline CSW achieves comparable scores with M AP = 0.85. This is due to the inherent span structure in Wikipedia, where a large portion of citations span up to a sentence (see <ref type="table">Table 4</ref>). Therefore, in approximately 64% of the cases the baselines will select the correct span. For the cases where the span is more than a sentence, the draw- back of these baselines is in coverage. We show in the next section a detailed decomposition of the re- sults and highlight why even in the simpler cases, a sentence level granularity has its shortcomings due to sequence skips as shown in <ref type="table">Table 5</ref>.</p><p>Overall, when comparing CS as the best per- forming baseline against our approach CSP S, we achieve an overall score of M AP = 0.83 (a slight decrease of 3.6%), whereas in term of F1 score, we have a decrease of 9%. The plain- classification approach CSP C achieves similar score with M AP = 0.86, whereas in terms of F1 score, we have a decrease of 8%. As de- scribed above and as we will see later on in Ta- ble 7, the overall good performance of the baseline approaches can be attributed to the citation span distribution in our ground-truth.</p><p>On the other hand, an interesting observation is that sophisticated approaches, geared towards sci- entific domains like M RF perform poorly. We attribute this to language style, i.e., in Wikipedia there are no explicit citation hooks that are present in scientific articles. Comparing to CSP S, we outperform M RF by a large margin with an in- crease in M AP by 84%.</p><p>When comparing the sequence classifier CSP S to the plain classifier CSP C, we see a marginal difference of 1.3% for F1. However, it will be- come more evident later that classifying jointly the text fragments for the different span buckets, out- performs the plain classification model.  Erroneous Span. One of the major drawbacks of competing approaches is the granularity at which the span is determined. This leads to er- roneous spans. <ref type="table">From Table 4</ref> we see that approx- imately in ∼10% of the cases the span is at sub- sentence level, and in 28% the span is more than a sentence. The best performing baseline CS has an erro- neous span of ∆ w = 35% and ∆ δ = 27%, in terms of extra words and sub-sentences, respec- tively. That is, nearly half of the determined span is erroneous, or in other words it is not covered in the provided citation. The M RF approach due to its poor M AP score provides the largest erro- neous spans with ∆ w = 308% and ∆ δ = 278%. The amount of erroneous span is unevenly dis- tributed, that is, in cases where the span is not at the sentence level granularity the amount of erro- neous span increases. A detailed analysis is pro- vided in the next section.</p><p>Contrary to the baselines, for CSP S and simi- larly for CSP C, we achieve the lowest erroneous spans with ∆ w = 32% and ∆ δ = 26%, and ∆ w = 24% and ∆ w = 23%, respectively.</p><p>Compared to the remaining baselines, we achieve an overall relative decrease of 9% for ∆ w (CSP S), and 34% for ∆ w (CSP C), when compared to the best performing baseline CS.</p><p>From the skips in sequences in <ref type="table">Table 5</ref> and the unsuitability of sentence granularity for citation spans, we analyze the locality of erroneous spans w.r.t to the sequence that contains c, specifically the distribution of erroneous spans preceding and succeeding it. For the CS baseline, 71% of the total erroneous spans are added by sequences pre- ceding the citing sequence, contrary to 35% which succeed it. In the case of CSP S, we have only 9% of erroneous spans (for ∆ δ ) preceding the citation.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.2">Citation Span and Feature Analysis</head><p>We now analyze how the approaches perform for the different citation spans in <ref type="table">Table 4</ref> 7 . Addition- ally, we analyze how our approach CSP S per- forms when determining the span without access to the content of c.</p><p>Citation Span. <ref type="table">Table 7</ref> shows the results for the approaches under comparison for all the citation span cases. In the case where the citation spans up to a sentence, that is (0.5, 1], which presents the simplest citation span case, the baselines per- form reasonably well. This is due to the heuris- tics they apply to determine the span, which in all cases includes the citing sentence. In terms of F 1 score, the baseline CS achieves a highly compet- itive score of F 1 = 0.97. Our approach CSP S in this case has slight increase of 1% for F 1 and an increase of 3% for M AP . CSP C achieves a similar performance in this case.</p><p>However, for the cases where the span is at the sub-sentence level or across multiple sentences, the performance of baselines drops drastically. In the first bucket (≤ 0.5) which accounts for 9% of ground-truth data, we achieve the highest score with M AP = 0.87, though with lower recall than the competitors with R = 0.56. The reason for this is that the baselines take complete sentences, thus, having perfect recall at the cost of accuracy. In terms of F 1 score we achieve 21% better results than the best performing baseline CS.</p><p>For the span of <ref type="bibr">(1,</ref><ref type="bibr">2]</ref> we maintain an overall high accuracy and recall, and have the highest F 1 score. The improvement is 8% in terms of F 1 score. Finally, for the last case where the span is more than 2 sentences, we achieve M AP = 0.74, a marginal increase of 3%, however with lower re- call, which results in an overall decrease of 4% for F 1. The statistical significance tests are indicated with ** and * in <ref type="table">Table 7</ref>. Erroneous Span. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Figure 5</ref> shows the erroneous spans in terms of words for the metric ∆ w for all citation span cases. It is noteworthy that the amount of error can be well beyond 100% due to the ratio of the suggested span and the actual span in our ground-truth, which can be higher.</p><p>In the first bucket (span of ≤ 0.5) with granu- larity less than a sentence, all the competing ap- proaches introduce large erroneous spans. For CSP S we have a M AP = 0.87, and conse- quentially we have the lowest ∆ w = 9%, while for CSP C we have only ∆ w = 11%. In con- trast, the non-ML competitors introduce a mini- mum of ∆ w (CS) = 182%, with MRFs having the highest error. We also perform well in the bucket (0.5, 1]. For larger spans, for instance, for <ref type="bibr">(1,</ref><ref type="bibr">2]</ref>, we are still slightly better, with roughly 3% less erroneous span when comparing CSP C and CS. However, only in the case of spans with &gt; 2, we perform below the CS baseline. Despite, the smaller erroneous span, the CS baseline never in- cludes more than one sentence, and as such it does not include many erroneous spans for the larger buckets. However, it is by definition unable to rec- ognize any longer spans.</p><p>Feature Analysis. It is worthwhile to investigate the performance gains in determining the citation span without analyzing the content of the citation. The reason for this is that there are several cita-  <ref type="table">Table 7</ref>: Evaluation results for the citation span approaches for the different span cases. For the results of CSP S we compute the relative increase/decrease of F 1 score compared to the best result (based on F 1) from the competitors. We mark in bold the best results for the evaluation metrics, and indicate with ** and * the results which are highly significant (p &lt; 0.001) and significant (p &lt; 0.05) based on t-test statistics when compared to the best performing baselines (CS, IC, CSW, MRF) based on F1 score, respectively.</p><formula xml:id="formula_9">≤ 0.5 (0.5, 1] (1, 2] &gt; 2 MAP R F1 MAP R F1 MAP R F1 MAP R F1 MRF</formula><p>tion categories for which access to the source can- not be easily automated. Models which can deter- mine the span accurately without the actual con- tent have the advantage of generalizing to other citation sources (e.g. books) for which the evalua- tion is more challenging. <ref type="bibr">8</ref> Here, we disregard the citation features from Section 4.2. In terms of M AP , we have a slight decrease with M AP = 0.82 when compared to the model with the citation features. For recall we have a drop of 3%, resulting in R = 0.67.</p><p>This shows that by solely relying on the struc- ture of the citing paragraph and other structural and discourse features we can perform the task with reasonable accuracy.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7">Conclusion</head><p>In this work, we tackled the problem of determin- ing the fine-grained citation span of references in Wikipedia. We started from the citing paragraph and decomposed it into sequences consisting of sub-sentences. To accurately determine the span we proposed features that leverage the structure of the paragraph, discourse and temporal features, and finally analyzed the similarity between the cit- ing paragraph and the citation content.</p><p>We introduce both a standard classifier as well as a sequence classifier using a linear-chain CRF model. For evaluation we manually annotated a ground-truth dataset of 509 citing paragraphs. We reported standard evaluation metrics and also in- 8 At worst, one needs to read and comprehend the entire book to determine if a fragment is covered by the citation. troduced metrics that measure the amount of erro- neous span.</p><p>We achieved a M AP = 0.86, in the case of the plain classification model CSP C, and with a marginal difference for CSP S with M AP = 0.83, across all cases with an erroneous span of ∆ w = 26% or ∆ w = 32%, depending on the model. Thus, we provide accurate means on de- termining the span and at the same time decrease the erroneous span by 34% compared to the best performing baselines. Moreover, we excel at de- termining citation spans at the sub-sentence level.</p><p>In conclusion, this presents an initial attempt on solving the citation span for references in Wikipedia. As future work we foresee a larger ground-truth and more robust approaches which take into account factors such as a reference being irrelevant to a citing paragraph and cases where the evidence for a paragraph is implied rather than explicitly stated in the reference.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2: Linear chain CRF representing the sequence of text fragments in a paragraph. In the factors we encode the fitness to the given citation.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>factor description f c ′ i presence of other citations in δi where c ′ ̸ = c f #s the number of sentences in p f |δ i | i the length in terms of characters of the sub-sequence f s i check if δi is in the same sentence as the citation c f s̸ =s ′ i check if δi is in the same sentence as δi−1 f c i the distance of fragment δi to the frag- ment which contains citation c</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Figure 3: Entity distribution based on the number of news citations.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>Figure 4 :</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Figure 4: Average document length for the different span buckets for citation types web and news.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head>Figure 5 :</head><label>5</label><figDesc>Figure 5: Erroneous spans for the different citation span buckets. The y-axis presents the ∆ w whereas in the x-axis are shown the different approaches.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" validated="false"><head>.</head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><table>sub 
sentence 
Obama was born on August 4, 1961 [c 1 ] , at 
Kapi'olani Maternity · · · Honolulu [c 2 ] ; he 
is the first · · · been born in Hawaii. [c 3 ] . 

sentence He was reelected to the Illinois Senate in 
1998, · · · in 2002. [c 1 ] 

multi 
sentence 
On May 25, 2011, Obama · · · to address · · · 
UK Parliament in Westminster Hall, Lon-
don. This was · · · Charles de Gaulle · · · and 
Pope Benedict XVI. [c 1 ] 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" validated="false"><head>Table 2 : Structural features for a fragment δ i .</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>From the features in Table 2, we highlight f c 

i 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" validated="false"><head>Table 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Dataset statistics for citing paragraphs, 
distinguishing between web and news references, 
showing the average number of sentences, frag-
ments, and covered fragments. 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4" validated="false"><head>Table 6 :</head><label>6</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Evaluation results for the different cita-
tion span approaches. 

</table></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/ Wikipedia:Identifying_reliable_sources</note>

			<note place="foot" n="2"> Note that, although discourse relations hold between at least two fragments or sentences, we only mark the individual fragment in which the connective occurs with the discourse relation type.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="5"> We excluded cases where the citation is not appropriate for the paragraph at all. This is, for example, the case when the language of c is not English.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="6"> http://news.bbc.co.uk/sport1/hi/ tennis/7601195.stm</note>

			<note place="foot" n="7"> The models were retrained and tested for the different buckets with 5-fold cross validation.</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>This work is funded by the ERC Advanced Grant ALEXANDRIA (grant no. 339233), and H2020 AFEL project (grant no. 687916).</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Reference scope identification in citing sentences</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Amjad</forename><surname>Abu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">-Jbara</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dragomir</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Radev</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Human Language Technologies: Conference of the North American Chapter of the Association of Computational Linguistics, Proceedings</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Montréal, Canada</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012-06-03" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="80" to="90" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Random forests. Machine Learning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Leo</forename><surname>Breiman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">45</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="5" to="32" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Blind men and elephants: What do citation summaries tell us about a research article?</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Aaron</forename><surname>Elkiss</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Siwei</forename><surname>Shen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Anthony</forename><surname>Fader</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Günes</forename><surname>Erkan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>States</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dragomir</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Radev</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">JASIST</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">59</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="51" to="62" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">How much is wikipedia lagging behind news?</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Besnik</forename><surname>Fetahu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Abhijit</forename><surname>Anand</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Avishek</forename><surname>Anand</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the ACM Web Science Conference</title>
		<meeting>the ACM Web Science Conference<address><addrLine>WebSci; Oxford, United Kingdom</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015-06-28" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">28</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">9</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Automated news suggestions for populating wikipedia entity pages</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Besnik</forename><surname>Fetahu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Katja</forename><surname>Markert</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Avishek</forename><surname>Anand</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 24th ACM International Conference on Information and Knowledge Management, CIKM 2015</title>
		<meeting>the 24th ACM International Conference on Information and Knowledge Management, CIKM 2015<address><addrLine>Melbourne, VIC, Australia</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015-10-19" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="323" to="332" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Finding news citations for wikipedia</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Besnik</forename><surname>Fetahu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Katja</forename><surname>Markert</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wolfgang</forename><surname>Nejdl</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Avishek</forename><surname>Anand</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 25th ACM International on Conference on Information and Knowledge Management, CIKM 2016</title>
		<meeting>the 25th ACM International on Conference on Information and Knowledge Management, CIKM 2016<address><addrLine>Indianapolis, IN, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016-10-24" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="337" to="346" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Citation indexes for science: A new dimension in documentation through association of ideas</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Eugene</forename><surname>Garfield</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">122</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3159</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="108" to="111" />
			<date type="published" when="1955" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Citation block determination using textual coherence</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dain</forename><surname>Kaplan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Takenobu</forename><surname>Tokunaga</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Simone</forename><surname>Teufel</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">JIP</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="540" to="553" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Conditional random fields: Probabilistic models for segmenting and labeling sequence data</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">John</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Lafferty</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Andrew</forename><surname>Mccallum</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Fernando</forename><forename type="middle">C N</forename><surname>Pereira</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Eighteenth International Conference on Machine Learning</title>
		<meeting>the Eighteenth International Conference on Machine Learning<address><addrLine>Williams College, Williamstown, MA, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2001-06-28" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="282" to="289" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">On the limited memory bfgs method for large scale optimization</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Dong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jorge</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Nocedal</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Mathematical programming</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">45</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="503" to="528" />
			<date type="published" when="1989" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Towards multi-paper summarization using reference information</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hidetsugu</forename><surname>Nanba</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Manabu</forename><surname>Okumura</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Sixteenth International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence, IJCAI 99</title>
		<meeting>the Sixteenth International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence, IJCAI 99<address><addrLine>Stockholm, Sweden</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1450" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="926" to="931" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The pyramid method: Incorporating human content selection variation in summarization evaluation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ani</forename><surname>Nenkova</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rebecca</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Passonneau</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kathleen</forename><surname>Mckeown</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">TSLP</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">4</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Citing statements: Computer recognition and use to improve retrieval</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O&amp;apos;</forename><surname>John</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Connor</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Inf. Process. Manage</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">18</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="125" to="131" />
			<date type="published" when="1982" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Crfsuite: a fast implementation of conditional random fields (crfs)</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Naoaki</forename><surname>Okazaki</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Automatically detecting and attributing indirect quotations</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Silvia</forename><surname>Pareti</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O&amp;apos;</forename><surname>Timothy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ioannis</forename><surname>Keefe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">James</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Konstas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Irena</forename><surname>Curran</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Koprinska</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2013 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing, EMNLP 2013</title>
		<meeting>the 2013 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing, EMNLP 2013<address><addrLine>Seattle, Washington, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013-10" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="989" to="999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>A meeting of SIGDAT, a Special Interest Group of the ACL</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Using syntax to disambiguate explicit discourse connectives in text</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Emily</forename><surname>Pitler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ani</forename><surname>Nenkova</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ACL 2009, Proceedings of the 47th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics and the 4th International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing of the AFNLP</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Singapore, Short Papers</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009-02-07" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="13" to="16" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Scientific paper summarization using citation summary networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Vahed</forename><surname>Qazvinian</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dragomir</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Radev</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">COLING 2008, 22nd International Conference on Computational Linguistics, Proceedings of the Conference</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>UK</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008-08" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="689" to="696" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Identifying non-explicit citing sentences for citationbased summarization</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Vahed</forename><surname>Qazvinian</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Dragomir</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Radev</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ACL 2010, Proceedings of the 48th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Uppsala, Sweden</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010-07-11" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="555" to="564" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Comparing citation contexts for information retrieval</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Anna</forename><surname>Ritchie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Stephen</forename><surname>Robertson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Simone</forename><surname>Teufel</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 17th ACM Conference on Information and Knowledge Management, CIKM</title>
		<meeting>the 17th ACM Conference on Information and Knowledge Management, CIKM<address><addrLine>Napa Valley, California, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008-10-26" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="213" to="222" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">How to find better index terms through citations</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Anna</forename><surname>Ritchie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Simone</forename><surname>Teufel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Stephen</forename><surname>Robertson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Workshop on How Can Computational Linguistics Improve Information Retrieval?, CLIIR &apos;06</title>
		<meeting>the Workshop on How Can Computational Linguistics Improve Information Retrieval?, CLIIR &apos;06<address><addrLine>Stroudsburg, PA, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="25" to="32" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Gembased entity-knowledge maintenance</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bilyana</forename><surname>Taneva</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gerhard</forename><surname>Weikum</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page">22</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<monogr>
				<title level="m">ACM International Conference on Information and Knowledge Management, CIKM&apos;13</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>San Francisco, CA, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013-11-01" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="149" to="158" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">On the summarization of dynamically introduced information: Online discussions and blogs</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Liang</forename><surname>Zhou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Eduard</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Hovy</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">AAAI Spring symposium: Computational approaches to analyzing weblogs</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
			<biblScope unit="page">237</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
