<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T13:03+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">The NLTK FrameNet API: Designing for Discoverability with a Rich Linguistic Resource</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
				<availability status="unknown"><p>Copyright Association for Computational Linguistics</p>
				</availability>
				<date>September 7-11, 2017. 2017</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nathan</forename><surname>Schneider</surname></persName>
							<email>nathan.schneider@georgetown.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Georgetown University Washington</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">Semantic Machines Berkeley</orgName>
								<address>
									<region>DC, CA</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chuck</forename><surname>Wooters</surname></persName>
							<email>wooters@semanticmachines.com</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Georgetown University Washington</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">Semantic Machines Berkeley</orgName>
								<address>
									<region>DC, CA</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">The NLTK FrameNet API: Designing for Discoverability with a Rich Linguistic Resource</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="j" type="main">EMNLP System Demonstrations</title>
						<meeting> <address><addrLine>Copenhagen, Denmark</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="6"/>
							<date type="published">September 7-11, 2017. 2017</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>A new Python API, integrated within the NLTK suite, offers access to the FrameNet 1.7 lexical database. The lexicon (struc-tured in terms of frames) as well as annotated sentences can be processed progra-matically, or browsed with human-readable displays via the interactive Python prompt.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>For over a decade, the Berkeley FrameNet (hence- forth, simply "FrameNet") project ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Baker et al., 1998</ref>) has been documenting the vocabulary of contemporary English with respect to the theory of frame semantics <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Fillmore, 1982)</ref>. A freely available, linguistically-rich resource, FrameNet now covers over 1,000 semantic frames, 10,000 lexical senses, and 100,000 lexical annotations in sentences drawn from corpora. The resource has formed a basis for much research in natural lan- guage processing-most notably, a tradition of semantic role labeling that continues to this day ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Gildea and Jurafsky, 2002;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Baker et al., 2007;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Das et al., 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b7">FitzGerald et al., 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr">Roth and Lapata, 2015, inter alia)</ref>.</p><p>Despite the importance of FrameNet, computa- tional users are often frustrated by the complexity of its custom XML format. Whereas much of the re- source is browsable on the web (http://framenet. icsi.berkeley.edu/), certain details of the lin- guistic descriptions and annotations languish in obscurity as they are not exposed by the HTML views of the data. <ref type="bibr">1</ref> The few open source APIs for <ref type="bibr">1</ref> For example, one of the authors was recently asked by a FrameNet user whether frame-to-frame relations in- clude mappings between individual frame elements. They do, but the user's confusion is understandable because these mappings are not exposed in the HTML frame definitions on the website. (They can be explored visually via the FrameGrapher tool on the website, https://framenet.icsi.</p><p>reading FrameNet data are now antiquated, and none has been widely adopted. <ref type="bibr">2</ref> We describe a new, user-friendly Python API for accessing FrameNet data. The API is included within recent releases of the popular NLTK suite ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Bird et al., 2009)</ref>, and provides access to nearly all the information in the FrameNet release.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Installation</head><p>Instructions for installing NLTK are found at nltk.org. NLTK is cross-platform and supports Python 2.7 as well as Python 3.x environments. It is bundled in the Anaconda and Enthought Canopy Python distributions for data scientists. <ref type="bibr">3</ref> In a working NLTK installation (version 3.2.2 or later), one merely has to invoke a method to download the FrameNet data: <ref type="bibr">4,</ref><ref type="bibr">5</ref> &gt;&gt;&gt; import nltk &gt;&gt;&gt; nltk.download <ref type="bibr">('framenet _ v17')</ref> berkeley.edu/fndrupal/FrameGrapher, if the user knows to look there.) In the interest of space, our API does not show them in the frame display, but they can be accessed via an individual frame relation object or with the fe _ relations() method, §4.4. <ref type="bibr">2</ref> We are aware of:</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">• github.com/dasmith/FrameNet-python (Python) • nlp.stanford.edu/software/framenet.shtml (Java) • github.com/FabianFriedrich/Text2Process/tree/ master/src/de/saar/coli/salsa/reiter/framenet (Java)</formula><p>• github.com/GrammaticalFramework/gf-contrib/tree/ master/framenet (Grammatical Framework) None of these has been updated in the past few years, so they are likely not fully compatible with the latest data release.</p><p>Subsequently, the framenet module is loaded as follows (with alias fn for convenience):</p><p>&gt;&gt;&gt; from nltk.corpus import framenet as fn</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Overview of FrameNet</head><p>FrameNet is organized around conceptual struc- tures known as frames. A semantic frame repre- sents a scene-a kind of event, state, or other sce- nario which may be universal or culturally-specific, and domain-general or domain-specific. The frame defines participant roles or frame elements (FEs), whose relationships forms the conceptual back- ground required to understand (certain senses of) vocabulary items. Oft-cited examples by Fillmore include:</p><p>• Verbs such as buy, sell, and pay, and nouns such as buyer, seller, price, and purchase, are all de- fined with respect to a commercial transaction scene (frame). FEs that are central to this frame- they may or may not be mentioned explicitly in a text with one of the aforementioned lexical items-are the Buyer, the Seller, the Goods be- ing sold by the Seller, and the Money given as payment in exchange by the Buyer.</p><p>• The concept of REVENGE-lexicalized in vocab- ulary items such as revenge, avenge, avenger, retaliate, payback, and get even-fundamentally presupposes an Injury that an Offender has in- flicted upon an Injured_party, for which an Avenger (who may or may not be the same as the Injured_party) seeks to exact some Punish- ment on the Offender.</p><p>• A hypotenuse presupposes a geometrical notion of right triangle, while a pedestrian presupposes a street with both vehicular and nonvehicular traffic. (Neither frame is currently present in FrameNet.) The FEs in a frame are formally listed alongside an English description of their function within the frame. Frames are organized in a network, includ- ing an inheritance hierarchy (e.g., REVENGE is a special case of an EVENT) and other kinds of frame- to-frame relations.</p><p>Vocabulary items listed within a frame are called lexical units (LUs). FrameNet's inventory of LUs includes both content and function words. For- mally, an LU links a lemma with a frame. <ref type="bibr">6</ref> In a text, a token of an LU is said to evoke the frame. Sentences are annotated with respect to frame-evoking tokens and their FE spans. Thus:</p><p>[Snape] Injured_party 's revenge [on Harry] Offender labels overt mentions of participants in the RE- VENGE frame.</p><p>The reader is referred to (Fillmore and Baker, 2009) for a contemporary introduction to the re- source and the theory of frame semantics upon which it is based. Extensive linguistic details are provided in <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(Ruppenhofer et al., 2016</ref>).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">API Overview</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">Design Principles</head><p>The API is designed with the following goals in mind:</p><p>Simplicity. It should be easy to access important objects in the database (primarily frames, lexical units, and annotations), whether by iterating over all entries or searching for particular ones. To avoid cluttering the API with too many methods, other information in the database should be reachable via object attributes. Calling the API's help() method prints a summary of the main methods for access- ing information in the database. Discoverability. Many of the details of the database are complex. The API makes it easy to browse what is in database objects via the Python interactive prompt. The main way it achieves this is with pretty-printed displays of the objects, such as the frame display in figure 1 (see §4.3). The display makes it clear how to access attributes of the object that a novice user of FrameNet might not have known about.</p><p>In our view, this approach sets this API apart from others. Some of the other NLTK APIs for complex structured data make it difficult to browse the structure without consulting documentation. On-demand loading. The database is stored in thousands of XML files, including files index- ing the lists of frames, frame relations, LUs, and full-text documents, plus individual files for all frames, LUs, and full-text documents. Unzipped, the FrameNet 1.7 release is 855 MB. Loading all of these files-particularly the corpus annotations-is slow and memory-intensive, costs which are unnec- essary for many purposes. Therefore, the API is carefully designed with lazy data structures to load XML files only as needed. Once loaded, all data is cached in memory for fast subsequent access.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>frame (347): Revenge</head><p>[URL] https://framenet2.icsi.berkeley.edu/fnReports/data/frame/Revenge.xml <ref type="bibr">[definition]</ref> This frame concerns the infliction of punishment in return for a wrong suffered. An Avenger performs a Punishment on a Offender as a consequence of an earlier action by the Offender, the Injury. The Avenger inflicting thePunishment need not be the same as the Injured _ Party who suffered the Injury, but the Avenger does have to share the judgment that the Offender's action was wrong. The judgment that the Offender had inflicted an Injury is made without regard to the law. '(1) They took revenge for the deaths of two loyalist prisoners.' '(2) Lachlan went out to avenge them.' '(3) The next day, the Roman forces took revenge on their enemies..'</p><p>[semTypes] 0 semantic types </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">Lexicon Access Methods</head><p>The main methods for looking up information in the lexicon are: The methods with plural names (left) are for search- ing the lexicon by regular expression pattern to be matched against the entry name. In addition (or instead), lus() and fes() allow for the results to be restricted to a particular frame. A short while later Joseph had his revenge on Watney 's . -------------------------^^^ ---******* ------------ Time</p><p>Avenge sup Ave Offender</p><p>[Injury:DNI] (Avenge=Avenger, sup=supp, Ave=Avenger)</p><p>Figure 2: A lexicographic sentence display. The visualization of the frame annotation set at the bottom is produced by pretty- printing the combined information in the text, Target, FE, and Noun layers. Abbreviations in the visualization are expanded at the bottom in parentheses ("supp" is short for "support"). "DNI" is FrameNet jargon for "definite null instantiation"; GF stands for "grammatical function"; and PT stands for "phrase type".</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3">Database Objects</head><p>All structured objects in the database-frames, LUs, FEs, etc.-are loaded as AttrDict data struc- tures. Each AttrDict instance is a mapping from string keys to values, which can be strings, num- bers, or structured objects. AttrDict is so called because it allows keys to be accessed as attributes: For the most important kinds of structured ob- jects, the API specifies textual displays that or- ganize the object's contents in a human-readable fashion. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref> shows the display for the RE- VENGE frame, which would be printed by entering fn.frame('Revenge') at the interactive prompt. The display gives attribute names in square brackets; e.g., lexUnit, which is a mapping from LU names to objects. Thus, after the code listing in the previous paragraph, f.lexUnit <ref type="bibr">['revenge.n']</ref> would access to one of the LU objects in the frame, which in turn has its own attributes and textual display.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.4">Advanced Lexicon Access</head><p>Frame relations. The inventory of frames is or- ganized in a semantic network via several kinds of frame-to-frame relations. For instance, the REVENGE frame is involved in one frame-to- frame relation: it is related to the more gen- eral REWARDS_AND_PUNISHMENTS frame by Inher- itance, as shown in the middle of <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">figure 1</ref>. RE- WARDS_AND_PUNISHMENTS, in turn, is involved in Inheritance relations with other frames. Each frame-to-frame relation bundles mappings between corresponding FEs in the two frames.</p><p>Apart from the frameRelations attribute of frame objects, frame-to-frame rela- tions can be browsed by the main method frame _ relations(frame, frame2, type), where the optional arguments allow for filtering by one or both frames and the kind of relation. Within a frame relation object, pairwise FE relations are stored in the feRelations attribute. Main method fe _ relations() provides direct access to links between FEs. The inventory of relation types, including Inheritance, Causative, Inchoative, Subframe, Perspective_on, and others, is available They 've been looking for him all the time for their revenge , ******* ******* Seeking Revenge <ref type="bibr">[3]</ref> ? <ref type="bibr">[2]</ref> but it is only now that they have begun to find him out . "</p><note type="other">full-text sentence (4148528) in Tiger _ Of _ San _ Pedro:</note><formula xml:id="formula_1">***** **** Proce Beco [1]</formula><p>[4] (Proce=Process _ start, Beco=Becoming _ aware) <ref type="figure">Figure 3</ref>: A sentence of full-text annotation. If this sentence object is stored under the variable sent, its frame annotation with respect to the target revenge is accessed as sent.annotationSet <ref type="bibr">[2]</ref>. (The ? under looking indicates that there is no corresponding LU defined in the SEEKING frame; in some cases the full-text annotators marked but did not define out-of- vocabulary LUs which fit an existing frame. Also, some full-text annotation sets annotate an LU without its FEs-these are shown with ! to reflect the annotation set's status code of <ref type="bibr">UNANN.)</ref> via main method frame _ relation _ types().</p><p>Semantic types. These provide additional se- mantic categorizations of FEs, frames, and LUs. For FEs, they mark selectional restrictions (e.g., f.FE <ref type="bibr">['Avenger']</ref>.semType gives the Sentient type). Main method propagate _ semtypes() propogates the FE semantic type labels marked explicitly to other FEs according to inference rules that follow the FE relations. This should be called prior to inspecting FE semtypes (it is not called by default because it takes several seconds to run).</p><p>The semantic types are database objects in their own right, and they are organized in their own inher- itance hierarchy. Main method semtypes() returns all semantic types as a list; main method semtype() looks up a particular one by name, ID, or abbre- viation; and main method semtype _ inherits() checks whether two semantic types have a subtype- supertype relationship.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.5">Corpus Access</head><p>Frame-semantic annotations of sentences can be ac- cessed via the exemplars and subCorpus attributes of an LU object, or via the following main methods: annotations() returns a list of frame annota- tion sets. Each annotation set consists of a frame- evoking target (token) within a sentence, the LU in the frame it evokes, its overt FE spans in the sentence, and the status of null-instatiated FEs. 8 Optionally, the user may filter by LU name, or limit by the type of annotation (see next paragraph): exemplars and full _ text both default to True. In the XML, the components of an annotation set are stored in several annotation layers: one (and some- times more than one) layer of FEs, as well as addi- tional layers for other syntactic information (includ- ing grammatical function and phrase type labels for each FE, and copular or support words relative to the frame-evoking target). Annotation sets are organized by sentence. Cor- pus sentences appear in two kinds of annota- tion: exemplars() retrieves sentences with lexi- cographic annotation (where a single target has been selected for annotation to serve as an example of an LU); the optional argument allows for filter- ing the set of LUs. ft _ sents() retrieves sentences from documents selected for full-text annotation (as many targets in the document as possible have been annotated); the optional argument allows for filtering by document name. sents() can be used to iterate over all sentences. Technically, each sen- tence object contains multiple annotation sets: the first is for sentence-level annotations, including the part-of-speech tagging and in some cases named entity labels; subsequent annotation sets are for frame annotations. As lexicographic annotations have only one frame annotation set, it is visualized in the sentence display: <ref type="figure">figure 2</ref> shows the display for f.lexUnit <ref type="bibr">['revenge.n']</ref>.exemplars <ref type="bibr">[20]</ref>. Full-text annotations display target information only, allow- ing the user to drill down to see each annotation set, as in <ref type="figure">figure 3</ref>.</p><p>Sentences of full-text annotation can also be browsed by document using the doc() and docs() methods. The document display lists the sentences with numeric offsets.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Limitations and future work</head><p>The main part of the Berkeley FrameNet data that the API currently does not support are valence patterns. For a given LU, the valence patterns summarize the FEs' syntactic realizations across annotated tokens. They are displayed in each LU's "Lexical Entry" report on the FrameNet website.</p><p>We intend to add support for valence patterns in future releases, along with more sophisticated querying/browsing capabilities for annotations, and better displays for syntactic information associated with FE annotations. Some of this functionality can be modeled after tools like FrameSQL <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Sato, 2003)</ref> and Valencer ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Kabbach and Ribeyre, 2016)</ref>. In ad- dition, it is worth investigating whether the API can be adapted for FrameNets in other languages, and to support cross-lingual mappings being added to 14 of these other FrameNets in the ongoing Mul- tilingual FrameNet project. 9</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>[Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: Textual display of the REVENGE frame. Shown in square brackets are attribute names for accessing the frame's contents. In parentheses are IDs for the frame, its LUs, and its FEs.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>frames(name) frame(nameOrId) lus(name,</head><label></label><figDesc>frame) lu(id) fes(name, frame)</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>&gt;&gt;&gt; f = fn.frame('Revenge') &gt;&gt;&gt; f.keys() dict _ keys(['cBy', 'cDate', 'name', 'ID', ' _ type', 'definition', 'definitionMarkup', 'frameRelations', 'FE', 'FEcoreSets', 'lexUnit', 'semTypes', 'URL']) &gt;&gt;&gt; f.name 'Revenge' &gt;&gt;&gt; f.ID 347</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>[</head><label></label><figDesc>POS] 25 tags [POS _ tagset] PENN [text] + [annotationSet]</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head>annotations(luname,</head><label></label><figDesc>exemplars, full _ text) sents() exemplars(luname) ft _ sents(docname) doc(id) docs(name)</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" validated="false"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>The frame() and lu() methods are for retriev- ing a single known entry by its name or ID. At- tempting to retrieve a nonexistent entry triggers an exception of type FramenetError. Two additional methods are available for frame lookup: frame _ ids _ and _ names(name) to get a mapping from frame IDs to names, and frames _ by _ lemma(name) to get all frames with some LU matching the given name pattern.</figDesc><table>The result is a 
list with 0 or more elements. If no arguments are 
provided, all entries in the lexicon are returned. 
An example of a search by frame name pattern: 7 

&gt;&gt;&gt; fn.frames('(?i)creat') 

7 (?i) makes the pattern case-insensitive. 

[&lt;frame ID=268 name=Cooking _ creation&gt;, 
&lt;frame ID=1658 name=Create _ physical _ artwork&gt;, ...] 

Similarly, a search by LU name pattern-note 
that the .v suffix is used for all verbal LUs: 

&gt;&gt;&gt; fn.lus(r'.+en\.v') 
[&lt;lu ID=5331 name=awaken.v&gt;, 
&lt;lu ID=7544 name=betoken.v&gt;, ...] 

exemplar sentence (929548): 
[sentNo] 0 
[aPos] 1113164 

[LU] (6067) revenge.n in Revenge 

[frame] (347) Revenge 

[annotationSet] 2 annotation sets 

[POS] 12 tags 

[POS _ tagset] BNC 

[GF] 4 relations 

[PT] 4 phrases 

[text] + [Target] + [FE] + [Noun] 

</table></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="3"> https://www.continuum.io/downloads, https://store.enthought.com/downloads 4 &gt;&gt;&gt; is the standard Python interactive prompt, generally invoked by typing python on the command line. Python code can then be entered at the prompt, where it is evaluated/executed. Henceforth, examples will assume familiarity with the basics of Python. 5 By default, the 855MB data release is installed under the user&apos;s home directory, but an alternate location can be specified: see http://www.nltk.org/data.html.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="6"> The lemma name incorporates a part-of-speech tag. The lemma may consist of a single word, such as surrender.v, or multiple words, such as give up.v.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="8"> In frame semantics, core FEs that are not overt but are conceptually required by a frame are said to be implicit via null instantiation (Fillmore and Baker, 2009).</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>We thank Collin Baker, Michael Ellsworth, and Miriam R. L. Petruck for helping us to understand the FrameNet annotation process and the techni-cal aspects of the data, and for co-organizing the FrameNet tutorial in which an early version of the API was introduced ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Baker et al., 2015</ref>). We also thank NLTK project leader Steven Bird, Mikhail Korborov, Pierpaolo Pantone, Rob Malouf, and any-one else who may have contributed to the release of the API by reviewing the code and reporting bugs; and anonymous reviewers for their suggestions.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">SemEval-2007 Task 19: frame semantic structure 9 github.com/icsi-berkeley/multilingual _ FN extraction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Collin</forename><surname>Baker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Ellsworth</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Katrin</forename><surname>Erk</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of SemEval</title>
		<meeting>of SemEval<address><addrLine>Prague, Czech Republic</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="99" to="104" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Getting the roles right: using FrameNet in NLP</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Collin</forename><surname>Baker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nathan</forename><surname>Schneider</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Miriam</forename><forename type="middle">R L</forename><surname>Petruck</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Ellsworth</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of the 2015 Conference of the North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics: Tutorial Abstracts</title>
		<meeting>of the 2015 Conference of the North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics: Tutorial Abstracts<address><addrLine>Denver, Colorado, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="10" to="12" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Berkeley FrameNet project</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Collin</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Baker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Charles</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Fillmore</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">John</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Lowe</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of COLING-ACL</title>
		<meeting>of COLING-ACL<address><addrLine>Montreal, Quebec, Canada</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="86" to="90" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Natural Language Processing with Python: Analyzing Text with the Natural Language Toolkit</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Steven</forename><surname>Bird</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ewan</forename><surname>Klein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Edward</forename><surname>Loper</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<pubPlace>O&apos;Reilly Media, Inc., Sebastopol, CA</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Frame-semantic parsing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dipanjan</forename><surname>Das</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Desai</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>André</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nathan</forename><surname>Martins</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Noah</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Schneider</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Smith</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Computational Linguistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">40</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="9" to="56" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Frame Semantics</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Charles</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Fillmore</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Linguistics in the Morning Calm</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Seoul, South Korea</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Hanshin Publishing Co</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1982" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="111" to="137" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A frames approach to semantic analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Charles</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Collin</forename><surname>Fillmore</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Baker</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">The Oxford Handbook of Linguistic Analysis</title>
		<editor>Bernd Heine and Heiko Narrog</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Oxford, UK</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Oxford University Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="791" to="816" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Semantic role labeling with neural network factors</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nicholas</forename><surname>Fitzgerald</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Oscar</forename><surname>Täckström</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kuzman</forename><surname>Ganchev</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dipanjan</forename><surname>Das</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of the 2015 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</title>
		<meeting>of the 2015 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language essing<address><addrLine>Lisbon</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="960" to="970" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Portugal</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Automatic labeling of semantic roles</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Daniel</forename><surname>Gildea</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Daniel</forename><surname>Jurafsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Computational Linguistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">28</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="245" to="288" />
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Valencer: an API to query valence patterns in FrameNet</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alexandre</forename><surname>Kabbach</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Corentin</forename><surname>Ribeyre</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of COLING 2016, the 26th International Conference on Computational Linguistics: System Demonstrations</title>
		<meeting>of COLING 2016, the 26th International Conference on Computational Linguistics: System Demonstrations<address><addrLine>Osaka, Japan</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="156" to="160" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Contextaware frame-semantic role labeling</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Roth</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mirella</forename><surname>Lapata</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Transactions of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="449" to="460" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Josef</forename><surname>Ruppenhofer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Ellsworth</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Miriam</forename><forename type="middle">R L</forename><surname>Petruck</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christopher</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Johnson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Collin</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Baker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">FrameNet II: extended theory and practice</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">FrameSQL: A software tool for FrameNet</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hiroaki</forename><surname>Sato</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of ASIALEX 2003</title>
		<meeting>of ASIALEX 2003<address><addrLine>Tokyo, Japan</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="251" to="258" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
