<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T12:20+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">KGEval: Accuracy Estimation of Automatically Constructed Knowledge Graphs</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
				<availability status="unknown"><p>Copyright Association for Computational Linguistics</p>
				</availability>
				<date>September 7-11, 2017. 2017</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Prakhar</forename><surname>Ojha</surname></persName>
							<email>prakhar@iisc.ac.in</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Indian Institute of Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Indian Institute of Science</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Partha</forename><surname>Talukdar</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Indian Institute of Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Indian Institute of Science</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">KGEval: Accuracy Estimation of Automatically Constructed Knowledge Graphs</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Natural Language Processing</title>
						<meeting> <address><addrLine>Copenhagen, Denmark</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="1741" to="1750"/>
							<date type="published">September 7-11, 2017. 2017</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Automatic construction of large knowledge graphs (KG) by mining web-scale text datasets has received considerable attention recently. Estimating accuracy of such automatically constructed KGs is a challenging problem due to their size and diversity and has largely been ignored in prior research. In this work, we try to fill this gap by proposing KGEval. KGEval uses coupling constraints to bind facts and crowdsource those few that can infer large parts of the graph. We demonstrate that the objective optimized by KGEval is submodular and NP-hard, allowing guarantees for our approximation algorithm. Through experiments on real-world datasets, we demonstrate that KGEval best estimates KG accuracy compared to other baselines, while requiring significantly lesser number of human evaluations .</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Automatic construction of Knowledge Graphs (KGs) from Web documents has received signif- icant interest over the last few years, resulting in the development of several large KGs consist- ing of hundreds of predicates (e.g., isCity, sta- diumLocatedInCity(Stadium, City)) and millions of their instances called beliefs (e.g., (Joe Luis Arena, stadiumLocatedInCity, Detroit)). Exam- ples of such KGs include NELL ( , Knowledge-Vault ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Dong et al., 2014</ref>) etc.</p><p>Due to imperfections in the automatic KG con- struction process, many incorrect beliefs are also found in these KGs. Knowing accuracy for each predicate in the KG can provide targeted feedback for improvement and highlight its strengths from weaknesses, whereas overall accuracy of a KG can quantify the effectiveness of its construction- process. Knowing accuracy at predicate-level granularity is immensely helpful for Question- Answering (QA) systems that integrate opinions from multiple KGs ( ). For such systems, being aware that a particular KG is more accurate than others in a certain domain, say sports, helps in restricting the search over relevant and accurate subsets of KGs, thereby improving QA-precision and response time. In comparison to the large body of recent work focused on con- struction of KGs, the important problem of accu- racy estimation of such large KGs is unexplored - we address this gap in this paper.</p><p>True accuracy of a predicate may be estimated by aggregating human judgments on correctness of each and every belief in the predicate <ref type="bibr">1</ref> . Even though crowdsourcing marketplaces such as Ama- zon Mechanical Turk (AMT) provide a convenient way to collect human judgments, accumulating such judgments at the scale of larges KGs is pro- hibitively expensive. We shall refer to the task of manually classifying a single belief as true or false as a Belief Evaluation Task (BET). Thus, the crucial problem is: How can we select a subset of beliefs to evaluate which will best estimate the true (but unknown) accuracy of KG and its predi- cates?</p><p>A naive and popular approach is to evalu- ate randomly sampled subset of beliefs from the KG. Since random sampling ignores relational- couplings present among the beliefs, it usually re- sults in oversampling and poor accuracy estimates. Let us motivate this through an example.</p><p>Motivating example: We motivate efficient ac- curacy estimation through the KG fragment shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref>. Here, each belief is an edge-triple in the graph, for example <ref type="bibr">(RedWings, isA, SportsTeam)</ref>. There are six correct and two incorrect beliefs (the two incident on Taj Mahal), result- ing in an overall accuracy of 75%(= 6/8) which we would like to estimate. Additionally, we would also like to estimate accuracies of the predi- cates: homeStadiumOf, homeCity, stadiumLocate- dInCity, cityInState and isA.</p><p>We now demonstrate how evaluation labels of beliefs are constrained by each other. Type con- sistency is one such coupling constraint. For in- stance, we know from KG ontology that the home- StadiumOf predicate connects an entity from Sta- dium category to another entity in Sports Team cat- egory. Now, if (Joe Louis Arena, homeStadiumOf, Red Wings) is evaluated to be correct, then from these type constraints we can infer that (Joe Louis Arena, isA, Stadium) and (Red Wings, isA, Sports Team) are also correct. Similarly, by evaluating (Taj Mahal, isA, State) as false, we can infer that (Detroit, cityInState, TajMahal) is incorrect.</p><p>Additionally, we have Horn-clause coupling constraints ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Lao et al., 2011</ref>), such as homeStadiumOf(x, y) ∧ homeCity(y, z) → stadiumLocatedInCity(x, z). By evaluating (Red Wings, homeCity, Detroit) and applying this horn- clause to the already evaluated facts mentioned above, we infer that (Joe Louis Arena, stadium- LocatedInCity, Detroit) is also correct. We ex- plore generalized forms of these constraints in Section 3.1.</p><p>Thus, evaluating only three beliefs, and exploit- ing constraints among them, we exactly estimate the overall true accuracy as 75% and also cover all predicates. In contrast, the empirical accuracy by randomly evaluating three beliefs, averaged over 5 trials, is 66.7%.</p><p>Our contributions in this paper are the follow- ing: (1). Systematic study into the important prob- lem of evaluation of automatically constructed Knowledge Graphs. (2). A novel crowdsourcing- based system KGEval to estimate accuracy of large knowledge graphs (KGs) by exploiting de- pendencies among beliefs for more accurate and faster KG accuracy estimation. <ref type="bibr">(3)</ref>. Extensive experiments on real-world KGs to demonstrate KGEval's effectiveness and also evaluate its ro- bustness and scalability. All the data and code used in the pa- per are available at http://talukdar.net/ mall-lab/KGEval 2 Overview and Problem Statement</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">KGEval: Overview</head><p>We try to estimate correctness of as many be- liefs as possible while evaluating only a subset of them through crowdsourcing. KGEval achieves this goal using an iterative algorithm which alter- nates between the following two stages:</p><p>• Control Mechanism (Section 3.4): In this step, KGEval selects the belief which is to be evaluated next using crowdsourcing.</p><p>• Inference Mechanism (Section 3.3): Cou- pling constraints are applied over evaluated beliefs to automatically estimate correctness of additional beliefs.</p><p>This iterative process is repeated until there are no more beliefs to be evaluated. Single iteration of KGEval over the KG fragment from <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref> is shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 2</ref> where, belief (John Louis Arena, homeStadiumOf, Red Wings) is selected and evaluated by crowdsourcing. Subsequently, the inference mechanism uses type coupling con- straints to infer (JL Arena, isA, Stadium) and (R. Wings, isA, Team) also as true. Next, we formalize the notations used in this paper.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">Notations and Problem Statement</head><p>We are given a KG with n beliefs. Evaluating a single belief as true or false forms a Belief Evalua- tion Task (BET). Coupling constraints are derived by determining relationships among BETs, which we further discuss in Section 3.1. Notations are also summarized in <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table 1</ref>. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>, hn}</head><p>Set of all n Belief Evaluation Tasks (BETs)</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">c(h) ∈ R+ Cost of labeling h from crowd C = {(Ci, θi)} Coupling constraints Ci with weights θi ∈ R+ t(h) ∈ {0, 1} True label of h l(h) ∈ {0, 1} Estimated label of h Hi = Dom(Ci) Hi ⊆ H which participate in Ci G = (H ∪ C, E)</formula><p>Evaluation Coupling Graph, e ∈ E between Hj and Cj denotes Hj ∈ Dom(Cj) .</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Q ⊆ H</head><p>BETs evaluated using crowd</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">I G, Q ⊆ H Inferable set for evidence Q: Φ(Q) = 1 |Q| h∈Q t(h)</formula><p>True accuracy of evaluated BETs Q Inference algorithm helps us work out evalua- tion labels of other BETs using constraints C. For a set of already evaluated BETs Q ⊆ H, we define inferable set I G, Q ⊆ H as BETs whose evalu- ation labels can be deduced by the inference algo- rithm. We calculate the average true accuracy of a given set of evaluated BETs</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">Q ⊆ I G, Q ⊆ H by Φ(Q) = 1 |Q| h∈Q t(h)</formula><p>. KGEval aims to sample and crowdsource a BET set Q with the largest inferable set, and solves the optimization problem:</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">arg max Q⊆H I G, Q<label>(1)</label></formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">KGEval: Method Details</head><p>In this section, we describe various components of KGEval.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Coupling Constraints</head><p>The evaluation labels of beliefs are often depen- dent on each other due to rich relational struc- ture of KGs. In this work, we derive coupling constraints C from the KG ontology and link- prediction algorithms, such as PRA ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Lao et al., 2011</ref>) over NELL and AMIE ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Galárraga et al., 2013</ref>) over Yago. These rules are jointly learned over entire KG with millions of facts and are as- sumed true.</p><p>We use conjunction-form first-order-logic rules and refer to them as Horn clauses. Examples of a few such coupling constraints are shown below.</p><formula xml:id="formula_4">C 2 : (x, homeStadiumOf, y) → (y, isA, sportsTeam) C 5 : (x, homeStadiumOf, y) ∧ (y, homeCity, z) → (x, stadiumLocatedInCity, z)</formula><p>Each coupling constraint C i operates over H i ⊆ H to the left of its arrow and infers label of the BET on the right of its arrow. C 2 enforces type consistency and C 5 is an instance of PRA path. These constraints have also been success- fully employed earlier during knowledge extrac- tion ( ) and integration ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">Pujara et al., 2013)</ref>. Note that the constraints are direc- tional and inference propagates in forward direc- tion.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Evaluation Coupling Graph (ECG)</head><p>To combine all beliefs and constraints at a com- mon place, for all H and C, we construct a graph with two types of nodes: (1) a node for each BET h ∈ H, and (2) a node for each constraint C i ∈ C. Each C i node is connected to all h nodes that participate in it. We call this graph the Evalua- tion Coupling Graph (ECG), represented as G = (H ∪ C, E) with set of edges</p><formula xml:id="formula_5">E = {(C i , h) | h ∈ Dom(C i ) ∀C i ∈ C}.</formula><p>Note that ECG is a bipartite factor graph ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Kschischang et al., 2001</ref>) with h as variable-nodes and C i as factor-nodes. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3">Inference Mechanism</head><p>Inference mechanism helps propagate true/false labels of evaluated beliefs to other non-evaluated beliefs using available coupling constraints ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Bragg et al., 2013</ref>). We use Probabilistic Soft Logic (PSL), <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Broecheler et al., 2010)</ref> as our infer- ence engine.Below we briefly describe the inter- nal workings of our inference engine for accuracy estimation problem.</p><p>Potential function ψ j is defined for each C j us- ing Lukaseiwicz t-norm and it depicts how satis- factorily constraint C j is satisfied. For example, C 5 mentioned earlier is transformed from first-order logical form to a real valued number by</p><formula xml:id="formula_6">ψ j (C 5 ) = max{0, h x + h y − 1 − h w } 2 (2)</formula><p>where</p><formula xml:id="formula_7">C 5 = h x ∧ h y → h w ,</formula><p>where h x denotes the evaluation score ∈ [0, 1] associated with the BETs. The probability distribution over label assign- ment is so structured such that labels which sat- isfy more coupling constraints are more proba- ble. Probability of any label assignment Ω H ∈ {0, 1} |H| over BETs in G is given by</p><formula xml:id="formula_8">P Ω H = 1 Z exp − |C| j=1 θ j ψ j C j (3)</formula><p>where Z is the normalizing constant and ψ j cor- responds to potential function acting over BETs h ∈ Dom(C j ). Final assignment of Ω(H) P SL ∈ {1, 0} |H| labels is obtained by solving the maxi- mum a-posteriori (MAP) optimization problem</p><formula xml:id="formula_9">Ω H P SL = arg max Ω(H) P Ω H</formula><p>We denote by M P SL (h, γ) ∈ [0, 1] the PSL- estimated score for label γ ∈ {1, 0} on BET h in the optimization above. Inferable Set using PSL: We define estimated la- bel for each BET h as shown below.</p><formula xml:id="formula_10">l(h) =      1 if MP SL(h, 1) ≥ τ 0 if MP SL(h, 0) ≥ τ ∅ otherwise</formula><p>where threshold τ is system hyper-parameter. In- ferable set is composed of BETs for which infer- ence algorithm (PSL) confidently propagates la- bels.</p><p>I(G, Q) = {h ∈ H | l(h) = ∅} Note that two BET nodes from ECG can interact with varying strengths through different constraint nodes; this multi-relational structure requires soft probabilistic propagation.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.4">Control Mechanism</head><p>Control mechanism selects the BET to be crowd- evaluated at every iteration. We first present the following two theorems involving KGEval's opti- mization in Equation (1). Please refer Appendix for proofs of both theorems. Theorem 1.</p><p>[Submodularity] The function op- timized by KGEval (Equation (1)) using the PSL-based inference mechanism is submodular <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">(Lovász, 1983)</ref>. The proof follows from the fact that all pairs of BETs satisfy the regularity condition ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Jegelka and Bilmes, 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Kolmogorov and Zabih, 2004</ref>), fur- ther used by a proven conjecture <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(Mossel and Roch, 2007)</ref>. Theorem 2. [NP-Hardness] The problem of se- lecting optimal solution in KGEval's optimization (Equation <ref type="formula" target="#formula_3">(1)</ref>) is NP-Hard. Proof follows by reducing NP-complete Set-cover Problem (SCP) to selecting Q which covers I(G, Q).</p><p>Justification for Greedy Strategy: From The- orem 1 and 2, we observe that the function op- timized by KGEval is NP-hard and submodular.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Algorithm 1 KGEval: Accuracy Estimation of Knowledge Graphs</head><p>Require: H: BETs, C: coupling constraints, B: assigned budget, S: seed set, c(h): BET cost 1: G = BUILDECG(H, C) 2: B r = B 3: Q 0 = S, t = 1 4: repeat 5:</p><formula xml:id="formula_11">h * = arg max h∈H−Q |I(G, Q t−1 ∪ {h})| 6: CROWDEVALUATE(h * ) 7: RUNINFERENCE(Q t−1 ∪ h * ) 8: Q t = I(G, Q t−1 ∪ {h * }) 9: B r = B r − c(h * ) 10: Q = Q ∪ Q t 11:</formula><p>if Q ≡ H then </p><formula xml:id="formula_12">Acc t = 1 |Q| h∈Q l(h) 15: t = t + 1 16: until CONVERGENCE 17: return Acc t</formula><p>Results from <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">(Nemhauser et al., 1978)</ref> prove that greedy hill-climbing algorithms solve such maxi- mization problem within an approximation factor of (1−1/e) ≈ 63% of the optimal solution. Hence we iteratively select the next BET which gives the greatest increase in size of inferable set.</p><p>We acknowledge the importance of crowd- sourcing aspects such as label-aggregation, worker's quality estimation etc. Appendix A.1 presents a mechanism to handle noisy crowd workers under limited budget.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.5">Bringing it All Together</head><p>Algorithm 1 presents KGEval. In Lines 1-3, we build the Evaluation Coupling Graph G = (H ∪ C, E) and use the labels of seed set S to initial- ize G. In lines 4-16, we repetitively run our in- ference mechanism, until either the accuracy esti- mates have converged, or all the BETs are covered. In each iteration, the BET with the largest infer- able set is identified and evaluated using crowd- sourcing (Lines 5-6). The new inferable set Q t is estimated. These automatically annotated nodes are added to Q (Lines 7-10). Convergence: In this paper, we define conver- gence whenever the variance of sequence of accu- racy estimates [ Acc t−k , . . ., Acc t−1 , Acc t ] is less than α. We set k = 9 and α = 0.002 for our experiments.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Experiments</head><p>To assess the effectiveness of KGEval, we ask the following questions: (1).How effective is KGEval in estimating KG accuracy, both at predicate-level and at overall KG-level? <ref type="bibr">(Section 4.3)</ref>. <ref type="formula">(2)</ref>. What is the importance of coupling constraints on its performance? <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">(Section 4.4)</ref>. <ref type="formula">(3)</ref>. And lastly, how robust is KGEval to estimating accuracy of KGs with varying quality? (Section 4.5).   gold evaluation of all beliefs in the evalu- ation set. Since obtaining gold evaluation of the entire (or large subsets of) NELL and Yago2 KGs will be prohibitively expensive, we take subset of these KGs for evaluation. (KGEval) consists of datasets used, their crowdsourced labels, coupling constraints and code for inference/control.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">Model Description</head><p>Initialization: Algorithm 1 requires initial seed set S which we generate by randomly evaluating |S| = 50 beliefs from H. To maintain fairness, all baselines start from S. For asserting true (or false) value for beliefs, we set a high soft label confidence threshold at τ = 0.8 (see Section 3.3).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1.2">Crowdsourcing of BETs</head><p>To compare KGEval predictions against human evaluations, we evaluate all BETs {H N ∪ H Y } on AMT. For the ease of workers, we translate each entity-relation-entity belief into human read- able format before posting to crowd.</p><p>We published BETs on AMT under 'classifi- cation project' category. We hired AMT recog- nized master workers for high quality labels and paid $0.01 per BET. To compare between 'mas- ter' and 'noisy' workers, we correlated their la- bels individually to expert labels on random subset and observed that master workers were better cor- related (93%) as compared to three non-masters (89%). Consequently we consider votes of mas- ter workers for {H N ∪ H Y } as gold labels, which we would like our inference algorithm to be able to predict. As the average turnaround time for AMT tasks runs into a few minutes ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Dupuis et al., 2013)</ref>, KGEval is effectively real-time within such turnaround time range.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1.3">Performance Evaluation Metrics</head><p>Performance of various methods are evaluated us- ing the following two metrics. To capture accuracy at the predicate level, we define ∆ predicate as the average of difference between gold and estimated accuracy of each of the R predicates in KG.</p><formula xml:id="formula_13">∆ predicate = 1 |R| ∀r∈R Φ(Hr) − 1 |Hr| ∀h∈Hr l(h)</formula><p>We define ∆ overall as the difference between gold and estimated accuracy over the entire evalu- ation set.</p><formula xml:id="formula_14">∆ overall = Φ(H) − 1 |H| ∀h∈H l(h)</formula><p>Above, Φ(H) is the overall gold accuracy, Φ(H r ) is the gold accuracy of predicate r and l(h) is the label assigned by the currently evalu- ated method. ∆ overall treats entire KG as a single bag of BETs whereas ∆ predicate segregates beliefs based on their type of predicate-relation. For both metrics, lower is better.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">Baseline Methods</head><p>Since accuracy estimation of large multi-relational KGs is a relatively unexplored problem, there are no well established baselines for this task (apart from random sampling). We present below the baselines which we compared against KGEval. Random: Randomly sample a BET h ∈ H with- out replacement and crowdsource for its correct- ness. Selection of every subsequent BET is inde- pendent of previous selections. Max-Degree: Sort the BETs in decreasing or- der of their degrees in ECG and select them from top for evaluation; this method favors selection of more centrally connected BETs first. Independent Cascade: This method is based on contagion transmission model where nodes only infect their immediate neighbors ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Kempe et al., 2003)</ref>. At every time iteration t, we choose a BET which is not evaluated yet, crowdsource for its la- bel and let it propagate its evaluation label in ECG. KGEval: Method proposed in Algorithm 1.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3">Effectiveness of KGEval</head><p>Experimental results of all methods comparing ∆ overall and ∆ predicate at convergence, are pre- sented in <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">Table 3</ref>. We observe that KGEval is able to achieve the best estimate across both datasets and metrics. Due to the significant positive bias in H Y (see <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">Table 2</ref>), all methods do fairly well as per ∆ overall on this dataset, even though KGEval still outperforms others. Also, KGEval is able to estimate KG accuracy most closely while utiliz- ing least number of crowd-evaluated queries. This clearly demonstrates KGEval's effectiveness.</p><p>Nodes in coupling graph with higher degrees are those which participate in large number of con- straints. In real KGs, such facts tend to be correct as they interact with several other facts. Hence, MaxDegree overestimates the accuracy by propa- gating True label. In contrast, Random samples True and False labels in unbiased fashion. Predicate-level Analysis: Here, we consider the top two baselines from     </p><formula xml:id="formula_15">∆ overall (%) Convergence C 140 0.5 C − C b3 259 0.9 C − C b3 − C b2 335 1.1</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.4">Importance of Coupling Constraints</head><p>This paper is largely motivated by the thesis -ex- ploiting richer relational couplings among BETs may result in faster and more accurate evalua- tions. To evaluate this thesis, we successively ab- lated Horn clause coupling constraints of body- length 2 and 3 from C N . We observe that with the full (non-ablated) con- straint set C N , KGEval takes least number of crowd evaluations of BETs to convergence, while providing best accuracy estimate. Whereas with ablated constraint sets, KGEval takes up to 2.4x more crowd-evaluation queries for convergence; thus validating our thesis.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.5">Additional Experiments</head><p>Other Baselines along with Inference: In or- der to evaluate how Random and Max-degree per- form in conjunction with inference mechanism, we replaced KGEval's greedy control mechanism in Line 5 of Algorithm 1 with these two con- trol mechanisms. In our experiments, we ob- served that both Random+inference and Max- degree+inference are able to estimate accuracy more accurately than their control-only variants. Secondly, even though the accuracies estimated by Random+inference and Max-degree+inference were comparable to that of KGEval, they required larger number of crowd-evaluation queries -1.2x and 1.35x more, respectively. This shows effec- tiveness of greedy mechanism.</p><p>Rate of Coverage: In case of large KGs with scarce budget, it is imperative to have a mecha- nism which covers greater parts of KG with lesser number of crowdsource queries. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_7">Figure 5</ref> shows the fraction of total beliefs whose evaluations were automatically inferred by different methods as a function of number of crowd-evaluated beliefs. We observe that KGEval infers evaluation for the largest number of BETs at each supervision level.</p><p>Robustness to Noise: In order to test ro- bustness of the methods in estimating accuracies    of KGs with different gold accuracies, we arti- ficially added noise to H N by flipping a fixed fraction of edges, otherwise following the same evaluation procedure as in Section 3.5. We ana- lyze ∆ overall (and not ∆ predicate ) because flipping edges in KG distorts predicate-relations dependen- cies and present in <ref type="table" target="#tab_8">Table 5</ref>. We evaluated all the methods and observed that while performance of other methods degraded significantly with dimin- ishing KG quality (more noise), KGEval was sig- nificantly robust to noise. Scalability comparisons with MLN: Markov Logic Networks ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">Richardson and Domingos, 2006</ref>) can serve as a candidate for Inference Mech- anism. We compared the runtime performance of KGEval with PSL and MLN as inference engines. While PSL took 320 seconds to complete one iter- ation, the MLN implementation (PyMLN) could not finish grounding the rules even after 7 hours. This justifies our choice of PSL as the inference engine for KGEval.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Related Work</head><p>Even though Knowledge Graph (KG) construc- tion is an active area of research, we are not aware of any previous research which systemati- cally studies the important problem of estimating accuracy of such automatically constructed KGs. Random sampling has traditionally been the most preferred way for large-scale KG accuracy estima- tion ( .</p><p>Traditional crowdsourcing research has typi- cally considered atomic allocation of tasks where the requester posts them independently. KGEval operates in a rather novel crowdsourcing set- ting as it exploits dependencies among its tasks (BETs or belief evaluations). Our notion of inter- dependence (coupling constraints) among tasks is more general and different than related ideas explored in the crowdsourcing literature before ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Kolobov et al., 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Bragg et al., 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b23">Sun et al., 2015)</ref>. Even though coupling constraints have been used for KG construction <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">(Nakashole et al., 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Galárraga et al., 2013;</ref>, they have so far not been exploited for KG evaluation. We address this gap in this paper.</p><p>The task of knowledge corroboration <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(Kasneci et al., 2010)</ref> proposes probabilistic model to uti- lize a fixed set of basic first-order logic rules for label propagation and is closely aligned with our motivations. However, unlike KGEval, it does not try to reduce the number of queries to crowdsource or maximize coverage.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Conclusion</head><p>In this paper, we have initiated a systematic study into the important problem of evaluation of auto- matically constructed Knowledge Graphs. In or- der to address this challenge, we have proposed KGEval, an instance of a novel crowdsourcing paradigm where dependencies among tasks pre- sented to humans (BETs) are exploited. To the best of our knowledge, this is the first method of its kind. We demonstrated that the objective opti- mized by KGEval is in fact NP-Hard and submod- ular, and hence allows for the application of sim- ple greedy algorithms with guarantees. Through extensive experiments on real datasets, we demon- strated effectiveness of KGEval. We hope to ex- tend KGEval to incorporate varying evaluation cost, and also explore more sophisticated evalu- ation aggregation.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>A Appendix</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Submodularity:</head><p>A real valued function f , which acts over subsets of any finite set H, is said to be submodular if ∀R, S ⊂ H it fulfills</p><formula xml:id="formula_16">f (R) + f (S) ≥ f (R ∪ S) + f (R ∩ S).</formula><p>We call potential function ψ as pairwise regular if for all pairs of BETs {p, q} ∈ H it satisfies Proof. (for Theorem 1) The additional utility, in terms of la- bel inference, obtained by adding a BET to larger set is lesser than adding it to any smaller subset. By construction, any two BETs which share a common factor node Cj are encouraged to have similar labels in G.</p><p>Potential functions ψj of Equation <ref type="formula">(3)</ref> satisfy pairwise reg- ularity property i.e., for all BETs {p, q} ∈ H</p><formula xml:id="formula_17">ψ(0, 1) + ψ(1, 0) ≥ ψ(0, 0) + ψ(1, 1)<label>(4)</label></formula><p>where {1, 0} represent true/false. Equivalence of submodu- lar and regular properties are established ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Kolmogorov and Zabih, 2004;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Jegelka and Bilmes, 2011</ref>). Using non-negative summation property <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">(Lovász, 1983)</ref>, j∈C θjψj is submod- ular for positive weights θj ≥ 0.</p><p>We consider a BET h to be confidently inferred when the soft score of its label assignment in I(G, Q) is greater than threshold τ h ∈ [0, 1]. From above we know that P(l(h)|Q) is submodular with respect to fixed initial set Q. Although max or min of submodular functions are not submodular in gen- eral, but ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Kempe et al., 2003)</ref> conjectured that global func- tion of Equation <ref type="formula" target="#formula_3">(1)</ref> is submodular if local threshold function P(h|Q) ≥ τ h respected submodularity, which holds good in our case of Equation <ref type="formula">(3)</ref>. This conjecture was further proved in <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(Mossel and Roch, 2007)</ref> and thus making our global opti- mization function of Equation <ref type="formula" target="#formula_3">(1)</ref> submodular.</p><p>Proof. (for Theorem 2) We reduce KGEval to NP-complete Set-cover Problem (SCP) so as to select Q which covers I(G, Q). For the proof to remain consistent with earlier nota- tions, we define SCP by collection of subsets I1, I2, . . . , Im from set H = {h1, h2, . . . , hn} and we want to deter- mine if there exist k subsets whose union equals H. We define a bipartite graph with m + n nodes corresponding to Ii's and hj's respectively and construct edge (Ii, hj) if hj ∈ Ii. We need to find a set Q, with cardinality k, such that |I(G, Q)| ≥ n + k.</p><p>Choosing our BET-set Q from SCP solution and further inferring evaluations of other remaining BETs using PSL will solve the problem in hand.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>A.1 Noisy Crowd Workers and Budget</head><p>Here, we provide a scheme to allot crowd workers so as to remain within specified budget and upper bound total error on accuracy estimate. We have not integrated this mechanism with Algorithm 1 to maintain its simplicity.</p><p>We resort to majority voting in our analysis and assume that crowd workers are not adversarial. So expectation over responses r h (u) for a task h with respect to multiple workers u is close to its true label t(h) <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">(Tran-Thanh et al., 2013)</ref>, i.e.,</p><formula xml:id="formula_18">E u∼D(u,h) [r h (u)] − t(h) ≤ 1 2 (5)</formula><p>where D is joint probability distribution of workers u and tasks h.</p><p>Our key idea is that we want to be more confident about BETs h with larger inferable set (as they impact larger parts of KG) and hence allocate them more budget to post to more workers. We determine the number of workers {w h 1 , . . . , w hn } for each task such that ht with larger in- ference set have higher w h t . For total budget B, we allocate</p><formula xml:id="formula_19">w h t = B i t (1−γ)</formula><p>c imax where it denotes the cardinality of inferable set I(G, Q∪ht), c the cost of querying crowd worker, imax the size of largest inferable set and γ ∈ [0, 1] constant.</p><p>This allocation mechanism easily integrates with Algo- rithm 1; in (Line 8) we determine size of inferable set it = |Qt| for task h and allocate w h crowd workers. Budget deple- tion (Line 9) is modified to Br = Br − w h c(h). The follow- ing theorem bounds the error with such allocation scheme.</p><p>Theorem 3. [Error bounds] The allocation scheme of re- dundantly posing ht to w h t workers does not exceed the total budget B and its expected estimation error is upper bounded by e −O(i t ) , keeping other parameters fixed. The expected es- timation error over all tasks is upper bounded by e −O(B) .</p><p>Proof. Let γ ∈ [0, 1] control the reduction in size of infer- able set by it+1 = γ it. By allocating w h t redundant work- ers for task ht, ∀t ∈ {1 · · · n} with size of inferable set it, we incur total cost of </p><formula xml:id="formula_20">= imax (1 − γ T ) (1 − γ) · B (1 − γ) imax ≤ B</formula><p>Note that the above geometric approximation helps in esti- mating summation n t=1 it at iteration t ≤ n. Error Bounds: Here we show that the expected error of estimating of ht for any time t decreases exponentially in the size of inferable set it. We use majority voting to aggregate w h t worker responses for ht, denoted byˆrbyˆ byˆr h t ∈ {0, 1}</p><formula xml:id="formula_21">ˆ r h t = 1 w h t w h t k=1 r h t (u k ) − 1 2 + 1<label>(6)</label></formula><p>where r h t (u k ) is the response by k th worker for ht. The error from aggregated response can be given by ∆(ht) = |ˆr|ˆr h t − t(ht)|, where t(ht) is its true label. From Equation <ref type="formula">(5)</ref> and Hoeffding-Azuma bounds over w h t i.i.d responses and error margin εt, we have</p><formula xml:id="formula_22">∆(ht) = P 1 w h t w h t k=1 r h t (u k ) − E(r h (u)) ≥ εt = 2 exp −2 B it (1 − γ) c imax ε 2 t</formula><p>For fixed budget B and given error margin εt, we have ∆(ht) = e −O(i t ) . Summing up over all tasks t, by union bounds we get the total expected error from absolute truth as ∆(B) = n t=1 ∆(ht). The accuracy estimation error will decay exponentially with increase in total budget for fixed parameters.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: Sample knowledge-graph (KG) fragment that is consistent but has erroneous beliefs.</figDesc><graphic url="image-1.png" coords="2,307.56,62.81,217.69,127.27" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2: Demonstration of one iteration of KGEval. Control mechanism selects a belief whose correctness is evaluated from crowd. In the above example, (J.L. Arena, homeStadiumOf, Red Wings) is crowd-evaluated to be true (indicated by tick with dotted square). (Section 2.1 and Section 3).</figDesc><graphic url="image-2.png" coords="3,74.27,62.81,449.02,134.64" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Figure 3: Evaluation Coupling Graph (ECG) constructed for example in Figure 1. (Section 3.2)</figDesc><graphic url="image-3.png" coords="4,90.43,62.80,181.41,155.50" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head>require</head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><head>Figure 4 :</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Figure 4: Comparing (1 − [∆ overall ] predicate ) of individual predicates (higher is better) in HN between KGEval and Random, the two top performing systems in Table 3. (see Section 4.3)</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_7"><head>Figure 5 :</head><label>5</label><figDesc>Figure 5: Fraction of total beliefs whose evaluation where automatically inferred by different methods for varying number of crowd-evaluated queries (x-axis) in HN .</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" validated="false"><head>Table 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Summary of notations used (Section 2.2). 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" validated="false"><head>Table 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Details of BET subsets used for accuracy evalua-

tion. (Section 4.1.2). 

4.1.1 Setup 

Datasets: For experiments, we consider two 
KGs: NELL and Yago2. From NELL (NELL), 
we choose a sub-graph of sports related be-
liefs NELL-sports, mostly pertaining to ath-
letes, coaches, teams, leagues, stadiums etc. 
We construct coupling constraints set C N us-
ing top-ranked PRA inference rules for available 
predicate-relations (Lao et al., 2011). The confi-
dence score returned by PRA are used as weights 
θ i . We use NELL-ontology's predicate-signatures 
to get information for type constraints. Please 
note that PSL is capable of handling weighted 
constraints and also learn their weights (relative 
importance). So, it is not critical to provide 
absolutely correct constraints. We also select 
YAGO2-sample (YAGO) , which unlike NELL-
sports, is not domain specific. We use AMIE horn 
clauses (Galárraga et al., 2013) to construct multi-
relational coupling constraints C Y . For each C i , 
the score returned by AMIE is used as rule weight 
θ i . Table 2 reports the statistics of datasets used, 
their true accuracy and number of coupling con-
straints. Obtaining gold-labels for millions of facts 
is non-trivial and expensive as crowdsourcing over 
full KG incurs significant cost. 
Size of evaluation set: NELL-sport consists of 
23, 422 beliefs with 13, 290 unique entities and 
53 unique predicates. Whereas YAGO-sample has 
31, 720 beliefs, with unique 32, 103 entities and 
17 predicates. In order to calculate accuracy, we </table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3" validated="false"><head>Table 3 , viz., Random and</head><label>3</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>NELL sports dataset (HN ) 
Method 
∆ predicate ∆ overall # Queries 
(%) 
(%) 
Random 
4.9 
1.3 
623 
Max-Deg 
7.7 
2.9 
1370 
Ind-Casc 
9.8 
0.8 
232 
KGEval 
3.6 
0.5 
140 
Yago dataset (HY ) 
Random 
1.3 
0.3 
513 
Max-Deg 
1.7 
0.5 
550 
Ind-Casc 
1.1 
0.7 
649 
KGEval 
0.7 
0.1 
204 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4" validated="false"><head>Table 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>∆ predicate (%) and ∆ overall (%) estimates (lower 

is better) of various methods with number of crowd-evaluated 
queries (BET evaluations) to reach the ∆ overall converged 
estimate. (See Section 4.3) 

worksFor 
teamPlaysIncity 
sportUsesStadium 
teamHomeStadium 
athleteHomeStadium 
coachesTeam 
athletePlaysForTeam 
stadiumLocatedInCity 
teamPlaysInLeague 
athletePlaysSport 
athleteLedSportsTeam 
athletePlaysInLeague 
sportsGameLoser 
athleteCoach 
Average 

0.60 

0.65 

0.70 

0.75 

0.80 

0.85 

0.90 

0.95 

1.00 

1 
− [∆ 

overall ] 

predicate 

Random 
KGEval 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_5" validated="false"><head>Table 3 .</head><label>3</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>(see 
Section 4.3) 

KGEval, and compare performance on the H N 
dataset. We use (1 − [∆ overall ] predicate ) as the 
metric, which means ∆ overall computed over indi-
vidual predicates. Here, we are interested in eval-
uating how well the two methods have estimated 
per-predicate accuracy when KGEval's ∆ overall 
has converged. Comparison of per-predicate per-
formances of the two methods is shown in Fig-
ure 4. Observe that KGEval significantly outper-
forms Random baseline. Its advantage lies in ex-
ploiting the coupling constraints among beliefs, 
where evaluating a belief from certain predicate 
helps infer beliefs from other predicates. 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_6" validated="false"><head>Table 4 : Performance of KGEval with ablated constraint</head><label>4</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>sets. Additional constraints help in better estimation with 
lesser iterations.(see Section 4.4) 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_8" validated="false"><head>Table 5 :</head><label>5</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Accuracy estimate (higher is better) over entire 

KG by various baselines in the presence of noise. 

</table></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> Note that belief evaluation can not be completely automated and will require human-judgment. If an algorithm could accurately predict correctness of a belief, then it may as well be used during KG construction rather than during evaluation.</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>This research has been supported by MHRD (Govt. of India) and in part by a gift from Google.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Amt</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://www.mturk.com" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Crowdsourcing multi-label classification for taxonomy creation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jonathan</forename><surname>Bragg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Daniel S Weld</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>In HCOMP</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Probabilistic similarity logic</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Matthias</forename><surname>Broecheler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lilyana</forename><surname>Mihalkova</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lise</forename><surname>Getoor</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">UAI</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Knowledge vault: A web-scale approach to probabilistic knowledge fusion</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xin</forename><surname>Dong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Evgeniy</forename><surname>Gabrilovich</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Geremy</forename><surname>Heitz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wilko</forename><surname>Horn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ni</forename><surname>Lao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kevin</forename><surname>Murphy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Thomas</forename><surname>Strohmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Shaohua</forename><surname>Sun</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wei</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">SIGKDD</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="601" to="610" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">An analysis of the use of amazons mechanical turk for survey research in the cloud</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marc</forename><surname>Dupuis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Barbara</forename><surname>Endicott-Popovsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Robert</forename><surname>Crossler</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ICCSM2013-Proceedings of the International Conference on Cloud Security Management: ICCSM 2013</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Academic Conferences Limited</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Amie: association rule mining under incomplete evidence in ontological knowledge bases</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Luis</forename><surname>Antonio Galárraga</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christina</forename><surname>Teflioudi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Katja</forename><surname>Hose</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Fabian</forename><surname>Suchanek</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">WWW</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="413" to="422" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Submodularity beyond submodular energies: coupling edges in graph cuts</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Stefanie</forename><surname>Jegelka</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jeff</forename><surname>Bilmes</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">CVPR</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1897" to="1904" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Bayesian knowledge corroboration with logical rules and user feedback</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gjergji</forename><surname>Kasneci</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jurgen</forename><surname>Van Gael</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ralf</forename><surname>Herbrich</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Thore</forename><surname>Graepel</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Machine Learning and Knowledge Discovery in Databases</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="18" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Maximizing the spread of influence through a social network</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Kempe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jon</forename><surname>Kleinberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">SIGKDD</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Kgeval</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://talukdar.net/mall-lab/KGEval" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">What energy functions can be minimized via graph cuts? Pattern Analysis and Machine Intelligence</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Vladimir</forename><surname>Kolmogorov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ramin</forename><surname>Zabih</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE Transactions on</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="147" to="159" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Joint crowdsourcing of multiple tasks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Andrey</forename><surname>Kolobov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Daniel S Weld</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">HCOMP</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Factor graphs and the sum-product algorithm. Information Theory</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Brendan</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Frank R Kschischang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H-A</forename><surname>Frey</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Loeliger</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE Transactions on</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">47</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="498" to="519" />
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Random walk inference and learning in a large scale knowledge base</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ni</forename><surname>Lao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tom</forename><surname>Mitchell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">William W</forename><surname>Cohen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">EMNLP</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="529" to="539" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Submodular functions and convexity</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">László</forename><surname>Lovász</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Mathematical Programming The State of the Art</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1983" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="235" to="257" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Never-ending learning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Mitchell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Cohen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Hruschka</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Talukdar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Betteridge</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Carlson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Dalvi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Gardner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Kisiel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Krishnamurthy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Lao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Mazaitis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Mohamed</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Nakashole</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Platanios</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Ritter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Samadi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Settles</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Wijaya</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Gupta</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Saparov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Greaves</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Welling</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of AAAI</title>
		<meeting>AAAI</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">On the submodularity of influence in social networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Elchanan</forename><surname>Mossel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sebastien</forename><surname>Roch</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ACM symposium on Theory of computing</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="128" to="134" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Scalable knowledge harvesting with high precision and high recall</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ndapandula</forename><surname>Nakashole</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Martin</forename><surname>Theobald</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gerhard</forename><surname>Weikum</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of WSDM</title>
		<meeting>WSDM</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">An analysis of approximations for maximizing submodular set functionsi</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Laurence</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>George L Nemhauser</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marshall L</forename><surname>Wolsey</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Fisher</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Mathematical Programming</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="265" to="294" />
			<date type="published" when="1978" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Knowledge graph identification</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jay</forename><surname>Pujara</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hui</forename><surname>Miao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lise</forename><surname>Getoor</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">William</forename><surname>Cohen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">The Semantic Web-ISWC 2013</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="542" to="557" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Pymln</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://ias.cs.tum.edu/people/jain/mlns" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Markov logic networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Matthew</forename><surname>Richardson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Pedro</forename><surname>Domingos</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Machine learning</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">62</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="107" to="136" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Askworld: budget-sensitive query evaluation for knowledge-on-demand</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mehdi</forename><surname>Samadi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Partha</forename><surname>Talukdar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Manuela</forename><surname>Veloso</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tom</forename><surname>Mitchell</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 24th International Conference on Artificial Intelligence</title>
		<meeting>the 24th International Conference on Artificial Intelligence</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>AAAI Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="837" to="843" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yuyin</forename><surname>Sun</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Adish</forename><surname>Singla</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dieter</forename><surname>Fox</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Andreas</forename><surname>Krause</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:1504.07302</idno>
		<title level="m">Building hierarchies of concepts via crowdsourcing</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
<note type="report_type">arXiv preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Efficient budget allocation with accuracy guarantees for crowdsourcing classification tasks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Long</forename><surname>Tran-Thanh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Matteo</forename><surname>Venanzi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alex</forename><surname>Rogers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nicholas R</forename><surname>Jennings</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">AAMAS</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
