<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T10:46+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main"></title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date>September 7-11, 2017</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jasabanta</forename><surname>Patro</surname></persName>
							<email>1 jasabantapatro@iitkgp.ac.in, 3 monojitc@microsoft.com, 4 animeshm@cse.iitkgp.ernet.in</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bidisha</forename><surname>Samanta</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Saurabh</forename><surname>Singh</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Abhipsa</forename><surname>Basu</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Prithwish</forename><surname>Mukherjee</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Monojit</forename><surname>Choudhury</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Animesh</forename><surname>Mukherjee</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Indian Institute of Technology Kharagpur</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>721302</postCode>
									<country key="IN">India</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">Microsoft Research India</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>560001</postCode>
									<settlement>Bangalore</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Natural Language Processing</title>
						<meeting> <address><addrLine>Copenhagen, Denmark</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="2264" to="2274"/>
							<date type="published">September 7-11, 2017</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<note>All that is English may be Hindi: Enhancing language identification through automatic ranking of likeliness of word borrowing in social media 1</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>In this paper, we present a set of computational methods to identify the likeliness of a word being borrowed, based on the signals from social media. In terms of Spearman&apos;s correlation values, our methods perform more than two times better (∼ 0.62) in predicting the borrowing like-liness compared to the best performing baseline (∼ 0.26) reported in literature. Based on this likeliness estimate we asked annotators to re-annotate the language tags of foreign words in predominantly native contexts. In 88% of cases the annotators felt that the foreign language tag should be replaced by native language tag, thus indicating a huge scope for improvement of automatic language identification systems.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>In social media communication, multilingual peo- ple often switch between languages, a phe- nomenon known as code-switching or code- mixing <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Auer, 1984)</ref>. This makes language iden- tification and tagging, which is perhaps a pre- requisite for almost all other language processing tasks that follow, a challenging problem ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Barman et al., 2014</ref>). In code-mixing people are subcon- sciously aware of the foreign origin of the code- mixed word or the phrase. A related but linguisti- cally and cognitively distinct phenomenon is lex- ical borrowing (or simply, borrowing), where a word or phrase from a foreign language say L 2 is used as a part of the vocabulary of native lan- guage say L 1 . For instance, in Dutch, the En- glish word "sale" is now used more frequently than the Dutch equivalent "uitverkoop". Some English words like "shop" are even inflected in Dutch as "shoppen" and heavily used. While it is difficult in general to ascertain whether a foreign word or phrase used in an utterance is borrowed or just an instance of code-mixing ( ), one tell tale sign is that only proficient mul- tilinguals can code-mix, while even monolingual speakers can use borrowed words because, by def- inition, these are part of the vocabulary of a lan- guage. In other words, just because an English speaker understands and uses the word "tortilla" does not imply that she can speak or understand Spanish. A borrowed word from L 2 initially ap- pears frequently in speech, then gradually in print media like newspaper and finally it loses its ori- gin's identity and is used in L 1 resulting in an in- clusion in the dictionary of L 1 <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">(Myers-Scotton, 2002;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b32">Thomason, 2003)</ref>. Borrowed words often take several years before they formally become part of L 1 dictionary. This motivates our research question "is early-stage automatic identification of likely to be borrowed words possible?". This is known to be a hard problem because (i) it is a socio-linguistic phenomenon closely related to ac- ceptability and frequency, (ii) borrowing is a dy- namic process; new borrowed words enter the lex- icon of a language as old words, both native and borrowed, might slowly fade away from usage, and (iii) it is a population level phenomenon that necessitates data from a large portion of the pop- ulation unlike standard natural language corpora that typically comes from a very small set of au- thors. Automatic identification of borrowed words in social media content (SMC) can improve lan- guage tagging by recommending the tagger to tag the language of the borrowed words as L 1 instead of L 2 . The above reasons motivate us to resort to the social media (in particular, Twitter), where a large population of bilingual/multilingual speak- ers are known to often tweet in code-mixed collo- quial languages <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Carter et al., 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b29">Solorio et al., 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Jurgens et al., 2017;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Rijhwani et al., 2017)</ref>. We designed our methodol- ogy to work for any pair of languages L 1 and L 2 subject to the availability of sufficient SMC. In the current study, we consider Hindi as L 1 and English as L 2 .</p><p>The main stages of our research are as follows: Metrics to quantify the likeliness of borrowing from social media signals: We define three novel and closely similar metrics that serve as social sig- nals indicating the likeliness of borrowing. We compare the likeliness of borrowing as predicted by our model and a baseline model with that from the ground truth obtained from human judges. Ground truth generation: We launch an exten- sive survey among 58 human judges of various age groups and various educational backgrounds to collect responses indicating if each of the can- didate foreign word is likely borrowed. Application: We randomly selected some words that have a high, low and medium borrowing like- liness as predicted by our metrics. Further, we randomly selected one tweet for each of the cho- sen words. The chosen words in almost all of these tweets have L 2 as their language tag while a majority of the surrounding words have a tag L 1 . We asked expert annotators to re-evaluate the lan- guage tags of the chosen words and indicate if they would prefer to switch this tag from L 2 from L 1 .</p><p>Finally, our key results are outlined below: 1. We obtained the Spearman's rank correlation between the ground-truth ranking and the ranking based on our metrics as ∼ 0.62 for all the three variants which is more than double the value (∼ 0.26) if we use the most competitive baseline ( ) available in the literature. 2. Interestingly, the responses of the judges in the age group below 30 seem to correspond even bet- ter with our metrics. Since language change is brought about mostly by the younger population, this might possibly mean that our metrics are able to capture the early signals of borrowing. 3. Those users that mix languages the least in their tweets present the best signals of borrowing in case they do mix the languages (correlation of our metrics estimated from the tweets of these users with that of the ground truth is ∼ 0.65). 4. Finally, we obtain an excellent re-annotation accuracy of 88% for the words falling in the surely borrowed category as predicted by our metrics.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Related work</head><p>In linguistics code-mixing and borrowing have been studied under the broader scope of language change and evolution. Linguists have for a long time focused on the sociological and the con- versational necessity of borrowing and mixing in multilingual communities (see <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Auer (1984)</ref> and <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Muysken (1996)</ref> for a review). In particular, <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">Sankoff et al. (1990)</ref> describes the complexity of choosing features that are indicative of borrow- ing. This work further showed that it is not al- ways true that only highly frequent words are bor- rowed; nonce words could also be borrowed along with the frequent words. More recently, <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">(Nzai et al., 2014</ref>) analyzed the formal conversation of Spanish-English multilingual people and found that code mixing/borrowing is not only restricted to daily speech but is also prevalent in formal con- versations. <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Hadei, 2016)</ref> showed that phonolog- ical integration could be evaluated to understand the phenomenon of word borrowing. Along sim- ilar lines, <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">(Sebonde, 2014</ref>) showed morphological and syntactic features could be good indicators for numerical borrowings. <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">(Senaratne, 2013)</ref> reported that in many languages English words are likely to be borrowed in both formal and semi-formal text.</p><p>Mixing in computer mediated communica- tion and social media: (Sotillo, 2012) investi- gated various types of code-mixing in a corpora of 880 SMS text messages. The author observed that most often mixing takes place at the beginning of a sentence as well as through simple insertions. Similar observations about chat and email mes- sages have been reported in <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Bock, 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b19">Negrón, 2009)</ref>. However, studies of code-mixing with Chinese-English bilinguals from Hong Kong ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Li, 2009)</ref> and Macao <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">(San, 2009)</ref> brings forth results that contrast the aforementioned findings and in- dicate that in these societies code-mixing is driven more by linguistic than social motivations.</p><p>Recently, the advent of social media has im- mensely propelled the research on code-mixing and borrowing as a dynamic social phenom- ena. <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(Hidayat, 2012)</ref> noted that in Facebook, users mostly preferred inter-sentential mixing and showed that 45% of the mixing originated from real lexical needs, 40% was used for conversa- tions on a particular topic and the rest 5% for con- tent clarification. In contrast, ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Das and Gambäck, 2014)</ref> showed that in case of Facebook messages, intra-sentential mixing accounted for more than half of the cases while inter-sentential mixing ac- counted only for about one-third of the cases. In fact, in the First Workshop on Computational Ap- proaches to Code Switching a shared task on code- mixing in tweets was launched and four differ- ent code-mixed corpora were collected from Twit- ter as a part of the shared task ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">Solorio et al., 2014)</ref>. Language identification task has also been handled for English-Hindi and English-Bengali code-mixed tweets in ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Das and Gambäck, 2013)</ref>. Part-of-speech tagging have been recently done for code-mixed English-Hindi tweets <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">(Solorio and Liu, 2008;</ref>).</p><p>Diachronic studies: As an aside, it is interest- ing to note that the availability of huge volumes of timestamped data (tweet streams, digitized books) is now making it possible to study various lin- guistic phenomena quantitatively over different timescales. For instance, ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Sagi et al., 2009</ref>) uses latent semantic analysis for detection and tracking of changes in word meaning, whereas (Frermann and Lapata, 2016) presents a Bayesian approach for the same problem. ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">Peirsman et al., 2010</ref>) presents a distributed model for automatic identi- fication of lexical variation between language va- rieties. (Bamman and Crane, 2011) discusses a method for automatically identifying word sense variation in a dated collection of historical books . ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Mitra et al., 2014</ref>) presents a computational method for automatic identification of change in word senses across different timescales. ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Cook et al., 2014</ref>) presents a method for novel sense identification of words over time.</p><p>Despite these diverse and rich research agendas in the field of code-switching and lexical dynam- ics, there has not been much attempt to quantify the likeliness of borrowing of foreign words in a language. The only work that makes an attempt in this direction is ( ), which is de- scribed in detail in Sec 3.1. One of the primary challenges faced by any quantitative research on lexical borrowing is that borrowing is a social phe- nomenon, and therefore, it is difficult to identify suitable indicators of such a lexical diffusion pro- cess unless one has access to a large population- level data. In this work, we show for the first time how certain simple and closely related signals en- coding the language usage of social media users can help us construe appropriate metrics to quan- tify the likeliness of borrowing of a foreign word.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Methodology</head><p>In this section, we present the baseline metric and propose three new metrics that quantify the likeli- ness of borrowing.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Baseline metric</head><p>Baseline metric -We consider the log(</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">F L 2 F L 1</formula><p>) value proposed in ( ) as the baseline met- ric. Here F L 2 denotes the frequency of the L 1 transliterated form of the word w in the standard L 1 newspaper corpus. F L 1 , on the other hand, de- notes the frequency of the L 1 translation of the word w in the same newspaper corpus. For our experiments discussed in the later sections, both the transliteration and the translation of the words have been done by a set of volunteers who are na- tive L 1 speakers. The authors in (  claim that the more positive the value of this met- ric is for a word w, the higher is the likeliness of its being borrowed. The more negative the value is, the higher are the chances that the word w is an instance of code-mixing. Ranking -Based on the values obtained from the above metric for a set of target words, we rank these words; words with high positive values fea- ture at the top of the rank list and words with high negative values feature at the bottom of the list. For two words having the same log(</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">F L 2 F L 1</formula><p>) value, we resolve the conflict by assigning each of these the average of their two rank positions. In a subse- quent section, we shall compare this rank list with the one obtained from the ground truth responses.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Proposed metric</head><p>In this section, we present three novel and closely related metrics based on the language usage pat- terns of the users of social media (in specific, Twit- ter). In order to define our metrics, we need all the words to be language tagged. The different tags that a word can have are: L 1 , L 2 , NE (Named En- tity) and Others. Based on the word level tag, we also create a tweet level tag as follows:</p><p>1.</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">L 1 : Almost every word (&gt; 90%) in the tweet is tagged as L 1 . 2. L 2 : Almost every word (&gt; 90%) in the tweet is tagged as L 2 .</formula><p>3. CM L 1 : Code-mixed tweet but majority (i.e., &gt; 50%) of the words are tagged as L 1 . 4. CM L 2 : Code-mixed tweet but majority (i.e., &gt; 50%) of the words are tagged as L 2 . 5. CMEQ: Code-mixed tweet having very sim- ilar number of words tagged as L 1 and L 2 respectively. 6. Code Switched: There is a trail of L 1 words followed by a trail of L 2 words or vice versa. Using the above classification, we define the following metrics: Unique User Ratio (U U R) -The Unique User Ra- tio for word usage across languages is defined as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">U U R(w) = U L 1 + U CM L 1 U L 2 (1)</formula><p>where</p><formula xml:id="formula_4">U L 1 (U L 2 , U CM L 1 )</formula><p>is the number of unique users who have used the word w in a</p><formula xml:id="formula_5">L 1 (L 2 , CM L 1 ) tweet at least once. Unique Tweet Ratio (U T R) -The Unique Tweet</formula><p>Ratio for word usage across languages is defined as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_6">U T R(w) = T L 1 + T CM L 1 T L 2 (2)</formula><p>where</p><formula xml:id="formula_7">T L 1 (T L 2 , T CM L 1 ) is the total number of L 1 (L 2 , CM L 1 )</formula><p>tweets which contain the word w. Unique Phrase Ratio (U P R) -The Unique Phrase Ratio for word usage across languages is defined as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_8">U P R(w) = P L 1 P L 2 (3)</formula><p>where</p><formula xml:id="formula_9">P L 1 (P L 2 ) is the number of L 1 (L 2 )</formula><p>phrases which contain the word w. Note that unlike the definitions of U U R and U T R that exploit the word level language tags, the definition of U P R exploits the phrase level language tags.</p><p>Ranking -We prepare a separate rank list of the target words based on each of the three proposed metrics -U U R, U T R and U P R. The higher the value of each of this metric the higher is the like- liness of the word w to be borrowed and higher up it is in the rank list. In a subsequent section, we shall compare these rank lists with the one pre- pared from the ground truth responses.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Experiments</head><p>In this section we discuss the dataset for our ex- periments, the evaluation criteria and the ground truth preparation scheme.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">Datasets and preprocessing</head><p>In this study, we consider code-mixed tweets gath- ered from Hindi-English bilingual Twitter users in order to study the effectiveness of our proposed metrics. The native language L 1 is Hindi and the foreign language L 2 is English. To bootstrap the data collection process, we used the language tagged tweets presented in ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">Rudra et al., 2016)</ref>. In addition to this, we also crawled tweets (be- tween Nov 2015 and Jan 2016) related to 28 hash- tags representing different Indian contexts cov- ering important topics such as sports, religion, movies, politics etc. This process results in a set of 811981 tweets. We language-tag (see de- tails later in this section) each tweet so crawled and find that there are 3577 users who use mixed language for tweeting. Next, we systematically crawled the time lines of these 3577 users between Feb 2016 and March 2016 to gather more mixed language tweets. Using this two step process we collected a total of 1550714 distinct tweets. From this data, we filtered out tweets that are not writ- ten in romanized script, tweets having only URLs and tweets having empty content. Post filtering we obtained 725173, tweets which we use for the rest of the analysis. The datasets can be downloaded from http://cnerg.org/borrow Language tagging: We tag each word in a tweet with the language of its origin using the method outlined in <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(Gella et al., 2013)</ref>. Hi represents a pre- dominantly Hindi tweet, En represents a predom- inantly English tweet, CMH (CME) represents code-mixed tweets with more Hindi (English) words, CMEQ represents code-mixed tweets with almost equal number of Hindi and English words and CS represents code-switched tweets (the num- ber and % of tweets in each of the above six cat- egories are presented in the supplementary mate- rial). Like the word level, the tagger also provides a phrase level language tag. Once again, the differ- ent tags that an entire phrase can have are: En, Hi and Oth (Other). The metrics defined in the pre- vious section are computed using these language tags.</p><p>Newspaper dataset for the baseline: As we had discussed in the previous section, for the construc- tion of the baseline ranking we need to resort to counting the frequency of the foreign words (i.e., English words) and their Hindi translations in a newspaper corpus as has been outlined in ( . For this purpose, we use the FIRE dataset built from the Hindi Jagaran newspaper corpus 1 which is written in Devanagari script.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">Target word selection</head><p>We first compute the most frequent foreign (i.e., English words) in our tweet corpus. Since we are interested in the frequency of the English word only when it appears as a foreign <ref type="bibr">word</ref>  In Example I the English word "film" is sur- rounded by mostly Hindi words. On the other hand, in Example II the English word "thing" is surrounded mostly by English words. Note that the word "film" is very commonly used by Hindi monolingual speakers and is therefore highly likely to have been borrowed unlike the English word "thing" which is arguably an instance of mixing. This socio-linguistic difference seems to be very appropriately captured by the language tag of the surrounding words of these two words in the respective tweets. Based on this hypothesis we arrange the 230 words into contextually similar groups (see supplementary material for the grouping details). Finally, using the baseline metric log( F E</p><note type="other">F H ) (E: English, H: Hindi), we proportionately choose words from these groups as follows: Words with very high or very low values of log( F E F H ) (hlws) -we select words having the highest and the lowest values of log( F E F H ) from each of the context groups. This constitutes a set of 30 words. Note that these words are baseline-biased and therefore the metric should be able to discriminate them well. Words with medium values of log( F E F H ) (mws) - we selected 27 words having not so high and not so low log( F E F H</note><p>) at uniformly at random. Full set of words (f ull) -Thus, in total we selected 57 target words for the purpose of our evaluation. We present these words in the box below.</p><p>Baseline-biased words -'thing', 'way', 'woman', 'press', 'wrong', 'well', 'matter', 'reason', 'ques- tion', 'guy', 'moment', 'week', 'luck', 'president', 'body', 'job', 'car', 'god', 'gift', 'status', 'univer- sity', 'lyrics', 'road', 'politics', 'parliament', 'review', 'scene', 'seat', 'film', 'degree' Randomly selected words -'people', 'play', 'house', 'service', 'rest', 'boy', 'month', 'money', 'cool', 'de- velopment', 'group', 'friend', 'day', 'performance', 'school', 'blue', 'room', 'interview', 'share', 'request', 'traffic', 'college', 'star', 'class', 'superstar', 'petrol', 'uncle'</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3">Evaluation criteria</head><p>We present a four step approach for evaluation as follows. We measure (i) how well the U U R, U T R and U P R based ranking of the hlws set, the mws set and the f ull set correlate with the ground truth ranking (discussed in the next section) in compar- ison to the rank given by the baseline metric, (ii) how well the different rank ranges obtained from our metric align with the ground truth as compared to the baseline metric, (iii) whether there are some systematic effects of the age group of the survey participants on the rank correspondence, (iv) how our metrics if computed from the tweets of users who (a) rarely mix languages, (b) almost always mix languages and (c) are in between (a) and (b), align with the ground truth. Rank correlation: We measure the standard Spearman's rank correlation (ρ) <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">(Zar, 1972)</ref> pair- wise between rank lists generated by (i) U U R (ii) U T R (iii) U P R (iv) baseline metric and the ground truth.</p><p>We shall describe the next four measurements taking U U R as the running example. The same can be extended verbatim for the other two similar metrics.</p><p>Rank ranges: We split each of the three rank lists (U U R, ground truth and baseline) into five differ- ent equal-sized ranges as follows -(i) surely bor- rowed (SB) containing top 20% words from each list, (ii) likely borrowed (LB) containing the next 20% words from each list, (iii) borderline (BL) constituting the subsequent 20% words from each list, (iv) likely mixed (LM) comprising the next 20% words from each list and (v) surely mixed (SM) having the last 20% words from each rank list. Therefore, we have three sets of five buckets, one set each for U U R, the ground truth and the baseline based rank list.</p><p>Next we calculate the bucket-wise correspon- dence between (i) the U U R and the ground truth set and (ii) the baseline and the ground truth set in terms of standard precision and recall measures. For our purpose, we adapt these measures as fol- lows. G: ground truth bucket set, B b : baseline bucket set, U b : U U R bucket set; BS ∈ {B b , U b }, T (type of bucket) = {SB, LB, BL, LM, SM}; b t = words in type t bucket from BS, g t = words in type t bucket from G, t ∈ T ; tp t (no. of true positives) = |b t ∩ g t |, f p t (no. of false positives) = |b t − g t |, tn t (no. of true nega- tives) = |g t − b t |; Bucket-wise precision and recall therefore:</p><formula xml:id="formula_10">precision(b t ) = tpt f pt+tpt ; recall(b t ) = tpt tnt+tpt</formula><p>For a given set, we obtained the overall macro pre- cision (recall) by averaging the precision (recall) values over the five buckets. For a given set, we also obtained the overall micro precision by first adding the true positives across all the buckets and then normalizing by the sum of the true and the false positives over all the buckets. We take an equivalent approach for obtaining the micro recall.</p><p>Age group effect: Here we construct two ground truth rank lists one using the responses of the par- ticipants with age below 30 (young population) and the other using the responses of the rest of the participants (elderly population). Next we repeat the above two evaluations considering each of the new ground truth rank lists.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Extent of language mixing:</head><p>Here we divide all the 3577 users into three categories -(i) High (users who have more than 20% of tweets as code- mixed), (ii) Mid (users who have 7-20% of their tweets as code-mixed, and (iii) Low (users who have less than 7% of their tweets as code-mixed).</p><p>We create three U U R based rank lists for each of these three user categories and respectively com- pare them with the ground truth rank list.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.4">Ground truth preparation</head><p>Since it is very difficult to obtain a suitable ground truth to validate the effectiveness of our proposed ranking scheme, we launched an online survey to collect human judgment for each of the 57 target words.</p><p>Online survey We conducted the online survey 2 among 58 volunteers majority of whom were ei- ther native language(Hindi) speakers or had very high proficiency in reading and writing in that lan- guage. The participants were selected from dif- ferent age groups and different educational back- grounds. Every participant was asked to respond to a multiple choice question about each of the 57 target words. Therefore, for every single tar- get word, 58 responses were gathered. The mul- tiple choice question had the following three op- tions and the participants were asked to select the one they preferred the most and found more natu- ral -(i) a Hindi sentence with the target word as the only English word, (ii) the same Hindi sen- tence in (i) but with the target word replaced by its Hindi translation and (iii) none of the above two options. There were no time restrictions imposed while gathering the responses, i.e., the volunteers theoretically had unlimited time to decide their re- sponses for each target word. of LP F appears at the top of the ground truth rank list and so on in that order. Tie breaking between target words having equal LP F values is done by assigning average rank to each of these words.</p><p>Age group based rank list: As discussed in the previous section, we prepare the age group based rank lists by first splitting the responses of the sur- vey participants in two groups based on their age -(i) young population (age &lt; 30) and (ii) elderly population (age ≥ 30). For each group we then construct a separate LP F based ranking of the target words.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Results</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.1">Correlation among rank lists</head><p>The Spearman's rank correlation coefficient (ρ) of the rank lists for the hlws set, the mws set and the f ull set according to the baseline metric, U U R, U T R and U P R with respect to the ground truth metric LP F are noted in table 1. We observe that for the f ull set, the ρ between the rank lists ob- tained from all the three metrics U U R, U T R, and U P R with respect to the ground truth is ∼ 0.62 which is more than double the ρ (∼ 0.26) between the baseline and the ground truth rank list. This clearly shows that the proposed metrics are able to identify the likeliness of borrowing quite accu- rately and far better than the baseline. Further, a remarkable observation is that our metrics outper- form the baseline metric even for the hlws set that is baseline-biased. Likewise, for the mws set, our metrics outperform the baseline indicating a supe- rior recall on arbitrary words. The ranking of the f ull set of words obtained from the ground truth, the baseline and the U U R metric is available in the supplementary material.</p><p>We present the subsequent results for the f ull set and the U U R metric. The results obtained for the other two metrics U T R and U P R are very similar and therefore not shown.</p><p>Bucket type Ground truth bucket Baseline bucket U U R bucket <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">SB  11  11  11  LB  11  11  11  BL  12  12  12  LM  11  11  11  SM  12  12  12</ref>   </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.2">Rank list alignment across rank ranges</head><p>The number of target words falling in each bucket across the three rank lists are the same and are noted in table 2. Thus, the precision and recall as per the definition are also the same. The bucket- wise precision/recall for the baseline and U U R with respect to the ground truth are noted in ta- ble 3. We observe that while in the SB bucket both the baseline and U U R perform equally well, for all the other buckets U U R massively outper- forms the baseline. This implies that for the case where the likeliness of borrowing is the strongest, the baseline does as good as U U R. However, as one moves down the rank list, U U R turns out to be a considerably better predictor than the base- line. The overall macro and micro precision/recall as shown in table 4 further strengthens our obser- vation that U U R is a better metric than the base- line.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.3">Age group based analysis</head><p>As already discussed earlier, we split the ground truth responses based on the age group of the sur- vey participants. We split the responses into two groups -(i) young population (age &lt; 30) and (ii) elderly population (age ≥ 30) so that there are al- most equal number of responses in both the groups (see supplementary material for the exact distribu- tion).  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Rank-List1 Rank-List2</head><p>ρ Baseline</p><p>Ground-truth-Young 0.26 U U R Ground-truth-Young 0.62 Baseline Ground-truth-Elder 0.27 U U R Ground-truth-Elder 0.53  Interestingly, the correlation between U U R rank list and the young population ground truth is better than the elderly population ground truth. This pos- sibly indicates that U U R is able to predict recent borrowings more accurately. However, note that the U U R rank list has a much higher correlation with both the ground truth rank lists as compared to the baseline rank list.</p><p>Rank ranges: <ref type="table" target="#tab_7">Table 6</ref> shows the bucket-wise pre- cision and recall for U U R and the baseline met- rics with respect to two new ground truths. For the young population once again the number of words in each bucket for all the three sets is the same thus making the values of the precision and the recall same. In fact, the precision/recall for this ground truth is exactly same as in the case of the original ground truth. In contrast, when we consider the ground truth based on the responses of the elderly population, the number of words across the different buckets are different across the three sets. In this case, we observe that the precision/recall values are better for the U U R metric in SB, LB and LM buckets.</p><p>Finally, the overall macro and micro precision and recall for both the age groups are noted in table 7. Once again, for both the young and the elderly population based ground truths, the macro and micro precision and recall values for the U U R metric are higher compared to that of the baseline.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.4">Extent of language mixing</head><p>As mentioned earlier, we divide the set of 3577 users into three categories. The Spearman's cor-   relation between U U R and the ground truth for each of these buckets are given in table 8. As we can see, for Low bucket the ρ value is maximum. This points to the fact that the signals of borrow- ing is strongest from the users who rarely mix lan- guages.</p><formula xml:id="formula_11">Measure Young- Baseline Young- U U R Elder- Baseline Elder- U U R Mac.</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Re-annotation results</head><p>In order to conduct the re-annotation experiments we performed the following. To begin with, we ranked all the 230 English nouns in non-increasing order of their U U R values. We then randomly se- lected 20 words each having (i) high U U R (top 20%) values (call T OP ), (ii) low U U R (bottom 20%) values (call BOT ), and (iii) middle U U R (middle 20%) values (call M ID). This makes a total of 60 words. Using this word list we ex- tracted one tweet each that contained the (foreign) word from this list along with all other words in the tweet tagged in Hindi (H all ). We similarly pre- pared another such list of 60 words and extracted one tweet each in which most of the other words were tagged in Hindi (H most ). We presented the selected words and the cor- responding tweets to a set of annotators and asked them to annotate these selected words once again. Over all the words, we calculated the mean (µ E→H ) and the standard deviation (σ E→H ) of the fraction of cases where the annotators altered the tag of the selected word from English to Hindi. The average inter-annotator agreement <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Fleiss, 1971)</ref> for our experiments was found to be as high as 0.64. For the words in the T OP list, the frac- tion of times the tag is altered is 0.91 (0.85) with an inter-annotator agreement of 0.84 (0.80) for the <ref type="bibr">Word</ref>   <ref type="table" target="#tab_12">Table 9</ref> shows the fractional changes for all the other possible cases. An in- teresting observation is that the annotators rarely flipped the tags for the words in the BOT list (i.e., the sure mixing cases) in either of the H all or the H most contexts. These results strongly support the inclusion of our metric in the design of future au- tomatic language tagging tasks.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7">Discussion and conclusion</head><p>In this paper, we proposed a few new metrics for estimating the likliness of borrowing that rely on signals from large scale social media data. Our best metric is two-fold better than the previous metric in terms of the accuracy of the predic- tion. There are some interesting linguistic aspects of borrowing as well as certain assumptions re- garding the social media users that have important repercussions on this work and its potential exten- sions, which are discussed in this section. Types of borrowing: Linguists define broadly three forms of borrowing, (i) cultural, (ii) core, and (iii) therapeutic borrowings. In cultural bor- rowing, a foreign word gets borrowed into native language to fill a lexical gap. This is because there is no equivalent native language word present to represent the same foreign word concept. For in- stance, the English word 'computer' has been bor- rowed in many Indian languages since it does not have a corresponding term in those languages <ref type="bibr">3</ref> . In core borrowing, on the other hand, a foreign word replaces its native language translation in the na- tive language vocabulary. This occurs due to over- whelming use of the foreign word over native lan- guage translation as a matter of prestige, ease of use etc. For example, the English word 'school' has become much more prevalent than its corre- sponding Hindi translation 'vidyalaya' among the native Hindi speakers. Finally, therapeutic bor- rowing refers to borrowing of words to avoid taboo and homonomy in the native language. In this paper, although we did not perform any category based studies, most of our focus was on core bor- rowing.</p><p>Language of social media users: We assumed that if a user is predominantly using Hindi words in a tweet then the chances of him/her being a na- tive Hindi speaker should be high, since, while the number of English native speakers in India is 0.02%, the number of Hindi native speakers is 41.03% <ref type="bibr">4</ref> . This assumption has also been made in earlier studies ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">Rudra et al., 2016)</ref>. Note that even if a user is not a native Hindi speaker but a proficient (or semi-proficient) Hindi speaker, the main results of our analysis should hold. For in- stance, consider two foreign words 'a' and 'b'. If 'a' is frequently borrowed in the native language, then the proficient speaker would also tend to bor- row 'a' similar to a native speaker. Even if due to lack of adequate native vocabulary, the non- native speaker borrows the word 'b' in some cases, these spurious signals should get eliminated since we are making an aggregate level statistics over a large population.</p><p>Future directions: It would be interesting to understand and develop theoretical justification for the metrics. Further, it would be useful to study and classify various other linguistic phe- nomena closely related to core borrowing, such as: (i) loanword, where a form of a foreign word and its meaning or one component of its meaning gets borrowed, (ii) calques, where a foreign word or idiom is translated into existing words of native language, and (iii) semantic loan, where the word in the native language already exists but an addi- tional meaning is borrowed from another language and added to existing meaning of the word.</p><p>Finally, we would also like to incorporate our findings into other standard tasks of multilingual IR and multilingual speech synthesis (for example to render the appropriate native accent to the bor- rowed word).</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" validated="true"><head>Table 2 : Number of words falling in each bucket of three bucket sets.</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Bucket type prec./rec. Baseline prec./rec. U U R 
SB 
0.27 
0.27 
LB 
0.09 
0.18 
BL 
0.08 
0.33 
LM 
0.18 
0.36 
SM 
0.33 
0.50 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3" validated="false"><head>Table 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Bucket-wise precision/recall. Best results 
are marked in bold. 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_5" validated="false"><head>Table 4 :</head><label>4</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Overall macro and micro precision/recall. 
Best results are marked in bold. </table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_6" validated="true"><head>Table 5 : Spearman's rank correlation across the two age groups. Best results are marked in bold.</head><label>5</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Bucket 
type 
Young-
Baseline 
p/r 

Young-
U U R 
p/r 

Elder-
Baseline 
p 

Elder-
U U R 
p 

Elder-
baseline 
r 

Elder-
U U R 
r 
SB 
0.27 
0.27 
0.27 
0.36 
0.25 
0.33 
LB 
0.09 
0.18 
0.09 
0.18 
0.08 
0.17 
BL 
0.08 
0.33 
0.16 
0.08 
0.28 
0.14 
LM 
0.18 
0.36 
0.18 
0.45 
0.14 
0.35 
SM 
0.33 
0.5 
0.41 
0.25 
0.41 
0.25 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_7" validated="false"><head>Table 6 :</head><label>6</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Bucket-wise precision (p)/recall (r) for 
U U R and the baseline metrics for the two new 
ground truths. Best results are marked in bold. 

two ground truth rank lists are shown in table 5. 
</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_9" validated="false"><head>Table 7 :</head><label>7</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Overall macro and micro precision and 
recall for the two new ground truths. Best results 
are marked in bold. 

Bucket 
Number of users 
ρ 
High 
302 
0.52 
Mid 
744 
0.60 
Low 
2531 
0.65 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_10" validated="false"><head>Table 8 :</head><label>8</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Spearman's correlation between U U R 
and the ground truth in the different user buckets. 
Best results are marked in bold. 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_12" validated="true"><head>Table 9 : Re-annotation results</head><label>9</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>H all (H most ) category. In other words, on average, 
in as high as 88% of cases the annotators altered 
the tags of the words that are highly likely to be 
borrowed (i.e., T OP ) in a largely Hindi context 
(i.e., H all or H most ). </table></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> Jagaran corpus: http:/fire.irsi.res.in/ fire/static/data</note>

			<note place="foot" n="2"> Survey portal: https://goo.gl/forms/ L0kJm8BNMhRj0jA53</note>

			<note place="foot" n="3"> Words for &quot;computer&quot; were coined in many Indian languages through morphological derivation from the term for &quot;compute&quot;, however, none of these words are used in either formal or informal contexts.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="4"> http://bit.ly/2ufOvea</note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Auer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Bilingual Conversation. John Benjamins</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1984" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">i am borrowing ya mixing?&quot; an analysis of englishhindi code mixing in facebook</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Bali</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Sharma</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Choudhury</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Vyas</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">First workshop on Computational approaches to code-switching</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="page">116</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Measuring historical word sense variation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Bamman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gregory</forename><surname>Crane</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 11th annual international ACM/IEEE joint conference on Digital libraries</title>
		<meeting>the 11th annual international ACM/IEEE joint conference on Digital libraries</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="10" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Code mixing: A challenge for language identification in the language of social media</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Utsab</forename><surname>Barman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Amitava</forename><surname>Das</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Joachim</forename><surname>Wagner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jennifer</forename><surname>Foster</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">EMNLP</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page">13</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Cyber socialising: Emerging genres and registers of intimacy among young south african students. Language Matters: Studies in the Languages of</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Bock</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Africa</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">44</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="68" to="91" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Micro-blog language identification: Overcoming the limitations of short, unedited and idiomatic text</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Carter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Weerkamp</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Tsagkias</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Language Resources and Evaluation</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">47</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="195" to="215" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Novel word-sense identification</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Paul</forename><surname>Cook</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Han</forename><surname>Lau</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Diana</forename><surname>Mccarthy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Timothy</forename><surname>Baldwin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">COLING</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1624" to="1635" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">code-mixing in social media text: The last language identification frontier? TAL</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Das</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Gambäck</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">54</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="41" to="64" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Identifying languages at the word level in code-mixed indian social media text</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Das</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Gambäck</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ICON</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="169" to="178" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Measuring nominal scale agreement among many raters</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Joseph L Fleiss</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological bulletin</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">76</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">378</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1971" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A bayesian model of diachronic meaning change</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lea</forename><surname>Frermann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mirella</forename><surname>Lapata</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Transactions of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="31" to="45" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Gella</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Sharma</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Bali</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Query word labeling and back transliteration for indian languages: Shared task system description. FIRE Working Notes</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page">3</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Single word insertions as codeswitching or established borrowing?</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Hadei</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">International Journal of Linguistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="14" to="25" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">An analysis of code switching used by facebookers (a case study in a social network site). In BA thesis. English Education Study Program, College of Teaching and Education (STKIP)</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Hidayat</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<pubPlace>Bandung, Indonesia</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Incorporating dialectal variability for socially equitable language identification</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Jurgens</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yulia</forename><surname>Tsvetkov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dan</forename><surname>Jurafsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Cantonese-english code-switching research in hong-kong: a y2k review</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">C S</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">World Englishes</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="305" to="322" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">That&apos;s sick dude!: Automatic identification of word sense change across different timescales</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sunny</forename><surname>Mitra</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ritwik</forename><surname>Mitra</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Martin</forename><surname>Riedl</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chris</forename><surname>Biemann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Animesh</forename><surname>Mukherjee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Pawan</forename><surname>Goyal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:1405.4392</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
<note type="report_type">arXiv preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Code-switching and grammatical theory</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Muysken</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">One speaker, two languages: Crossdisciplinary perspectives on code-switching</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Cambridge University Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="177" to="198" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Contact linguistics: Bilingual encounters and grammatical outcomes</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Myers-Scotton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
			<publisher>Oxford University Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Spanish-english code-switching in email communication</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Negrón</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Language@Internet</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Understanding code-switching &amp; word borrowing from a pluralistic approach of multilingualism</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Nzai</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y-L</forename><surname>Feng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Medina-Jiménez</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Ekiaka-Oblazamengo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The automatic identification of lexical variation between language varieties</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yves</forename><surname>Peirsman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dirk</forename><surname>Geeraerts</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dirk</forename><surname>Speelman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Natural Language Engineering</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">16</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="469" to="491" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Estimating code-switching on twitter with a novel generalized word-level language detection technique</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Shruti</forename><surname>Rijhwani</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Royal</forename><surname>Sequiera</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Monojit</forename><surname>Choudhury</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kalika</forename><surname>Bali</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chandra</forename><forename type="middle">Shekhar</forename><surname>Maddila</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Understanding language preference for expression of opinion and sentiment: What do hindienglish speakers do on twitter?</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Koustav</forename><surname>Rudra</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Shruti</forename><surname>Rijhwani</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rafiya</forename><surname>Begum</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kalika</forename><surname>Bali</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Monojit</forename><surname>Choudhury</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Niloy</forename><surname>Ganguly</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2016 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</title>
		<meeting>the 2016 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1131" to="1141" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Semantic density analysis: Comparing word meaning across time and phonetic space</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Eyal</forename><surname>Sagi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Stefan</forename><surname>Kaufmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Brady</forename><surname>Clark</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Workshop on Geometrical Models of Natural Language Semantics</title>
		<meeting>the Workshop on Geometrical Models of Natural Language Semantics</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="104" to="111" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Association for Computational Linguistics</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Chinese-english code-switching in blogs by macao young people</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>San</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">MSc. thesis. University of Edinburgh</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The case of the nonce loan in tamil</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Sankoff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Poplack</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Vanniarajan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Language variation and change</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">01</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="71" to="101" />
			<date type="published" when="1990" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Code-switching or lexical borrowing: Numerals in chasu language of rural tanzania</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">Y</forename><surname>Sebonde</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Arts and Humanities</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">67</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Borrowings or code mixes: The presence of lone english nouns in mixed discourse</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">D W</forename><surname>Senaratne</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Overview for the first shared task on language identification in code-switched data</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Solorio</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Blair</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Maharjan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Bethard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Diab</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Gohneim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Hawwari</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Alghamdi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Hirschberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Chang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Fung</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">EMNLP First Workshop on Computational Approaches to Code Switching</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="62" to="72" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Part-of-speech tagging for english-spanish code-switched text</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Solorio</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</title>
		<meeting>the Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1051" to="1060" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Ehhhh utede hacen plane sin mi???:@ im feeling left out :( form, function and type of code switching in sms texting</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Sotillo</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ICAME</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="309" to="310" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Contact as a source of language change. The handbook of historical linguistics</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Thomason</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="687" to="712" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">POS tagging of english-hindi codemixed social media content</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Vyas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Gella</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Sharma</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Bali</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Choudhury</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">EMNLP</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="974" to="979" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Significance testing of the spearman&apos;s rank correlation coefficient</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Zar</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of the American Statistical Association</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">67</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">339</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="578" to="580" />
			<date type="published" when="1972" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
