<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T11:47+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Interactive Visualization for Linguistic Structure</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
				<availability status="unknown"><p>Copyright Association for Computational Linguistics</p>
				</availability>
				<date>September 7-11, 2017. 2017</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Aaron</forename><surname>Sarnat</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Allen Institute for Artificial Intelligence Seattle</orgName>
								<address>
									<region>WA</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Vidur</forename><surname>Joshi</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Allen Institute for Artificial Intelligence Seattle</orgName>
								<address>
									<region>WA</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Cristian</forename><surname>Petrescu-Prahova</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Allen Institute for Artificial Intelligence Seattle</orgName>
								<address>
									<region>WA</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alvaro</forename><surname>Herrasti</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Allen Institute for Artificial Intelligence Seattle</orgName>
								<address>
									<region>WA</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Brandon</forename><surname>Stilson</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Allen Institute for Artificial Intelligence Seattle</orgName>
								<address>
									<region>WA</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mark</forename><surname>Hopkins</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Allen Institute for Artificial Intelligence Seattle</orgName>
								<address>
									<region>WA</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Interactive Visualization for Linguistic Structure</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="j" type="main">EMNLP System Demonstrations</title>
						<meeting> <address><addrLine>Copenhagen, Denmark</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="49" to="54"/>
							<date type="published">September 7-11, 2017. 2017</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<note>node-to-text correspondence.</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>We provide a visualization library and web interface for interactively exploring a parse tree or a forest of parses. The library is not tied to any particular linguistic representation, but provides a general-purpose API for the interactive exploration of hierarchical linguistic structure. To facilitate rapid understanding of a complex structure, the API offers several important features, including expand/collapse func-tionality, positional and color cues, explicit visual support for sequential structure , and dynamic highlighting to convey</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Interpreting visual representations of linguistic structure can be challenging and time-consuming. Consider the examples provided in <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref>, which visualize syntactic parses of the sentence "Although some people have provided negative re- views, her restaurants have reliably great music, good food, and excellent service, and they de- liver!" These representations can result in cogni- tive overload, due to several concrete issues:</p><p>• The visualizations are static. If one is us- ing the visualization for debugging purposes, then typically one cares about only a part of the linguistic structure, not every last detail. Unfortunately, a static visualization must in- clude all information that could possibly be relevant.</p><p>• The visualizations are large. The screen real estate in <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref> is dominated by arrows that must be carefully tracked by the eye, in order to understand the relationships between nodes. Visualizations of long sentences of- ten run off the side of the screen, requiring the user to scroll to discover the endpoints of these arrows.</p><p>• All node relationships look identical.</p><p>Predicate-argument relationships (e.g. "restaurants" as the subject of "have") get the same visual treatment as modifier relationships (e.g. "good" as a modifier of "food") and sequence elements (e.g. "good food" as an element of the sequence "great music, good food, and excellent service").</p><p>In this work, we provide a library and web in- terface for the interactive visualization of linguis- tic structure, seeking to minimize the cognitive load required to understand syntactic and seman- tic parses. <ref type="figure">Figure 2</ref> shows a screenshot of our web UI for the same sentence as <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref>. It reflects several of our visualization strategies (described in more detail in Section 3):</p><p>• Instead of a static visualization, we pro- vide an interactive visualization with an ex- pand/collapse functionality that allows the user to focus on what is relevant to her. For instance, the subclause "although some peo- ple have provided negative reviews" is col- lapsed in <ref type="figure">Figure 2</ref>, but can be expanded by clicking on it.</p><p>• To reduce the size of the visualization, we use a box layout, and use badging to eliminate simple leaf nodes (e.g. instead of creating a separate node for the article "her", it is repre- sented by a badge on the node "restaurant").</p><p>• We use positional cues to highlight predicate- argument relationships (subjects appear to the left, objects to the right, modifiers attach <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref>: Typical visualizations of a constituency parse (top) and a dependency parse (bottom) for the sentence "Although some people have provided negative reviews, her restaurants have reliably great music, good food, and excellent service, and they deliver!"</p><p>to the bottom) and we provide specialized vi- sualization for sequential structures (this oc- curs at two different levels in <ref type="figure">Figure 2</ref>, both for the clause sequence as well as the entity sequence "reliably great music, good food, and excellent service").</p><p>Our library is not tied to any particular linguistic formalism. In Section 4, we describe the flexible and configurable API. While our primary use case has been for creating custom grammars for math- ematical language <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Hopkins et al., 2017)</ref>, we also provide a demonstration of how our API can be used to visualize output from the Stanford Parser ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Socher et al., 2013</ref>).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Related Work</head><p>Most parse visualizations use the source sentence as an anchor, leaving it readable left-to-right. For constituency parses (where the words of the sen- tence are the leaves of the tree), this gives a rep- resentation like <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref> (top). For dependency parses (where the words of the sentences are the nodes of the tree), this gives a representation like <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref> (bottom). <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref> was generated from <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Podgursky, 2015)</ref>, which provides open-source code and a web interface for a static rendering of a con- stituency parse. There are a number of libraries ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Stenetorp et al., 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Montani, 2016;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Athar, 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Yimam et al., 2013</ref>) that provide static ren- derings of dependency parses similar to <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref> (bottom). Among these, Brat (Stenetorp et al., 2012) provides some interactive elements (like mouseover highlighting of subtrees, and the abil- ity to add dependencies via drag-and-drop). Dis- placy (Montani, 2016) provides a general API for the static rendering of various dependency parsing schemes, e.g. Universal Dependencies ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Nivre et al., 2016)</ref> and Stanford Dependencies <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(De Marneffe and Manning, 2008</ref>).</p><p>We are not aware of any recent tools for explor- ing parse forests. Historically, the REDWOODS annotation environment <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Oepen et al., 2004</ref>) pro- duced a static parse forest from a hand-built gram- mar, and then allowed users to select the best <ref type="figure">Figure 2</ref>: A screenshot of our parse visualization tool for the sentence "Although some people have provided negative reviews, her restaurants have reliably great music, good food, and excellent service, and they deliver!"</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">Figure 3:</formula><p>Three screenshots of our visual- izer for the question "How much wood would a woodchuck chuck, if a woodchuck could chuck wood?": partially expanded (top), fully collapsed (middle), and fully expanded (bottom). parse from this forest by repeatedly specifying constraints (called discriminants in the paper).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Key Features</head><p>In this section, we describe our key features for fa- cilitating a rapid understanding of linguistic struc- ture. As a companion to this section, we invite readers to use our web demonstration at http:// hierplane.allenai.org/explain to in- teractively explore examples. <ref type="bibr">1</ref> </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Expand/Collapse Functionality</head><p>Rather than a static rendering, our dynamic ex- pand/collapse functionality allows the user to fo- cus on relevant parts of the linguistic structure, while the rest is conveniently summarized at a coarser granularity. In <ref type="figure">Figure 3</ref>, the top screenshot shows a partially expanded structure that delves into the internal structure of the if-clause. The middle and bottom screenshots respectively show the fully collapsed and expanded visualizations.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Positional Cues to Distinguish Node Relations</head><p>Linguistic relationships can often be organized into intuitive clusters. For instance, subjects and objects can be roughly viewed as required argu- ments of a verb (exactly one per verb), while mod- ifiers are optional (a verb can take any number of them, including zero). Our library allows the visual expression of these "relationship families" through positional cues. In <ref type="figure">Figure 3</ref>, the subject is attached to the left of its verb, the object is at- tached to the right of its verb, and all modifiers are attached beneath. For consistency, the object of the preposition "if" is also attached to its right. At a glance, this representation allows the user to read a gloss of the main clause by simply skimming the top line of the visualization (i.e. "a woodchuck would chuck how much wood?").</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3">Color Cues to Distinguish Node Types</head><p>Our library provides support for using color to distinguish node types. In <ref type="figure">Figure 3</ref>, green rep- resents events, blue represents entities, red repre- sents modifiers, and gray is a catch-all for anything else.</p><p>Figure 4: Dynamic highlighting of the correspondence between the linguistic structure and the source text: "If Peter and Paula had really picked a peck of pickled peppers, how many peppers did they pick?"</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.4">Badging</head><p>Some leaf nodes of linguistic structures convey very simple information about their parent node. We allow these nodes to be represented as badges rather than separate nodes. In <ref type="figure">Figure 3</ref>, the de- terminers ("a" for "a woodchuck") and modals ("would" for "would chuck") are represented as badges.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.5">Sequence Support</head><p>Sequential structure is a fundamental linguistic el- ement that is often difficult to access in a parse vi- sualization. We make sequences visually explicit as a container of linked nodes. Examples include "Peter and Paula" in <ref type="figure">Figure 4</ref> or the sequence of top-level clauses "her restaurants have...excellent service" and "they deliver" in <ref type="figure">Figure 2</ref>. Contrast this to the undistinguished representations of se- quential structure found in <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.6">Dynamic Node-to-Text Highlighting</head><p>It can be difficult (particularly in semantic parses) to ascertain how the source text and the linguis- tic representation correspond. Upon mouse-over of a node, our visualizer highlights the part of the source text corresponding to the subtree rooted at that node. Parts that do not also correspond to some descendant node in the subtree are strongly highlighted. In <ref type="figure">Figure 4</ref>, upon mouse-over of the lower "pick" node, the corresponding segment "Peter and Paula had really picked a peck of pick- led peppers" is weakly highlighted. The tokens "had" and "pecked" are strongly highlighted, be- <ref type="figure">Figure 5</ref>: Before-and-after screenshots of forest exploration for the sentence "Because he ate the pasta with chopsticks, he chipped a tooth."</p><p>cause they do not correspond to any of the node's descendants.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.7">Modular Forest Exploration</head><p>Our interactive setting permits a convenient explo- ration of parse forests. For instance, see <ref type="figure">Figure 5</ref>.</p><p>The subtree rooted at "eat" has two interpretations, attaching "with chopsticks" to the verb or to the object. An indicator in the node's upper-right al- lows the user to browse these interpretations. We localize ambiguities to the lowest possible node to allow the user to explore the forest in a convenient, modular fashion (rather than cycling through an exponential number of parses at the root). </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">APIs</head><p>Our web interface, hosted at http: //hierplane.allenai.org/explain, has the architecture shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 6</ref>. The front-end accepts text input from the user. It forwards this text to the back-end and receives a JSON that contains an annotated tree and styling instructions. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 7</ref> shows a simplified version of the JSON that renders the "He ate pasta with chopsticks" subtree in <ref type="figure">Figure 5</ref>. This JSON is passed to the visualization library, which renders it in HTML and returns this HTML to the front-end.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">Basic Features</head><p>A key feature of our architecture is that the back- end is in charge of defining the node and edge types, and specifying how these should be dis- played. This allows the visualization library to be independent of any particular linguistic annotation scheme. To demonstrate this flexibility, our demo provides two alternative back-ends. By default, it uses a custom grammar that we have been devel- oping for parsing mathematical language (e.g.</p><p>http://hierplane. allenai.org/explain/He% 20ate%20pasta%20with% 20chopsticks</p><p>utilizes the default back-end). However, we have also wrapped the Stanford Parser ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Socher et al., 2013)</ref> as an alternative back-end. For any given sentence, one can try out this alternative by replac- ing the URL prefix will parse "He ate pasta with chopsticks" using the Stanford parser.</p><p>In the JSON returned by the back-end, each node in the tree is annotated with its kind and la- bel ("word"), the type of edge ("link") connecting it to its parent, and its badges ("attributes"). The linkToPosition map allows each node to be posi- tioned according to its relation to its parent (e.g. subjects are positioned to the left of their parents, according to the example JSON). The kindToStyle map specifies colors for the various node types.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">Advanced Features</head><p>To enable interactive node-to-text highlighting, nodes in the input JSON tree can each be anno- tated with a span field that contains the indexes of the start and end characters of the substring cor- responding to the node. To enable modular for- est navigation, each node with a next or previous subtree can be annotated with codes identifying these subtrees. Navigation arrows are only ren- dered when they lead to another subtree. When a user clicks on one, the front-end sends the code identifying the desired subtree to the back-end, and expects the requested subtree as a response.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Conclusion</head><p>In this work, we have tried to rethink the visu- alization of hierarchical linguistic structure from the ground up, first identifying the problems that cause cognitive load (large, static visualizations with no cues to distinguish node or edge families), and then designing new tactics to counter these problems (e.g. expand/collapse functionality, po- sitional cues to distinguish node relations, explicit sequence visualization, and dynamic node-to-text highlighting). We have also created the first tool to explore parse forests using modern web design. We plan to make our visualizer freely available as an open-source library and a web interface.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 6 :</head><label>6</label><figDesc>Figure 6: System architecture for our web interface. Similar architectures are employed by Brat and WebAnno.</figDesc><graphic url="image-6.png" coords="5,73.14,87.39,216.00,136.93" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 7 :</head><label>7</label><figDesc>Figure 7: A simplified version of the JSON that describes the parse tree for "He ate pasta with chopsticks."</figDesc><graphic url="image-7.png" coords="5,308.41,62.80,216.00,496.90" type="bitmap" /></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> The user may experience some slowness when parsing certain sentences. This is due to the speed of the back-end parser, not the visualization library.</note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Dependensee: A dependency parse visualization tool</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Awais</forename><surname>Athar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Stanford typed dependencies manual</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marie-Catherine De</forename><surname>Marneffe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christopher D</forename><surname>Manning</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>Stanford University</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
<note type="report_type">Technical report</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Beyond sentential semantic parsing: Tackling the math sat with a cascade of tree transducers</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mark</forename><surname>Hopkins</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Cristian</forename><surname>Petrescu-Prahova</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Roie</forename><surname>Levin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Le</forename><surname>Ronan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alvaro</forename><surname>Bras</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Vidur</forename><surname>Herrasti</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Joshi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">EMNLP</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Displacy dependency visualizer</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ines</forename><surname>Montani</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://demos.explosion.ai/displacy" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2017" to="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Universal dependencies v1: A multilingual treebank collection</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Joakim</forename><surname>Nivre</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marie-Catherine</forename><surname>De Marneffe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Filip</forename><surname>Ginter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yoav</forename><surname>Goldberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jan</forename><surname>Hajic</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Christopher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ryan</forename><surname>Manning</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Slav</forename><surname>Mcdonald</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sampo</forename><surname>Petrov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Natalia</forename><surname>Pyysalo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Silveira</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 10th International Conference on Language Resources and Evaluation (LREC 2016)</title>
		<meeting>the 10th International Conference on Language Resources and Evaluation (LREC 2016)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1659" to="1666" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Lingo redwoods</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Stephan</forename><surname>Oepen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dan</forename><surname>Flickinger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kristina</forename><surname>Toutanova</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christopher D</forename><surname>Manning</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Research on Language and Computation</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="575" to="596" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ben</forename><surname>Podgursky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://nlpviz.bpodgursky.com" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2017" to="2021" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Parsing with compositional vector grammars</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Richard</forename><surname>Socher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">John</forename><surname>Bauer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Christopher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Andrew Y</forename><surname>Manning</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Ng</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ACL (1)</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="455" to="465" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">brat: a web-based tool for nlp-assisted text annotation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Pontus</forename><surname>Stenetorp</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sampo</forename><surname>Pyysalo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Goran</forename><surname>Topic</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tomoko</forename><surname>Ohta</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sophia</forename><surname>Ananiadou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jun&amp;apos;ichi</forename><surname>Tsujii</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">EACL</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Webanno: A flexible, web-based and visually supported system for distributed annotations</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Iryna</forename><surname>Seid Muhie Yimam</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Richard</forename><surname>Gurevych</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chris</forename><surname>Eckart De Castilho</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Biemann</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 51st Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics: System Demonstrations</title>
		<meeting>the 51st Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics: System Demonstrations<address><addrLine>Sofia, Bulgaria</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="6" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
