<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T11:05+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Learning what to read: Focused machine reading</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
				<availability status="unknown"><p>Copyright Association for Computational Linguistics</p>
				</availability>
				<date>September 7-11, 2017. 2017</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Enrique</forename><surname>Noriega-Atala</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">University of Arizona Tucson</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Arizona</settlement>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marco</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Valenzuela-Escárcega</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">University of Arizona Tucson</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Arizona</settlement>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Clayton</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Morrison</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">University of Arizona Tucson</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Arizona</settlement>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mihai</forename><surname>Surdeanu</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">University of Arizona Tucson</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Arizona</settlement>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Learning what to read: Focused machine reading</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Natural Language Processing</title>
						<meeting> <address><addrLine>Copenhagen, Denmark</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="2905" to="2910"/>
							<date type="published">September 7-11, 2017. 2017</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Recent efforts in bioinformatics have achieved tremendous progress in the machine reading of biomedical literature, and the assembly of the extracted biochemical interactions into large-scale models such as protein signaling pathways. However , batch machine reading of literature at today&apos;s scale (PubMed alone indexes over 1 million papers per year) is unfea-sible due to both cost and processing overhead. In this work, we introduce a focused reading approach to guide the machine reading of biomedical literature towards what literature should be read to answer a biomedical query as efficiently as possible. We introduce a family of algorithms for focused reading, including an intuitive, strong baseline, and a second approach which uses a reinforcement learning (RL) framework that learns when to explore (widen the search) or exploit (narrow it). We demonstrate that the RL approach is capable of answering more queries than the baseline, while being more efficient, i.e., reading fewer documents.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>The millions of academic papers in the biomedi- cal domain contain a vast amount of information that may lead to new hypotheses for disease treat- ment. However, scientists are faced with a prob- lem of "undiscovered public knowledge," as they struggle to read and assimilate all of this informa- tion <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Swanson, 1986)</ref>. Furthermore, the literature is growing at an exponential rate <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Pautasso, 2012)</ref>; PubMed 1 has been adding more than a million pa- pers per year since 2011. We have surpassed our 1 http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed ability to keep up with and integrate these findings through manual reading alone.</p><p>Large ongoing efforts, such as the BioNLP task community <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Nédellec et al., 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Kim et al., 2012</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Kim et al., , 2009</ref>) and the DARPA Big Mechanism Pro- gram <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Cohen, 2015)</ref>, are making progress in ad- vancing methods for machine reading and as- sembly of extracted biochemical interactions into large-scale models. However, to date, these meth- ods rely either on the manual selection of relevant documents, or on the processing of large batches of documents that may or may not be relevant to the model being constructed.</p><p>Batch machine reading of literature at this scale poses a new, growing set of problems. First, access to some documents is costly. The PubMedCentral (PMC) Open Access Subset 2 (OA) is estimated <ref type="bibr">3</ref> to comprise 20% 4 of the total literature; the remain- ing full-text documents are only available through paid access. Second, while there have been great advances in quality, machine reading is still not solved. Updates to our readers requires reprocess- ing the documents. For large document corpora, this quickly becomes the chief bottleneck in infor- mation extraction for model construction and anal- ysis. Finally, even if we could cache all reading results, the search for connections between con- cepts within the extracted results should not be done blindly. At least in the biology domain, the many connections between biological entities and processes leads to a very high branching factor, making blind search for paths intractable.</p><p>To effectively read at this scale, we need to in- corporate methods for focused reading: develop the ability to pose queries about concepts of in- terest and perform targeted, incremental search through the literature for connections between concepts while minimizing reading documents that are likely irrelevant.</p><p>In this paper we present what we believe is the first algorithm for focused reading. We make the following contributions:</p><p>(1) Present a general framework for a family of possible focused reading algorithms along with a baseline instance.</p><p>(2) Cast the design of focused reading algorithms in a reinforcement learning (RL) setting, where the machine decides if it should explore (i.e., cast a wider net) or exploit (i.e., focus reading on a spe- cific topic). (3) Evaluate our focused reading policies in terms of search efficiency and quality of information ex- tracted. The evaluation demonstrates the effective- ness of the RL method: this approach found more information than the strong baseline we propose, while reading fewer documents.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Related Work</head><p>The past few years have seen a large body of work on information extraction (IE), particularly in the biomedical domain. This work is too vast to be comprehensively discussed here. We re- fer the interested reader to the BioNLP commu- nity ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Nédellec et al., 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Kim et al., 2012</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Kim et al., , 2009</ref>, inter alia) for a starting point. However, most of this work focuses on how to read, not on what to read given a goal. To our knowledge, we are the first to focus on the latter task.</p><p>Reinforcement learning has been used to achieve state of the art performance in several natural language processing (NLP) and informa- tion retrieval (IR) tasks. For example, RL has been used to guide IR and filter irrelevant web content <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(Seo and Zhang, 2000;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Zhang and Seo, 2001</ref>). More recently, RL has been combined with deep learning with great success, e.g., for improv- ing coreference resolution <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Clark and Manning, 2016)</ref>. Finally, RL has been used to improve the efficiency of IE by learning how to incrementally reconcile new information and help choose what to look for next <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Narasimhan et al., 2016)</ref>, a task close to ours. This serves as an inspiration for the work we present here, but with a critical differ- ence: <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Narasimhan et al. (2016)</ref> focus on slot filling using a pre-existing template. This makes both the information integration and stopping criteria well- defined. On the other hand, in our focused reading  domain, we do not know ahead of time which new pieces of information are necessarily relevant and must be taken in context.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Focused Reading</head><p>Here we consider focused reading for the biomed- ical domain, and we focus on binary promo- tion/inhibition interactions between biochemical entities. In this setting, the machine reading (or IE) component constructs a directed graph, where vertices represent participants in an interaction (e.g., protein, gene, or a biological process), and edges represent directed activation interactions. Edge labels indicate whether the controller entity has a positive (promoting) or negative (inhibitory) influence on the controlled participant. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 1</ref> shows an example edge in this graph.</p><p>We use REACH <ref type="bibr">5</ref> , an open source IE sys- tem ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Valenzuela-Escárcega et al., 2015)</ref>, to extract interactions from unstructured biomedical text and construct the graph above. We couple this IE sys- tem with a Lucene 6 index of biomedical publica- tions to retrieve papers based on queries about par- ticipant mentions in the text (as discussed below).</p><p>Importantly, we essentially use IE as a black box (thus, our method could potentially work with any IE system), and focus on strategies that guide what the IE system reads for a complex informa- tion need. In particular, we consider the com- mon scenario where a biologist (or other model- building process) queries the literature on:</p><p>How does one participant (source) affect another (destination), where the connec- tion is typically indirect?</p><p>This type of queries is common in biology, where such direct/indirect interactions are observed in experiments, but the explanation of why these de- pendencies exist is unclear.</p><p>Algorithm 1 outlines the general focused read- ing algorithm for this task. In the algorithm, S, D, A, and B represent individual participants, where S and D are the source and destination en- tities in the initial user query. G is the interaction graph that is iteratively constructed during the fo- cused reading procedure, with V being the set of vertices (biochemical entities), and E the set of edges (promotion/inhibition interactions). Σ is the strategy that chooses which two entities/vertices to be used in the next information retrieval iteration. Q is a Lucene query automatically constructed in each iteration to retrieve new papers to read.</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">Algorithm 1 Focused reading framework 1: procedure FOCUSEDREADING(S, D) 2: G ← {{S, D}, ∅} 3: repeat 4: Σ ← ENDPOINTSTRATEGY(G) 5: (A, B) ← CHOOSEENDPOINTS(Σ , G) 6: Q ← CHOOSEQUERY(A, B, G) 7: (V, E) ← LUCENE+REACH(Q) 8: EXPAND(V, E, G) 9: until ISCONNECTED(S, D) OR STOPCONDITIONMET(G)</formula><p>10: end procedure</p><p>The algorithm initializes the search graph as containing the two unconnected participants as vertices: {S, D} (line 2). The algorithm then en- ters into its central loop (lines 3 through 9). The loop terminates when one or more directed paths connecting S to D are found, or when a stopping condition is met: either G has not changed since the previous run through the loop, or after exceed- ing some number of iterations through the loop (in this work, ten).</p><p>At each pass through the loop the algorithm grows the search graph as follows:</p><p>1. The graph G is initialized with two nodes, the source and destination in the user's informa- tion need, and no edges (because we have not read any papers yet). 2. Given the current graph, choose a strategy, Σ , for selecting which entities to query next: exploration or exploitation (line 4). In gen- eral, exploration aims to widen the search space by adding many more nodes to the graph, whereas exploitation aims to narrow the search by focusing on entities in a spe- cific region of the graph. 3. Using strategy Σ , choose the next entities to attempt to link: (A, B) (line 5). 4. Choose a query, Q: again, using explo- ration or exploitation, following the same intuition as with the entity choice strategy (line 6). Here exploration queries retrieve a wider range of documents, while exploitation queries are more restrictive. 5. Run the Lucene query to retrieve papers and process the papers using the IE system. The result of this call is a set of interactions, sim- ilar to that in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 1</ref> (line 7</p><note type="other">). 6. Add the new interaction participant entities (vertices V ) and directed influences (edges E) to the search graph (line 8). 7. If the source and destination entities are con- nected in G, stop: the user's information need has been addressed. Otherwise, con- tinue from step 2. The central loop performs a bidirectional search in which each iteration expands the search hori- zon outward from S and D. Algorithm 1 repre- sents a family of possible focused reading algo- rithms, differentiated by how each of the functions in the main loop are implemented. In this work, ISCONNECTED stops after a single path is found, but a variant could consider finding multiple paths, paths of some length, or incorporate other criteria about the properties of the path. We next consider particular choices for the inner loop functions.</note></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Baseline Algorithm and Evaluation</head><p>The main functions that affect the search behav- ior of Algorithm 1 are ENDPOINTSTRATEGY and CHOOSEQUERY. Here we describe a baseline focused reading implementation in which END- POINTSTRATEGY and CHOOSEQUERY aim to find any path between S and D as quickly as pos- sible.</p><p>For ENDPOINTSTRATEGY, we follow the intu- ition that some participants in a biological graph tend to be connected to more participants than oth- ers, and therefore more likely to yield interactions providing paths between participants in general. Our heuristic is therefore to choose new partici- pants to query that currently have the most inward and outgoing edges (i.e., highest vertex degree) in the current state of G (disallowing choosing an en- tity pair used in a previous query). Now that we have our candidate participants (A, B), our next step is to formulate how we will use these participants to retrieve new papers. Here we consider two classes of query: (1) we restrict our query to only retrieve papers that simultane- ously mention both A and B, therefore more likely retrieving a paper with a direct link between A and B (exploit), or (2) we retrieve papers that mention  either A or B, therefore generally retrieving more papers that will introduce more new participants (explore). For our baseline, where we are trying to find a path between S and D as quickly as possi- ble, we implement a greedy CHOOSEQUERY: first try the conjunctive exploitation query; if no docu- ments are retrieved, then "relax" the search to the disjunctive exploration query.</p><p>To evaluate the baseline, we constructed a data set based on a collection of papers seeded by a set of 132 entities that come from the Univer- sity of Pittsburgh DyCE 7 model, a biomolecular model of pancreatic cancer <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Telmer et al., 2017)</ref>. Using these entities, we retrieved 70,719 papers that mention them. We processed all papers us- ing REACH, extracting all of the interactions men- tioned, and converted them into a single graph. The resulting graph consisted of approximately 80,000 vertices, 115,000 edges, and had an aver- age (undirected) vertex degree of 24. We will refer to this graph as the REACH graph, as it represents what can be retrieved by REACH from the set of 70K papers. Next, we identified which pairs of the original 132 entities are connected by directed paths in DyCE. A total of 789 pairs were found. We used 289 of these entity pairs as testing queries (i.e., generating queries that aim to explain how a given pair is connected according to the literature). The other 500 pairs were held out to train the RL method described below.</p><p>We ran this baseline focused reading algorithm on each of the 289 pairs of participants, in each case attempting to recover a directed path from one to the other. The results are summarized in the middle column of <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table 1</ref>. By issuing 573 queries, the baseline read 26,197 papers out of the total 70,719 papers (37% of the corpus), in order to recover 189 of the 289 paths (65%).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Reinforcement Learning for Focussed Reading</head><p>We analyzed the baseline's behavior in the evalua- tion to identify the conditions under which it failed to find paths. From this, we found that some of the failures could be avoided had we used a dif- 7 Dynamic Cell Environment model of pancreatic cancer. ferent strategy for CHOOSEQUERY, i.e., the base- line chose to exploit when it should have explored more. The conditions for making different choices depend on the current state of G, and earlier query behavior can affect later query opportunities, mak- ing this an iterative decision making problem and a natural fit for a RL formulation.</p><p>Inspired by this observation, we consider RL for finding a better policy for CHOOSEQUERY. We'll refer to an instance of the focused reading algo- rithm with a learned CHOOSEQUERY policy as the RL Query Policy. All other focus reading function- ality is the same as in the baseline. For actions, we consider a simple binary action choice: exploit (conjunctive query) or explore (disjunctive query). We represent the state of the search using a set of features that include: (f1) the current iteration of the search; (f2) the number of times a participant has been used in previous queries; (f3) whether the participants are chosen from the same connected component in G; (f4) the vertex degree of partici- pants; and (f5) the search iteration in which a par- ticipant was introduced. With the goal of recov- ering paths as quickly as possible, we provide a reward of +1 if the algorithm successfully finds a path, a reward of −1 if the search fails to find a path, and assess a "living reward" of −0.05 for each step during the search, to encourage trying to finish the search as quickly as possible.</p><p>We trained the RL Query Policy using the SARSA (Sutton and Barto, 1998) RL algorithm. As the number of unique states is large, we used a linear approximation of the q-function. Once the policy converged during training, we then fixed the linear estimate of the q-function and used this as a fixed policy for selecting queries. We trained the RL Query Policy on the separate set of 500 entity pairs, and evaluated it on the same data set of 289 participant pairs used to evaluate the baseline. Ta- ble 1 summaries the results of both the baseline and the RL Query Policy. The Query Policy re- sulted in a 25% decrease in the number of queries that were run, leading to a 24% drop in the num- ber of papers that were read, while at the same time increasing the number of paths recovered by 3%. We tested the statistical significance of the   difference in results between the baseline and RL policy by performing a bootstrap resampling test. Our hypotheses were that the policy reads fewer papers, makes fewer queries and finds more paths.</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">All − Iteration − Query − Same − Ranks (f4) − Particip. features number (f1) counts (f2) component (f3) intro. (f5)</formula><p>The resulting estimated p-values for fewer papers and fewer queries was found to be near 0, and &lt; 0.003 for finding more paths. An ablation study of the state features found that features (f2) and (f5) had the largest impact on number of papers read; both model the history of the reading task (see the next section for details). This highlights that the RL model is indeed learning to model the entire iterative process.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Analysis</head><p>Feature Ablation Test: We performed an abla- tion test on the features that encode the RL state.</p><p>The results are summarized in <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">Table 2</ref>. Similar to Section 5, we grouped the features into five dif- ferent groups, and we measured the impact of re- moving one feature group at a time. Overall, the amount of paths found doesn't have a significant amount of variance, but the efficiency of the search (amount of papers read and number of queries made) depends on several feature groups. For ex- ample, features (f1), (f2), and (f4) have a large ef- fect on both the number of papers read and the number of queries made. Removing the feature (f5) actually reduces the number of papers read by approximately 2K with a minimal reduction in the number of paths found, which suggests that this task could benefit from feature selection.</p><p>RL Policy Error Analysis: Lastly, we analyzed the execution trace of eighteen (20% of the errors) of the searches that failed to find a path under RL.</p><p>The results are summarized in <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">Table 3</ref>. The table shows that the main source of failures is receiv- ing no results from the information retrieval query, i.e., when the IR system returns zero documents for the chosen query. This is typically caused by over-constrained queries. The second most com- mon source of failures was ungrounded partici- pants, i.e., when at least one of the selected par- ticipants that form the query could not be linked to our protein knowledge base. This is generally caused by mistakes in our NER sequence model, and also tends to yield no results from the IR com- ponent. Finally, the low yield from IE situation ap- pears when the the information produced through machine reading in one iteration is scarce and adds no new components to the interaction graph, again resulting in a stop condition.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7">Discussion and future work</head><p>We introduced a framework for the focused read- ing of biomedical literature, which is necessary to handle the data overload that plagues even ma- chine reading approaches. We have presented a generic focused reading algorithm, an intuitive, strong baseline algorithm that instantiates it, and formulated an RL approach that learns how to efficiently query the paper repository that feeds the machine reading component. We showed that the RL-based focused reading is more efficient than the baseline (i.e., it reads 24% fewer papers), while answering 7% more queries. There are many exciting directions in which to take this work. First, more of the focused reading algorithm can be subject to RL, with the CHOOSEENDPOINTS policy being the clear next candidate. Second, we can expand focused read- ing to efficiently search for multiple paths between S and D. Finally, we will incorporate additional biological constraints (e.g., focus on pathways that exist in specific species) into the search itself.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: Example of a graph edge encoding the relation extracted from the text: mTOR triggers cellular apoptosis.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Baseline</head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" validated="true"><head>Table 1 : Results of the baseline and RL Query Policy for the focused reading of biomedical literature.</head><label>1</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>RL Query Policy 
# IR queries 
573 
433 
25% decrease 
Unique papers read 
26,197 
19,883 
24% decrease 
# Paths recovered (out of 289) 189 (65%) 
198 (68%) 
3% increase 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" validated="false"><head>Table 2 : Ablation test on the features used to represent the RL state.</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Empty query Ungrounded Low yield 
results 
participant(s) 
from IE 
Error cause 
12 
4 
2 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3" validated="false"><head>Table 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Error analysis on 18 queries that failed 
under the RL algorithm. 

</table></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="2"> https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/ tools/openftlist/ 3 https://tinyurl.com/bachman-oa 4 This includes 5% from PMC author manuscripts.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="5"> https://github.com/clulab/reach 6 https://lucene.apache.org</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>This work was partially funded by the DARPA Big Mechanism program under ARO contract W911NF-14-1-0395.</p><p>Dr. Mihai Surdeanu discloses a financial inter-est in Lum.ai. This interest has been disclosed to the University of Arizona Institutional Review Committee and is being managed in accordance with its conflict of interest policies.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Deep reinforcement learning for mention-ranking coreference models</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kevin</forename><surname>Clark</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Christopher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Manning</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:1609.08667</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
<note type="report_type">arXiv preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">DARPA&apos;s Big Mechanism program</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Paul</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Cohen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Physical Biology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">45008</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The genia event and protein coreference tasks of the bionlp shared task</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jin-Dong</forename><surname>Kim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ngan</forename><surname>Nguyen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yue</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Toshihisa</forename><surname>Jun&amp;apos;ichi Tsujii</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Akinori</forename><surname>Takagi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Yonezawa</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">BMC bioinformatics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Overview of bionlp&apos;09 shared task on event extraction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jin-Dong</forename><surname>Kim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tomoko</forename><surname>Ohta</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sampo</forename><surname>Pyysalo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yoshinobu</forename><surname>Kano</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jun&amp;apos;ichi</forename><surname>Tsujii</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Workshop on Current Trends in Biomedical Natural Language Processing: Shared Task</title>
		<meeting>the Workshop on Current Trends in Biomedical Natural Language Processing: Shared Task</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="9" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Improving information extraction by acquiring external evidence with reinforcement learning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Karthik</forename><surname>Narasimhan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Adam</forename><surname>Yala</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Regina</forename><surname>Barzilay</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</title>
		<meeting>the Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Overview of bionlp shared task 2013</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Claire</forename><surname>Nédellec</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Robert</forename><surname>Bossy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jin-Dong</forename><surname>Kim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jungjae</forename><surname>Kim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tomoko</forename><surname>Ohta</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sampo</forename><surname>Pyysalo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Pierre</forename><surname>Zweigenbaum</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the BioNLP Shared Task 2013 Workshop</title>
		<meeting>the BioNLP Shared Task 2013 Workshop</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="7" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Publication growth in biological sub-fields: patterns, predictability and sustainability</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marco</forename><surname>Pautasso</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Sustainability</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3234" to="3247" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A reinforcement learning agent for personalized information filtering</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Young-Woo</forename><surname>Seo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Byoung-Tak</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 5th international conference on Intelligent user interfaces</title>
		<meeting>the 5th international conference on Intelligent user interfaces</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="248" to="251" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Reinforcement learning: An introduction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Richard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Andrew G</forename><surname>Sutton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Barto</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
			<publisher>MIT press Cambridge</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Undiscovered public knowledge</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Don R Swanson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The Library Quarterly</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">56</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="103" to="118" />
			<date type="published" when="1986" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Telmer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Sayed</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Butchy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Kaltenmeir</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Lotze</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Miskov-Zivanov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Manuscript in preparation</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A domain-independent rule-based framework for event extraction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Marco</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gustave</forename><surname>Valenzuela-Escárcega</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Thomas</forename><surname>Hahnpowell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mihai</forename><surname>Hicks</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Surdeanu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 53rd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics and the 7th International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing of the Assian Federation of Natural Language Processing: Software Demonstrations (ACL-IJCNLP)</title>
		<meeting>the 53rd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics and the 7th International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing of the Assian Federation of Natural Language Processing: Software Demonstrations (ACL-IJCNLP)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Personalized web-document filtering using reinforcement learning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tak</forename><surname>Byoung</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Young-Woo</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Seo</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Applied Artificial Intelligence</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="665" to="685" />
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
