<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T10:27+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Word Etymology as Native Language Interference</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
				<availability status="unknown"><p>Copyright Association for Computational Linguistics</p>
				</availability>
				<date>September 7-11, 2017. 2017</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Vivi</forename><surname>Nastase</surname></persName>
							<email>nastase@cl.uni-heidelberg.de</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">University of Heidelberg Heidelberg</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Trento</settlement>
									<country>Germany, Italy</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Carlo</forename><surname>Strapparava</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">University of Heidelberg Heidelberg</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Trento</settlement>
									<country>Germany, Italy</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Fondazione</forename><forename type="middle">Bruno</forename><surname>Kessler</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">University of Heidelberg Heidelberg</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Trento</settlement>
									<country>Germany, Italy</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Word Etymology as Native Language Interference</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Natural Language Processing</title>
						<meeting> <address><addrLine>Copenhagen, Denmark</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="2702" to="2707"/>
							<date type="published">September 7-11, 2017. 2017</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>We present experiments that show the influence of native language on lexical choice when producing text in another language in this particular case English. We start from the premise that non-native En-glish speakers will choose lexical items that are close to words in their native language. This leads us to an etymology-based representation of documents written by people whose mother tongue is an Indo-European language. Based on this representation we grow a language family tree, that matches closely the Indo-European language tree.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>In second-language writing, vestiges of the native language such as pronunciation, vocabulary and grammar are well-attested, and the phenomenon is called native language interference <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">(Odlin, 1989)</ref>. At the lexical level, the choice as well as the spelling can be indicative of the native language, through the choice of cognates, true or false friends -e.g. a writer with native language Ger- man may choose bloom cognate with blume, while a French one may choose flower, cognate with fleur. Misspellings -cuestion instead of question are also indicative, as the writer will tend to spell words close to the form from her original language <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">(Nicolai et al., 2013)</ref>.</p><p>In this paper we also look at native language in- terference starting from the lexical level, but ab- stract away from the actual word forms, and focus instead on the language of the etymological an- cestors. The hypothesis we investigate is that the collective evidence of etymological ancestor lan- guages are indicative of the language of the native speaker, and that this effect is sufficiently strong  <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref>: Examples of etymological ancestry from Wiktionary to allow us to rebuild an Indo-European language family tree. We use a corpus of essays written by English language learners, whose native language cover the languages from the Indo-European fam- ily. Etymological information is provided by an et- ymological dictionary extracted from Wiktionary.</p><p>The fact that word etymologies are included in the native-language interference phenomena could be used in various ways, i.a.: (i) to influence the selection of material for language learning, by fo- cusing on vocabulary closer etymologically to the native language of the student, thus facilitating lexical retention; (ii) to reveal lexical choice er- rors caused by "etymological interference"; (iii) together with other interference phenomena, for the automatic corrections of language errors.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Related Work</head><p>English is a widespread common language for communication in a variety of fields -science, news, entertainment, politics, etc. A consequence is that numerous people learn English as a sec- ond (or indeed n th language). The study of native language interference with the learning of English can be used in multiple ways, including devising methods to make the learning easier and correct- ing language errors ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Leacock et al., 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Gamon, 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Dahlmeier and Ng, 2011</ref>). <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Massung and Zhai (2016)</ref> present an overview of approaches to the task of natural language iden- tification (NLI). Various surface indicators hold clues about a speaker's native language, that make their way into language production in a non-native language. <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Nagata and Whittaker (2013)</ref>, <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Nagata (2014)</ref> find that grammatical patterns from the na- tive language seep into the production of English texts. <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Tsur and Rappoport (2007)</ref> verify the hy- pothesis that lexical choice of non-native speak- ers is influenced by the phonology of their native language, and <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">Wong and Dras (2009)</ref> propose the idea that (grammatical) errors are also influenced by the native language. One could draw the infer- ence that character n-grams then could be indica- tive of the native language, and this was shown to be the case by <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Ionescu et al. (2014)</ref>. The natural language identification task ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Tetreault et al., 2013</ref>) attracted 29 participat- ing teams, which used a variety of features to accomplish the NLI task as a classification exercise: n-grams of lexical tokens (words and POS tags), skip-grams, grammatical information (dependency parses, parse tree rules, preference for particular grammatical forms, e.g. active or passive voice), spelling errors.</p><p>Apart from morphological, lexical, grammati- cal features, words also have an etymological di- mension. The language family tree itself is drawn based on the analysis of the evolution of lan- guages. Language evolution includes, or starts with, word etymologies. Word etymologies have been under-used for tasks related to NLI. They have been used implicitly in work that investi- gates cognate interference <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">(Nicolai et al., 2013)</ref>, and explicitly by <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Malmasi and Cahill, 2015</ref>) who use words with Old English and Latin etymolo- gies as unigram features in building classifiers for the TOEFL11 dataset. Etymological informa- tion is obtained from the Etymological WordNet (de <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Melo and Weikum, 2010)</ref>.</p><p>We also investigate here the impact of ety- mological information, but unlike previous work, we do not extract unigram/n-gram features for classification, but we look at the collective evi- dence captured by the etymological "fingerprint" for each document and set of essays.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Etymological fingerprints</head><p>To investigate the influence of etymological an- cestor languages, we represent each essay through etymological features, based on which we also built language vectors for each Indo-European lan- guage represented in the corpus. Essay vectors are then used to test native language identification po- tential, and the language vectors are used to grow a language family tree.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Word etymologies</head><p>Dictionaries customarily include etymological in- formation for their entries. Wikipedia's Wik- tionary has amassed a considerable number of en- tries that joined this trend. The etymological in- formation can, and indeed has been extracted and prepared for machine consumption (de Melo and Weikum, 2010): Etymological WordNet 1 contains 6,031,431 entries for 2,877,036 words (actually, morphemes) in 397 languages. Because we pro- cess essays written in English, we use only the entries that give etymological origins for English words -240,656. <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref> shows as an example of the kind of information formalized in the Ety- mological WordNet the etymological ancestry for the words flower, blossom, bloom.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Document/collection modeling</head><p>Essay representation After tokenization, POS tagging and lemmatization, each essay in the dataset is represented as a vector of etymological ancestry proportions obtained through the follow- ing processing steps:</p><p>1. for each token that has an entry in the ety- mological dictionary, we replace it with the language of its etymological ancestor -e.g. sight will be replaced by ang (Old English), vision by lat (Latin) ( <ref type="table">Table 1</ref> shows the num- ber of words with etymological ancestors in the subsets corresponding to each language);</p><p>2. compute the proportion of each etymological language in the essay, and represent the es- say as a vector of language proportions 2 . We experimented with using etymological infor- mation going back through several ancestry levels, but using the first level led to the best results.</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">e i ∼ p il 1 , ..., p iln where p il k = n il k N i,etym</formula><p>n il k is the number of words with etymologi- cal ancestor l k in the i-th essay, and N i,etym is the number of words with etymological in- formation in essay i.</p><p>Language vectors For each subcollection corre- sponding to one (student native) language L j , we build the language vectors by averaging over the essay vectors in the subcollection:</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">V L j = p L j l 1 , ..., p L j lm where p L j l k = lang(e i )=L j p il k |{e i |lang(e i )=L j }| p L j l k</formula><note type="other">is the proportion of etymological an- cestor language l k in all essays whose author has as native language L j . The essay and language vectors are filtered by removing etymological languages whose corre- sponding values in the language vectors are less than 10 −4 .</note></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Experiments</head><p>We investigate the strength of the etymological "fingerprint" of individual and collective essays written by non-native speakers of English, through two tasks -native language identification and lan- guage family tree construction. Towards this end, we work with a collection of essays written by contributors whose native language is an Indo- European language. The dataset is described in Section 4.1. For etymological information we rely on an etymological dictionary, described briefly in Section 3.1. Data modeling and the experiments conducted are described in Section 3.2.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">Data</head><p>We used the ICLE dataset ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Granger et al., 2009</ref>), consisting of English essays written by non- native English speakers. We filter out those that were written by people whose mother tongue is not from the Indo-European family (i.e. Chinese, Japanese, Turkish and Tswana). <ref type="table">Table 1</ref> shows a summary of the data statistics, including the num- ber of words for which we have found ancestors in the etymological dictionary used. The corpus con- sists entirely of essays written by students. Two types of essay writing are present: argumentative essay writings and literature examination papers. <ref type="table">Table 2</ref> displays a list of topics in the corpus. The essays should be at least 500 words long and up to 1,000, and contain all the spelling mistakes made by their authors.</p><p>Following <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Nagata and Whittaker (2013)</ref>, who also built the Indo-European family tree based on n-grams composed of function words and open- class parts of speech, essays that do not respect one of the following rules are filtered out: (i) the writer has only one native language, (ii) the writer has only one language at home; (iii) the two lan- guages in (i) and (ii) are the same as the native language of the subcorpus to which the essay be- longs. <ref type="table">Table 1</ref> shows a summary of the data statis- tics after filtering, including the number of words for which we have found ancestors in the etymo- logical dictionary used. Most university degrees are theoretical and do not prepare students for the real world. They are therefore of very little value. 4</p><p>A man/woman's financial reward should be commensurate with their contribution to the society they live in. 5</p><p>The role of censorship in Western society. 6</p><p>Marx once said that religion was the opium of the masses. If he was alive at the end of the 20th century, he would replace religion with television. 7</p><p>All armies should consist entirely of professional soldiers : there is no value in a system of military service. 8</p><p>The Gulf War has shown us that it is still a great thing to fight for one's country. 9</p><p>Feminists have done more harm to the cause of women than good. 10</p><p>In his novel Animal Farm, George Orwell wrote "All men are equal: but some are more equal than others". How true is this today? 11</p><p>In the words of the old song "Money is the root of all evil". 12</p><p>Europe. 13</p><p>In the 19th century, Victor Hugo said: "How sad it is to think that nature is calling out but humanity refuses to pay heed. "Do you think it is still true nowadays ? 14</p><p>Some people say that in our modern world, dominated by sci- ence technology and industrialization, there is no longer a place for dreaming and imagination. What is your opinion ? <ref type="table">Table 2</ref>: Topics in the ICLE dataset.</p><p>The suitability of the dataset above for NLI was questioned by <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Brooke and Hirst (2012)</ref>. They have shown that the fact that the corpus consists of sets of essays on a number of topics causes an overes-timation of the results of NLI when random split- ting, particularly for groups of contributors that were presented with very different topics -e.g. students from Asia vs. students from Europe. We have analyzed the distribution of essays into top- ics using the essay titles, and observed that con- tributions from Europe (which are our focus) have similar distributions across the featured topics.</p><p>Growing the language tree To grow the lan- guage tree from the language vectors built from the English essays, we use a variation of the UPMGA -Unweighted Pair Group Method with Arithmetic Mean -algorithm. Starting with the language vectors V L j , we compute the distance be- tween each pair of vectors using a distance met- ric algorithm. At each step we choose the closest pair (L a , L b ) and combine them in a subtree, then combine their corresponding sub-collection of es- says, and build the language vector for the "com- posite" language L a,b , and compute its distance to the other language vectors.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">Results</head><p>We test whether etymological information sur- faces as native language interference that is de- tectible through the tasks of native language iden- tification and reconstruction of the language fam- ily tree. <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">Table 3</ref> shows results on the multi-class classification of essays according to the native lan- guage of the author, in the form of F-score av- erage results using SVM classification in 5-fold cross-validation (using Weka's SMO implementa- tion 3 with polynomial kernel and default param- eters). The baseline corresponds to the language distribution in the dataset. We use as additional comparison point another set of features used to reconstruct the language family tree -the (closed- class) word and POS 3grams Nagata and Whit- taker (2013), such as the NN of; a JJ NN; the JJ NN. We build all such patterns for the data, and keep the top 1000 by overall frequency.</p><p>Adding etymological features that capture the distribution of etymological ancestors for each es- say led to improved results for all languages, vary- ing from a non-significant improvement of 0.2% point for Russian, to a significant and high 5.3% improvement for German. Using only words, the accuracy is 73.2%, which increases marginally to 73.7 when etymology information is added. Us- ing a full complement of standard features -word,  Despite the rather low results when etymology is used on its own for language identification, the cumulative evidence leads to a language family tree that closely matches the gold standard ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure  2</ref>). The tree on top is the gold standard cf. <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Nagata and Whittaker, 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Crystal, 1997)</ref>. The tree is grown by computing the euclidean distance be- tween pairwise vectors, and then iteratively group- ing together the closest vectors at each step as de- scribed in Section 4.1.  The two wrongly placed languages in our lan- guage family tree are Czech and Dutch. Czech is grouped with the Germanic languages. Histori- cally, the country which is now the Czech Repub- lic has been under German occupation for long pe- riods of time. We propose the hypothesis that this has influenced the Czech language at the lexical level, and our etymological fingerprinting charac- terizes mostly the lexical aspects of language. We plan to verify this theory as etymological informa- tion for Czech and German becomes more read- ily available in sufficient quantities. We have not yet found an explanation for the grouping of Dutch with the Slavic languages. Like mentioned before, the language vectors we built rely exclusively on lexical information, and it is possible that Dutch's grammatical structure is what defines it best as be- ing a part of the Germanic language family, as op- posed to the lexical dimension.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Conclusion</head><p>In this paper we have shown an exploration of a novel indicator of native language interference in second language learning, particularly etymol- ogy. While cross-linguistically related words (cognates, false and true friends) have been part of the repertoire of features for native language iden- tification and cross-language studies, we have fo- cused here on the language of etymological ances- tors of words, and in particular their distribution in documents. Experiments in recreating the Indo- European family tree have shown that the com- position of a document in terms of etymological languages is indicative of the native language of the writer to the extent that fundamental charac- teristics of languages -typological relatedness be- tween languages -emerge.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Spanish French Italian Russian Bulgarian Polish Czech Norwegian Swedish German Dutch Spanish French Italian Russian Dutch Bulgarian Polish Norwegian Swedish Czech German Romance Slavic Germanic Indo-European family tree Family tree generated based on etymology distributions in ICLE essays</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2: Language family trees-the gold standard and the automatically generated one</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3" validated="false"><head>Table 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>5-fold cross-validation F-scores and ac-
curacy for language classification 

lemma and character ngrams (n=1..3) (built fol-
lowing (Lahiri and Mihalcea, 2013)) -gives an 
average accuracy (over 5 fold cross-validation) of 
85.7%. Adding etymology does not lead to im-
provements when added to this set. 
</table></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> http://www1.icsi.berkeley.edu/ ˜ demelo/etymwn/ 2 Using automatically corrected typos (first option of ispell) did not change the results significantly.</note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Robust, lexicalized native language identification</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Julian</forename><surname>Brooke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Graeme</forename><surname>Hirst</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">The COLING 2012 Organizing Committee</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Mumbai, India</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="391" to="408" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Proceedings of COLING 2012</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The Cambridge Encyclopedia of Language</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Crystal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
			<publisher>Cambridge University Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Correcting semantic collocation errors with l1-induced paraphrases</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Daniel</forename><surname>Dahlmeier</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hwee Tou</forename><surname>Ng</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing, EMNLP &apos;11</title>
		<meeting>the Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing, EMNLP &apos;11<address><addrLine>Stroudsburg, PA, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="107" to="117" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Using mostly native data to correct errors in learners&apos; writing: A meta-classifier approach</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Gamon</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Human Language Technologies: The 2010 Annual Conference of the North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics, HLT &apos;10</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Stroudsburg, PA, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="163" to="171" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sylviane</forename><surname>Granger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Estelle</forename><surname>Dagneaux</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Fanny</forename><surname>Meunier</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Magali</forename><surname>Paquot</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">International Corpus of Learner English</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>ICLE</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Can characters reveal your native language? a language-independent approach to native language identification</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tudor</forename><surname>Radu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marius</forename><surname>Ionescu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Aoife</forename><surname>Popescu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Cahill</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2014 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP)</title>
		<meeting>the 2014 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP)<address><addrLine>Doha, Qatar</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1363" to="1373" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Association for Computational Linguistics</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Using ngram and word network features for native language identification</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Shibamouli</forename><surname>Lahiri</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rada</forename><surname>Mihalcea</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of BEA@NAACL-HLT 2013</title>
		<meeting>of BEA@NAACL-HLT 2013</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="251" to="259" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Automated grammatical error detection for language learners</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Claudia</forename><surname>Leacock</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Martin</forename><surname>Chodorow</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Gamon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Joel</forename><surname>Tetreault</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Synthesis Lectures on Human Language Technologies</title>
		<editor>Graeme Hirst</editor>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Morgan and Claypool</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>2nd edition</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Measuring feature diversity in native language identification</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Shervin</forename><surname>Malmasi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Aoife</forename><surname>Cahill</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Tenth Workshop on Innovative Use of NLP for Building Educational Applications</title>
		<meeting>the Tenth Workshop on Innovative Use of NLP for Building Educational Applications<address><addrLine>Denver, Colorado</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="49" to="55" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Nonnative text analysis: A survey</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sean</forename><surname>Massung</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chenkxiang</forename><surname>Zhai</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Natural Language Engineering</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">163186</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Towards universal multilingual knowledge bases</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gerhard</forename><surname>Gerard De Melo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Weikum</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Principles, Construction, and Applications of Multilingual Wordnets. Proceedings of the 5th Global WordNet Conference (GWC 2010)</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>New Delhi, India</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="149" to="156" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Language family relationship preserved in non-native english</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ryo</forename><surname>Nagata</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of COLING 2014, the 25th International Conference on Computational Linguistics: Technical Papers</title>
		<meeting>COLING 2014, the 25th International Conference on Computational Linguistics: Technical Papers<address><addrLine>Dublin, Ireland</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1940" to="1949" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Dublin City University and Association for Computational Linguistics</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Reconstructing an indo-european family tree from nonnative english texts</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ryo</forename><surname>Nagata</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Edward</forename><surname>Whittaker</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 51st</title>
		<meeting>the 51st</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<monogr>
				<title level="m">Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Sofia, Bulgaria</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1137" to="1147" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Association for Computational Linguistics</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Cognate and misspelling features for natural language identification</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Garrett</forename><surname>Nicolai</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bradley</forename><surname>Hauer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mohammad</forename><surname>Salameh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lei</forename><surname>Yao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Grzegorz</forename><surname>Kondrak</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Eighth Workshop on Innovative Use of NLP for Building Educational Applications</title>
		<meeting>the Eighth Workshop on Innovative Use of NLP for Building Educational Applications<address><addrLine>Atlanta, Georgia</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="140" to="145" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Language Transfer</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Terence</forename><surname>Odlin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1989" />
			<publisher>Cambridge University Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A report on the first native language identification shared task</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Joel</forename><surname>Tetreault</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Daniel</forename><surname>Blanchard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Aoife</forename><surname>Cahill</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Eighth Workshop on Innovative Use of NLP for Building Educational Applications</title>
		<meeting>the Eighth Workshop on Innovative Use of NLP for Building Educational Applications<address><addrLine>Atlanta, Georgia</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="48" to="57" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Using classifier features for studying the effect of native language on the choice of written second language words</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Oren</forename><surname>Tsur</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ari</forename><surname>Rappoport</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Workshop on Cognitive Aspects of Computational Language Acquisition, CACLA &apos;07</title>
		<meeting>the Workshop on Cognitive Aspects of Computational Language Acquisition, CACLA &apos;07<address><addrLine>Stroudsburg, PA, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="9" to="16" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Association for Computational Linguistics</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Contrastive analysis and native language identification</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jojo</forename><surname>Sze-Meng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mark</forename><surname>Wong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Dras</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Australasian Language Technology Association Workshop</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Sydney, Australia</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="53" to="61" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
