<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T13:01+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">RACE: Large-scale ReAding Comprehension Dataset From Examinations</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
				<availability status="unknown"><p>Copyright Association for Computational Linguistics</p>
				</availability>
				<date>September 7-11, 2017. 2017</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Guokun</forename><surname>Lai</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Language Technologies Institute Carnegie Mellon University Pittsburgh</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>15213</postCode>
									<region>PA</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Qizhe</forename><surname>Xie</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Language Technologies Institute Carnegie Mellon University Pittsburgh</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>15213</postCode>
									<region>PA</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">⇤</forename></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Language Technologies Institute Carnegie Mellon University Pittsburgh</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>15213</postCode>
									<region>PA</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hanxiao</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Language Technologies Institute Carnegie Mellon University Pittsburgh</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>15213</postCode>
									<region>PA</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yiming</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Language Technologies Institute Carnegie Mellon University Pittsburgh</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>15213</postCode>
									<region>PA</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Eduard</forename><surname>Hovy</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Language Technologies Institute Carnegie Mellon University Pittsburgh</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>15213</postCode>
									<region>PA</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">RACE: Large-scale ReAding Comprehension Dataset From Examinations</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Natural Language Processing</title>
						<meeting> <address><addrLine>Copenhagen, Denmark</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="785" to="794"/>
							<date type="published">September 7-11, 2017. 2017</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>We present RACE, a new dataset for benchmark evaluation of methods in the reading comprehension task. Collected from the English exams for middle and high school Chinese students in the age range between 12 to 18, RACE consists of near 28,000 passages and near 100,000 questions generated by human experts (English instructors), and covers a variety of topics which are carefully designed for evaluating the students&apos; ability in understanding and reasoning. In particular, the proportion of questions that requires reasoning is much larger in RACE than that in other benchmark datasets for reading comprehension, and there is a significant gap between the performance of the state-of-the-art models (43%) and the ceiling human performance (95%). We hope this new dataset can serve as a valuable resource for research and evaluation in machine comprehension. The dataset is freely available at</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Constructing an intelligence agent capable of un- derstanding text as people is the major challenge of NLP research. With recent advances in deep learning techniques, it seems possible to achieve human-level performance in certain language un- derstanding tasks, and a surge of effort has been devoted to the machine comprehension task where people aim to construct a system with the ability to ⇤ * indicates equal contribution answer questions related to a document that it has to comprehend <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Chen et al., 2016;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Dhingra et al., 2016;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b18">Yang et al., 2017)</ref>.</p><p>Towards this goal, several large-scale datasets ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Rajpurkar et al., 2016;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Onishi et al., 2016;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Hill et al., 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Trischler et al., 2016;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Hermann et al., 2015)</ref> have been proposed, which allow re- searchers to train deep learning systems and ob- tain results comparable to the human performance. While having a suitable dataset is crucial for eval- uating the system's true ability in reading compre- hension, the existing datasets suffer several critical limitations. Firstly, in all datasets, the candidate options are directly extracted from the context (as a single entity or a text span), which leads to the fact that lots of questions can be solved trivially via word-based search and context-matching with- out deeper reasoning; this constrains the types of questions as well. Secondly, answers and ques- tions of most datasets are either crowd-sourced or automatically-generated, bringing a significant amount of noises in the datasets and limits the ceil- ing performance by domain experts, such as 82% for Childrens Book Test and 84% for Who-did- What. Yet another issue in existing datasets is that the topic coverages are often biased due to the spe- cific ways that the data were initially collected, making it hard to evaluate the ability of systems in text comprehension over a broader range of topics.</p><p>To address the aforementioned limitations, we constructed a new dataset by collecting a large set of questions, answers and associated pas- sages in the English exams for middle-school and high-school Chinese students within the 12-18 age range. Those exams were designed by do- main experts (instructors) for evaluating the read- ing comprehension ability of students, with en- sured quality and broad topic coverage. Fur- thermore, the answers by machines or by hu- mans can be objectively graded for evaluation and comparison using the same evaluation met- rics. Although efforts have been made with a sim- ilar motivation, including the MCTest dataset cre- ated by ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Richardson et al., 2013</ref>) (containing 500 passages and 2000 questions) and several others <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(Peñas et al., 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Rodrigo et al., 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Khashabi et al., 2016;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Shibuki et al., 2014)</ref>, the usefulness of those datasets is significantly restricted due to their small sizes, especially not suitable for train- ing powerful deep neural networks whose success relies on the availability of relatively large training sets.</p><p>Our new dataset, namely RACE, consists of 27,933 passages and 97,687 questions. After read- ing each passage, each student is asked to answer several questions where each question is provided with four candidate answers -only one of them is correct . Unlike existing datasets, both the ques- tions and candidate answers in RACE are not re- stricted to be the text spans in the original passage; instead, they can be described in any words. A sample from our dataset is presented in <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>.</p><p>Our latter analysis shows that correctly answer- ing a large portion of questions in RACE requires the ability of reasoning, the most important fea- ture as a machine comprehension dataset <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Chen et al., 2016)</ref>. RACE also offers two important sub- divisions of the reasoning types in its questions, namely passage summarization and attitude anal- ysis, which have not been introduced by the any of the existing large-scale datasets to our knowledge.</p><p>In addition, compared to other existing datasets where passages are either domain-specific or of a single fixed style (namely news stories for CNN/- Daily Mail, NEWSQA and Who-did-What, fiction stories for Children's Book Test and Book Test, and Wikipedia articles for SQUAD), passages in RACE almost cover all types of human articles, such as news, stories, ads, biography, philosophy, etc., in a variety of styles. This comprehensiveness of topic/style coverage makes RACE a desirable resource for evaluating the reading comprehension ability of machine learning systems in general.</p><p>The advantages of our proposed dataset over ex- isting large datasets in machine reading compre- hension can be summarized as follows:</p><p>• All questions and candidate options are gen- erated by human experts, which are intention- ally designed to test human agent's ability in reading comprehension. This makes RACE a relatively accurate indicator for reflecting the text comprehension ability of machine learn- ing systems under human judge.</p><p>• The questions are substantially more difficult than those in existing datasets, in terms of the large portion of questions involving reason- ing. At the meantime, it is also sufficiently large to support the training of deep learning models.</p><p>• Unlike existing large-scale datasets, candi- date options in RACE are human generated sentences which may not appear in the origi- nal passage. This makes the task more chal- lenging and allows a rich type of questions such as passage summarization and attitude analysis.</p><p>• Broad coverage in various domains and writ- ing styles: a desirable property for evaluating generic (in contrast to domain/style-specific) comprehension ability of learning models.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Related Work</head><p>In this section, we briefly outline existing datasets for the machine reading comprehension task, in- cluding their strengths and weaknesses.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">MCTest</head><p>MCTest ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Richardson et al., 2013</ref>) is a popular dataset for question answering in the same for- mat as RACE, where each question is associated with four candidate answers with a single cor- rect answer. Although questions in MCTest are of high-quality ensured by careful examinations through crowdsourcing, it contains only 500 stores and 2000 questions, which substantially restricts its usage in training advanced machine compre- hension models. Moreover, while MCTest is de- signed for 7 years old children, RACE is con- structed for middle and high school students at 12-18 years old hence is more complicated and requires stronger reasoning skills. In other words, RACE can be viewed as a larger and more difficult version of the MCTest dataset.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">Cloze-style datasets</head><p>The past few years have witnessed several large- scale cloze-style datasets ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Hermann et al., 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Hill et al., 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Onishi et al., 2016)</ref>, whose questions are formulated by obliter- ating a word or an entity in a sentence.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Passage:</head><p>In a small village in England about 150 years ago, a mail coach was standing on the street. It didn't come to that village often. People had to pay a lot to get a letter. The person who sent the letter didn't have to pay the postage, while the receiver had to. "Here's a letter for Miss Alice Brown," said the mailman. " I'm Alice Brown," a girl of about 18 said in a low voice. Alice looked at the envelope for a minute, and then handed it back to the mailman. "I'm sorry I can't take it, I don't have enough money to pay it", she said. A gentleman standing around were very sorry for her. Then he came up and paid the postage for her. When the gentleman gave the letter to her, she said with a smile, " Thank you very much, This letter is from Tom. I'm going to marry him. He went to London to look for work. I've waited a long time for this letter, but now I don't need it, there is nothing in it." "Really? How do you know that?" the gentleman said in surprise. "He told me that he would put some signs on the envelope. Look, sir, this cross in the corner means that he is well and this circle means he has found work. That's good news."</p><p>The gentleman was Sir Rowland Hill. He didn't forgot Alice and her letter. "The postage to be paid by the receiver has to be changed," he said to himself and had a good plan. "The postage has to be much lower, what about a penny? And the person who sends the letter pays the postage. He has to buy a stamp and put it on the envelope." he said . The government accepted his plan. Then the first stamp was put out in 1840. It was called the "Penny Black". It had a picture of the Queen on it.</p><p>Questions:  <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>: Sample reading comprehension problems from our dataset.</p><p>CNN/Daily Mail ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Hermann et al., 2015</ref>) are the largest machine comprehension datasets with 1.4M questions. However, both require limited reasoning ability <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Chen et al., 2016)</ref>. In fact, the best machine performance obtained by researchers ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Chen et al., 2016;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Dhingra et al., 2016</ref>) is close to human's performance on CNN/Daily Mail.</p><p>Childrens Book Test (CBT) ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Hill et al., 2015</ref>) and Book Test (BT) (Bajgar et al., 2016) are con- structed in a similar manner. Each passage in CBT consist of 20 contiguous sentences extracted from children's books and the next (21st) sentence is used to make the question. The main difference between the two datasets is the size of BT being 60 times larger. Machine comprehension models have also matched human performance on CBT ( .</p><p>Who Did What (WDW) ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Onishi et al., 2016</ref>) is yet another cloze-style dataset constructed from the LDC English Gigaword newswire corpus. The authors generate passages and questions by pick- ing two news articles describing the same event, using one as the passage and the other as the ques- tion.</p><p>High noise is inevitable in cloze-style datasets due to their automatic generation process, which is reflected in the human performance on these datasets: 82% for CBT and 84% for WDW.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3">Datasets with Span-based Answers</head><p>In datasets such as SQUAD ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Rajpurkar et al., 2016</ref>), NEWSQA ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Trischler et al., 2016</ref>) and MS MARCO ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Nguyen et al., 2016</ref>), the answer to each question is in the form of a text span in the article. Articles of SQUAD, NEWSQA and MS MARCO come from Wikipedia, CNN news and the Bing search engine respectively. The answer to a cer- tain question may not be unique and could be mul- tiple spans. Instead of evaluating the accuracy, re- searchers need to use F1 score, BLEU ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Papineni et al., 2002</ref>) or ROUGE ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Lin and Hovy, 2003)</ref> as metrics, which measure the overlap between the prediction and ground truth answers since the questions come without candidate spans.</p><p>Datasets with span-based answers are challeng- ing as the space of possible spans is usually large. However, restricting answers to be text spans in the context passage may be unrealistic and more importantly, may not be intuitive even for humans, indicated by the suffered human performance of 80.3% on SQUAD (or 65% claimed by <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Trischler et al. (2016)</ref>) and 46.5% on NEWSQA. In other words, the format of span-based answers may not necessarily be a good examination of reading com- prehension of machines whose aim is to approach the comprehension ability of humans.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.4">Datasets from Examinations</head><p>There have been several datasets extracted from examinations, aiming at evaluating systems un- der the same conditions as how humans are evalu- ated in schools. E.g., the AI2 Elementary School Science Questions dataset ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Khashabi et al., 2016)</ref> contains 1080 questions for students in elementary schools; NTCIR QA Lab ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Shibuki et al., 2014</ref>) evaluates systems by the task of solving real-world university entrance exam questions; The Entrance Exams task at CLEF QA Track ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Peñas et al., 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Rodrigo et al., 2015</ref>) evaluates the system's read- ing comprehension ability. However, data pro- vided in these existing tasks are far from sufficient for the training of advanced data-driven machine reading models, partially due to the expensive data generation process by human experts.</p><p>To the best of our knowledge, RACE is the first large-scale dataset of this type, where questions are created based on exams designed to evaluate human performance in reading comprehension.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Data Analysis</head><p>In this section, we study the nature of questions covered in RACE at a detailed level. Specifically, we present the dataset statistics in Section 3.1, and then analyze different reasoning/question types in RACE in the remaining subsections.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Dataset Statistics</head><p>As mentioned in section 1, RACE is collected from English examinations designed for 12-15 year-old middle school students, and 15-18 year- old high school students in China. To distin- guish the two subgroups with drastic difficulty gap, RACE-M denotes the middle school exami- nations and RACE-H denotes high school exami- nations. We split 5% data as the development set and 5% as the test set for RACE-M and RACE-H respectively. The number of samples in each set is shown in <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Table 2</ref>. The statistics for RACE-M and RACE-H is summarized in <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">Table 3</ref>. We can find that the length of the passages and the vocabulary size in the RACE-H are much larger than that of the RACE-M, an evidence of the higher difficulty of high school examinations.</p><p>However, notice that since the articles and ques- tions are selected and designed to test Chinese students learning English as a foreign language, the vocabulary size and the complexity of the lan- guage constructs are simpler than news articles and Wikipedia articles in other QA datasets.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Reasoning Types of the Questions</head><p>To get a comprehensive picture about the reason- ing difficulty requirement of RACE, we conduct human annotations of questions types. Following <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Chen et al. (2016)</ref>; <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Trischler et al. (2016)</ref>, we strat- ify the questions into five classes as follows with ascending order of difficulty:</p><p>• Word matching: The question exactly matches a span in the article. The answer is self-evident.</p><p>• Paraphrasing: The question is entailed or paraphrased by exactly one sentence in the passage. The answer can be extracted within the sentence.</p><p>• Single-sentence reasoning: The answer could be inferred from a single sentence of the arti- cle by recognizing incomplete information or conceptual overlap.</p><p>• Multi-sentence reasoning: The answer must be inferred from synthesizing information distributed across multiple sentences.</p><p>• Insufficient/Ambiguous: The question has no answer or the answer is not unique based on the given passage.</p><p>We refer readers to <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Chen et al., 2016;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Trischler et al., 2016</ref>) for examples of each category.</p><p>To obtain the proportion of different question types, we sample 100 passages from RACE (50 from RACE-M and 50 from RACE-H), all of which have 5 questions hence there are 500 ques- tions in total. We put the passages on Amazon Me- chanical Turk 1 , and a Hit is generated by a passage  <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">-M  RACE-H  RACE  Subset  Train  Dev  Test  Train  Dev  Test  Train  Dev  Test  All  # passages  6,409  368  362 18,</ref>   <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">Table 4</ref>. The higher difficulty level of RACE is justified by its higher ratio of rea- soning questions in comparison to CNN, SQUAD and NEWSQA. Specifically, 59.2% questions of RACE are either in the category of single-sentence reasoning or in the category of multi-sentence reasoning, while the ratio is 21%, 20.5% and 33.9% for CNN, SQUAD and NEWSQA respec- tively. Also notice that the ratio of word match- ing questions on RACE is only 15.8%, the lowest among several categories. In addition, questions in RACE-H are more complex than questions in RACE-M since RACE-M has more word match- ing questions and fewer reasoning questions.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="728">1,021 1,045 25,137 1,389 1,407 27,933 # questions 25,421 1,436 1,436 62,445 3,451 3,498 87,866 4,887 4,934 97,687</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3">Subdividing Reasoning Types</head><p>To better understand our dataset and facilitate fu- ture research, we list the subdivisions of ques- tions under the reasoning category. We find the most frequent reasoning subdivisions include: de- tail reasoning, whole-picture understanding, pas- sage summarization, attitude analysis and world knowledge. One question may fall into multiple divisions. Definition of these subdivisions and their associated examples are as follows:</p><p>1. Detail reasoning: to answer the question, the agent should be clear about the details of the pas- sage. The answer appears in the passage but it can- not be found by simply matching the question with the passage. For example, Question 1 in the sam- ple passage falls into this category.</p><p>2. Whole-picture reasoning: the agent needs to understand the whole picture of the story to ob- tain the correct answer. For example, to answer the Question 2 in the sample passage, the agent is required to comprehend the entire story.</p><p>3. Passage summarization: The question re- quires the agent to select the best summarization of the passage among four candidate summariza- tions. A typical question of this type is "The main idea of this passage is .". An example question can be found in Appendix A.1.</p><p>4. Attitude analysis: The question asks about the opinions/attitudes of the author or a character in the story towards somebody or something, e.g.,</p><p>• Evidence:</p><p>". . . Many people optimistically thought industry awards for better equipment would stimulate the production of quieter appliances. It was even suggested that noise from building sites could be alleviated . . . "</p><p>• Question: What was the author's attitude towards the industry awards for quieter?</p><p>• Options: A.suspicious B.positive C.enthusiastic D.indifferent 5. World knowledge: Certain external knowl- edge is needed. Most frequent questions under this category involve simple arithmetic.</p><p>• Evidence: "The park is open from 8 am to 5 pm."</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">• Question:</formula><p>The park is open for hours a day.</p><p>• Options: A.eight B.nine C.ten <ref type="bibr">D.eleven</ref> To the best of our knowledge, questions like passage summarization and attitude analysis have not been introduced by any of the existing large- scale machine comprehension datasets. Both are crucial components in evaluating humans' reading comprehension abilities.   </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Collection Methodology</head><p>We collected the raw data from three large free public websites 234 in China <ref type="bibr">5</ref> , where the reading comprehension problems are extracted from En- glish examinations designed by teachers in China.</p><p>The data before cleaning contains 137,918 pas- sages and 519,878 questions in total, where there are 38,159 passages with 156,782 questions in the middle school group, and 99,759 passages with 363,096 questions in the high school group. The following filtering steps are conducted to clean the raw data. Firstly, we remove all prob- lems and questions that do not have the same for- mat as our problem setting, e.g., a question would be removed if the number of its options is not four. Secondly, we filter all articles and questions that are not self-contained based on the text informa- tion, i.e. we remove the articles and questions con- taining images or tables. We also remove all ques- tions containing keywords "underlined" or "para- graph", since it is difficult to reproduce the effect of underlines and the paragraph segment informa- tion. Thirdly, we remove all duplicated articles.</p><p>On one of the websites (xkw.com), the answers are stored as images. We used two standard OCR programs tesseract <ref type="bibr">6</ref> and ABBYY FineReader 7 to process the images. We remove all the answers that two software disagree. The OCR task is easy since we only need to recognize printed alphabet A, B, C, D with a standard font. Finally, we get the cleaned dataset RACE, with 27,933 passages and 97,687 questions.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Stanford Attentive Reader Stanford Attentive</head><p>Reader (Stanford AR) <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Chen et al., 2016</ref>) is a strong model that achieves state-of-the-art results on CNN/Daily Mail. Moreover, the authors claim that their model has nearly reached the ceiling per- formance on these two datasets.</p><p>Suppose that the triple of passage, question and options is denoted by (p, q, o 1,··· ,4 ). We first em- ploy bidirectional GRUs to encode p and q respec- tively into h p 1 , h p 2 , . . . , h p n and h q . Then we sum- marize the most relevant part of the passage into s p with an attention model. Following <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Chen et al. (2016)</ref>, we adopt a bilinear attention form. Specif- ically,</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">↵ i = Softmax i ((h p i ) T W 1 h q ) s p = X i ↵ i h p i<label>(1)</label></formula><p>Similarly, we use bidirectional GRUs to encode option o i into a vector h o i . Finally, we com- pute the matching score between the i-th option (i = 1, · · · , 4) and the summarized passage using   a bilinear attention. We pass the scores through softmax to get a probability distribution. Specif- ically, the probability of option i being the right answer is calculated as</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>RACE-M RACE-H RACE MCTest CNN DM CBT-N CBT-C WDW</head><formula xml:id="formula_2">p i = Softmax i (h o i W 2 s d ) (2)</formula><p>Gated-Attention Reader Gated AR ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Dhingra et al., 2016</ref>) is the state-of-the-art model on mul- tiple datasets. To build query-specific represen- tations of tokens in the document, it employs an attention mechanism to model multiplicative in- teractions between the query embedding and the document representation. With a multi-hop ar- chitecture, GA also enables a model to scan the document and the question iteratively for multi- ple passes. In other words, the multi-hop struc- ture makes it possible for the reader to refine token representations iteratively and the attention mech- anism find the most relevant part of the document. We refer readers to ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Dhingra et al., 2016</ref>) for more details.</p><p>After obtaining a query specific document rep- resentation s d , we use the same method as bilinear operation listed in Equation 2 to get the output.</p><p>Note that our implementation slightly differs from the original GA reader. Specifically, the At- tention Sum layer is not applied at the final layer and no character-level embeddings are used.</p><p>Implementation Details We follow <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Chen et al. (2016)</ref> in our experiment settings. The vocabulary size is set to 50k. We choose word embedding size d = 100 and use the 100-dimensional Glove word embedding ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Pennington et al., 2014</ref>) as em- bedding initialization. GRU weights are initial- ized from Gaussian distribution N (0, 0.1). Other parameters are initialized from a uniform distri- bution on (0.01, 0.01). The hidden dimension- ality is set to 128 and the number of layers is set to one for both Stanford AR and GA. We use vanilla stochastic gradient descent (SGD) to train our models. We apply dropout on word embed- dings and the gradient is clipped when the norm of the gradient is larger than 10. We use a grid search on validation set to choose the learning rate within {0.05, 0.1, 0.3, 0.5} and dropout rate within {0.2, 0.5, 0.7}. The highest accuracy on validation set is obtained by setting learning rate to 0.1 for Stanford AR and 0.3 for GA and dropout rate to 0.5. The data of RACE-M and RACE-H is used together to train our model and testing is performed separately.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.2">Human Evaluation</head><p>As described in section 3.2, a randomly sam- pled subset of test set has been labeled by Ama- zon Turkers, which contains 500 questions with half from RACE-H and with the other half from RACE-M. The turkers' performance is 85% for RACE-M and 70% for RACE-H. However, it is hard to guarantee that every turker performs the survey carefully, given the difficult and long pas- sages of high school problems. Therefore, to ob- tain the ceiling human performance on RACE, we manually labeled the proportion of valid ques- tions. A question is valid if it is unambiguous and has a correct answer. We found that 94.5% of the data is valid, which sets the ceiling human per- formance. Similarly, the ceiling performance on RACE-M and RACE-H is 95.4% and 94.2% re- spectively.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.3">Main Results</head><p>We compare models' and human ceiling perfor- mance on datasets which have the same evalua- tion metric with RACE. The compared datasets include RACE, MCTest, CNN/Daily Mail (CNN and DM), CBT and WDW. On CBT, we report per- formance on two subsets where the missing token is either a common noun (CBT-C) or name entity (CBT-N) since the language models have already reached human-level performance on other types ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Hill et al., 2015)</ref>. The comparison is shown in <ref type="table" target="#tab_6">Table 5</ref>.</p><p>Performance of Sliding Window We first com- pare MCTest with RACE using Sliding Window, where it is unable to train Stanford AR and Gated AR on MCTest's limited training data. Slid- ing Window achieves an accuracy of 51.5% on MCTest while only 37.3% on RACE, meaning that to answer the questions of RACE requires more reasoning than MCTest.</p><p>The performance of sliding window on RACE is not directly comparable with CBT and WDW since CBT has ten candidate answers for each question and WDW has an average of three. In- stead, we evaluate the performance improvement of sliding window on the random baseline. Larger improvement indicates more questions solvable by simple matching. On RACE, Sliding Window is 28.6% better than the random baseline, while the improvement is 58.5%, 92.2% and 50% for CBT- N, CBT-C and WDW.</p><p>The accuracy on RACE-M (37.3%) and RACE- H (30.4%) indicates that the middle school ques- tions are simpler based on the matching algorithm.</p><p>Performance of Neural Models We further compare the difficulty of different datasets by state-of-the-art neural models' performance. A lower performance means that more problems are unsolvable by machines. The Stanford AR and Gated AR achieve an accuracy of only 43.3% and 44.1% on RACE while their accuracy is much higher on CNN/Daily Mail, Childrens Book Test and Who-Did-What. It justifies the fact that, among current large-scale machine comprehen- sion datasets, RACE is the most challenging one.</p><p>Human Ceiling Performance The human per- formance is 94.5% which shows our data is quite clean compared to other large-scale machine com- prehension datasets. Since we cannot enforce ev- ery turker do the test cautiously, the result shows a gap between turkers' performance and human performance. Reasonably, problems in the high school group with longer passages and more com- plex questions lead to more significant divergence. Nevertheless, the start-of-the-art models still have a large room to be improved to reach turkers' per- formance. The performance gap is 41% for the middle school problems and 25% for the high school problems. What's more, The performance of Stanford AR and GA is only less than a half of the ceiling human performance, which indicates that to match the humans' reading comprehension ability, we still have a long way to go.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.4">Reason Types Analysis</head><p>We evaluate human and models on different types of questions, shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 1</ref>. Turkers do the best on word matching problems while doing the worst on reasoning problems. Sliding window performs better on word matching than problems needing reasoning or paraphrasing. Surprisingly, Stanford AR does not have a stronger performance on the word matching category than reasoning cat- egories. A possible reason is that the proportion of data in reasoning categories is larger than that of data. Also, the candidate answers of simple matching questions may share similar word em- beddings. For example, if the question is about color, it is difficult to distinguish candidate an- swers, "green", "red", "blue" and "yellow", in the embedding vector space. The similar performance on different categories also explains the reason that the performance of the neural models is close in the middle and high school groups in <ref type="table" target="#tab_6">Table 5</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Conclusion</head><p>We introduce a large, high-quality dataset for read- ing comprehension that is carefully designed to examine human ability on this task. Some desir- able properties of RACE include the broad cover- age of domains/styles and the richness in the ques- tion format. Most importantly, it requires substan- tially more reasoning to do well on RACE than on other datasets, as there is a significant gap be- tween the performance of state-of-the-art machine comprehension models and that of the human. We hope this dataset will stimulate the development of more advanced machine comprehension models.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Dataset</head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: Test accuracy of different baselines on each reasoning type category introduced in Section 3.2, where Word-Match, Single-Reason, Multi-Reason and Ambiguous are the abbreviations for Word matching, Single-sentence Reasoning, Multi-sentence Reasoning and Insufficient/Ambiguous respectively.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" validated="false"><head>Table 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>The separation of the training, development and test sets of RACE-M,RACE-H and RACE 

Dataset 
RACE-M RACE-H RACE 
Passage Len 
231.1 
353.1 
321.9 
Question Len 
9.0 
10.4 
10.0 
Option Len 
3.9 
5.8 
5.3 
Vocab size 
32,811 
125,120 136,629 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" validated="false"><head>Table 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Statistics of RACE where Len denotes 
length and Vocab denotes Vocabulary. 

with 5 questions. Each question is labeled by two 
crowdworkers. We require the turkers to both an-
swer the questions and label the reasoning type. 
We pay $0.70 and $1.00 per passage in RACE-M 
and RACE-H respectively, and restrict the access 
to master turkers only. Finally, we get 1000 labels 
for the 500 questions. 
The statistics about the reasoning type is sum-
marized in </table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4" validated="false"><head>Table 4 :</head><label>4</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Statistic information about Reasoning type in different datasets. * denotes the numbers coming 
from (Trischler et al., 2016) based on 1000 samples per dataset, and numbers with  † come from (Chen 
et al., 2016). 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_6" validated="false"><head>Table 5 :</head><label>5</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Accuracy of models and human on the each dataset, where  † denotes the results coming from 
previous publications. DM denotes Daily Mail and WDW denotes Who-Did-What . 

</table></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> https://www.mturk.com/mturk/welcome</note>

			<note place="foot" n="2"> http://www.21cnjy.com/ 3 http://5utk.ks5u.com/ 4 http://zujuan.xkw.com/ 5 We checked that our dataset does not include example questions of exams with copyright, such as SSAT, SAT, TOEFL and GRE. 6 https://github.com/tesseract-ocr 7 https://www.abbyy.com/FineReader 5 Experiments In this section, we compare the performance of several state-of-the-art reading comprehension models with human performance. We use accuracy as the metric to evaluate different models. 5.1 Methods for Comparison Sliding Window Algorithm Firstly, we build the rule-based baseline introduced by Richardson et al. (2013). It chooses the answer having the highest matching score. Specifically, it first concatenates the question and the answer and then calculates the TF-IDF style matching score between the concatenated sentence with every window (a span of text) of the article. The window size is decided by the model performance in the training and dev sets.</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgement</head><p>We would like to thank Graham Neubig for sug-gestions on the draft and Diyi Yang's help on ob-taining the crowdsourced labels.</p><p>This research was supported in part by DARPA grant FA8750-12-2-0342 funded under the DEFT program.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Embracing data abundance: Booktest dataset for reading comprehension</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ondrej</forename><surname>Bajgar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rudolf</forename><surname>Kadlec</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jan</forename><surname>Kleindienst</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:1610.00956</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
<note type="report_type">arXiv preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">A thorough examination of the cnn/daily mail reading comprehension task</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Danqi</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jason</forename><surname>Bolton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christopher D</forename><surname>Manning</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:1606.02858</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
<note type="report_type">arXiv preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Gated-attention readers for text comprehension</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bhuwan</forename><surname>Dhingra</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hanxiao</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ruslan</forename><surname>William W Cohen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Salakhutdinov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:1606.01549</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
<note type="report_type">arXiv preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Teaching machines to read and comprehend</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Karl</forename><surname>Moritz Hermann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tomas</forename><surname>Kocisky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Edward</forename><surname>Grefenstette</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lasse</forename><surname>Espeholt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Will</forename><surname>Kay</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mustafa</forename><surname>Suleyman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Phil</forename><surname>Blunsom</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Advances in Neural Information Processing Systems</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1693" to="1701" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The goldilocks principle: Reading children&apos;s books with explicit memory representations</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Felix</forename><surname>Hill</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Antoine</forename><surname>Bordes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sumit</forename><surname>Chopra</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jason</forename><surname>Weston</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:1511.02301</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
<note type="report_type">arXiv preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rudolf</forename><surname>Kadlec</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Martin</forename><surname>Schmid</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ondrej</forename><surname>Bajgar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:1603.01547</idno>
		<title level="m">Text understanding with the attention sum reader network</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
<note type="report_type">arXiv preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Question answering via integer programming over semi-structured knowledge</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Daniel</forename><surname>Khashabi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tushar</forename><surname>Khot</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ashish</forename><surname>Sabharwal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Peter</forename><surname>Clark</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Oren</forename><surname>Etzioni</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dan</forename><surname>Roth</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:1604.06076</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
<note type="report_type">arXiv preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Automatic evaluation of summaries using n-gram cooccurrence statistics</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chin-Yew</forename><surname>Lin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Eduard</forename><surname>Hovy</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2003 Conference of the North American Chapter</title>
		<meeting>the 2003 Conference of the North American Chapter</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="71" to="78" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Ms marco: A human generated machine reading comprehension dataset</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tri</forename><surname>Nguyen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mir</forename><surname>Rosenberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xia</forename><surname>Song</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jianfeng</forename><surname>Gao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Saurabh</forename><surname>Tiwary</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rangan</forename><surname>Majumder</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Li</forename><surname>Deng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:1611.09268</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
<note type="report_type">arXiv preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Who did what: A large-scale person-centered cloze dataset</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Takeshi</forename><surname>Onishi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hai</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mohit</forename><surname>Bansal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:1608.05457</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
<note type="report_type">arXiv preprint</note>
	<note>Kevin Gimpel, and David McAllester</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Bleu: a method for automatic evaluation of machine translation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kishore</forename><surname>Papineni</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Salim</forename><surname>Roukos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Todd</forename><surname>Ward</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Weijing</forename><surname>Zhu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 40th annual meeting on association for computational linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the 40th annual meeting on association for computational linguistics</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="311" to="318" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Overview of clef qa entrance exams task</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Anselmo</forename><surname>Peñas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yusuke</forename><surname>Miyao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alvaro</forename><surname>Rodrigo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Eduard</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Hovy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Noriko</forename><surname>Kando</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">CLEF (Working Notes)</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1194" to="1200" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Glove: Global vectors for word representation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jeffrey</forename><surname>Pennington</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Richard</forename><surname>Socher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christopher D</forename><surname>Manning</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">EMNLP</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1532" to="1543" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Squad: 100,000+ questions for machine comprehension of text</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Pranav</forename><surname>Rajpurkar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jian</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Konstantin</forename><surname>Lopyrev</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Percy</forename><surname>Liang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:1606.05250</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
<note type="report_type">arXiv preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Mctest: A challenge dataset for the open-domain machine comprehension of text</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Matthew</forename><surname>Richardson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Christopher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Erin</forename><surname>Burges</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Renshaw</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">4</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Overview of clef qa entrance exams task</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Anselmo</forename><surname>793´ 793´alvaro Rodrigo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yusuke</forename><surname>Peñas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Miyao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Eduard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Noriko</forename><surname>Hovy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Kando</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">CLEF (Working Notes)</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Overview of the ntcir-11 qa-lab task</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hideyuki</forename><surname>Shibuki</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kotaro</forename><surname>Sakamoto</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yoshinobu</forename><surname>Kano</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Teruko</forename><surname>Mitamura</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Madoka</forename><surname>Ishioroshi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Kelly</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Di</forename><surname>Itakura</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tatsunori</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Noriko</forename><surname>Mori</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Kando</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">NTCIR</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Adam</forename><surname>Trischler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tong</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xingdi</forename><surname>Yuan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Justin</forename><surname>Harris</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alessandro</forename><surname>Sordoni</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Philip</forename><surname>Bachman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kaheer</forename><surname>Suleman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:1611.09830</idno>
		<title level="m">Newsqa: A machine comprehension dataset</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
<note type="report_type">arXiv preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Zhilin</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Junjie</forename><surname>Hu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ruslan</forename><surname>Salakhutdinov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">William W</forename><surname>Cohen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:1702.02206</idno>
		<title level="m">Semi-supervised qa with generative domain-adaptive nets</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
<note type="report_type">arXiv preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
