<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T12:26+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Word Re-Embedding via Manifold Dimensionality Retention</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
				<availability status="unknown"><p>Copyright Association for Computational Linguistics</p>
				</availability>
				<date>September 7-11, 2017. 2017</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Souleiman</forename><surname>Hasan</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory">Lero-The Irish Software Research Centre</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">National University of Ireland</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Galway</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Edward</forename><surname>Curry</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory">Lero-The Irish Software Research Centre</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">National University of Ireland</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Galway</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Word Re-Embedding via Manifold Dimensionality Retention</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Natural Language Processing</title>
						<meeting> <address><addrLine>Copenhagen, Denmark</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="321" to="326"/>
							<date type="published">September 7-11, 2017. 2017</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Word embeddings seek to recover a Eu-clidean metric space by mapping words into vectors, starting from words co-occurrences in a corpus. Word embed-dings may underestimate the similarity between nearby words, and overestimate it between distant words in the Euclidean metric space. In this paper, we re-embed pre-trained word embeddings with a stage of manifold learning which retains dimen-sionality. We show that this approach is theoretically founded in the metric recovery paradigm, and empirically show that it can improve on state-of-the-art embed-dings in word similarity tasks 0.5 − 5.0% points depending on the original space.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Concepts have been hypothesized in the cognitive psychometric literature as points in a Euclidean metric space, with empirical support from human judgement experiments <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">(Rumelhart and Abrahamson, 1973;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b19">Sternberg and Gardner, 1983)</ref>. Word embeddings, such as GloVe ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Pennington et al., 2014a</ref>) and Word2Vec ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Mikolov et al., 2013)</ref>, harvest observed features of the latent Euclidean space such as words co-occurrence counts in a corpus and turn words into dense vectors of a few hundred dimensions. Word embeddings have proved useful in downstream NLP tasks such as Part of Speech Tagging <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Collobert, 2011)</ref>, Named Entity Recognition ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Turian et al., 2010)</ref>, and Ma- chine Translation <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Devlin et al., 2014</ref>). However, the potential of word embeddings and further im- provements remain a research question.</p><p>When comparing word pairs similarities ob- tained from word embeddings, to word pairs sim- ilarities obtained from human judgement, it is ob- served that word embeddings slightly underesti- mate the similarity between similar words, and overestimate the similarity between distant words. For example, in the WS353 ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Finkelstein et al., 2001</ref>) word similarity ground truth: sim("shore", "woodland") = 3.08 &lt; sim("physics", "proton") = 8.12</p><p>However, the use of GloVe 42B 300d embed- ding with cosine similarity (see Section 4) yields the opposite order: sim("shore", "woodland") = 0.36 &gt; sim("physics", "proton") = 0.33</p><p>Re-embedding the space using a manifold learning stage can rectify this. Manifold learning works by estimating the distance between nearby words using direct similarity assignment in a lo- cal neighbourhood, while distance between far- away words is approximated by multiple neigh- bourhoods based on the manifold shape. This ob- servation forms the basis for the rest of this paper.</p><p>For instance, using Locally Linear Embedding (LLE) ) on top of GloVe, as described in this paper, can recover the right pairs order yielding: sim("shore", "woodland") = 0.08 &lt; sim("physics", "proton") = 0.25 <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Hashimoto et al. (Hashimoto et al., 2016</ref>) put word embeddings under a paradigm which seeks to recover the underlying Euclidean metric seman- tic space. In this paradigm, word embeddings land into a space where a Euclidean metric can be used. They show that co-occurrence counts are the results of random walk sequences in the metric space, corresponding to sentences in a corpus.</p><p>Hashimoto et al. link this to manifold learn- ing which also seeks to recover a Euclidean space (Human Judgement) Euclidean Metric Space e.g. <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">(Rumelhart &amp; Abrahamson, 1973;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b19">Sternberg &amp; Gardner, 1983)</ref> Word Embedding Start: words co-occurrence e.g. <ref type="bibr">GloVe (Pennington et al., 2014</ref>), <ref type="bibr">Word2Vec (Mikolov et al., 2013</ref>).  but starting from local neighbourhoods of objects, such as images or words. Global distances are built by adding up small local neighbourhoods. The authors show that word embedding algorithms can be used to solve manifold learning by generat- ing random walks, aka sentences, on the manifold neighbourhood graph, and then embedding them. In this work we follow a methodology which adheres to this paradigm and adopt a different an- gle, as per <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref>. We start from an off-the-shelf word embedding, then we take a sample of it and feed it into manifold learning which leverages lo- cal word neighbourhoods formed in the original embedding space, learns the manifold, and em- beds it into a new Euclidean space. The result- ing re-embedding space is a recovery of a Eu- clidean metric space that is empirically better than the original word embedding when tested on word similarity tasks.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Manifold Learning</head><p>These results show that word embeddings can be improved in estimating the latent metric. Such an approach can provide new opportunities to im- prove our understanding of embedding methods, their properties, and limits. It also allows us to reuse and re-embed off-the-shelf pre-trained em- beddings, saving time on training, while aiming at improved results in downstream NLP tasks, and other data processing tasks <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Hasan and Curry, 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Hasan, 2017;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Freitas and Curry, 2014)</ref>.</p><p>Section 2 discusses the related literature to this work. Section 3 details the proposed approach. Sections 4 and 5 discuss the experiments and re- sults. The paper concludes with Section 6.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Related Work</head><p>The relationship to related work is depicted in Fig- ure 1. Word embeddings are unsupervised meth- ods based on word co-occurrence counts which can be directly observed in a corpus. Mikolov et al. presents a neural network-based architecture which learns a word representation by learning to predict its context words ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Mikolov et al., 2013</ref>). Pennington et al. proposed GloVe, which directly leverages nonzero word-word co-occurrences in a global manner <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(Pennington et al., 2014a</ref>).</p><p>The idea of embedding objects from a high di- mensional space, e.g. images, into a smaller di- mensional space constitute the area of manifold learning. For instance, Roweis and Saul present the Locally Linear Embedding (LLE) algorithm and show that pixel-based distance between im- ages is meaningful only at a local neighbourhood scale ). Reconstructions can capture the underlying manifold of the data, and can embed the high dimensional objects, into a lower dimensional Euclidean space while preserv- ing neighbourhoods. Other methods exist such as Isomap ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Balasubramanian and Schwartz, 2002</ref>) and t-SNE ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Maaten and Hinton, 2008)</ref>.</p><p>Hashimoto et al. show that word embed- dings and manifold learning are both methods to recover a Euclidean metric using co-occurrence counts and high dimensional features respectively ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Hashimoto et al., 2016)</ref>. They show that word embeddings can be used to solve manifold learn- ing when starting from a high dimensional space. In this paper we start from a trained word embed- ding space, and learn a manifold from it to im- prove results. We do not use manifold learning to reduce dimensionality, but to transform between two equally-dimensional coordinate systems.</p><p>Other related work comes from word embed- ding post-processing. Labutov and Lipson use a supervised model to re-embed words for a tar- get task <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Labutov and Lipson, 2013</ref>). Lee et al. filter out abnormal dimensions from a GloVe space according to their histograms and show a slight improvement in performance ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Lee et al., 2016</ref>). Mu at al. perform similar post-processing through the removal of the mean vector and vec- tors re-projection ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Mu et al., 2017)</ref>. We see man- ifold learning as a generic, unsupervised, non- linear, and theoretically-founded model for post- processing that can cover linear post-processing such as PCA and normalization of vectors.   <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 2</ref> illustrates our re-embedding method. We start from an original embedding space with vec- tors ordered by words frequencies. In step (a), we pick a sample window of vectors from this space to be used for learning the manifold. In step (b), we fit the manifold learning model to the selected sample using an algorithm such as LLE. We re- tain the dimensionality at this stage. In step (c), an arbitrary test vector can be selected from the orig- inal space. In step (d), the resulting fitted model serves as a transformation which can be used to transform the test vector into a vector which lives in the new re-embedding space, and used in down- stream tasks.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Approach</head><p>In step (a), a sample subset of the words is used based on word frequency rank. The ratio- nal is that word embedding attempts to recover a metric space and frequent words co-occurrences can represent a better sampling of the underlying space due to their frequent usage, rather than being handled equally with other points, thus can better recover the manifold shape. Experimenting with subsets from all the vocabulary or non-frequent words, may yield no improvement. Additionally, manifold learning on all points is computationally expensive. The sampling used here follows a slid- ing sample window to study the effect of its start position and size. Various ways to choose a sam- ple, e.g. random sampling, can be followed, but word frequency should remain a factor in where the sample is taken from.</p><p>In step (b), the sample is used to fit a mani- fold. For LLE , that is done through learning the weights which can re- construct each word vector from the sample X through its K-nearest neighbours in the sample, by minimizing the error function:</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">E(W ) = i X i − j W ij X j 2<label>(1)</label></formula><p>such that W ij = 0 if X j is not in the K-nearest neighbours of X i . The weights are then used to construct a new embedding Y of the sample X via a neighbourhood-preserving mapping through minimizing the cost function:</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">Φ(Y ) = i Y i − j W ij Y j 2<label>(2)</label></formula><p>In steps (c) and (d), to transform an arbitrary vector x, the weights are first constructed from only the K-nearest neighbours of x in the sample X, by minimizing the function:</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">E(W x ) = x − j W x j X j 2<label>(3)</label></formula><p>such that W x j = 0 if X j is not in the K-nearest neighbours of x. The weights are then used along with the new embedding Y to transform x into y which lives in the new embedding space through the equation:</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">y = j W x j Y j<label>(4)</label></formula><p>where Y j is the transform, from step (b), of X j that is in the K-nearest neighbours of x.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Experiments</head><p>Original Embedding Spaces. The original word embeddings used are pre-trained GloVe models: Wikipedia 2014 + Gigaword 5 (6B tokens, <ref type="bibr">400K vocab, 50d, 100d, 200d, &amp; 300d vectors)</ref>, and Common Crawl (42B tokens, 1.9M vocab, 300d vectors) ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Pennington et al., 2014b</ref>). The vectors are ordered by the frequency of their correspond- ing words, so the vector representing the word 'the' comes first in the space.</p><p>Task. We use similarity tasks WS353 <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Finkelstein et al., 2001</ref>) and RG65 <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(Rubenstein and Goodenough, 1965)</ref>.   Baseline. We use the performance by the origi- nal word embeddings on the tasks. For each orig- inal space, we normalize features using their min- imum and maximum values to <ref type="bibr">[−1, +1]</ref>, and then normalize vectors to unit norms. For each pair of words in the similarity task, we get the normal- ized vectors and measure the cosine similarity. We finally compute the Spearman Rank Correlation with human judgements.</p><p>Approach. For a given original embedding, we normalize vectors to unit norms, then we conduct Manifold (Mfd) Re-Embedding using LLE as ex- plained in Section 3. For each similarity task, we transform the vectors of test words into the re-embedding space before computing the cosine similarity, and the final Spearman score. We vary relevant parameters and see what effect they have on the performance, so we can understand the ef- fectiveness of the approach and its limits.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Results and Discussion</head><p>Average Performance. <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">Table 1</ref> shows that the re-embedding method outperforms the baseline in most cases with improvements from 0.5% to 5.0%. These results are achieved for effective manifold training windows which start anywhere between 5000 and 15000. The table also shows that improvements are over spaces with underly- ing bigger corpora and vectors, i.e. good quality vectors which facilitate the embedding.</p><p>Manifold Dimensionality Retention. <ref type="figure">Figure 3</ref> shows that for a given window, the re-embedding performs better when the dimensionality of the learned manifold is chosen to be closer to the orig- inal space dimensionality. In other words, dimen- sional reduction on the original space will bare a cost in performance. Manifold learning typically starts from a high- dimensional raw space, such as pixels, and aims to reduce the dimensionality. In our method we start from a word embedding which is already a good embedding of the raw word co-occurrences. So, dimensionality shall be retained, as suggested by <ref type="figure">Figure 3</ref>, or otherwise information can be lost during eigenvectors computation and selection in the manifold learning.</p><p>Effect of Window Length. <ref type="figure">Figure 4</ref> shows that the best window length to choose is as close as possible to the number of local neighbours used by the manifold learning. Performance drops slightly with higher values of window length, but becomes stable after an initial drop.</p><p>Effect of Window Start. <ref type="figure">Figure 5</ref> shows that the performance is first modest when the manifold is trained on the most frequent word vectors (i.e. stop words), but then picks up and outperforms the baseline for most cases. Performance drops grad- Mfd Re-Embedding (GloVe+LLE) Baseline (GloVe) (c) 6B 300d, WS353 ually as the manifold is trained on relatively less frequent word vectors.</p><p>Effect of the Number of Local Neighbours. <ref type="figure">Figure 6</ref> shows that the performance is generally stable with variation in the number of local neigh- bours that the manifold is learned upon. Generally lower numbers of local neighbours mean faster manifold learning.</p><p>Discussion. The above results show that word re-embedding based on manifold learning can help the original space recover the Euclidean metric, and thus improves performance on word similar- ity tasks. The ability of re-embedding to achieve improved results depends on the quality of the vec- tors in the original space. It also depends on the choice of the window used to learn the manifold. The window start is the most influential variable, and it should be chosen just after the stop words in the original space. The choice of other param- eters is relatively easier: the length of the window should be close or equal to the number of local neighbours, which in turn can be chosen from a wide range with no significant difference. The dimensionality of the original embedding space should be retained and used for learning the man- ifold to guarantee the best re-embedding.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Conclusions and Future Work</head><p>In this paper we presented a new method to re-embed words from off-the-shelf embeddings based on manifold learning. We showed that such an approach is theoretically founded in the metric recovery paradigm and can empirically improve the performance of state-of-the-art embeddings in word similarity tasks. In future work we intend to extend the experiments to include other origi- nal pre-trained embeddings, and other algorithms for manifold learning. We also intend to extend the experiments to other NLP tasks in addition to word similarity such as word analogies.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: Methodology and Related Work.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2: Re-Embedding via Manifold Learning.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Space</head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>Figure 3 :Figure 4 :</head><label>34</label><figDesc>Figure 3: Accuracy on WS353 similarity task as a function of manifold dimensionality. (Space is GloVe 42B 300d. Window start = 7000, LLE local neighbours =1000, Window length = 1001.)</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head>Figure 5 :Figure 6 :</head><label>56</label><figDesc>Figure 5: Accuracy on similarity tasks as a function of window start. (a) Original space GloVe 42B 300d, with WS353. (b) 42B 300d, with RG65. (c) 6B 300d, with WS353. (LLE local neighbours =1000, Window length = 1001, Manifold dimensionality = 300.)</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3" validated="false"><head>Table 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Average performance on similarity tasks. 
(Window start ∈ [5000, 15000], Number of LLE 
local neighbours =1000, Window length = 1001, 
Manifold dimensionality = Space dimensionality.) 

</table></figure>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgements</head><p>This work was supported with the financial sup-port of the Science Foundation Ireland grant 13/RC/2094 and co-funded under the European Regional Development Fund through the South-ern &amp; Eastern Regional Operational Programme to Lero-the Irish Software Research Centre (www.lero.ie).</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mukund</forename><surname>Balasubramanian</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Eric</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Schwartz</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The isomap algorithm and topological stability. Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">295</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5552</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="7" to="7" />
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Deep learning for efficient discriminative parsing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ronan</forename><surname>Collobert</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">AISTATS</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="224" to="232" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Fast and robust neural network joint models for statistical machine translation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jacob</forename><surname>Devlin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rabih</forename><surname>Zbib</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Zhongqiang</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Thomas</forename><surname>Lamar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Richard</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Schwartz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">John</forename><surname>Makhoul</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ACL</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Citeseer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1370" to="1380" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Placing search in context: The concept revisited</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lev</forename><surname>Finkelstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Evgeniy</forename><surname>Gabrilovich</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yossi</forename><surname>Matias</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ehud</forename><surname>Rivlin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Zach</forename><surname>Solan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gadi</forename><surname>Wolfman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Eytan</forename><surname>Ruppin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 10th international conference on World Wide Web</title>
		<meeting>the 10th international conference on World Wide Web</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="406" to="414" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Natural language queries over heterogeneous linked data graphs: A distributional-compositional semantics approach</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">André</forename><surname>Freitas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Edward</forename><surname>Curry</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 19th international conference on Intelligent User Interfaces</title>
		<meeting>the 19th international conference on Intelligent User Interfaces</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="279" to="288" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Nosym: Non-symbolic databases for data decoupling</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Souleiman</forename><surname>Hasan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">the Conference on Innovative Data Systems Research (CIDR)</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Thematic event processing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Souleiman</forename><surname>Hasan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Edward</forename><surname>Curry</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 15th International Middleware Conference, Middleware &apos;14</title>
		<meeting>the 15th International Middleware Conference, Middleware &apos;14<address><addrLine>New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="109" to="120" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Word embeddings as metric recovery in semantic spaces</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Tatsunori</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Hashimoto</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tommi</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Alvarez-Melis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Jaakkola</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Transactions of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="273" to="286" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Re-embedding words</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Igor</forename><surname>Labutov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hod</forename><surname>Lipson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ACL</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="489" to="493" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Less is more: Filtering abnormal dimensions in glove</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yang-Yin</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hao</forename><surname>Ke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Hen-Hsen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hsinhsi</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 25th International Conference Companion on World Wide Web</title>
		<meeting>the 25th International Conference Companion on World Wide Web</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="71" to="72" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>International World Wide Web Conferences Steering Committee</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Visualizing data using t-sne</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Laurens</forename><surname>Van Der Maaten</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Geoffrey</forename><surname>Hinton</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Machine Learning Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2579" to="2605" />
			<date type="published" when="2008-11" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Distributed representations of words and phrases and their compositionality</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tomas</forename><surname>Mikolov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ilya</forename><surname>Sutskever</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kai</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Greg</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Corrado</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jeff</forename><surname>Dean</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Advances in neural information processing systems</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3111" to="3119" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jiaqi</forename><surname>Mu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Suma</forename><surname>Bhat</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Pramod</forename><surname>Viswanath</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:1702.01417</idno>
		<title level="m">Simple and effective postprocessing for word representations</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
<note type="report_type">arXiv preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Glove: Global vectors for word representation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jeffrey</forename><surname>Pennington</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Richard</forename><surname>Socher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christopher D</forename><surname>Manning</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">EMNLP</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1532" to="1543" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jeffrey</forename><surname>Pennington</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Richard</forename><surname>Socher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christopher D</forename><surname>Manning</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://nlp.stanford.edu/projects/glove/" />
		<title level="m">Glove resources. Available at</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Nonlinear dimensionality reduction by locally linear embedding. science</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Sam</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lawrence K</forename><surname>Roweis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Saul</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">290</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2323" to="2326" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Contextual correlates of synonymy</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Herbert</forename><surname>Rubenstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">John B</forename><surname>Goodenough</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Communications of the ACM</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="627" to="633" />
			<date type="published" when="1965" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A model for analogical reasoning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>David</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Adele</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Rumelhart</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Abrahamson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognitive Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="28" />
			<date type="published" when="1973" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Lawrence</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Saul</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Sam T Roweis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>An introduction to locally linear embedding. Available at: www.cs.toronto.edu/%7Eroweis/lle/publications.html</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Unities in inductive reasoning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Robert</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michael K</forename><surname>Sternberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Gardner</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Psychology: General</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">112</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">80</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1983" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Word representations: a simple and general method for semi-supervised learning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Joseph</forename><surname>Turian</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lev</forename><surname>Ratinov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yoshua</forename><surname>Bengio</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 48th annual meeting of the association for computational linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the 48th annual meeting of the association for computational linguistics</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="384" to="394" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
