<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T13:00+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Visualization of the Topic Space of Argument Search Results in args.me</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date>October 31-November 4, 2018</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yamen</forename><surname>Ajjour</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Henning</forename><surname>Wachsmuth</surname></persName>
							<email>henningw@upb.de</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dora</forename><surname>Kiesel</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Patrick</forename><surname>Riehmann</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Fan</forename><surname>Fan</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Giuliano</forename><surname>Castiglia</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rosemary</forename><surname>Adejoh</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bernd</forename><surname>Fröhlich</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Benno</forename><surname>Stein</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Bauhaus-Universität Weimar</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Weimar</settlement>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">Paderborn University</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Paderborn</settlement>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Visualization of the Topic Space of Argument Search Results in args.me</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2018 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (System Demonstrations)</title>
						<meeting>the 2018 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (System Demonstrations) <address><addrLine>Brussels; Belgium</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="60" to="65"/>
							<date type="published">October 31-November 4, 2018</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<note>60</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>In times of fake news and alternative facts, pro and con arguments on controversial topics are of increasing importance. Recently, we presented args.me as the first search engine for arguments on the web. In its initial version, args.me ranked arguments solely by their relevance to a topic queried for, making it hard to learn about the diverse topical aspects covered by the search results. To tackle this shortcoming, we integrated a visualization interface for result exploration in args.me that provides an instant overview of the main aspects in a barycentric coordinate system. This topic space is generated ad-hoc from controversial issues on Wikipedia and argument-specific LDA models. In two case studies, we demonstrate how individual arguments can be found easily through interactions with the visu-alization, such as highlighting and filtering.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>For many controversial topics in life and politics, people disagree on what is the right stance towards them, be it the need for feminism, the influence of religion, or the assassination of dictators. Stance is affected by the subjective assessment and weight- ing of pro and con arguments on the diverse aspects of a topic <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Kock, 2007)</ref>. Building stance in a self- determined manner is getting harder and harder in times of fake news and alternative facts, due to the unclear reliability of many sources and their bias in stance and covered aspects. This was our societal motivation for the development of the first dedicated argument search engine, args.me. <ref type="bibr">1</ref> args.me allows querying for arbitrary controver- sial topics. As search results, it opposes pro and con arguments from the web, ranked by their computed relevance to the topic. args.me is non-commercial and aims to avoid bias towards either stance. In ( <ref type="bibr">Wachsmuth et al., 2017b</ref>), we introduced the soft- ware framework and the initial argument index un- derlying args.me as well as its basic user interface.</p><p>In its first version, args.me presented arguments in textual form with linked sources, similar to the web page snippets of conventional search engines, but with color-encoded stance. Examples are given below in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figures 1 and 2</ref>. This is adequate for com- prehending those arguments deemed most relevant. Unlike for many general information needs <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Croft et al., 2009)</ref>, however, reading the top results is not enough for building an informed stance. Rather, diverse aspects of a controversial topic need to be explored. In our recent study with 97 international users, aspect coverage was seen as the second most important ranking criterion -after source reliabil- ity but before recency, user ratings, and others. <ref type="bibr">2</ref> A simple relevance ranking of possibly thousands of arguments provides weak support in that regard.</p><p>This paper shows a novel way of presenting ar- gument search results, which we designed and inte- grated into args.me to support a rapid exploration of the aspects of a topic. In particular, we visualize this topic space in a barycentric coordinate system ( <ref type="bibr">Riehmann et al., 2018)</ref>, representing the distribu- tion of pro and con arguments over the main cov- ered aspects (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Figure 3</ref>). Possible aspects were derived offline from the Wikipedia list of controver- sial issues 3 as well as from LDA topic models built based on the 291k arguments in our index, whereas the aspects actually visualized are derived ad-hoc from the search results. Through interactions with the visualization, a user can easily highlight and filter arguments on the aspects of interest. In two case studies, we demonstrate how the visualization speeds up argument search notably.  All these works focus on single arguments or the set of arguments within a single debate or text. In contrast, we present a visualization that summa- rizes arguments from many different texts. Unlike in ( <ref type="bibr">Wachsmuth et al., 2017a</ref>), where we illustrated structural argumentation patterns in the texts of a corpus, here we target the content of arguments. As the above-mentioned system ConToVi, we visu- alize the topic space covered by a set of arguments. While ConToVi provides insights into the flow of aspects during the discussion of a controversial topic, our visualization aims to make arguments on specific aspects easily findable. Moreover, we allow arguments to cover a weighted distribution of multiple aspects rather than only a single aspect. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Argument Search with args.me</head><p>As presented in ( <ref type="bibr">Wachsmuth et al., 2017b</ref>), the ini- tial version of args.me follows approved concepts of conventional search engines (such as Google or Bing), but it adapts them to the specific goals of ar- gument search. Via the interface of args.me, users can enter free text queries on controversial topics, such as "feminism" and "assassination of dictators". While conventional search engines return links to web pages along with short textual excerpts as re- sults, args.me directly returns all arguments found to be relevant, linked to their source web pages.</p><p>Originally, args.me provided two views that dis- played the found arguments in a textual result list with color-encoded stance, as shown in Figures 1 and 2: a pro vs. con view that opposes the most rele- vant pros and cons, and an overall ranking view that ranks all arguments by their relevance irrespective of stance. A fundamental question in this regard is what arguments are actually deemed most relevant? Argument search implies specific ranking criteria, such as recency, perceived quality, aspect coverage, and source reliability. Assessing these criteria is all but trivial and partly unsolved. In its current state (mid 2018), args.me therefore still relies on standard information retrieval measures <ref type="bibr">(Robertson and Zaragoza, 2009)</ref>, i.e., it ranks arguments higher the more they match the words in the query.</p><p>So far, however, for many queries the top-ranked arguments neither appear to be the strongest on the given topic, nor do they cover the whole di- versity of the topic. Having only a textual result list can then make it hard to find the best argu- ments or specific arguments of interest. This is why we aimed for new ways to support an efficient search space exploration -one main goal of infor- mation visualization <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">(Munzner, 2014)</ref>. While our recent user study suggested that source reliability is most important (see Section 1), the 291,440 argu- ments currently indexed by args.me anyway come from five selected sources only ( <ref type="bibr">Wachsmuth et al., 2017b</ref>). Instead, we thus focus on the second most important ranking criterion: aspect coverage.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Visualization of the Topic Space</head><p>For building an informed stance on a controversial topic, obtaining insights into the variety of aspects touched by the topic is crucial. We aid this process by accompanying the textual result list in args.me with a topic space visualization, which puts the aspects covered by the listed arguments into the focus, highlights the main aspect of each argument, and groups arguments covering similar aspects.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">Determining Topical Aspects</head><p>The first step to develop the visualization was to build a topic model that can represent the aspects of each argument in the result list. We compared two alternative approaches for this purpose:</p><p>First, we computed the relative distribution of all the over 1000 terms from the Wikipedia list of controversial issues in each indexed argument. For instance, if "Women" occurs ten times, "Woman" six times, "Feminism" four times, and no other term, then we have (Women 0.5, Woman 0.3, Femi- nism 0.2) with implicit zeros for all others. Second, we performed LDA topic modeling ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Blei et al., 2003</ref>) based on the words in all arguments from our index. With an interval size of 10, we tested all numbers of topics from 10 to 100 and chose the number that minimized perplexity: 40. Each aspect is then represented by all words of one LDA topic, and the relative aspect distribution is calculated by counting the occurrence of all associated words in each argument. We found the Wikipedia-based topic model to be more convincing, which is why it is set as the default in args.me. <ref type="bibr">4</ref> </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">Visualizing Topical Aspects</head><p>To visualize the aspect-based topic space, we opted for generalized barycentric coordinates <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">(Meyer et al., 2002</ref>), as they naturally fit our purpose: We represent an argument as a linear combination of weights for all aspects, while barycentric coordi- nates represent a point as a linear combination of the vertices of a polygon (both adding up to 1.0). Thus, the topic model can be used as input for the visualization without recalculation. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Figure 3</ref> shows the visualization of the results for the query "femi- nism", consisting of two main elements: the topic space and the argument glyphs within this space.</p><p>The topic space is depicted as a regular poly- gon with one vertex for each represented aspect. Both given topic model alternatives comprise too many aspects to depict them all. To reduce visual clutter in favor of a lean visualization, we limit the maximum number of visualized aspects, such that readability is not diminished. In particular, we keep only those eight aspects that are the most frequent in the argument search results. All other aspects are merged into a ninth aspect "other". The labels for the aspects are short terms in case of the Wikipedia-based topic model or visualized as word clouds in case of the LDA topic model.</p><p>Each argument glyph represents one argument in the form of a colored circle (green for pro, red for con) with a small arrow pointing to the main covered aspect. The glyphs are positioned based on their aspect distribution: the stronger one aspect, the stronger a glyph is "pulled" in that direction, as sketched in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Figure 4</ref>. Accordingly, similar argu- ments are placed spatially near to each other. To ensure the visibility of all glyphs and to avoid over- plotting, arguments placed on top of each other are aggregated into a single glyph. The glyph size de- pends on a logarithmic mapping of the number of represented arguments. Since arguments with both stances may be grouped, the color of an aggregate glyph represents the majority stance of all argu- ments contained, from green (all pro), over gray (balanced pro/con), to red (all con).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3">Interacting with Topical Aspects</head><p>The integration of our visualization into args.me is shown below in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_7">Figures 7 and 8</ref>. This new topic space view replaces the old overall ranking view: it includes the textual argument ranking and adds the visualization to the right. At first, the visualization shows only the information outlined above, but it provides further details upon interaction.</p><p>Barycentric coordinates are ambiguous and may place arguments with different aspects at similar locations. For disambiguation, users can hover over a glyph to reveal all covered aspects, as exemplified in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">Figure 5</ref>. The represented arguments are also highlighted in the textual list, given that they appear on the current result page. Vice versa, hovering over a textual argument highlights the respective glyph with a wide green or red border. In addition, the visualization enables a filtering of the textual results: A user can select one or more arguments by clicking or brushing (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">Figure 6</ref>), in order to narrow down the list to the aspects of interest. All other arguments are grayed out.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Case Studies</head><p>To verify the benefit of our visualization, we finally explore two typical use cases of argument search: topic space exploration and search refinement.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.1">Topic Space Exploration</head><p>First, we consider a query for "feminism". 659 arguments are returned by args.me for this topic, as shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_7">Figure 7</ref>. While the top-ranked arguments seem highly relevant in general, our visualization reveals that also some rather specific aspects are covered by the search results, such as "Abortion" and "United Nations". Interacting with the visual- ization helps explore the entire topic space.</p><p>In particular, hovering over the argument glyphs clarifies what aspects they exactly cover, such as "Woman", "Women", and "Feminism" itself for the highlighted argument in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_7">Figure 7</ref>. After a first ex- ploration via hovering, a result subset of interest can be filtered through brushing, say, the four top- most glyphs (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">Figure 6</ref> above). The selected arguments are then shown at the top of the textual result list (all below are grayed out). From the se- lected arguments, we learn that Emma Watson has made the need for feminism a point at the United Nations, whereas the claimed necessity of abortion is used as an analogy to justify the necessity of  feminism. Without the visualization, these insights would have been hard to gain; the two respective arguments were ranked at position #43 and #46.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.2">Search Refinement</head><p>As a second example, we assume that a user looks for new arguments on the "assassination of dicta- tors", for which args.me provides 119 results. If the user wants to refine a search to restrict it to a specific aspect of the topic only (e.g., to arguments covering Muammar Gaddafi), a simple click on the respective argument glyph in the topic space visu- alization suffices, as illustrated in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_8">Figure 8</ref>. The associated arguments are filtered and placed at the top of the result list (only one argument in the illus- trated case). With the existing interaction methods of args.me, the argument text can be extended and its source web page shows up after clicking on it. In the old overall ranking view, the argument would have been ranked at position #34.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Conclusion</head><p>This paper has presented a new visual interface for our argument search engine, args.me. The visual- ization supports users in learning about the topical aspects covered by the arguments returned in re- sponse to a query. In two case studies, we have demonstrated how this topic space visualization enables an efficient exploration and refinement of argument search results. Future research on model- ing the aspects of an argument can further enhance the usability of the visualization.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: The pro vs. con view of args.me, showing the argument search results for the query "feminism".</figDesc><graphic url="image-1.png" coords="2,72.82,62.80,216.63,126.45" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>2</head><label></label><figDesc>Related Work Different systems to visually create and analyze arguments have been introduced in the past. Some of their visualizations serve as a mind map to sup- port ongoing discussions, such as gIBIS (Conklin and Begeman, 1988), Belvedere (Suthers et al., 1995), ArgVis (Karamanou et al., 2011), Dicode (Tzagarakis and Karacapilidis, 2013), and Debate- Graph (Baldwin and Price, 2018). Others allow for evaluating the structure and schemes of argu- ments, such as Araucaria (Reed and Rowe, 2004), Rationale (van Gelder, 2007), ArgueApply (Pührer, 2017), Argunet (Betz et al., 2018), and Truthmap- ping (Truthmapping, 2018). To support achieving consensus in a discussion, SEAS (Lowrance et al., 2000), VUE (Baroni et al., 2015), and Dialectic Map (Niu, 2016) provide a combination of automatic argument analysis and vi- sual argument summaries. With similar intentions, Lexical Episode Plots (Gold et al., 2015), ConToVi (El-Assady et al., 2016), NEREx (El-Assady et al., 2017), and Jentner et al. (2017) visualize specific aspects of transcribed discussions.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2: The overall ranking view of the initial version of args.me, showing results for the query "feminism".</figDesc><graphic url="image-2.png" coords="2,308.10,62.80,216.63,126.45" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>Figure 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Figure 3: Topic space visualization for the query "feminism", positioning the retrieved arguments according to the eight main covered aspects and other.</figDesc><graphic url="image-3.png" coords="3,72.00,62.81,218.27,203.69" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head>Figure 4 :</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Figure 4: Positioning an argument glyph in the topic space: the black arrow shows the linear combination of weighted vertices (Aspect 3 0.2, Aspect 5 0.3, Aspect 1 0.5). The glyph itself points to the main covered aspect.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><head>Figure 5 :</head><label>5</label><figDesc>Figure 5: Hovering over an argument reveals the aspects it covers (main aspect marked by a small arrow).</figDesc><graphic url="image-4.png" coords="4,72.00,62.81,218.27,202.93" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_6"><head>Figure 6 :</head><label>6</label><figDesc>Figure 6: Selecting arguments in the topic space visualization filters them in the textual result list of args.me.</figDesc><graphic url="image-5.png" coords="4,307.28,62.80,218.27,203.28" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_7"><head>Figure 7 :</head><label>7</label><figDesc>Figure 7: The args.me search results for the query "feminism", along with the integrated topic space visualization. The argument hovered over in the visualization is highlighted in the textual result list ("Women don't need...").</figDesc><graphic url="image-6.png" coords="5,83.97,62.81,429.60,218.70" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_8"><head>Figure 8 :</head><label>8</label><figDesc>Figure 8: The single filtered args.me search result on the aspect Muammar Gaddafi for the query "assassination of dictators". The filtering is the result of clicking in the respective argument glyph in the topic space visualization.</figDesc><graphic url="image-7.png" coords="5,99.80,323.61,397.95,172.50" type="bitmap" /></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> Also known as just args, found at: https://args.me</note>

			<note place="foot" n="2"> The user study, also including other questions related to argument search, is going to be published in another venue. 3 Issue list: https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/ Wikipedia:List_of_controversial_issues</note>

			<note place="foot" n="4"> The LDA alternative can be activated in args.me by changing the value of the v-parameter in the URL field to &quot;lda&quot;.</note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="annex">
			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Peter</forename><surname>Baldwin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Price</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://debategraph.org" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Automatic evaluation of design alternatives with quantitative argumentation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Pietro</forename><surname>Baroni</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marco</forename><surname>Romano</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Francesca</forename><surname>Toni</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marco</forename><surname>Aurisicchio</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Giorgio</forename><surname>Bertanza</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Argument &amp; Computation</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="24" to="49" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gregor</forename><surname>Betz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sebastian</forename><surname>Cacean</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christian</forename><surname>Voigt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://www.argunet.org" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Latent dirichlet allocation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Blei</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Andrew</forename><forename type="middle">Y</forename><surname>Ng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michael</forename><forename type="middle">I</forename><surname>Jordan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Machine Learning Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="993" to="1022" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">gIBIS: A hypertext tool for exploratory policy discussion</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jeff</forename><surname>Conklin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michael</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Begeman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">ACM Transactions on Information Systems</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="303" to="331" />
			<date type="published" when="1988" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bruce</forename><surname>Croft</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Donald</forename><surname>Metzler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Trevor</forename><surname>Strohman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Search Engines: Information Retrieval in Practice</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Addison-Wesley Publishing Company</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>1st edition</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">ConToVi: Multi-party conversation exploration using topic-space views</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mennatallah</forename><surname>El-Assady</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Valentin</forename><surname>Gold</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Carmela</forename><surname>Acevedo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christopher</forename><surname>Collins</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Daniel</forename><surname>Keim</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Computer Graphics Forum</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">NEREx: Named-entity relationship exploration in multi-party conversations</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mennatallah</forename><surname>El-Assady</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rita</forename><surname>Sevastjanova</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bela</forename><surname>Gipp</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Daniel</forename><surname>Keim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christopher</forename><surname>Collins</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Computer Graphics Forum</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">36</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="213" to="225" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tim</forename><surname>Van Gelder</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">The rationale for rationale. Law, Probability &amp; Risk</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="23" to="42" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Exploratory text analysis using lexical episode plots</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Valentin</forename><surname>Gold</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christian</forename><surname>Rohrdantz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mennatallah</forename><surname>El-Assady</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Eurographics Conference on Visualization (EuroVis)-Short Papers. The Eurographics Association</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Feature alignment for the analysis of verbatim text transcripts</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wolfgang</forename><surname>Jentner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mennatallah</forename><surname>El-Assady</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bela</forename><surname>Gipp</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Daniel</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Keim</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">EuroVis Workshop on Visual Analytics</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>EuroVA</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Areti</forename><surname>Karamanou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Nikolaos Loutas, and Konstantinos Tarabanis. 2011. ArgVis: Structuring political deliberations using innovative visualisation technologies. Electronic Participation</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="87" to="98" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dialectical obligations in political debate</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christian</forename><surname>Kock</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Informal Logic</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">27</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="233" to="247" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Structured argumentation for analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">John</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Lowrance</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ian</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Harrison</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Andres</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Rodriguez</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 12th International Conference on Systems Research, Informatics, and Cybernetics: Focus Symposia on Advances in ComputerBased and Web-Based Collaborative Systems</title>
		<meeting>the 12th International Conference on Systems Research, Informatics, and Cybernetics: Focus Symposia on Advances in ComputerBased and Web-Based Collaborative Systems</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="47" to="57" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Generalized barycentric coordinates on irregular polygons</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mark</forename><surname>Meyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alan</forename><surname>Barr</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Haeyoung</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mathieu</forename><surname>Desbrun</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Graphics Tools</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="13" to="22" />
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Visualization Analysis and Design. AK Peters Visualization Series</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tamara</forename><surname>Munzner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<publisher>CRC Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Pedagogical Efficacy of Argument Visualization Tools</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hui</forename><surname>Niu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
			<publisher>Faculty of Education</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
<note type="report_type">Ph.D. thesis</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">ArgueApply: A mobile app for argumentation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jörg</forename><surname>Pührer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">International Conference on Logic Programming and Nonmonotonic Reasoning</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="250" to="262" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Araucaria: Software for argument analysis, diagramming and representation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chris</forename><surname>Reed</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Glenn</forename><surname>Rowe</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">International Journal on Artificial Intelligence Tools</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">04</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="961" to="979" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
