<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T12:13+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Syntactical Analysis of the Weaknesses of Sentiment Analyzers</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
				<availability status="unknown"><p>Copyright Association for Computational Linguistics</p>
				</availability>
				<date>October 31-November 4, 2018. 2018</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rohil</forename><surname>Verma</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">MIT</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>77 Massachusetts Avenue</addrLine>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Samuel</forename><surname>Kim</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">MIT</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>77 Massachusetts Avenue</addrLine>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Walter</surname></persName>
							<email>dwalter@mit.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="institution">MIT</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>77 Massachusetts Avenue</addrLine>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Syntactical Analysis of the Weaknesses of Sentiment Analyzers</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2018 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</title>
						<meeting>the 2018 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing <address><addrLine>Brussels, Belgium</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="1122" to="1127"/>
							<date type="published">October 31-November 4, 2018. 2018</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<note>1122</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>We carry out a syntactic analysis of two state-of-the-art sentiment analyzers, Google Cloud Natural Language and Stanford CoreNLP, to assess their classification accuracy on sentences with negative polarity items. We were motivated by the absence of studies investigating sentiment analyzer performance on sentences with polarity items, a common construct in human language. Our analysis fo-cuses on two sentential structures: downward entailment and non-monotone quantifiers; and demonstrates weaknesses of Google Natural Language and CoreNLP in capturing polarity item information. We describe the particular syntactic phenomenon that these analyzers fail to understand that any ideal sentiment analyzer must. We also provide a set of 150 test sentences that any ideal sentiment analyzer must be able to understand.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Sentiment analysis of texts, from relatively long product and movie reviews ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Pang et al., 2002</ref>) to short tweets ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Go et al., 2009)</ref>, is a rich and evolv- ing field. Probabilistic analyzers, such as Google's Natural Language client <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(Google, 2018)</ref> and Stan- ford's CoreNLP package ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Manning et al., 2014</ref>), have improved in recent years, but major chal- lenges remain in classifying practical sentences. In this paper, we focus on a particular grammat- ical phenomena analyzers often misclassify: the presence of specific polarity items.</p><p>As one of the fundamental components of nat- ural language, polarity items (e.g. nothing, any, ever) are lexical items that can appear only in spe- cific licensing contexts. Thus, we should be able to identify the grammatical polarity of a sentence by the presence of such polarity items, allowing us to determine its sentiment. However, these licens- ing contexts are challenging to identify and are generally different for each item <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Baker, 1970)</ref>. We aim to understand how negative polarity items are involved in misclassified sentences and use this knowledge to characterize the syntactic phe- nomenon an ideal sentiment analyzer must learn.</p><p>First, we present a brief background on senti- ment analyzers and polarity items. In the next section, we describe our methodology in terms of what kinds of sentences we want to use and how we can best test the sentiment analyzers. Our methodology involves trying sentences with negative polarity items under two different li- censing contexts, downward entailment and non- monotone quantifiers. We then evaluate variations of the sentences to show that the sentiment ana- lyzers are not correctly using the polarity items. By exploring these misclassified sentences, we de- scribe the particular syntactic configuration that leads to misclassification, presenting weaknesses in the state-of-the-art sentiment analyzers in un- derstanding and handling polarity items.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Background and Previous Work</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">Sentiment Analyzers</head><p>Most sentiment analyzers ( <ref type="bibr">Wang et al., 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Pak and Paroubek, 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Cambria et al., 2013</ref>) are based on a statistical approach, relying on a con- glomeration of sentiments of the individual words in a sample. The main assumption behind such statistical approaches is that keywords contain es- sential information to infer the sentiment of a whole sample. Therefore, this type of statistical approach does not readily consider complex syn- tactic interactions between individual words; in- stead, the main focus lies in the system's learning of the relevant knowledge through texts relevant to the sentiment analysis task.</p><p>Statistical methods often employ bag-of-words as input features and represent a document by the summation of all bag-of-words features in that document. A model, such as a maximum entropy classifier or support vector machine <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Mullen and Collier, 2004</ref>), can be trained to learn which words or combinations of words are relevant for senti- ment analysis <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(Pang et al., 2002</ref>). With bag-of- words as the input of a model, we lose spatial structure for a document, so a classifier is inca- pable of differentiating "I knew the dog would never bite" from "The dog knew the man would never bite" or "Bite never I knew the dog would."</p><p>To overcome such challenges, deep learning models have gained popularity for this task. ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Glorot et al., 2011</ref>) use domain adaptation to train an adversarial network, where two models are pit- ted against each other: one classifying sentiment and the other creating input documents. This ap- proach allows the system to learn from data sets across multiple domains, increasing the flexibility of the sentiment classifier. However, the weakness of this approach is that the system uses a bigram bag-of-words as input, making it unable to learn long-distance syntactic phenomena.</p><p>Recent methods have proposed learning word embeddings ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Tang et al., 2014</ref>) or applying deep neural architectures (Dos Santos and Gatti <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">de Bayser, 2014</ref>) to extract context and sentiment from short texts, as these contain minimal infor- mation. Although these techniques have shown performance improvements, they have not been completely successful in capturing long-distance dependencies, leading to the proposal of memory networks <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">(Weston et al., 2014</ref>) and attention-based mechanisms ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Wang et al., 2016</ref>).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">Polarity Items</head><p>In Emergence of Meaning (Crain, 2012), Crain puts forward polarity items, like "some" and "any" that are similar, but are sometimes interpreted dif- ferently. He presents the example of (1) "John didn't eat any of the kangaroo." and compares it to (2) "John didn't eat some of the kangaroo." The sentence with "some" implies that John did eat a part of the kangaroo, but there is a part of it that he did not eat. The sentence with "any" implies the stronger statement that John did not eat any of the kangaroos. These two interpretations differ due to the polarity of the two words. "Any" is only accepted in negative contexts, so it has negative polarity, whereas "some" can be accepted in both positive and negative contexts and possesses posi- tive polarity. To observe that "any" only works in negative contexts, consider the sentence (3) "John ate any of the kangaroo." which has positive con- text, and is incorrect with the word "any".</p><p>Further, the words "any" and "some" can some- times be used interchangeably and have the same interpretation. (4) "You'll never convince me that John didn't eat some/any of the kangaroo." con- tains (1) and (2). In (4) there is negation (never) in a higher clause; then the latter clause contains negation and "any"/"some". These practical ex- amples demonstrate that word ordering in a sen- tence matters, and that polarity items can exist in complex statements requiring a fundamental un- derstanding of human language for correct inter- pretation. Therefore, a model just working with bag-of-words or even n-gram features does not ap- pear to be sufficient for practical sentences that re- quire spatial or syntactic understanding.</p><p>Polarity items are permitted only within specific licensing contexts, which means they can only oc- cur in specific sentential structures. Our paper ex- plores two licensing contexts: downward entail- ment and non-monotone quantifiers. Under down- ward entailment, the sentence acts as a monotone decreasing function such that when parts of the sentence are removed monotonically, the relative strength of a statement monotonically decreases. For example, "nobody moved into the house" im- plies "nobody moved into the house quickly", so "nobody moved" is a monotone-decreasing phrase. On the other hand, non-monotone quan- tifiers lack clear downward or upward entailment <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Giannakidou, 2002</ref>). For example, the phrase "exactly three men never moved" does not en- tail "exactly three men never moved quickly" and vice-versa, so it has non-monotone entailment. The linguistic phenomenon of licensing contexts and polarity items are a fundamental part of hu- man language, and the metric to measure the per- formance of a sentiment analyzer should consider how it handles these polarity items.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Related Work</head><p>To the best of our knowledge, there are no previous studies investigating the weaknesses of Google Natural Language, CoreNLP, or other probabilis- tic sentiment analyzers in classifying sentences with polarity items.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Classification accuracy Downward entailment</head><p>Non-monotone quantifier</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">a b c d e a' b' c' d'</formula><p>e' Google NLP 0% 0% 0% 80% 80% 0% 0% 0% 93.3% 86.7% Stanford CoreNLP 0% 0% 0% 33.3% 53.3% 0% 0% 0% 33.3% 66.7% </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Experiment</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">Methodology</head><p>We developed 150 test sentences derived from two base sentences, under two different licensing con- texts: downward entailment and non-monotone quantifiers. We first tested on Google Cloud Natu- ral Language <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(Google, 2018)</ref> and then repeated the experiment on the Stanford CoreNLP sentiment analyzer <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(Socher et al., 2013)</ref>. Each base sentence consists of a subject phrase, a verb phrase, some polarity item(s), and some modifiers (e.g. painful). The rest of the test sentences consist of variations on the base sentences in the specific phrases, po- larity items or modifiers used, allowing us to iden- tify the sentence element responsible for misclas- sification. We chose 15 sentences with minimal sentiment ambiguity per category, allowing us to demonstrate with statistical confidence the inabil- ity of these sentiment analyzers to capture syntac- tic phenomena.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">Results</head><p>For both downward entailment and non-monotone quantifiers, we considered two base sentences: For (A), we used subject phrases such as "I" and "Bill and his friends", and in the case of non- monotone quantifiers, we used subjects such as "exactly half", "99% of people", and "exactly ten students".</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2.1">Downward entailment</head><p>Sentences in category a (eg: "Bill has never done anything terrible") should be classified as positive. Both Google Natural Language and CoreNLP achieved 0% accuracy on sentences in this cate- gory as shown in <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table 1</ref>. The sentiment analyz- ers classified these sentences as either negative or neutral. We consider neutral classification incor- rect, as the overall sentence is expressing a posi- tive sentiment towards the subject for possessing good moral character. Our varied adjectives re- veals that the adjective used is not the reason for misclassfication.</p><p>To investigate misclassification further, we var- ied the subject phrase (A) with fifteen different subject phrases (category b). We observed that sentences such as "Bill has never done anything terrible" and "Bill in my English class has never done anything terrible." are classified as nega- tive by Google Natural Language and CoreNLP. The magnitude of the negative sentiment remains the same, indicating that minor variations in the subject phrases do not affect the sentiment of the sentence. However, while CoreNLP classi- fies "Bill has never done anything grumpy" as neutral, it classifies "Sally has never done any- thing grumpy" as negative. Google Natural Lan- guage classifies both as negative, although the score changes slightly. This example demonstrates another weakness of the sentiment analyzers: they treat subject phrases with the same context ("Bill" vs. "Sally") differently.</p><p>Next, we show that the reason for misclassifica- tion is not the presence of "never" by varying the sentences to contain "not" (category c; e.g. "Bill has not done anything terrible"). Both Google Natural Language and CoreNLP classify all 15 sentences as negative and yield the same classi- fication accuracy of 0%. We note that for some sentences there is a minor change in the score, but</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>(ROOT (S (NP (NNP Bill)) (VP (VBZ has) (ADVP (RB never)) (VP (VBN done) (S (ADJP (NN anything) (JJ terrible))))) (.)))</head><p>Figure 1: Parse tree for "Bill has never done anything terrible." the sentiment of sentences remains the same.</p><p>We now consider sentences in category (2) that are semantically opposite to sentences in category (1). For example, "Bill has done something ter- rible" or other variations (types d and e) should be unambiguously classified as negative. Here, Google Natural Language achieves a classification accuracy of 80% (12 out of 15 test sentences) com- pared to CoreNLP's 33.3% (5 out of 15 test sen- tences). For Google Natural Language, it is ev- ident that the element that causes misclassifica- tion is the negative polarity item that the analyzer fails to interpret. The analyzer fails to invert the negative sentiment of negative adjectives (B) and thus classifies the sentence as negative or neutral. CoreNLP, however, does poorly on all categories, although it does significantly better on sentences in category (2).</p><p>We now consider the parse tree of the original sentence "Bill has never done anything terrible" <ref type="figure">(Figure 1</ref>) to demonstrate the successful parse of "has never done anything terrible" as a single verb phrase. The failure of the analyzers to correctly determine sentiment implies that despite noting the sentence's hierarchical structure, they are un- able to understand long-term dependencies -they lack an understanding of the c-command relation <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Radford, 2004</ref>).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2.2">Non-monotone quantifiers</head><p>We repeated the same analysis for non-monotone quantifiers by including non-monotone quantifiers within the subject phrase. For example, "Exactly half had never done anything terrible" and its sis- ter sentences (e.g. "Ninety percent of parents had never done anything terrible") should be classi- fied as positive. Similar to our findings on down- ward entailment, both Google Natural Language and CoreNLP achieve a classification accuracy of (ROOT (S (ADVP (RB Exactly)) (NP (NN half)) (VP (VBD had) (ADVP (RB never)) (VP (VBN done) (S (ADJP (NN anything) (JJ terrible))))) (.)))</p><p>Figure 2: Parse tree for "Exactly half had never done anything terrible." 0% on the three classes of sentences within cat- egory (1): a total of 45 sentences from class (a'), (b'), and (c') as shown in <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table 1</ref>. Analyzers again determine "had never done anything terrible" as a single verb phrase, as shown in a parse tree in <ref type="figure">Fig</ref> For semantically opposite sentences (class <ref type="bibr">(d')</ref> and (e')), we get a similar result as in down- ward entailing sentences, although the classifica- tion accuracy slightly increases for both analyz- ers. Again, we consider neutral classification as a misclassification, as the sentence clearly contains either a positive or negative sentiment towards the subject.</p><p>We interpret our experiment with non- monotone quantifiers as follows: (1) both CoreNLP and Google Natural Language lack an understanding of the negative polarity item "anything" and (2) the variation of subject phrases results in a minor change in the sentiment. We note that, as in the case of downward entailment, the failure of the analyzers implies an inability to understand the c-command relation <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Radford, 2004</ref>). We note a limitation of our experiment: the selection of arbitrary adjectives. However, the 15 adjectives used are commonly used to describe humans, and the result was quite consistent. Fur- ther, we found coherent results for both downward entailment and non-monotone quantifiers and were able to highlight the lack of long-distance dependency understanding in state-of-the-art analyzers. Finally, we highlight the importance of assessing performance of sentiment analyzers using practical sentences that involve not only negation as in previous studies <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(Socher et al., 2013</ref>), but also polarity items such as the 150 sentences used in our experiment.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Discussion</head><p>Our experiment indicates that the Stanford CoreNLP sentiment analyzer <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(Socher et al., 2013)</ref> and Google Cloud Natural Language <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(Google, 2018)</ref> do not understand the c-command relation <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Radford, 2004</ref>). We now argue that this issue is not a result of the training set used, but rather a fundamental inability of the model class. First, we note that long-term dependencies are a well- known weakness of probabilistic models, even those specifically designed to capture them, such as bidirectional RNNs or LSTMs ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">Zhang et al., 2018)</ref>. Next, we note that the sentences that we tested are general sentences whose components could be found in any linguistic corpus; in fact, CoreNLP's treebank does contain annotated sen- tences containing the "... has never ..." or "... has no ..." constructions, and so the model should correctly analyze such sentences. As a result, we draw the conclusion that these models lack an un- derstanding of long-term dependencies, and based on our experiments, they specifically fail to under- stand the c-command relation <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Radford, 2004)</ref>. Fi- nally, we remind readers that the c-command rela- tion is associated with Chomskyan grammars; and need not be necessary within other models of syn- tax. Consequently, learning the c-command rela- tion may lead to better analyzers, but it need not be the only way to improve performance.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Conclusions</head><p>We evaluated two state-of-the-art sentiment ana- lyzers, Stanford CoreNLP ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Socher et al., 2013)</ref> and Google Cloud Natural Language <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(Google, 2018)</ref>, using sentences with negative polarity items under two different licensing contexts: downward entailment and non-monotone quanti- fiers. Through such analysis, we noted that cur- rent analyzers lack a complete understanding of negative polarity items, and by extension, the c- command relation. We have also produced a set of sentences that can be used to test future analyzers. This work can be extended to validate other ana- lyzers, test non-probabilistic sentiment analyzers or build, new improved sentiment analyzers. We have made the set of misclassified sentences avail- able as supplementary material.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" validated="false"><head>Table 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Summary of classification accuracy on downward entailment and non-monotone quantifiers. Each cate-
gory indicates 15 test sentences. a: Bill has never done anything [negative adjective], b: [subject phrase] has never 
done anything [negative adjective], c: Bill has not done anything [negative adjective], d: Bill has done something 
[negative adjective], e: [subject phrase] has done something [negative adjective]. a'-e': instead of Bill, we use a 
non-monotone quantifier (e.g. exactly half). 

</table></figure>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7">Acknowledgements</head><p>The authors would like to thank Professor Robert C. Berwick for his guidance in preparing this work.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Double negatives. Linguistic inquiry</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C Lee</forename><surname>Baker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1970" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="169" to="186" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Statistical approaches to concept-level sentiment analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Erik</forename><surname>Cambria</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bjorn</forename><surname>Schuller</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bing</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Haixun</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Catherine</forename><surname>Havasi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE Intelligent Systems</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">28</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="6" to="9" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The emergence of meaning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Stephen</forename><surname>Crain</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<publisher>Cambridge University Press</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="volume">135</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Deep convolutional neural networks for sentiment analysis of short texts</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dos</forename><surname>Cicero</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Maira Gatti De</forename><surname>Santos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Bayser</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">International Conference on Computational Linguistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Licensing and sensitivity in polarity items: from downward entailment to nonveridicality</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Anastasia</forename><surname>Giannakidou</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">CLS</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">38</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="29" to="53" />
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Domain adaptation for large-scale sentiment classification: A deep learning approach</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xavier</forename><surname>Glorot</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Antoine</forename><surname>Bordes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yoshua</forename><surname>Bengio</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 28th international conference on machine learning (ICML-11)</title>
		<meeting>the 28th international conference on machine learning (ICML-11)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="513" to="520" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Twitter sentiment analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alec</forename><surname>Go</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lei</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Richa</forename><surname>Bhayani</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Entropy</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">252</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Google Cloud Natural Language</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Google</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://cloud.google.com/natural-language/" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018-05" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The stanford corenlp natural language processing toolkit</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christopher</forename><surname>Manning</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mihai</forename><surname>Surdeanu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">John</forename><surname>Bauer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jenny</forename><surname>Finkel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Steven</forename><surname>Bethard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Mcclosky</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of 52nd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics: System Demonstrations</title>
		<meeting>52nd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics: System Demonstrations</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="55" to="60" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Sentiment analysis using support vector machines with diverse information sources</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tony</forename><surname>Mullen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nigel</forename><surname>Collier</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2004 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</title>
		<meeting>the 2004 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Twitter as a corpus for sentiment analysis and opinion mining</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alexander</forename><surname>Pak</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Patrick</forename><surname>Paroubek</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">LREc</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Thumbs up?: sentiment classification using machine learning techniques</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bo</forename><surname>Pang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lillian</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Shivakumar</forename><surname>Vaithyanathan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the ACL-02 conference on Empirical methods in natural language processing</title>
		<meeting>the ACL-02 conference on Empirical methods in natural language processing</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="79" to="86" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">English syntax: An introduction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Radford</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Recursive deep models for semantic compositionality over a sentiment treebank</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Richard</forename><surname>Socher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alex</forename><surname>Perelygin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jean</forename><surname>Wu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jason</forename><surname>Chuang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Christopher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Andrew</forename><surname>Manning</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christopher</forename><surname>Ng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Potts</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2013 conference on empirical methods in natural language processing</title>
		<meeting>the 2013 conference on empirical methods in natural language processing</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1631" to="1642" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Learning sentimentspecific word embedding for twitter sentiment classification</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Duyu</forename><surname>Tang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Furu</forename><surname>Wei</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nan</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ming</forename><surname>Zhou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ting</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bing</forename><surname>Qin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">52nd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics, ACL 2014-Proceedings of the Conference</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1555" to="1565" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">François Bar, and Shrikanth Narayanan. 2012. A system for real-time twitter sentiment analysis of 2012 us presidential election cycle</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hao</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dogan</forename><surname>Can</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Abe</forename><surname>Kazemzadeh</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the ACL 2012 System Demonstrations</title>
		<meeting>the ACL 2012 System Demonstrations</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="115" to="120" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Association for Computational Linguistics</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Attention-based lstm for aspect-level sentiment classification</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yequan</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Minlie</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xiaoyan</forename><surname>Zhu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Li</forename><surname>Zhao</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2016 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</title>
		<meeting>the 2016 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="606" to="615" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jason</forename><surname>Weston</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sumit</forename><surname>Chopra</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Antoine</forename><surname>Bordes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>abs/1410.3916</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Deep learning for sentiment analysis : A survey</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lei</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Shuai</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bing</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
