<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T12:13+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">SimpleQuestions Nearly Solved: A New Upperbound and Baseline Approach</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date>October 31-November 4, 2018</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Petrochuk</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">Allen Institute for Artificial Intelligence</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Seattle</settlement>
									<region>WA</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Luke</forename><surname>Zettlemoyer</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Paul</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Allen</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">School of Computer Science &amp; Engineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Univ. of Washington</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Seattle</settlement>
									<region>WA</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">SimpleQuestions Nearly Solved: A New Upperbound and Baseline Approach</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2018 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</title>
						<meeting>the 2018 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing <address><addrLine>Brussels; Belgium</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="554" to="558"/>
							<date type="published">October 31-November 4, 2018</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<note>554</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>The SimpleQuestions dataset is one of the most commonly used benchmarks for studying single-relation factoid questions. In this paper , we present new evidence that this benchmark can be nearly solved by standard methods. First, we show that ambiguity in the data bounds performance at 83.4%; many questions have more than one equally plausible interpretation. Second, we introduce a baseline that sets a new state-of-the-art performance level at 78.1% accuracy, despite using standard methods. Finally, we report an empirical analysis showing that the upperbound is loose; roughly a quarter of the remaining errors are also not resolvable from the linguistic signal. Together, these results suggest that the SimpleQuestions dataset is nearly solved.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>We present new evidence that the SimpleQues- tions benchmark ( ) can be nearly solved by standard methods. First, we show that ambiguity in the data bounds perfor- mance; there are often questions have more than one equally plausible interpretation. Second, we introduce a baseline that sets a new state-of-the-art performance level, despite using standard meth- ods. Finally, we report an empirical analysis showing that the upperbound is loose.</p><p>The simple questions task involves mapping an English question (e.g. "Who wrote Gulliver's travels?") to an analogous Freebase ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Bollacker et al., 2008)</ref> query, used to answer the ques- tion. The query consists of a Freebase rela- tion (e.g. /film/film/story by) and subject (e.g. 090s 0 [gulliver's travels]). To understand how we might bound performance on the SimpleQuestions dataset, our first contribution in this paper, con- sider the following examples: a. who wrote gulliver's travels?</p><p>(film/film/story by, 090s 0 [gulliver's travels, In example (a) the phrase "Gulliver's travels" is mapped to a TV miniseries, while in (b) it is mapped to a book. This introduces an unintended ambiguity, since either mapping is equally plau- sible for both examples (i.e. both books and TV miniseries have authors and characters). We intro- duce a method for automatically identifying many such ambiguities in the data, for both the entities and relations, and show that performance is upper- bounded at 83.4%.</p><p>Our second main contribution is a baseline that sets a new state-of-the-art performance level, de- spite using standard methods. Our approach in- cludes (1) a CRF used to tag the mention of the subject in a question and (2) a BiLSTM used to classify the Freebase relation. Despite its simplic- ity, this approach achieves 78.1% accuracy for pre- dicting Freebase subject-relation queries, surpass- ing all previous models.</p><p>Finally, we present an empirical error analy- sis of this model which shows the upperbound is loose and that there is likely not much more than 4% of performance to be gained with fu- ture work on the data. Together, these re- sults suggest that the SimpleQuestions dataset is nearly solved. Our code and pretrained models are available at github.com/PetrochukM/ Simple-Question-Answering.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Background</head><p>Single-relation factoid questions (simple ques- tions) are common in many settings (e.g. Mi- crosoft's search query logs ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Yih et al., 2014</ref>) and WikiAnswers web questions <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(Fader et al., 2013)</ref>). The SimpleQuestions dataset is one of the most commonly used benchmarks for studying such questions.</p><p>The Freebase knowledge graph (KG) pro- vides the facts for answering the questions in the SimpleQuestions dataset. It includes 3 bil- lion triples of the form (subject, relation, ob- ject) (e.g. [04b5zb (Fires Creek), location/lo- cation/containedby, 0f80hy (Nantahala National Forest)]). We denote such triples as (s, r, o).</p><p>The SimpleQuestions task is to rewrite ques- tions into subject-relation pairs of the form (sub- ject, relation), denoted in this paper as <ref type="bibr">(s, r)</ref>. Each pair defines a graph query that can be used to answer the corresponding natural language ques- tion. The subject is a Freebase object with a identifier called an MID (e.g. 04b5zb ). Free- base objects also typically include one or more string aliases (e.g. MID 04b5zb is named "Fires Creek"), which we will use later when comput- ing our upper bounds. The relation is an ob- ject property (e.g. location/location/containedby) defined by the Freebase ontology. For example, the question "which forest is fires creek in" cor- responds with the subject-relation pair (04b5zb <ref type="bibr">[Fires Creek]</ref>, location/location/containedby). Fi- nally, the SimpleQuestions task is evaluated on subject-relation pair accuracy.</p><p>The SimpleQuestions dataset provides a set of 108,442 simple questions; each question is accom- panied by a ground truth triple (s, r, o). This dataset also provides two subsets of Freebase: FB2M and FB5M. <ref type="bibr">1</ref> </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Dataset Ambiguity and Upperbound</head><p>The ambiguity in the SimpleQuestions dataset likely comes from the way the data was created. Annotators were shown a single Freebase triple and asked to write a question. For example, given any of the following triples:</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">• (0btc7 [Gulliver's Travels, Book], book/written work/author, o3 dj [Dean Swift])</formula><p>• (06znpjr [Gulliver's Travels, American film], film/film/written by, 03whnyn [Nicholas Stroller]) <ref type="bibr">1</ref> The FB2M and FB5M subsets of Freebase KG can com- plete 7,188,636 and 7,688,234 graph queries respectively; therefore, the FB5M subset is 6.9% larger than the FB2M subset. More previous research has cited FB2M numbers than FB5M; therefore, we report our numbers on FB2M.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Subject Description 0btc7</head><p>Gulliver's Travels (Book) 090s 0</p><p>Gulliver's Travels (TV miniseries) 06znpjr Gulliver's Travels (American film) 02py9bj Gulliver's Travels (French film)  The annotator might reasonably contribute the question "who wrote gulliver's travels?" However, adding all of these pairs to the data is problematic. Systems are evaluated on producing the correct subject-relation pair, and cannot learn a determin- istic mapping that would get these three examples correct. In this section, we present a simple heuris- tic method for finding many such instances of am- biguity, and use it to upper bound performance on this benchmark.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Approach</head><p>Given an example question q with the ground truth (s, r, o), our goal is to determine the set of all other subject-relation pairs that are equally supported by the text in q.</p><p>We first determine a string alias a for the subject by matching a phrase in q with a Freebase alias for s, in our example yielding "gulliver's travels". For 97% of questions q, some string alias a ex- actly matched a question q phrase. We then find all other Freebase entities that share this alias a and add them to a set S, in our example S is the subject column of <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Table 1</ref>.</p><p>We define an abstract predicate p (e.g. "who wrote e?") as q with alias a abstracted. We de- termine the set of potential relations R as the re- lations p co-occurs with in the SimpleQuestions dataset, in our example R is the relation column of <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">Table 2</ref>.</p><p>Finally, if there exists a subject-relation pair (s, r) ∈ KG such that r ∈ R ∧ s ∈ S we de-fine that as an accurate semantic interpretation of q. q is unanswerable if there exists multiple valid subject-relation pairs (s, r). In our example above, the question is unanswerable because of the many different subject, relation pairs that co-occur with "gulliver's travels" and "who wrote e?"</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Results</head><p>We find that 33.9% of examples in the Simple- Questions dataset are unanswerable. In these cases, we can predict a majority baseline (i.e. al- ways guess the most commonly seen Freebase en- tity or relation), yielding an upperbound of 85.2%.</p><p>Finally, we also found that 1.8% of example questions were noisy. For example, "Which book is written about?" does not reference the corre- sponding ground truth subject 01n7q (california). We also consider these examples unanswerable, yielding a final upperbound of 83.4%.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Baseline Model</head><p>Our second main contribution is a baseline that sets a new state-of-the-art performance level, de- spite using standard methods. Our approach in- cludes (1) a CRF tagger to determine the subject alias, and (2) a BiLSTM to classify the relation.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">Approach</head><p>Given a question q (e.g. "who wrote gulliver's travels?") our model must predict the correspond- ing subject-relation pair (s, r). We predict (s, r) with a pipeline that first runs top-k subject recog- nition and then relation classification.</p><p>We make use of two learned distributions. The subject recognition model P (a|q) ranges over text spans A within the question q, in our example A includes the correct subject "gulliver's travels". This distribution is modeled with a CRF, as de- fined in more detail below. The relation classifica- tion model P (r|q, a) will be used to select a Free- base relation r that matches q. The distribution ranges over all relations in Freebase that co-occur with a subject that is named a. It is modeled with an LSTM, that encodes q, again as defined in more detail below.</p><p>Given these distributions, we predict the final subject-relation pair (s, r) as follows. First, we determine the most likely subject alias a according to P (a|q) that also matches a subject alias in the KG. We define set S as all Freebase entities named a, in our example S is the subject column of <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Table   1</ref>. Second, we define all potential relations R such that ∀(s, r) ∈ KG{r ∈ R ∧ s ∈ S}. Using the relation classification model p(r|q, a), we predict the most likely relation r max ∈ R.</p><p>Now, the answer candidates are subject-relation pairs such that (s, r max ) ∈ KG{r ∈ R ∧ s ∈ S}. In our example question, if r max is film/film/story by then S includes both subjects 06znpjr (Gullivers Travels, American film) and 02py9bj (Gullivers Travels, French film). Be- cause there is no explicit linguistic signal to dis- ambiguate this choice, we pick the subject that co- occurs most often with r max in Freebase.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">Model Details</head><p>Our approach requires two models, in this section we cover training and configuring these models.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Top-K Subject Recognition</head><p>We model top-k subject recognition P (a|q) using a linear-chain conditional random field tagger (CRF) with a con- ditional log likelihood loss objective. k candidates are inferred with the top-k Viterbi algorithm.</p><p>Our model is trained on a dataset of questions each with their corresponding subject alias span delimited with IO tagging. The gold standard sub- ject alias spans are determined by heuristically matching a phrase in the question with a Freebase alias for the subject.</p><p>All hyperparameters are hand tuned and then a limited set are further tuned with grid search to in- crease validation accuracy. In total we evaluated at most 100 hyperparameter configurations. The word embeddings are initialized with GloVe <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">(Pennington et al., 2014</ref>) and frozen. <ref type="bibr">Adam (Kingma and Ba, 2014)</ref>, initialized with a learning rate of 0.001, is employed to optimize the model weights. Finally, we halve the learning rate if the validation accuracy has not improved in 3 epochs.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Relation Classification</head><p>The relation classifica- tion distribution P (r|q, a) is modeled with a one layer BiLSTM batchnorm softmax classifier. The BiLSTM encodes an abstract predicate string (e.g. "who wrote e?"), as described in Section 4.1. The last LSTM output vector is provided as input to an output block consisting of batch normalization, ReLU, and softmax.</p><p>All hyperparameters are hand tuned and then a limited set are further tuned with Hyperband ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Li et al., 2017</ref>) to increase validation accuracy. Hy- perband is allowed at most 30 epochs per model and a total of 1000 epochs. In total we evalu- ated at most 500 hyperparameter configurations. The word embeddings are initialized with Fast- Text ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Bojanowski et al., 2017</ref>) and frozen. We use the AMSGrad variant of Adam ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Reddi et al., 2018)</ref>, initialized with an learning rate of 0.001. Finally, we double the batch size ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">Smith et al., 2017</ref>) if the validation accuracy has not improved in 3 epochs.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3">Results</head><p>Finally, we present our results on the SimpleQues- tions test set.</p><p>SimpleQuestions Task Our model achieves 78.1% accuracy on the SimpleQuestions test set, a new state-of-the-art without ensembling or data augmentation <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">(Table 3</ref>). These results suggest that relatively standard architectures work well when carefully tuned, and approach the level set by our upper bound earlier in the paper. This further con- firms the results of .</p><p>Further Qualitative Analysis We also analyze the remaining errors, to point toward directions for future work.</p><p>In Section 3, we showed that questions can pro- vide equal evidence for multiple subject-relation 1 Türe and Jojic 2017 reported a 86.8% accuracy but we and Mohammed et al. <ref type="bibr">2017</ref> have not been able to replicate their results. <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">Wang et al. 2017</ref> scored 77.5% but removed 0.5% of the test examples. pairs. To remove this ambiguity, we count any of these options as correct, and our performance jumps to 91.5%.</p><p>The remaining 8.5% error comes from a number of sources. First, we find that 1.9% of examples were incorrect due to noise, as described in Sec- tion 3. To better understand the remaining 6.5% gap, we do an empirical error analysis on a sample of 50 negative examples.</p><p>First we found that for 14 of 50 cases the question provided equal linguistic evidence for both the ground truth options and the predicted subject-relation pair, similar to the dataset am- biguity found in Section 3, suggesting that our upper bound is loose. We note that Section 3 did not cover all possible question-subject-relation pair ambiguities. The approach relied on exact string matching to discover ambiguity; therefore, missing other paraphrases. For example, the ab- stract predicate "what classification is e" had more examples than "what classification is the e" al- lowing our approach to programmatically define more subject-relation pair ambiguities for the for- mer predicate than the latter.</p><p>The remaining 36 of 50 cases were linguistic mistakes by our model. Among the 36 cases, we identified these error cases:</p><p>• Low Shot (16 of 36) The relation label was seen in the training data less than 10 times.</p><p>• Span Identification (14 of 36) The subject span was incorrectly labeled.</p><p>• Noise (2 of 36) The question did not make grammatical sense.</p><p>Together, this error analysis shows that the up- perbound is loose. There is likely not much more than 4% of performance to be gained with future work on the data.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Conclusions and Future Work</head><p>The SimpleQuestions dataset is one of the most commonly used benchmarks for studying single- relation factoid questions. In this paper, we pre- sented new evidence to suggest that this bench- mark can be nearly solved by standard methods. These results suggest there is likely not much more than 4% to be gained with future work on the data.</p><p>Finally, other KG (e.g. Freebase) query datasets should consider providing a set of correct subject- relation pairs when there is ambiguity in the lin- guistic input.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" validated="false"><head>Table 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>FB2M entities with the alias "gulliver's trav-
els" 

Relation 
Count 
book/written work/author 132 
film/film/written by 
67 
film/film/story by 
9 
. . . 
. . . 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" validated="false"><head>Table 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>SimpleQuestions dataset abstract predicate 
"who wrote e?" relation count 

• (06znpjr [Gulliver's Travels, American film], 
film/film/story by, o3 dj [Dean Swift]) 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3" validated="false"><head>Table 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Summary of past results on the SimpleQues- tions benchmark along with the neural models em- ployed. Note that an "&amp;" indicates multiple neural models.</figDesc><table></table></figure>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Bordes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nn (</forename><surname>Memory</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Bordes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
			<biblScope unit="page">61</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Attn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Golub</forename><surname>Lstm (he</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">70</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Gru (lukovnikov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">71</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">-Crf &amp;amp; ;</forename><surname>Bigru</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Mohammed</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">BiLSTM &amp; BiGRU</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">73</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">9</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>BiGRU</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">&amp;amp;</forename><surname>Bigru</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Bigru</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Dai</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">75</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">CNN &amp; Attn. CNN &amp;</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">76</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">-Crf (</forename><surname>Bilstm</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Yin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>HR-BiLSTM &amp; CNN &amp; 77.0</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">-Crf (</forename><surname>Bilstm</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Yu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">BiLSTM-CRF &amp; BiLSTM (Ours)</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">78</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Enriching word vectors with subword information</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Piotr</forename><surname>References</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Edouard</forename><surname>Bojanowski</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Armand</forename><surname>Grave</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tomas</forename><surname>Joulin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Mikolov</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">TACL</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="135" to="146" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Freebase: a collaboratively created graph database for structuring human knowledge</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kurt</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Bollacker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Colin</forename><surname>Evans</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Praveen</forename><surname>Paritosh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tim</forename><surname>Sturge</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jamie</forename><surname>Taylor</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">SIGMOD Conference</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Large-scale simple question answering with memory networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Antoine</forename><surname>Bordes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nicolas</forename><surname>Usunier</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sumit</forename><surname>Chopra</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jason</forename><surname>Weston</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>abs/1506.02075</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
			<publisher>CoRR</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Cfo: Conditional focused neural question answering with largescale knowledge bases</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Zihang</forename><surname>Dai</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lei</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wei</forename><surname>Xu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>abs/1606.01994</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
			<publisher>CoRR</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Paraphrase-driven learning for open question answering</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Anthony</forename><surname>Fader</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Luke</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Zettlemoyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Oren</forename><surname>Etzioni</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ACL</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Character-level question answering with attention</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xiaodong</forename><surname>He</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Golub</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">EMNLP</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Adam: A method for stochastic optimization</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Diederik</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jimmy</forename><surname>Kingma</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Ba</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>abs/1412.6980</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<publisher>CoRR</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Hyperband: Bandit-based configuration eval-uation for hyperparameter optimization</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lisha</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kevin</forename><surname>Jamieson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Giulia</forename><surname>Desalvo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Afshin</forename><surname>Rostamizadeh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ameet</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Talwalkar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Neural network-based question answering over knowledge graphs on word and character level</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Denis</forename><surname>Lukovnikov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Asja</forename><surname>Fischer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jens</forename><surname>Lehmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sören</forename><surname>Auer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">WWW</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Strong baselines for simple question answering over knowledge graphs with and without neural networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Salman</forename><surname>Mohammed</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Peng</forename><surname>Shi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jimmy</forename><surname>Lin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>abs/1712.01969</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
			<publisher>CoRR</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Glove: Global vectors for word representation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jeffrey</forename><surname>Pennington</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Richard</forename><surname>Socher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christopher</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Manning</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">EMNLP</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">On the convergence of adam and beyond</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Sashank</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Satyen</forename><surname>Reddi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sanjiv</forename><surname>Kale</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Kumar</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ICLR</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Don&apos;t decay the learning rate, increase the batch size</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Samuel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Pieter-Jan</forename><surname>Smith</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Kindermans</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Quoc</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Le</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>abs/1711.00489</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
			<publisher>CoRR</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ferhan</forename><surname>Türe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Oliver</forename><surname>Jojic</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Simple recurrent neural networks work! In EMNLP</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Question answering with character-level lstm encoders and model-based data augmentation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Runze</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chen-Di</forename><surname>Zhan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Zhen-Hua</forename><surname>Ling</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">CCL</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Semantic parsing for single-relation question answering</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xiaodong</forename><surname>Wen-Tau Yih</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christopher</forename><surname>He</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Meek</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ACL</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Simple question answering by attentive convolutional neural network</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wenpeng</forename><surname>Yin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mo</forename><surname>Yu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bing</forename><surname>Xiang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bowen</forename><surname>Zhou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hinrich</forename><surname>Schütze</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<editor>COLING</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Improved neural relation detection for knowledge base question answering</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mo</forename><surname>Yu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wenpeng</forename><surname>Yin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kazi</forename><surname>Saidul Hasan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Cícero</forename><surname>Nogueira</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bing</forename><surname>Santos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bowen</forename><surname>Xiang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Zhou</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ACL</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
