<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T12:41+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Adaptive Semi-supervised Learning for Cross-domain Sentiment Classification</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date>October 31-November 4, 2018</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ruidan</forename><surname>He</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">National University of Singapore ‡ SAP Innovation Center</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="SG">Singapore</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wee</forename><forename type="middle">Sun</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">National University of Singapore ‡ SAP Innovation Center</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="SG">Singapore</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hwee</forename><forename type="middle">Tou</forename><surname>Ng</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">National University of Singapore ‡ SAP Innovation Center</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="SG">Singapore</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Daniel</forename><surname>Dahlmeier</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">National University of Singapore ‡ SAP Innovation Center</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="SG">Singapore</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Adaptive Semi-supervised Learning for Cross-domain Sentiment Classification</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2018 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</title>
						<meeting>the 2018 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing <address><addrLine>Brussels; Belgium</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="3467" to="3476"/>
							<date type="published">October 31-November 4, 2018</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<note>3467</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>We consider the cross-domain sentiment classification problem, where a sentiment classi-fier is to be learned from a source domain and to be generalized to a target domain. Our approach explicitly minimizes the distance between the source and the target instances in an embedded feature space. With the difference between source and target minimized, we then exploit additional information from the target domain by consolidating the idea of semi-supervised learning, for which, we jointly employ two regularizations-entropy minimization and self-ensemble bootstrapping-to incorporate the unlabeled target data for classifier refinement. Our experimental results demonstrate that the proposed approach can better leverage unlabeled data from the target domain and achieve substantial improvements over baseline methods in various experimental settings.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>In practice, it is often difficult and costly to anno- tate sufficient training data for diverse application domains on-the-fly. We may have sufficient la- beled data in an existing domain (called the source domain), but very few or no labeled data in a new domain (called the target domain). This issue has motivated research on cross-domain sentiment classification, where knowledge in the source do- main is transferred to the target domain in order to alleviate the required labeling effort.</p><p>One key challenge of domain adaptation is that data in the source and target domains are drawn from different distributions. Thus, adaptation per- formance will decline with an increase in distribu- tion difference. Specifically, in sentiment analy- sis, reviews of different products have different vo- cabulary. For instance, restaurants reviews would contain opinion words such as "tender", "tasty", or "undercooked" and movie reviews would contain "thrilling", "horrific", or "hilarious". The intersec- tion between these two sets of opinion words could be small which makes domain adaptation difficult.</p><p>Several techniques have been proposed for ad- dressing the problem of domain shifting. The aim is to bridge the source and target domains by learning domain-invariant feature representa- tions so that a classifier trained on a source do- main can be adapted to another target domain. In cross-domain sentiment classification, many works ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Blitzer et al., 2007;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b18">Pan et al., 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b27">Zhou et al., 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b23">Wu and Huang, 2016;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b26">Yu and Jiang, 2016</ref>) utilize a key intuition that domain-specific features could be aligned with the help of domain- invariant features (pivot features). For instance, "hilarious" and "tasty" could be aligned as both of them are relevant to "good".</p><p>Despite their promising results, these works share two major limitations. First, they highly de- pend on the heuristic selection of pivot features, which may be sensitive to different applications. Thus the learned new representations may not ef- fectively reduce the domain difference. Further- more, these works only utilize the unlabeled tar- get data for representation learning while the sen- timent classifier was solely trained on the source domain. There have not been many studies on ex- ploiting unlabeled target data for refining the clas- sifier, even though it may contain beneficial infor- mation. How to effectively leverage unlabeled tar- get data still remains an important challenge for domain adaptation.</p><p>In this work, we argue that the information from unlabeled target data is beneficial for do- main adaptation and we propose a novel Domain Adaptive Semi-supervised learning framework (DAS) to better exploit it. Our main intuition is to treat the problem as a semi-supervised learn- ing task by considering target instances as unla-beled data, assuming the domain distance can be effectively reduced through domain-invariant rep- resentation learning. Specifically, the proposed approach jointly performs feature adaptation and semi-supervised learning in a multi-task learning setting. For feature adaptation, it explicitly mini- mizes the distance between the encoded represen- tations of the two domains. On this basis, two semi-supervised regularizations -entropy mini- mization and self-ensemble bootstrapping -are jointly employed to exploit unlabeled target data for classifier refinement.</p><p>We evaluate our method rigorously under multi- ple experimental settings by taking label distribu- tion and corpus size into consideration. The re- sults show that our model is able to obtain sig- nificant improvements over strong baselines. We also demonstrate through a series of analysis that the proposed method benefits greatly from incor- porating unlabeled target data via semi-supervised learning, which is consistent with our motivation. Our datasets and source code can be obtained from https://github.com/ruidan/DAS.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Related Work</head><p>Domain Adaptation: The majority of feature adaptation methods for sentiment analysis rely on a key intuition that even though certain opinion words are completely distinct for each domain, they can be aligned if they have high correlation with some domain-invariant opinion words (pivot words) such as "excellent" or "terrible". <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Blitzer et al. (2007)</ref> proposed a method based on struc- tural correspondence learning (SCL), which uses pivot feature prediction to induce a projected fea- ture space that works well for both the source and the target domains. The pivot words are selected in a way to cover common domain-invariant opinion words. Subsequent research aims to better align the domain-specific words ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">Pan et al., 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b9">He et al., 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b23">Wu and Huang, 2016)</ref> such that the domain discrepancy could be reduced. More re- cently, <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">Yu and Jiang (2016)</ref> borrow the idea of pivot feature prediction from SCL and extend it to a neural network-based solution with auxiliary tasks. In their experiment, substantial improve- ment over SCL has been observed due to the use of real-valued word embeddings. Unsupervised representation learning with deep neural networks (DNN) such as denoising autoencoders has also been explored for feature adaptation <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Glorot et al., 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Chen et al., 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b25">Yang and Eisenstein, 2014)</ref>. It has been shown that DNNs could learn transferable representations that disentangle the underlying factors of variation behind data sam- ples.</p><p>Although the aforementioned methods aim to reduce the domain discrepancy, they do not explic- itly minimize the distance between distributions, and some of them highly rely on the selection of pivot features. In our method, we formally con- struct an objective for this purpose. Similar ideas have been explored in many computer vision prob- lems, where the representations of the underlying domains are encouraged to be similar through ex- plicit objectives ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">Tzeng et al., 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Ganin and Lempitsky, 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Long et al., 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b29">Zhuang et al., 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Long et al., 2017</ref>) such as maximum mean discrepancy (MMD) ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Gretton et al., 2012)</ref>. In NLP tasks, <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Li et al. (2017)</ref> and <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Chen et al. (2017)</ref> both proposed using adversarial training framework for reducing domain difference. In their model, a sub- network is added as a domain discriminator while deep features are learned to confuse the discrim- inator. The feature adaptation component in our model shares similar intuition with MMD and ad- versary training. We will show a detailed compar- ison with them in our experiments. Semi-supervised Learning: We attempt to treat domain adaptation as a semi-supervised learning task by considering the target instances as unla- beled data. Some efforts have been initiated on transfer learning from unlabeled data <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Dai et al., 2007;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Jiang and Zhai, 2007;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Wu et al., 2009</ref>). In our model, we reduce the domain discrep- ancy by feature adaptation, and thereafter adopt semi-supervised learning techniques to learn from unlabeled data. Primarily motivated by <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Grandvalet and Bengio, 2004)</ref> and <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Laine and Aila, 2017)</ref>, we employed entropy minimization and self-ensemble bootstrapping as regularizations to incorporate unlabeled data. Our experimental re- sults show that both methods are effective when jointly trained with the feature adaptation objec- tive, which confirms to our motivation.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Model Description</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Notations and Model Overview</head><p>We conduct most of our experiments under an un- supervised domain adaptation setting, where we have no labeled data from the target domain. Con- sider two sets D s and</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">D t . D s = {x (s) i , y (s) i }| ns i=1 is</formula><p>from the source domain with n s labeled examples, where y i 2 R C is a one-hot vector representation of sentiment label and C denotes the number of classes.</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">D t = {x (t) i }| nt i=1</formula><p>is from the target domain with n t unlabeled examples. N = n s + n t denotes the total number of training documents including both labeled and unlabeled 1 . We aim to learn a sentiment classifier from D s and D t such that the classifier would work well on the target domain. We also present some results under a setting where we assume that a small number of labeled target examples are available (see <ref type="figure">Figure 3)</ref>.</p><p>For the proposed model, we denote G parame- terized by ✓ g as a neural-based feature encoder that maps documents from both domains to a shared feature space, and F parameterized by ✓ f as a fully connected layer with softmax activation serv- ing as the sentiment classifier. We aim to learn fea- ture representations that are domain-invariant and at the same time discriminative on both domains, thus we simultaneously consider three factors in our objective: (1) minimize the classification error on the labeled source examples; (2) minimize the domain discrepancy; and (3) leverage unlabeled data via semi-supervised learning.</p><p>Suppose we already have the encoded features of documents {⇠</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">(s,t) i = G(x (s,t) i ; ✓ g )}| N i=1</formula><p>(see Section 4.1), the objective function for purpose (1) is thus the cross entropy loss on the labeled source examples</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">L = 1 n s ns X i=1 C X j=1 y (s) i (j) log˜ylog˜ log˜y (s) i (j) (1)</formula><p>where˜ywhere˜ where˜y</p><formula xml:id="formula_4">(s) i = F(⇠ (s)</formula><p>i ; ✓ f ) denotes the predicted la- bel distribution. In the following subsections, we will explain how to perform feature adaptation and domain adaptive semi-supervised learning in de- tails for purpose (2) and (3) respectively.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Feature Adaptation</head><p>Unlike prior works ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Blitzer et al., 2007;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b26">Yu and Jiang, 2016)</ref>, our method does not attempt to align domain-specific words through pivot words. In our preliminary experiments, we found that word embeddings pre-trained on a large corpus are able to adequately capture this information. As we will later show in our experiments, even without adap- tation, a naive neural network classifier with pre- trained word embeddings can already achieve rea- sonably good results.</p><p>We attempt to explicitly minimize the distance between the source and target feature represen- tations ({⇠</p><formula xml:id="formula_5">(s) i }| ns i=1 and {⇠ (t) i } nt i=1</formula><p>). A few meth- ods from literature can be applied such as Maxi- mum Mean Discrepancy (MMD) ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Gretton et al., 2012</ref>) or adversary training ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Li et al., 2017;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Chen et al., 2017</ref>). The main idea of MMD is to esti- mate the distance between two distributions as the distance between sample means of the projected embeddings in Hilbert space. MMD is implicitly computed through a characteristic kernel, which is used to ensure that the sample mean is injective, leading to the MMD being zero if and only if the distributions are identical. In our implementation, we skip the mapping procedure induced by a char- acteristic kernel for simplifying the computation and learning. We simply estimate the distribution distance as the distance between the sample means in the current embedding space. Although this ap- proximation cannot preserve all statistical features of the underlying distributions, we find it performs comparably to MMD on our problem. The follow- ing equations formally describe the feature adap- tation loss J :</p><formula xml:id="formula_6">J = KL(g s ||g t ) + KL(g t ||g s ) (2) g 0 s = 1 n s ns X i=1 ⇠ (s) i , g s = g 0 s kg 0 s k 1 (3) g 0 t = 1 n t nt X i=1 ⇠ (t) i , g t = g 0 t kg 0 t k 1 (4)</formula><p>L 1 normalization is applied on the mean represen- tations g 0 s and g 0 t , rescaling the vectors such that all entries sum to 1. We adopt a symmetric ver- sion of KL divergence ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">Zhuang et al., 2015</ref>) as the distance function. Given two distribution vectors</p><formula xml:id="formula_7">P, Q 2 R k , KL(P||Q) = P k i=1 P(i) log( P(i) Q(i) ).</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3">Domain Adaptive Semi-supervised Learning (DAS)</head><p>We attempt to exploit the information in target data through semi-supervised learning objectives, which are jointly trained with L and J . Normally, to incorporate target data, we can minimize the cross entropy loss between the true label distri- butions y (t) i and the predicted label distributions</p><formula xml:id="formula_8">3470˜y 3470˜ 3470˜y (t) i = F(⇠ (t)</formula><p>i ; ✓ f ) over target samples. The chal- lenge here is that y (t) i is unknown, and thus we attempt to estimate it via semi-supervised learn- ing. We use entropy minimization and bootstrap- ping for this purpose. We will later show in our experiments that both methods are effective, and jointly employing them overall yields the best re- sults. Entropy Minimization: In this method, y (t) i is estimated as the predicted label distributioñ y</p><p>i , which is a function of ✓ g and ✓ f . The loss can thus be written as</p><formula xml:id="formula_10">= 1 n t nt X i=1 C X j=1˜y j=1˜ j=1˜y (t) i (j) log˜ylog˜ log˜y (t) i (j)<label>(5)</label></formula><p>Assume the domain discrepancy can be effectively reduced through feature adaptation, by minimiz- ing the entropy penalty, training of the classifier is influenced by the unlabeled target data and will generally maximize the margins between the tar- get examples and the decision boundaries, increas- ing the prediction confidence on the target domain.</p><p>Self-ensemble Bootstrapping: Another way to estimate y (t) i corresponds to bootstrapping. The idea is to estimate the unknown labels as the predictions of the model learned from the pre- vious round of training.</p><p>Bootstrapping has been explored for domain adaptation in previous works <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Jiang and Zhai, 2007;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Wu et al., 2009</ref>). However, in their methods, domain discrepancy was not explicitly minimized via feature adap- tation. Applying bootstrapping or other semi- supervised learning techniques in this case may worsen the results as the classifier can perform quite bad on the target data.</p><p>Inspired by the ensembling method proposed in (Laine and Aila, 2017), we estimate y (t) i by forming ensemble predictions of labels during training, using the outputs on different training epochs. The loss is formulated as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_11">⌦ = 1 N N X i=1 C X j=1˜z j=1˜ j=1˜z (s,t) i (j) log˜ylog˜ log˜y (s,t) i (j)<label>(6)</label></formula><p>where˜zwhere˜ where˜z denotes the estimated labels computed on the ensemble predictions from different epochs.</p><p>The loss is applied on all documents. It serves for bootstrapping on the unlabeled target data, and it also serves as a regularization that encourages</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Algorithm 1 Pseudocode for training DAS</head><formula xml:id="formula_12">Require: D s , D t , G, F Require: ↵ = ensembling momentum, 0  ↵ &lt; 1 Require: w(t) = weight ramp-up function Z 0 [N ⇥C] ˜ z 0 [N ⇥C] for t 2 [1, max-epochs] do for each minibatch B (s) , B (t) , B (u) in D s , D t , {x (s,t) i }| N i=1 do compute loss L on [x i2B (s) , y i2B (s) ] compute loss J on [x i2B (s) , x j2B (t) ] compute loss on x i2B (t) compute loss ⌦ on [x i2B (u) , ˜ z i2B (u) ] overall-loss L + 1 J + 2 + w(t)⌦ update network parameters end for Z 0 i F(G(x i )), for i 2 N Z ↵Z + (1 ↵)Z 0 ˜ z one-hot-vectors(Z) end for</formula><p>the network predictions to be consistent in differ- ent training epochs. ⌦ is jointly trained with L, J , and . Algorithm 1 illustrates the overall train- ing process of the proposed domain adaptive semi- supervised learning (DAS) framework.</p><p>In Algorithm 1, 1 , 2 , and w(t) are weights to balance the effects of J , , and ⌦ respectively.</p><p>1 and 2 are constant hyper-parameters. We set w(t) = exp[5(1 t max-epochs ) 2 ] 3 as a Gaus- sian curve to ramp up the weight from 0 to 3 . This is to ensure the ramp-up of the bootstrapping loss component is slow enough in the beginning of the training. After each training epoch, we com- pute Z 0 i which denotes the predictions made by the network in current epoch, and then the ensemble prediction Z i is updated as a weighted average of the outputs from previous epochs and the current epoch, with recent epochs having larger weight. For generating estimated labels˜zlabels˜ labels˜z i , Z i is converted to a one-hot vector where the entry with the maxi- mum value is set to one and other entries are set to zeros. The self-ensemble bootstrapping is a gener- alized version of bootstrappings that only use the outputs from the previous round of training <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Jiang and Zhai, 2007;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Wu et al., 2009</ref>). The ensemble prediction is likely to be closer to the correct, un- known labels of the target data. <ref type="table">Book  Set 1 2000 2000 2000 6000  Set 2 4824  513  663 6000  Electronics Set 1 2000 2000 2000 6000  Set 2 4817  694  489 6000  Beauty  Set 1 2000 2000 2000 6000  Set 2 4709  616  675 6000  Music  Set 1 2000 2000 2000 6000  Set 2 4441  785  774</ref>  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Domain #Pos #Neg #Neu Total</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Experiments</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">CNN Encoder Implementation</head><p>We have left the feature encoder G unspecified, for which, a few options can be considered. In our implementation, we adopt a one-layer CNN structure from previous works <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(Kim, 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b26">Yu and Jiang, 2016)</ref>, as it has been demonstrated to work well for sentiment classification tasks. Given a re- view document x = (x 1 , x 2 , ..., x n ) consisting of n words, we begin by associating each word with a continuous word embedding ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Mikolov et al., 2013</ref>) e x from an embedding matrix E 2 R V ⇥d , where V is the vocabulary size and d is the embed- ding dimension. E is jointly updated with other network parameters during training. Given a win- dow of dense word embeddings e x 1 , e x 2 , ..., e x l , the convolution layer first concatenates these vec- tors to form a vectorˆxvectorˆ vectorˆx of length ld and then the output vector is computed by Equation <ref type="formula" target="#formula_13">(7)</ref>:</p><formula xml:id="formula_13">Conv(ˆ x) = f (W · ˆ x + b)<label>(7)</label></formula><p>✓ g = {W, b} is the parameter set of the en- coder G and is shared across all windows of the sequence. f is an element-wise non-linear activa- tion function. The convolution operation can cap- ture local contextual dependencies of the input se- quence and the extracted feature vectors are sim- ilar to n-grams. After the convolution operation is applied to the whole sequence, we obtain a list of hidden vectors H = (h 1 , h 2 , ..., h n ). A max- over-time pooling layer is applied to obtain the fi- nal vector representation ⇠ of the input document.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">Datasets and Experimental Settings</head><p>Existing benchmark datasets such as the Amazon benchmark ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Blitzer et al., 2007</ref>) typically remove reviews with neutral labels in both domains. This is problematic as the label information of the tar- get domain is not accessible in an unsupervised domain adaptation setting. Furthermore, remov- ing neutral instances may bias the dataset favor- ably for max-margin-based algorithms like ours, since the resulting dataset has all uncertain labels removed, leaving only high confidence examples. Therefore, we construct new datasets by ourselves.</p><p>The results on the original Amazon benchmark is qualitatively similar, and we present them in Ap- pendix A for completeness since most of previous works reported results on it. Small-scale datasets: Our new dataset was de- rived from the large-scale Amazon datasets 2 re- leased by <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">McAuley et al. (2015)</ref></p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>. It contains four domains 3 : Book (BK), Electronics (E), Beauty (BT), and Music (M). Each domain contains two datasets. Set 1 contains 6000 instances with ex- actly balanced class labels, and set 2 contains</head><p>6000 instances that are randomly sampled from the large dataset, preserving the original label dis- tribution, which we believe better reflects the label distribution in real life. The examples in these two sets do not overlap. Detailed statistics of the gen- erated datasets are given in <ref type="table">Table 1a</ref>.</p><p>In all our experiments on the small-scale datasets, we use set 1 of the source domain as the only source with sentiment label information dur- ing training, and we evaluate the trained model on set 1 of the target domain. Since we cannot con- trol the label distribution of unlabeled data during training, we consider two different settings:</p><p>Setting (1): Only set 1 of the target domain is used as the unlabeled set. This tells us how the method performs in a condition when the target domain has a close-to-balanced label distribution. As we also evaluate on set 1 of the target domain, this is also considered as a transductive setting.</p><p>Setting (2): Set 2 from both the source and target domains are used as unlabeled sets. Since set 2 is directly sampled from millions of reviews, it better reflects real-life sentiment distribution. Large-scale datasets: We further conduct ex- periments on four much larger datasets: IMDB <ref type="bibr">4</ref> (I), Yelp2014 (Y), Cell Phone (C), and Baby (B). IMDB and Yelp2014 were previously used in ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Tang et al., 2015;</ref>. Cell phone and Baby are from the large-scale Amazon dataset <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(McAuley et al., 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">He and McAuley, 2016)</ref>. Detailed statistics are summarized in Ta- ble 1b. We keep all reviews in the original datasets and consider a transductive setting where all target examples are used for both training (without la- bel information) and evaluation. We perform sam- pling to balance the classes of labeled source data in each minibatch B (s) during training.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3">Selection of Development Set</head><p>Ideally, the development set should be drawn from the same distribution as the test set. However, un- der the unsupervised domain adaptation setting, we do not have any labeled target data at training phase which could be used as development set. In all of our experiments, for each pair of domains, we instead sample 1000 examples from the train- ing set of the source domain as development set. We train the network for a fixed number of epochs, and the model with the minimum classification er- ror on this development set is saved for evaluation. This approach works well on most of the problems since the target domain is supposed to behave like the source domain if the domain difference is ef- fectively reduced.</p><p>Another problem is how to select the values for hyper-parameters. If we tune 1 and 2 directly on the development set from the source domain, most likely both of them will be set to 0, as un- labeled target data is not helpful for improving in- domain accuracy of the source domain. Other neu- ral network models also have the same problem for hyper-parameter tuning. Therefore, our strategy is to use the development set from the target domain to optimize 1 and 2 for one problem (e.g., we only do this on E!BK), and fix their values on the other problems. This setting assumes that we have at least two labeled domains such that we can op- timize the hyper-parameters, and then we fix them for other new unlabeled domains to transfer to.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.4">Training Details and Hyper-parameters</head><p>We initialize word embeddings using the 300- dimension GloVe vectors supplied by <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">Pennington et al., (2014)</ref>, which were trained on 840 billion tokens from the Common Crawl. For each pair of domains, the vocabulary consists of the top 10000 most frequent words. For words in the vocabulary but not present in the pre-trained embeddings, we randomly initialize them.</p><p>We set hyper-parameters of the CNN en- coder following previous works <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(Kim, 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b26">Yu and Jiang, 2016</ref>) without specific tuning on our datasets. The window size is set to 3 and the size of the hidden layer is set to 300. The nonlinear activation function is Relu. For regularization, we also follow their settings and employ dropout with probability set to 0.5 on ⇠ i before feeding it to the output layer F, and constrain the l 2 -norm of the weight vector ✓ f , setting its max norm to 3.</p><p>On the small-scale datasets and the Aamzon benchmark, 1 and 2 are set to 200 and 1, respectively, tuned on the development set of task E!BK under setting 1. On the large-scale datasets, 1 and 2 are set to 500 and 0.2, re- spectively, tuned on I!Y. We use a Gaussian curve w(t) = exp[5(1 t tmax ) 2 ] 3 to ramp up the weight of the bootstrapping loss ⌦ from 0 to 3 , where t max denotes the maximum number of training epochs. We train 30 epochs for all exper- iments. We set 3 to 3 and ↵ to 0.5 for all experi- ments.</p><p>The batch size is set to 50 on the small-scale datasets and the Amazon benchmark. We increase the batch size to 250 on the large-scale datasets to reduce the number of iterations. RMSProp opti- mizer with learning rate set to 0.0005 is used for all experiments.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.5">Models for Comparison</head><p>We compare with the following baselines:</p><p>(1) Naive: A non-domain-adaptive baseline with bag-of-words representations and SVM clas- sifier trained on the source domain.</p><p>(2) mSDA (Chen et al., 2012): This is the state- of-the-art method based on discrete input features. Top 1000 bag-of-words features are kept as pivot features. We set the number of stacked layers to 3 and the corruption probability to 0.5.</p><p>(3) NaiveNN: This is a non-domain-adaptive CNN trained on source domain, which is a variant of our model by setting 1 , 2 , and 3 to zeros.</p><p>(4) AuxNN (Yu and Jiang, 2016): This is a neu- ral model that exploits auxiliary tasks, which has achieved state-of-the-art results on cross-domain sentiment classification. The sentence encoder used in this model is the same as ours.    tion difference between domains. The original pa- per uses a simple feedforward network as encoder. For fair comparison, we replace it with our CNN- based encoder. We train 5 iterations on the dis- criminator per iteration on the encoder and senti- ment classifier as suggested in their paper.</p><p>(6) MMD: MMD has been widely used for min- imizing domain discrepancy on images. In those works ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">Tzeng et al., 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Long et al., 2017)</ref>, vari- ants of deep CNNs are used for encoding images and the MMDs of multiple layers are jointly mini- mized. In NLP, adding more layers of CNNs may not be very helpful and thus those models from image-related tasks can not be directly applied to our problem. To compare with MMD-based method, we train a model that jointly minimize the classification loss L on the source domain and MMD between {⇠ (s)</p><formula xml:id="formula_14">i | ns i=1 } and {⇠ (t) i | nt i=1 }.</formula><p>For computing MMD, we use a Gaussian RBF which is a common choice for characteristic kernel.</p><p>In addition to the above baselines, we also show results of different variants of our model. DAS as shown in Algorithm 1 denotes our full model. DAS-EM denotes the model with only entropy minimization for semi-supervised learning (set 3 = 0). DAS-SE denotes the model with only self-ensemble bootstrapping for semi-supervised learning (set 2 = 0). FANN (feature-adaptation neural network) denotes the model without semi- supervised learning performed (set both 2 and 3 to zeros). posed domain adaptive semi-supervised learning framework. DAS-EM is more effective than DAS- SE in most cases, and the full model DAS with both techniques jointly employed overall has the best performance. (2) When comparing the two settings on the small-scale dataset, all domain- adaptive methods 6 generally perform better under setting 1. In setting 1, the target examples are bal- anced in classes, which can provide more diverse opinion-related features. However, when consid- ering unsupervised domain adaptation, we should not presume the label distribution of the unlabeled data. Thus, it is necessary to conduct experiments using datasets that reflect real-life sentiment dis- tribution as what we did on setting2 and the large- scale dataset. Unfortunately, this is ignored by most of previous works. (3) Word-embeddings are very helpful, as we can see even NaiveNN can sub- stantially outperform mSDA on most tasks. To see the effect of semi-supervised learning alone, we also conduct experiments by setting 1 = 0 to eliminate the effect of feature adapta- tion. Both entropy minimization and bootstrap- ping perform very badly in this setting. En- tropy minimization gives almost random predic- tions with accuracy below 0.4, and the results of bootstrapping are also much lower compared to NaiveNN. This suggests that the feature adap- tation component is essential. Without it, the learned target representations are less meaning- ful and discriminative. Applying semi-supervised <ref type="bibr">6</ref> Results of Naive and NaiveNN do not change under both settings as they are only trained on the source domain. learning in this case is likely to worsen the results.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.6">Main Results</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.7">Further Analysis</head><p>In <ref type="figure">Figure 2</ref>, we show the change of accuracy with respect to the percentage of unlabeled data used for training on three particular problems under set- ting 1. The value at x = 0 denotes the accuracies of NaiveNN which does not utilize any target data. For DAS, we observe a nonlinear increasing trend where the accuracy quickly improves at the be- ginning, and then gradually stabilizes. For other methods, this trend is less obvious, and adding more unlabeled data sometimes even worsen the results. This finding again suggests that the pro- posed approach can better exploit the information from unlabeled data.</p><p>We also conduct experiments under a setting with a small number of labeled target examples available. <ref type="figure">Figure 3</ref> shows the change of accuracy with respect to the number of labeled target exam- ples added for training. We can observe that DAS is still more effective under this setting, while the performance differences to other methods gradu- ally decrease with the increasing number of la- beled target examples.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.8">CNN Filter Analysis</head><p>In this subsection, we aim to better understand DAS by analyzing sentiment-related CNN filters. To do that, 1) we first select a list of the most re- lated CNN filters for predicting each sentiment la- bel (positive, negative neutral). Those filters can be identified according to the learned weights ✓ f of the output layer F. Higher weight indicates stronger relatedness. 2) Recall that in our im- plementation, each CNN filter has a window size of 3 with Relu activation. We can thus represent each selected filter as a ranked list of trigrams with highest activation values.</p><p>We analyze the CNN filters learned by NaiveNN, FANN and DAS respectively on task E!BT under setting 1. We focus on E!BT for study because electronics and beauty are very dif- ferent domains and each of them has a diverse set of domain-specific sentiment expressions. For each method, we identify the top 10 most related filters for each sentiment label, and extract the top trigrams of each selected filter on both source and target domains. Since labeled source examples are used for training, we find the filters learned by the three methods capture similar expressions on the source domain, containing both domain-invariant and domain-specific trigrams. On the target do- main, DAS captures more target-specific expres- sions compared to the other two methods. Due to space limitation, we only present a small sub- set of positive-sentiment-related filters in <ref type="table">Table 2</ref>. The complete results are provided in Appendix C. From <ref type="table">Table 2</ref>, we can observe that the filters learned by NaiveNN are almost unable to cap- ture target-specific sentiment expressions, while FANN is able to capture limited target-specific words such as "clean" and "scent". The filters learned by DAS are more domain-adaptive, cap- turing diverse sentiment expressions in the target domain.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Conclusion</head><p>In this work, we propose DAS, a novel frame- work that jointly performs feature adaptation and semi-supervised learning. We have demonstrated through multiple experiments that DAS can better leverage unlabeled data, and achieve substantial improvements over baseline methods. We have also shown that feature adaptation is an essen- tial component, without which, semi-supervised learning is not able to function properly. The pro- posed framework could be potentially adapted to other domain adaptation tasks, which is the focus of our future studies.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>( 5 )</head><label>5</label><figDesc>ADAN (Chen et al., 2017): This method exploits adversarial training to reduce representa-</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>(b) Accuracy on the small-scale dataset under setting 2.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>DAS-SE Ours: DAS-EM Ours: DAS Macro-F1 (%) (c) Macro-F1 on the large-scale dataset.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: Performance comparison. Average results over 5 runs with random initializations are reported for each neural method. ⇤ indicates that the proposed method (either of DAS, DAS-EM, DAS-SE) is significantly better than other baselines (baseline 1-6) with p &lt; 0.05 based on one-tailed unpaired t-test.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head>Figure 1 5Figure 2 :Figure 3 :</head><label>123</label><figDesc>Figure 1 5 shows the comparison of adaptation results (see Appendix B for the exact numerical numbers). We report classification accuracy on the small-scale dataset. For the large-scale dataset, macro-F1 is instead used since the label distribution in the test set is extremely unbalanced. Key observations are summarized as follows. (1) Both DAS-EM and DAS-SE perform better in most cases compared with ADAN, MDD, and FANN, in which only feature adaptation is performed. This demonstrates the effectiveness of the pro</figDesc></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> Note that unlabeled source examples can also be included for training. In that case, N = ns + nt + n s 0 where n s 0 denotes the number of unlabeled source examples. This corresponds to our experimental setting 2. For simplicity, we only consider ns and nt in our description.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="2"> http://jmcauley.ucsd.edu/data/amazon/ 3 The original reviews were rated on a 5-point scale. We label them with rating &lt; 3, &gt; 3, and = 3 as negative, positive, and neutral respectively. 4 IMDB is rated on a 10-point scale, and we label reviews with rating &lt; 5, &gt; 6, and = 5/6 as negative, positive, and neutral respectively.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="5"> We exclude results of Naive, mSDA and AuxNN on the large-scale dataset. Both Naive and mSDA have difficulties to scale up to the large dataset. AuxNN relies on manually selecting positive and negative pivots before training.</note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="annex">
			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Biographies, Bollywood, boom-boxes and blenders: domain adaptation for sentiment classification</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">John</forename><surname>Blitzer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mark</forename><surname>Dredze</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Fernando</forename><surname>Pereira</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Marginalized denoising autoencoders for domain adaptation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Minmin</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Zhixiang</forename><surname>Xu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kilian</forename><forename type="middle">Q</forename><surname>Weinberger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Fei</forename><surname>Sha</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">The 29th International Conference on Machine Learning</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Adversarial deep averaging networks for cross-lingual sentiment classifier</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xilun</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yu</forename><surname>Sun</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ben</forename><surname>Athiwarakun</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Claire</forename><surname>Cardie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kilian</forename><surname>Weinberger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:1606.01614</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Transferring naive Bayes classifiers for text classification</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wenyuan</forename><surname>Dai</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gui</forename><surname>Rong Xue</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Qiang</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yong</forename><surname>Yu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Unsupervised domain adaptation by backpropagation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yaroslav</forename><surname>Ganin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Victor</forename><surname>Lempitsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">International Conference on Machine Learning</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Domain adaptation for large-scale sentiment classification: a deep learning approach</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xavier</forename><surname>Glorot</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Antoine</forename><surname>Bordes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yoshua</forename><surname>Bengio</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">The 28th International Conference on Machine Learning</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Semisupervised learning by entropy minimization</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yves</forename><surname>Grandvalet</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yoshua</forename><surname>Bengio</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Neural Information Processing Systems</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A kernel two-sample test</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Arthur</forename><surname>Gretton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Karsten</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Borgwardt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Malte</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Rasch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bernhard</forename><surname>Schölkopf</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alexander</forename><surname>Smola</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Machine Learning Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="723" to="773" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Ups and downs: modeling the visual evolution of fashion trends with one-class collaborative filtering</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ruining</forename><surname>He</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Julian</forename><surname>Mcauley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
			<publisher>WWW</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Automatically extracting polarity-bearing topics for cross-domain sentiment classification</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yulan</forename><surname>He</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chenghua</forename><surname>Lin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Harith</forename><surname>Alani</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ACL</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Instance weighting for domain adaptation in NLP</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jing</forename><surname>Jiang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chengxiang</forename><surname>Zhai</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Convolutional neural networks for sentence classification</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yoon</forename><surname>Kim</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Temporal ensembling for semi-supervised learning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Samuli</forename><surname>Laine</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Timo</forename><surname>Aila</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">International Conference on Learning Representation</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">End-to-end adversarial memory network for cross-domain sentiment classification</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Zheng</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yun</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ying</forename><surname>Wei</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yuxiang</forename><surname>Wu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Qiang</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">The 26th International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Learning transferable features with deep adaptation networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mingsheng</forename><surname>Long</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yue</forename><surname>Cao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jianmin</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michael</forename><forename type="middle">I</forename><surname>Jordan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">International Conference on Machine Learning</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Deep transfer learning with joint adaptation networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mingsheng</forename><surname>Long</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Han</forename><surname>Zhu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jianmin</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michael</forename><forename type="middle">I</forename><surname>Jordan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">International Conference on Machine Learning</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Image-based recommendations on styles and substitutes</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Julian</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Mcauley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christopher</forename><surname>Targett</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">The 38th International ACM SIGIR Conference on Research and Development in Information Retrieval</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Qinfeng Shi, and Anton van den Hengel</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Distributed representations of words and phrases and their compositionality</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tomas</forename><surname>Mikolov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ilya</forename><surname>Sutskever</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kai</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Greg</forename><surname>Corrado</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jeffrey</forename><surname>Dean</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Neural Information Processing Systems</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Cross-domain sentiment classification via spectral feature alignment</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xiaochuan</forename><surname>Sinno Jialin Pan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jian-Tao</forename><surname>Ni</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Qiang</forename><surname>Sun</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Zheng</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">The 19th International World Wide Web Conference</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">GloVe: Global vectors for word representation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jeffrey</forename><surname>Pennington</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Richard</forename><surname>Socher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christopher D</forename><surname>Manning</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Learning semantic representation of users and products for document level sentiment classification</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Duyu</forename><surname>Tang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bing</forename><surname>Qin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ting</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Deep domain confusion: maximizing for domain invariance</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Eric</forename><surname>Tzeng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Judy</forename><surname>Hoffman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ning</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kate</forename><surname>Saenko</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Trevor</forename><surname>Darrell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:1412.3474</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Domain adaptive bootstrapping for named entity recognition</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dan</forename><surname>Wu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nan</forename><surname>Wee Sun Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hai</forename><forename type="middle">Leong</forename><surname>Ye</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Chieu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Sentiment domain adaptation with multiple sources</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Fangzhao</forename><surname>Wu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yongfeng</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A simple regularization-based algorithm for learning cross-domain word embeddings</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wei</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wei</forename><surname>Lu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Vincent</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Zheng</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Fast easy unsupervised domain adaptation with marginalized structured dropout</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yi</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jacob</forename><surname>Eisenstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Learning sentence embeddings with auxiliary tasks for cross-domain sentiment classification</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jianfei</forename><surname>Yu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jing</forename><surname>Jiang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Linking heterogeneous input features with pivots for domain adaptation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Guangyou</forename><surname>Zhou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tingting</forename><surname>He</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wensheng</forename><surname>Wu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xiaohua Tony</forename><surname>Hu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">The 24th International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Bi-transferring deep neural networks for domain adaptation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Guangyou</forename><surname>Zhou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Zhiwen</forename><surname>Xie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jimmy</forename><forename type="middle">Xiangji</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tingting</forename><surname>He</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Supervised representation learning: transfer learning with deep autoencoders</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Fuzhen</forename><surname>Zhuang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xiaohu</forename><surname>Cheng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ping</forename><surname>Luo</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">The 24th International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Sinno Jialin Pan, and Qing He</note>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
