<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T11:36+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">A State-transition Framework to Answer Complex Questions over Knowledge Base</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
				<availability status="unknown"><p>Copyright Association for Computational Linguistics</p>
				</availability>
				<date>October 31-November 4, 2018. 2018. 2098</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sen</forename><surname>Hu</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Peking University</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lei</forename><surname>Zou</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Peking University</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">Beijing Institute of Big Data Research</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xinbo</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Peking University</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">A State-transition Framework to Answer Complex Questions over Knowledge Base</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2018 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</title>
						<meeting>the 2018 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing <address><addrLine>Brussels, Belgium</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="2098" to="2108"/>
							<date type="published">October 31-November 4, 2018. 2018. 2098</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Although natural language question answering over knowledge graphs have been studied in the literature, existing methods have some limitations in answering complex questions. To address that, in this paper, we propose a State Transition-based approach to translate a complex natural language question N to a semantic query graph (SQG) Q S , which is used to match the underlying knowledge graph to find the answers to question N. In order to generate Q S , we propose four primitive operations (expand, fold, connect and merge) and a learning-based state transition approach. Extensive experiments on several benchmarks (such as QALD, WebQuestions and ComplexQuestions) with two knowledge bases (DBpedia and Freebase) confirm the superiority of our approach compared with state-of-the-arts.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Complex Question Answering, in which the ques- tion corresponds to multiple triples in knowledge base, has attracted researchers' attentions recently ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Bao et al., 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Xu et al., 2016;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Berant and Liang, 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Bast and Haussmann, 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b21">Yih et al., 2015)</ref>. However, most of existing solu- tions employ the predefined patterns or templates in understanding complex questions. For exam- ple, ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Bao et al., 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Xu et al., 2016</ref>) use de- pendency tree patterns to decompose a complex question to several simple questions. <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Berant and Liang, 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Bast and Haussmann, 2015</ref>) rely on templates to translate natural language sentences to predefined logical forms. Obviously, it is im- possible to cover all real-world cases using those handcrafted templates. The recent work STAGG ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">Yih et al., 2015)</ref> proposes a state transition strat- egy to tackle complex questions. However, the generated query graph's structure in STAGG is limited, as shown in <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref>. Generally, the struc- ture is formed by linking the topic entity e and the answer node t through a core relation. It only al- lows entity constraints (such as c) and one vari- able (the answer node t), the expressivity is quite limited. It cannot cover all types of complex ques- tions such as the question in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 2</ref>, whose query graph contains variable constraint (v 4 ) and multi- edges (between v 1 and v 4 ). Therefore, in this pa- per, we propose a more flexible strategy to answer complex questions without handcrafted templates or restricting the query graph's structure.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.1">Properties and Challenges of Complex Questions</head><p>We first analyze the inherent challenges for com- plex question answering, which has not been well studied in existing literatures. Multi or Implicit relations. A complex ques- tion has multiple relations and some relations may be multi-hop or implicit. Consider the question N 1 = "Which Russian astronauts died in the same place they were born in?". Obviously there are two explicit relations represented by the two phrases "died in" and "born in", but many tradi- tional methods only extract a single relation be- tween topic entity and the answer node. On the other hand, there is an implicit relation between "Russian" and "astronauts" (i.e., Nationality), which lacks a corresponding relation phrase. Multi or No entities. Different from simple (one- hop) questions that only contain a single topic en- tity in the question sentence N , complex questions may have multiple entities. For example, "Which Russian astronauts were died in Moscow and born in Soviet Union". There are three entities "Rus- sian", "Moscow" and "Soviet Union". In some cases, the question sentence does not include any entity, such as "Who died in the same place they were born in". Therefore, existing methods that e t c</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Topic Entity Answer Constraint</head><p>Figure 1: The query graph structure of STAGG. Node e is the "topic entity", path e-t is the "core inferential chain" and c represents "augmenting constraints". Notice we omit the CVT node as it is a virtual node only existed in Freebase.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Russia ?cosmonauts v 1 v 2 v 3</head><p>Which cosmonauts died in the same place they were born in? only care about a single topic entity cannot work for such types of complex questions.</p><p>Variables and Co-reference. Existing solutions assume that there is a single variable in the ques- tion N , i.e., the wh-word, which is focus of the question (representing the answer node). How- ever, complex questions may have other variables. Consider the question in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 2</ref>, there are four variables "Which", "cosmonauts", "place" and "they" recognized. While the three in yellow grid ("Which", "cosmonaut", "they") refer to the same thing, which is the co-reference phenomenon.</p><p>Composition. In the simple questions, the query graph's structure is determinate (one-hop edge). For complex questions, even when all entities, variables and relations are recognized, how to as- semble them to logical forms or executable queries (query graphs) is still a challenge. As mentioned earlier, existing solutions that depend on prede- fined templates (such as ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Xu et al., 2016;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Bast and Haussmann, 2015)</ref>) or query graph structure pat- terns (such as ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">Yih et al., 2015)</ref>) may not be suit- able due to the diversity of complex questions.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.2">Our Solution</head><p>Considering the above challenges, we propose a state transition based framework to translate users' question N into a semantic query graph (SQG) Q S , further the answers of N can be found by matching Q S over the knowledge graph G. Specifically, we first recognize nodes (such as en- tities and variables) from N as the initial state (Section 2.1). Then, to enable and speed up the state transition process, we propose four primitive operations with corresponding conditions (Section 2.2). The entity/relation candidates are extracted using existing entity linking algorithms and our proposed MCCNN model (Section 2.3). To guide the state transition, we learn a reward function us- ing SVM ranking algorithm (Section 3) to greedily select a subsequent state. Compared with existing solutions, our frame- work has stronger expressivity to solve more types of complex questions (considering the challenges introduced in Section 1.1) and does not rely on handcrafted templates.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Semantic Query Graph Generation</head><p>This section outlines the whole framework of our system. Given a natural language question N , we aim to translate N into a semantic query graph (SQG) (see Definition 1).</p><p>Definition 1 (Semantic Query Graph). A seman- tic query graph (denoted as Q S ) is a connected graph, in which each vertex v i corresponds a phrase in the question sentence N and associated with a list of entity/type/literal candidates; and each edge v i v j is associated with a list of relation candidates,</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">1 ≤ i, j ≤ |V (Q S )|.</formula><p>Given a question sentence N 1 = "Which cos- monauts died in the same place they were born in?", the corresponding semantic query graph Q S 1 is given in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 2</ref>. In Q S 1 , the subgraph {v 1 , v 2 and v 3 } corresponds "cosmonauts", v 4 corre- sponds "place". The relation phrases "born in" and "died in" denote two relations between v 1 and v 4 . Each edge in Q S has a list of relation(predicate) candidates with confidence probabilities. In this paper, we only draw one relation candidate of each edge for simplicity. Notice that the edge v 1 v 3 and v 1 v 2 have no relation phrases, however, they still have corresponding relation candidates nationality and type.</p><p>After obtaining semantic query graph Q S , we find matches of Q S over the underlying knowl- edge graph G to find answers to the original ques- tion N . This stage is identical to gAnswer ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Zou et al., 2014</ref>) and NFF ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Hu et al., 2018</ref>). Thus, in this paper, we concentrate ourselves on discussing how to generate semantic query graph Q S , which is different from NFF that relies on the paraphras- ing dictionaries and heuristic rules to build Q S .</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">Node Recognition</head><p>The first step is to detect the "nodes" (for build- ing SQG Q S ) in users' question sentences. Ac- cording to Definition 1, each node in the semantic query graph is a phrase corresponding to a subject or object in the SPARQL query. Generally, con- stant nodes (e.g., Titanic) can be divided into three categories according to their roles (entity, type, lit- eral) in knowledge graph. Besides, a variable node (e.g., ?place) has the potential to map any vertices in knowledge graph.</p><p>Generally, the node recognition task is regarded as a sequence labeling problem and we adopt a BLSTM-CRF model <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Huang et al., 2015</ref>) to re- alize it. However, this model doesn't work very well on recognizing entity/type nodes as the entity phrases may be too long or too complex. There- fore, we first detect entity and type nodes by uti- lize existing entity linking algorithms of specific knowledge bases (see section 2.3), and then detect variable/literal nodes by the BLSTM-CRF model. A phrase w ij , which contains the words from i to j in the question, is recognized as entity/type node if we can find entity/type mappings of w ij through the entity linking algorithm. We check all possible phrases and select the longer one if two candidate nodes share any words. The detected entity/type nodes will be replaced by special tokens E or T before calling the BLSTM-CRF model.</p><p>In practice, we find that some nodes have hid- den information, which can be expanded to a subgraph (i.e, one or multiple triples). For ex- ample, the hidden information of "?cosmonauts" in question N 1 in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 2</ref> can extends two triples: ?cosmonauts rdf:type dbo:Astronaut and ?cosmonauts dbo:nationality dbr:Russia. Such information can help us to reduce the matching space and make the answers more accurate.</p><p>We mine those nodes with hidden information from several QA benchmarks 1 and build a transla- tion dictionary D T in offline. Given a question N with the gold query graph Q G , we try to match Q G to the SQG Q S generated by our approach. Each unmatched connected subgraph in Q G is regarded as hidden information of the nearest matched node v. For the benchmarks only have gold question- answers pairs, we utilize the method in <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">(Zhang and Zou, 2017)</ref> to mine the gold query graph first. <ref type="bibr">1</ref>  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Figure 3: Samples of Operations</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">SQG's Structure Construction</head><p>As mentioned earlier, our SQG's structure is gen- erated in a state-transition paradigm. Initially, the state only contains several isolated nodes that are recognized in the first step. To enable the state transition, we propose four primitive operations as follows.</p><p>1. Connect. Given two operate nodes u 1 and u 2 , we introduce an edge u 1 u 2 between them by the connect operation. Note that the rela- tion mention and candidate relations (predi- cates) of the edge u 1 u 2 can be found through relation extraction model (see section 2.3).</p><p>2. Merge. Given a SQG Q S = {V, E} and two operate nodes u,v, this operation is to merge the node u into v.</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">The new SQG Q S = {V \ {u}, (E \ E d ) ∪ E a }, E d = {uw ∈ E} and E a = {vw|uw ∈ E ∧ w = v}.</formula><p>Notice that v also inherits the properties of u. The merge operation is designed to support co-reference resolution. The <ref type="figure">Figure 3</ref>(b) gives an example. For the question "Which presidents died in the same place they were born in?", the node v 2 ("which") is redundant and can be merged into v 1 ("presidents"). The node v 4 ("they") and v 1 ("presidents") are co-reference, we can merge v 4 to v 1 . The edge v 3 v 4 (birthPlace) is replaced by edge v</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">3 v 1 (birthPlace).</formula><p>3. Expand. Given a SQG Q S = {V, E} and the operate node u ∈ V , this operation is to expand u to a subgraph</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">Q S u = {V u , E u }. The new SQG Q S = {V ∪ V u , E ∪ E u }.</formula><p>The expand operation is designed to those </p><formula xml:id="formula_4">Connect(v 1, v 2 ) v' 1 v' 3</formula><p>Figure 4: Semantic Query Graph Generation nodes that have hidden information. Let us see <ref type="figure">Figure 3</ref>(c). The word "cosmonauts"(v 1 ) means "Russia astronauts", but it cannot be mapped to a certain entity or type in the knowledge base directly. To match "cosmo- nauts", we can expand it to an equivalent sub- graph {v</p><formula xml:id="formula_5">1 ,v 2 ,v</formula><p>3 } (according to the transition dictionary D T ) that can match the underlying knowledge base.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>4.</head><p>Fold. Given a SQG Q S = {V, E} and an op- erate node u ∈ V , this operation is to delete u and merge the associated relations. For- mally, the new SQG</p><formula xml:id="formula_6">Q S = {V \ {u}, (E \ E d ) ∪ E a }, in which E d = {uv i ∈ E} and E a = {v i v j |uv i ∈ E ∧ uv j ∈ E ∧ i = j}.</formula><p>The fold operation is designed to eliminate those nodes which are useless or mis-recognized. <ref type="figure">Figure 3(d)</ref> gives an ex- ample. For the question "Who composed the soundtrack for Cameron's Titanic?", SQG {v 1 , v 2 , v 3 } cannot find matches in knowl- edge base because there are no correct rela- tions of v 1 v 2 and v 1 v 3 . By applying a fold operation, these two edges with the redundant node v 1 are removed, while the new edge v 1 v 2 can be matched to the correct relation musicComposer (according to the relation extraction model).</p><p>We focus on generating the correct SQG with the above operations. Obviously, it is impossible to enumerate all possible transitions in each step due to exponential search space. Therefore, we propose a greedy search algorithm 2 inspired by ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">Yih et al., 2015</ref>). The intention is that an better intermediate state should have more opportunities to be visited and produce subsequent states. As each state can be seen as a partial SQG, we pro- pose a reward function using a log-linear model (see Section 3) to estimate the likelihood of each state. A priority queue is utilized to maintain the <ref type="bibr">2</ref> The formal algorithm can be found in Appendix A. order of unvisited states. Each turn we choose the state with maximum correctness likelihood and try all possible transitions by each operation. Specif- ically, the connect and merge operations try every pair of nodes in current state as the two operate nodes, while the expand and fold operations try each node as the operate node. The newly gener- ated states are estimated by the learning model and pushed into the priority queue. Note that redupli- cated states will not be added. The algorithm ends when a complete SQG Q S is found and Q S can not generates any better subsequent states.</p><p>To reduce the search space of the state- transition process, we also propose several con- straints for each operation. Only when the condi- tions are satisfied, the corresponding operation can be executed. Experiments show that those condi- tions not only speeds up the QA process but also improves the precision (see Section 4.4). The con- ditions are listed as follows.</p><p>Condition 1 (Condition for Connect) Two nodes v 1 and v 2 can be connected if and only if there exists no other node v * that occurs in the shortest path between v 1 and v 2 of the dependency parse tree 3 of question sentence N .</p><p>Condition 2 (Condition for Merge) For the merge operation, there should be at least one vari- able v in the two operate nodes. And v should be a wh-word or pronoun, which may co-reference <ref type="bibr">3</ref> with an other node.</p><p>Condition 3 (Condition for Expand) For the ex- pand operation, the operate node u should be a variable, and we need to be able to find u and its hidden information in the transition dictionary D T .</p><p>Condition 4 (Condition for Fold) For the fold operation, we require at least one of the connected edges with the operate node have no relation can- didates or the confidence probabilities of the cor- responding relations are less than a threshold τ .</p><p>The following example illustrates the process of SQG generation. Note that it can have other tran- sition sequences to get the final state.</p><p>Example 1 Consider <ref type="figure">Figure 4</ref>. Given a question N 1 = "Which cosmonauts died in the same place they were born in?", we first extract four nodes v 1 , v 2 , v 3 , v 4 , which are all variable nodes. Accord- ing the condition 1, we connect (v 1 ,v 2 ), (v 1 ,v 3 ), and (v 3 ,v 4 ). The simple path between v 1 and v 3 in the dependency parse tree can be regarded as the relation phrase of v 1 v 3 , which is "died in". Simi- larly, the relation phrase of v 3 v 4 is "born in". As</p><note type="other">v 1 and v 2 are neighbors in the dependency parse tree, the corresponding relation phrase is empty. Then we merge (v 1 ,v 2 ) as they are recognized co- reference. Similarly v 1 and v 4 are merged. Notice that the associated edge v 3 v 4 have been reserved, then there are two edges between v 1 and v 3 in the new SQG. In the end, we expand v 1 to the sub- graph {v 1 , v 4 , v 2 } and get the final SQG.</note></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3">Finding entity/relation candidates and matches of SQG</head><p>During SQG construction, there are two sub- tasks: entity extraction and relation extraction. We briefly discuss the two steps as follows. Given a node phrase in Q S , we find the candi- date entities/types with confidence probabilities by using existing entity linking approaches. Specifi- cally, we use S-MART ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">Yang and Chang, 2015)</ref> for Freebase dataset and DBpeida Lookup 4 for DBpedia dataset.</p><p>Given two connected nodes v i and v j in Q S , we need to find the relation candidates between them. Inspired by the recent success of neural rela- tion extraction models in KBQA ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">Yih et al., 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Dong et al., 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Xu et al., 2016)</ref>, we propose a Multi-Channel Convolutional Neural Network (MCCNN) to extract all relations in the question N exploiting both syntactic and sentential infor- mation. We use the simple path between v i and v j in the dependency tree Y (N ) as input to the first channel. The input of second channel is the whole question sentence excluded all nodes, which rep- resents the context of the relation we want to pre- dict. If v i and v j are neighbors in Y (N ), we need to extract an implicit relation. To tackle this task, we use v i , v j and their types as input to the third channel. For v i = "Chinese" and v j = "actor", the input is "Chinese-Country-actor-Actor". Different from ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Xu et al., 2016</ref>) which can only extract one explicit relation, our model can not only extract multiple relations from N by taking different node pairs, but also extract the implicit relation considering the embedded information in the two nodes v i and v j .</p><p>After generating the SQG Q S , we employ the subgraph matching algorithm ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Hu et al., 2018)</ref> to find matches of Q S over the underlying RDF knowledge graph G. Once the matches are found, it is straightforward to derive the answers.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Learning the reward function</head><p>Given an intermediate state s during SQG gener- ation process, we may transit to multiple subse- quent states s by applying different operations. Thus, we greedily select a subsequent state s with the maximum γ(s ), where γ() is a reward func- tion taking the features and outputting the reward of corresponding state. In this work, the reward function γ() is a linear model trained with the SVM ranking loss. Below we describe the fea- tures, learning process and how to generate the training data.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Features</head><p>Note that for any intermediate state s, we also re- gard it as a SQG Q S (s) even though it is a dis- connected graph. For a given SQG Q S , we extract the following features which are passed as an input vector to the SVM ranker.</p><p>Nodes. For each entity/type node v, we utilize entity linking systems to find the candidate entities or types and corresponding confidence probabili- ties. We use the largest confidence probability as the score of v, and use the average score of all en- tity nodes as the feature. In addition, the number of constant nodes and variable nodes in current Q S are considered as features.</p><p>Edges. For each edge v i v j , the relation extrac- tion model returns a list of candidate predicates with the corresponding confidence probabilities. We use the largest confidence probability as the score of v i v j , and use the average score of all edges as the feature. We also consider the to- tal number of edges in Q S , the number of edges which have relation phrase and which have no re- lation phrase.</p><p>Matches. We also consider the matching be- tween Q S and the knowledge graph G. A new state s would get a low score if its corresponding SQG Q S could not find any matches in G. We do not discard s directly from the search queue as we allow the fold operation of it. To speed up the matching process, we build the index of all entities and relations in offline. For a given SQG Q S , we use the offline index to check whether it is valid.</p><p>Given a valid state s, if all of its possible subse- quent states s have smaller reward function value than that of s, we will terminate the state transi- tion process and return s as the final state. The corresponding SQG Q S (s) is used to match the knowledge base to retrieve answers.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Learning</head><p>The task of reward function can be viewed as a ranking problem, in which the appropriate SQGs should be ranked in the front. In this work, we rank them using a SVM rank classifier <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(Joachims, 2006</ref>).</p><p>Given a SQG Q S = {V, E}, the ranking score that we use to train our reward function γ() is cal- culated by the following function.</p><formula xml:id="formula_7">R(Q S ) = |P (V )| |V | + |P (E)| |E | + max(F (A i , A ))</formula><p>(1) V and E are the gold node set and relation set ex- tracted from the gold SPARQL query. P (V ) con- tains the nodes existing in both V and V . P (E) contains the relations existing in both E and E . F (A i , A ) is the F-1 measure where A is the gold answer set and A i is one of the subgraph matches between Q S and knowledge graph G obtained by the executing method in ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Hu et al., 2018)</ref>. No- tice that for the benchmark without gold SPARQL queries, R(Q S ) = max(F (A i , A )).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3">Generating Training Data</head><p>To generate the training data of the reward func- tion, given a question N = {w 1 , w 2 , ..., w n }, we first check all possible phrases w ij by existing en- tity linking system and get the candidate entity list C v i = {e 1 , e 2 , ..., e m } for each entity node v i . If two entity node v i and v j have conflict, i.e, v i and v j share one or more words, we reserve the longer one. We replace each entity node v i with a spe- cial token to denote the type of entity e j , where e j ∈ C v i and has the largest confidence possi- bility. Then the whole node set V can be pre- dicted by the well-trained node recognition model. Q S = {V, φ} is the initial state. Further we do state transition by applying the predefined opera- tions using a BFS algorithm. Meanwhile, only the states satisfied with corresponding conditions are considered if enabling the condition mechanism. Once we get a new Q S we call the well-trained relation extraction model to get the relation can- didate list of each new edge v i v j ∈ E, while the features are collected according Section 3.1 and the ranking score is calculated using Equation 1.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Evaluation</head><p>We evaluate our system on several benchmarks with two knowledge base DBpedia and Freebase. For DBpedia, we use the QALD-6 benchmark. We compare our method STF (State Transition Frame- work) with all systems in QALD-6 competition as well as Aqqu ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Bast and Haussmann, 2015)</ref>, gAnswer ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Zou et al., 2014</ref>) and NFF ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Hu et al., 2018)</ref>. For Freebase, we use WebQuestions <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Berant et al., 2013)</ref> and ComplexQuestions ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Abujabal et al., 2017</ref>) as benchmarks and compare our method with corresponding state-of-art systems.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">Setup</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1.1">Knowledge Bases</head><p>DBpedia RDF repository is a knowledge base derived from Wikipedia ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Bizer et al., 2009</ref>). We use the version of DBpedia 2014 and the statistics are given in <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">Table 1</ref>. Freebase is a collaboratively edited knowledge base. We use the version of Freebase 2013, which is same with <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Berant and Liang, 2014</ref>). The statis- tics are given in <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">Table 1</ref>.   <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">Number of Entities  5.4 million  41 million  Number of Triples  110 million 596 million  Number of Predicates  9708  19456  Size of KBs (in GB)</ref> 8.7 56.9 53.6% 54.3% STAGG ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">Yih et al., 2015)</ref> 52.5% - QUINT ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Abujabal et al., 2017)</ref> 51.0% 49.2% NFF <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">(Hu et al., 2018)</ref> 49.6% - Aqqu ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Bast and Haussmann, 2015)</ref> 49.4% 27.8% Aqqu++ ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Bast and Haussmann, 2015)</ref> 49.4%</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1.2">Benchmarks</head><p>46.7%  <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">and Haussmann, 2015)</ref>. QUINT is the model used in the original Com- plexQuestions paper and Aqqu is the best publicly available QA system on WebQuestions. The aver- age F1 of our system (53.6% for WQ and 54.3% for CQ) are better than the other systems. Aqqu defines three query templates for We- bQuestions and try to match test questions to pre- defined templates. It has a poor performance (27.8%) on ComplexQuestions when answering the test questions directly. Aqqu++ shows the result (46.7%) by taking manually decomposed subquestions as input and getting the intersection of subquestions' answer sets. QUINT is a sys- tem that automatically learns utterance-query tem- plates from the pairs of question and answer set. NFF builds a relation paraphrase dictionary and leverages it to extract relations from the questions. STAGG proposes a state-transition based query graph generation method. However, its query graph structure is limited as in the <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref>, which is very similar with the templates of Aqqu.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">Results on WebQuestions and ComplexQuestions</head><p>To generate the training data of relation extrac- tion model on the WebQuestions, for each two nodes u and v in the training question, we explore all simple relations between u and v in Freebase. Note that if u or v is the answer node, we will anchor the answer entity first and select the rela- tion which can handle most of answer entities as the gold relation. Each entity will be replaced in text by a special token representing its type before training. As there are no training data in Com- plexQuestions, we use the models trained on We- bQuestions directly. Generally, WebQuestions benchmark has low diversity and contains some incorrect or incom- plete labeled answers. Most of questions in We- bQuestions are simple questions, which can be translated to a "one-triple" query. The results on WebQuestions benchmark prove our approach is able to obtain good performance on simple questions. ComplexQuestions benchmark is more complex than WebQuestions. The experiments re- sults show that the two template based methods QUINT and Aqqu can solve a part of the complex questions. However, it still lack of the capacity to tackle all questions due to the error of dependency parse or the mismatch of the templates. On the other hand, our system outperforms them because we do not rely on templates and have better gener- alization ability to solve complex questions. <ref type="table" target="#tab_6">Table 3</ref> shows the evaluation results on the test set of QALD-6. We compare our system with all participants of QALD-6 as well as gAnswer ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Zou et al., 2014</ref>), NFF ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Hu et al., 2018)</ref> and Aqqu ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Bast and Haussmann, 2015)</ref>. To enable the comparison, we show the experiment results in the QALD com- petition report format. "Processed" denotes the number of questions can be processed and "Right" refers to the number of questions that were an- swered correctly. Our approach can answer 70 questions correctly, and get the 0.80 F-1 score.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3">Results on QALD</head><p>The experiment results show that we can beat all systems in QALD-6 campaign in F-1 ex- cept for CANaLI (Mazzeo and Zaniolo). Note that CANaLI is not an automatic QA system, as it needs users to specify the precise entities and predicates in the question sentences. gAn- swer ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Zou et al., 2014</ref>) proposes a relation first framework to generate the semantic query graph while it can not detect implicit relations. NFF ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Hu et al., 2018</ref>) proposes a node first framework which performs well on answering complex ques-  tions (0.78 F1 score on QALD-6). However it re- lies on the predefined paraphrasing dictionaries to extract relations and could not tackle with redun- dant nodes.</p><p>As QALD has the gold SPARQL queries, we can obtain the training data of node recognition and relation extraction model directly. Different from the WebQuestions and ComplexQuestions which have only special questions, the QALD benchmark also has general questions and imper- ative sentence. Besides, there are some questions that have no entities or multiple entities.</p><p>Generally, QALD benchmark has both high di- versity and quality. The performance of Aqqu in QALD is worse than its performance in We- bQuestions and ComplexQuestions as it has only designed the templates to WebQuestions. In con- trast, our approach do not rely specific benchmark or knowledge base. The evaluation results show that our approach performs well on various types of complex questions.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.4">Comparison experiments of the four conditions</head><p>We run experiments on QALD-6 test set to verify the effectiveness of the four conditions proposed in Section 2.2. We first compare the elapsed time of state transition with conditions or without con- ditions. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 5</ref> shows the results of 10 ques- tions selected randomly and AVG means the av- erage time consumption among all 100 test ques- tions. The average elapsed time with conditions is 700 ms while it rises to 1200 ms without the conditions. The results declare that using the con- ditions in the search process can avoid unneces- sary searches and save SQG construction time. In some questions (such as Q66 and Q81), the gap of elapsed time are very little because the number of recognized nodes are less than three. In other words, those simple questions do not need the con- ditions to speed up the SQG construction process.</p><p>On the other hand, using conditions can im- prove the evaluation performance (see <ref type="table" target="#tab_7">Table 4</ref>). That because the conditions help system to re- duce search space and avoid local optimum, es- pecially the condition of connect operation. When the question has multiple nodes, if we do not use the condition of connect operation, it tries to con- nect each two nodes and enrolls too many mis- taken states.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.5">Error Analysis</head><p>We provide the error analysis of our approach on QALD-6 test set (100 questions), which contains gold SPARQL queries and more diversified ques- tions. The ratio of each error type and the corre- sponding examples are given in <ref type="table" target="#tab_8">Table 5</ref>.</p><p>There are mainly four reasons for the failure of some questions in our approach. The first reason is the structure failure, which means we generate a wrong SQG. That usually occurred when the cor- rect SQG needs a fold operation. For example, the correct SQG of question "In which countries do people speak Japanese" has only two nodes "coun- tries", "Japanese". However, we recognized the phrase "people" as a variable node by mistake and connected it to both "countries" and "Japanese" to generate a wrong SQG Q S . It should be elimi- nated by the fold operation to get the correct SQG Q S . However, the score of Q S that we get from the reward function is higher than the score of Q S . The inherent reason is the lack of training data.</p><p>The second reason is the failure of entity link- ing, for example, we could not find the correct en- tity of the node "loyalty" in the question "What color expresses loyalty?". It has smallest propor- tion as the existing entity linking algorithms al- ready have high accuracy on QA task.</p><p>The third reason is the failure of relation ex- traction. For example, the correct relation be- tween "What" and "Prince Charles" in the ques- tion 'What is the full name of Prince Charles?" is alias. However, we got a wrong relation name. The relation extraction problem is very important to QA task, which can be improved by designing more elegant models and combining more useful information.</p><p>The last one is that our method cannot answer some complex aggregation questions, which need to detect the aggregation constraint first and then infer the related node and corresponding relation. Using predefined templates or utilizing textual ev- idence maybe works but not good enough.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Related Work</head><p>Generally, the solutions of KBQA can be di- vided into information retrieval-based and seman- tic parsing-based methods. The general process of information retrieval-based methods is to se- lect candidate answers first and then rank them by various methods <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(Veyseh, 2016;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Dong et al., 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Xu et al., 2016;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Bordes et al., 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Yao and Durme, 2014</ref>). The main difference among in- formation retrieval-based methods is how to rank the candidate answers. ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Bordes et al., 2014</ref>) uti- lizes subgraph embedding to predict the confi- dence of candidate answers. ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Dong et al., 2015)</ref> maximize the similarity between the distributed representation of a question and its answer can- didates using Multi-Column Convolutional Neural Networks (MCCNN), while ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Xu et al., 2016</ref>) aims to predicate the correct relations between topic en- tity and answer candidates with text evidence.</p><p>The semantic parsing-based methods try to translate the natural language question into seman- tic equivalent logical forms, such as simple λ- DCS ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Berant et al., 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Berant and Liang, 2014</ref>), query graph ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">Yih et al., 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Zou et al., 2014)</ref>, or executable queries such as SPARQL ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Bast and Haussmann, 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Unger et al., 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b18">Yahya et al., 2012)</ref>. Then the logical forms are executed by corresponding technique and get the answers from knowledge base. For answering complex ques- tions, the key is how to construct the logical form. Different from existing systems relying on the pre- defined templates, we build the query graph by state transition, which has stronger representation power and more robustness.</p><p>( <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Dong and Lapata, 2016)</ref> trains a sequence to tree model to translate natural language to logical forms directly, which needs a lot of training data. ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Yu et al., 2017</ref>) uses deep bidirectional LSTMs to learn both relation-level and word-level ques- tion/relation representations and match the ques- tion to candidate relations. The pipeline of ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Yu et al., 2017</ref>) is similar with ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">Yih et al., 2015)</ref>, which detect topic entity and relation first and then recognize constraints by enumerating all con- nected entities of answer node or CVT node in knowledge base. The issue is they assume the question N only have one relation, which is from the topic entity to the answer. Different from ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Yu et al., 2017)</ref>, we consider the question can have many nodes (including entities and variables) and recognize them by a BLSTM model. We also al- low multi relations between these nodes and ex- tract them by the MCCNN model.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Conclusions</head><p>In this paper, we propose a state transition frame- work to utilize neural networks to answer complex questions, which generates semantic query graph based on four primitive operations. We train a BLSTM-CRF model to recognize nodes including entities and variables from the question sentence. To extract the relations between those nodes, we propose a MCCNN model which can tackle both explicit and implicit relations. Comparing with existing solutions, our framework do not rely on handcrafted templates and has the potential to gen- erate all kinds of SQGs given enough training data. Extensive experiments on multi benchmark datasets confirm that our approach have the state- of-art performance.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2: The example of complex questions with semantic query graph</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 5 :</head><label>5</label><figDesc>Figure 5: The elapsed time comparison of state transition with conditions or without conditions in QALD-6 test set</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" validated="false"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>QALD is a series of open-domain question an- swering campaigns, which have several different tasks. We only consider the task of English ques- tion answering over DBpedia in QALD-6 (Unger et al., 2016), which has 350 training questions and 100 test questions, with gold SPARQL queries and answer sets. WebQuestions (Berant et al., 2013) consists of 3778 training questions and 2032 test questions, which are collected using the Google Suggest API and crowdsourcing. It only provides the pairs of question and answer set. ComplexQuestions (Abujabal et al., 2017) is composed of 150 test questions that exhibit compositionality through multiple clauses, which is constructed using the crawl of WikiAnswers (http://wiki.answers.com) and human annotator. It has no training questions and SPARQL queries.</figDesc><table></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3" validated="false"><head>Table 1 : Statistics of Knowledge Bases</head><label>1</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>DBpedia 
Freebase 
</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4" validated="false"><head>Table 2 : The average F1 score of WebQuestions and ComplexQuestions benchmark</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>WQ 
CQ 
STF (Our approach) 
</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_5" validated="false"><head>Table 2 shows</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>the results on the test set of 
WebQuestions(WQ) and ComplexQuestions(CQ), 
which are based on the Freebase. We com-
pare our system with STAGG (Yih et al., 2015), 
QUINT (Abujabal et al., 2017), NFF (Hu et al., 
2018) and Aqqu(Bast </table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_6" validated="true"><head>Table 3 : Evaluating QALD-6 Testing Questions</head><label>3</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Processed 
Right 
Recall 
Precision 
F-1 
Our approach 
100 
70 
0.72 
0.89 
0.80 
CANaLI 
100 
83 
0.89 
0.89 
0.89 
UTQA 
100 
63 
0.69 
0.82 
0.75 
KWGAnswer 
100 
52 
0.59 
0.85 
0.70 
SemGraphQA 
100 
20 
0.25 
0.70 
0.37 
UIQA1 
44 
21 
0.63 
0.54 
0.25 
UIQA2 
36 
14 
0.53 
0.43 
0.17 
NFF 
100 
68 
0.70 
0.89 
0.78 
gAnswer 
100 
40 
0.43 
0.77 
0.55 
Aqqu 
100 
36 
0.37 
0.39 
0.38 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_7" validated="false"><head>Table 4 : The performance comparison of state transi- tion with conditions or without conditions in QALD-6 test set</head><label>4</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Right Recall Precision F-1 
with condition 
70 
0.72 
0.89 
0.80 
no condition 
62 
0.64 
0.84 
0.72 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_8" validated="true"><head>Table 5 : Failure Analysis on QALD-6</head><label>5</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Reason 
# (Ratio) Sample question 
Structure 
Failure 

6 (20%) 
Q55: In which countries do 
people speak Japanese? 
Entity 
Mapping 

5 (17%) 
Q88: What color expresses 
loyalty? 
Relation 
Mapping 

10 (33%) 
Q44: What is the full name 
of Prince Charles? 
Complex 
Aggregation 

9 (30%) 
Q80: How short is the 
shortest active NBA player? 

</table></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="3"> We utilize the Stanford CoreNLP dependency parser and coreference annotator (Manning et al., 2014)</note>

			<note place="foot" n="4"> http://wiki.dbpedia.org/projects/dbpedia-lookup</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>This work was supported by The National Key Re-search and Development Program of China under grant 2016YFB1000603 and NSFC under grant 61622201 and 61532010. Lei Zou is the corre-sponding author of this work. This work is also supported by Key Laboratory of Science, Technol-ogy and Standard in Press Industry (Key Labora-tory of Intelligent Press Media Technology).</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Automated template generation for question answering over knowledge graphs</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Abdalghani</forename><surname>Abujabal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mohamed</forename><surname>Yahya</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mirek</forename><surname>Riedewald</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gerhard</forename><surname>Weikum</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 26th International Conference on World Wide Web</title>
		<meeting>the 26th International Conference on World Wide Web<address><addrLine>Perth, Australia</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017-04-03" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1191" to="1200" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Knowledge-based question answering as machine translation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jun-Wei</forename><surname>Bao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nan</forename><surname>Duan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ming</forename><surname>Zhou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tiejun</forename><surname>Zhao</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 52nd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics, ACL 2014</title>
		<meeting>the 52nd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics, ACL 2014<address><addrLine>Baltimore, MD, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Long Papers</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2014-06-22" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="967" to="976" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">More accurate question answering on freebase</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hannah</forename><surname>Bast</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Elmar</forename><surname>Haussmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 24th ACM International Conference on Information and Knowledge Management, CIKM 2015</title>
		<meeting>the 24th ACM International Conference on Information and Knowledge Management, CIKM 2015<address><addrLine>Melbourne, VIC, Australia</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015-10-19" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1431" to="1440" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Semantic parsing on freebase from question-answer pairs</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jonathan</forename><surname>Berant</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Andrew</forename><surname>Chou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Roy</forename><surname>Frostig</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Percy</forename><surname>Liang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">EMNLP</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1533" to="1544" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Semantic parsing via paraphrasing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jonathan</forename><surname>Berant</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Percy</forename><surname>Liang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 52nd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics, ACL 2014</title>
		<meeting>the 52nd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics, ACL 2014<address><addrLine>Baltimore, MD, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Long Papers</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2014-06-22" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1415" to="1425" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dbpedia-a crystallization point for the web of data</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christian</forename><surname>Bizer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jens</forename><surname>Lehmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Georgi</forename><surname>Kobilarov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sören</forename><surname>Auer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christian</forename><surname>Becker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Richard</forename><surname>Cyganiak</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sebastian</forename><surname>Hellmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Web Sem</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="154" to="165" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Question answering with subgraph embeddings</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Antoine</forename><surname>Bordes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sumit</forename><surname>Chopra</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jason</forename><surname>Weston</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2014 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</title>
		<meeting>the 2014 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing<address><addrLine>Doha, Qatar</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014-10-25" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="615" to="620" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>A meeting of SIGDAT, a Special Interest Group of the ACL</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Language to logical form with neural attention</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Li</forename><surname>Dong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mirella</forename><surname>Lapata</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 54th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics, ACL 2016</title>
		<meeting>the 54th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics, ACL 2016<address><addrLine>Berlin, Germany</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Long Papers</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2016-08-07" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Question answering over freebase with multicolumn convolutional neural networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Li</forename><surname>Dong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Furu</forename><surname>Wei</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ming</forename><surname>Zhou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ke</forename><surname>Xu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 53rd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics and the 7th International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing of the Asian Federation of Natural Language Processing</title>
		<meeting>the 53rd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics and the 7th International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing of the Asian Federation of Natural Language Processing<address><addrLine>Beijing, China</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Long Papers</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2015-07-26" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="260" to="269" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Answering natural language questions by subgraph matching over knowledge graphs</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sen</forename><surname>Hu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lei</forename><surname>Zou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jeffrey</forename><forename type="middle">Xu</forename><surname>Yu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Haixun</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dongyan</forename><surname>Zhao</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE Trans. Knowl. Data Eng</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">30</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="824" to="837" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Bidirectional LSTM-CRF models for sequence tagging</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Zhiheng</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wei</forename><surname>Xu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kai</forename><surname>Yu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>abs/1508.01991</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
			<publisher>CoRR</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Training linear svms in linear time</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Thorsten</forename><forename type="middle">Joachims</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Twelfth ACM SIGKDD International Conference on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining</title>
		<meeting>the Twelfth ACM SIGKDD International Conference on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining<address><addrLine>Philadelphia, PA, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006-08-20" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="217" to="226" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The stanford corenlp natural language processing toolkit</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christopher</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Manning</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mihai</forename><surname>Surdeanu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">John</forename><surname>Bauer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jenny</forename><forename type="middle">Rose</forename><surname>Finkel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Steven</forename><surname>Bethard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Mcclosky</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 52nd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics, ACL</title>
		<meeting>the 52nd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics, ACL<address><addrLine>Baltimore, MD, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014-06-22" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>System Demonstrations</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Answering controlled natural language questions on RDF knowledge bases</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Giuseppe</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Mazzeo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Carlo</forename><surname>Zaniolo</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 19th International Conference on Extending Database Technology, EDBT 2016</title>
		<meeting>the 19th International Conference on Extending Database Technology, EDBT 2016<address><addrLine>Bordeaux, France; Bordeaux, France</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1516-03" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="608" to="611" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Template-based question answering over rdf data</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christina</forename><surname>Unger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lorenz</forename><surname>Bühmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jens</forename><surname>Lehmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Axel-Cyrille Ngonga</forename><surname>Ngomo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Daniel</forename><surname>Gerber</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Philipp</forename><surname>Cimiano</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">WWW</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="639" to="648" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">6th open challenge on question answering over linked data (QALD-6)</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christina</forename><surname>Unger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Axel-Cyrille Ngonga</forename><surname>Ngomo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Elena</forename><surname>Cabrio</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Semantic Web Challenges-Third SemWebEval Challenge at ESWC 2016</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Heraklion, Crete, Greece</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016-05-29" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="171" to="177" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Revised Selected Papers</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Cross-lingual question answering using common semantic space</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ben</forename><surname>Amir Pouran</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Veyseh</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of TextGraphs@NAACL-HLT 2016: the 10th Workshop on Graph-based Methods for Natural Language Processing</title>
		<meeting>TextGraphs@NAACL-HLT 2016: the 10th Workshop on Graph-based Methods for Natural Language Processing<address><addrLine>San Diego, California, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016-06-17" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="15" to="19" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Question answering on freebase via relation extraction and textual evidence</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kun</forename><surname>Xu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Siva</forename><surname>Reddy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yansong</forename><surname>Feng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Songfang</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dongyan</forename><surname>Zhao</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 54th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics, ACL 2016</title>
		<meeting>the 54th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics, ACL 2016<address><addrLine>Berlin, Germany</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Long Papers</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2016-08-07" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Natural language questions for the web of data</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mohamed</forename><surname>Yahya</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Klaus</forename><surname>Berberich</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Shady</forename><surname>Elbassuoni</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Maya</forename><surname>Ramanath</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Volker</forename><surname>Tresp</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gerhard</forename><surname>Weikum</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">EMNLP-CoNLL</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="379" to="390" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">S-MART: novel tree-based structured learning algorithms applied to tweet entity linking</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yi</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ming-Wei</forename><surname>Chang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 53rd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics and the 7th International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing of the Asian Federation of Natural Language Processing</title>
		<meeting>the 53rd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics and the 7th International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing of the Asian Federation of Natural Language Processing<address><addrLine>Beijing, China</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Long Papers</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2015-07-26" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="504" to="513" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Information extraction over structured data: Question answering with freebase</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xuchen</forename><surname>Yao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Benjamin</forename><surname>Van Durme</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 52nd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics, ACL 2014</title>
		<meeting>the 52nd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics, ACL 2014<address><addrLine>Baltimore, MD, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Long Papers</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2014-06-22" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="956" to="966" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Semantic parsing via staged query graph generation: Question answering with knowledge base</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ming-Wei</forename><surname>Wen-Tau Yih</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xiaodong</forename><surname>Chang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jianfeng</forename><surname>He</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Gao</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 53rd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics and the 7th International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing of the Asian Federation of Natural Language Processing</title>
		<meeting>the 53rd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics and the 7th International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing of the Asian Federation of Natural Language Processing<address><addrLine>Beijing, China</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Long Papers</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2015-07-26" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1321" to="1331" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Improved neural relation detection for knowledge base question answering</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mo</forename><surname>Yu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wenpeng</forename><surname>Yin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kazi</forename><surname>Saidul Hasan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Cícero</forename><surname>Nogueira</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bing</forename><surname>Santos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bowen</forename><surname>Xiang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Zhou</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 55th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the 55th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics<address><addrLine>Vancouver, Canada</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Long Papers</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2017-07-30" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="571" to="581" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Improving the precision of RDF question/answering systems: A why not approach</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xinbo</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lei</forename><surname>Zou</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 26th International Conference on World Wide Web Companion</title>
		<meeting>the 26th International Conference on World Wide Web Companion<address><addrLine>Perth, Australia</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017-04-03" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="877" to="878" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Natural language question answering over RDF: a graph data driven approach</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lei</forename><surname>Zou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ruizhe</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Haixun</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jeffrey</forename><forename type="middle">Xu</forename><surname>Yu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wenqiang</forename><surname>He</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dongyan</forename><surname>Zhao</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">International Conference on Management of Data</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Snowbird, UT, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014-06-22" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="313" to="324" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
