<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T10:32+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">SyntaViz: Visualizing Voice Queries through a Syntax-Driven Hierarchical Ontology</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date>October 31-November 4, 2018</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><roleName>Md</roleName><forename type="first">Iftekhar</forename><surname>Tanveer</surname></persName>
							<email>itanveer@cs.rochester.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Comcast Applied AI Research Washington DC</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Rochester Rochester</orgName>
								<address>
									<region>NY</region>
									<country>USA, USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ferhan</forename><surname>Ture</surname></persName>
							<email>ferhan ture@comcast.com</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Comcast Applied AI Research Washington DC</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Rochester Rochester</orgName>
								<address>
									<region>NY</region>
									<country>USA, USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">SyntaViz: Visualizing Voice Queries through a Syntax-Driven Hierarchical Ontology</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="j" type="main">Brussels</title>
						<meeting>the 2018 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (System Demonstrations) <address><addrLine>Belgium</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="6"/>
							<date type="published">October 31-November 4, 2018</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<note>1</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>This paper describes SYNTAVIZ, a visualiza-tion interface specifically designed for analyzing natural-language queries that were created by users of a voice-enabled product. SYN-TAVIZ provides a platform for browsing the ontology of user queries from a syntax-driven perspective, providing quick access to high-impact failure points of the existing intent understanding system and evidence for data-driven decisions in the development cycle. A case study on Xfinity X1 (a voice-enabled entertainment platform from Comcast) reveals that SYNTAVIZ helps developers identify multiple action items in a short amount of time without any special training. SYNTAVIZ has been open-sourced for the benefit of the community .</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Voice-driven interactions with computing devices are becoming increasingly prevalent. Amazon's Alexa, Apple's Siri, Microsoft's Cortana, and the Google Assistant are prominent examples. Google observed that mobile devices surpassed tradi- tional computers in terms of search traffic <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(Sterling, 2015)</ref>, and that 20% of mobile searches are voice queries <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Pichai, 2016)</ref>. As opposed to the keyword-based shorter queries received by web- based search engines, voice-enabled natural lan- guage processing (NLP) systems deal with longer, natural-language queries. This raises the question of how such data should be utilized for continuous improvements of the underlying methods.</p><p>In this paper, we introduce SYNTAVIZ, a web interface for visualizing natural-language queries based on a syntax-driven ontology, thereby en- abling its user to quickly gain insights on the statistical and structural properties of large-scale customer-generated data. We provide use cases of SYNTAVIZ on a dataset of 1 million unique voice queries issued by users of the Xfinity X1 enter- tainment platform of Comcast-one of the largest cable companies in the United States with approxi- mately 22 million subscribers. We are planning to make the source code of SYNTAVIZ freely avail- able as a contribution to the community.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Related Work</head><p>There is a growing body of literature that deals with various text visualization techniques: Paul- heim and Probst (2012) provided a survey of vari- ous ontology-enhanced user interfaces. Most prior work utilizes topic modeling to group and/or par- tition the collection in a way that lexically differ- ent yet semantically similar queries are clustered together. <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Wei et al. (2010)</ref> proposed using Latent Dirichlet Allocation (LDA) to induce topic models for an exploratory text analytics system. <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Hoque and Carenini (2016)</ref> utilized topic modeling and sentiment analysis to visualize blog texts and as- sociated comments. A combination of latent topic analysis, discriminative feature selection and vari- ous ranking methods was developed by <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Singh et al. (2017)</ref> as part of a visualization interface for large text corpora. <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Dasiopoulou et al. (2015)</ref> developed a predicate-argument based ontology for exploring text elements and their relations. Their framework was demonstrated on excerpts from patent docu- ments. Despite the similarities with our proposed approach, none of the techniques directly suits the use case described in the next section.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Methods</head><p>SYNTAVIZ is a web interface that visualizes a col- lection of queries by grouping them in human- understandable clusters. The clusters are formed in a hierarchy based on the dependency parse of the tree of the natural language queries. The de- sign rationale and an elaborate description of so-lution are given in the following subsections.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Need Finding</head><p>The project stemmed from a need to optimize the engineering process of the existing intent under- standing system. We arranged an informal dis- cussion with the engineering team to understand the current workflow for developing the software that understands the intent of the users from their voice queries. The discussion provided clues that the current design is based on an "open-loop" de- sign process, where the team starts by coming up with many variations of voice queries that would describe a certain intent. For example, for the CHANNELTUNE intent, the first step would be to imagine query patterns such as "tune to ...", "switch over to ...", or simply "channel ...". The next step is to implement an algorithm to convert every such query to its corresponding intent (e.g., "tune to HBO" ⇒ CHANNELTUNE).</p><p>The design process does not involve any anal- ysis of historical query logs. This creates the risk of potential gaps between the capabilities of the developed software and the users' expecta- tions. Even though the engineers agreed that such data analyses would help design a better prod- uct, the lack of suitable techniques and/or a vi- sualization/analysis tool resulted in this subopti- mal process.</p><p>Our conclusion from these dis- cussions was that the development team was not able to gain useful insights about the incoming voice queries. For example, assigning the word "show" to carry an intent of watching TV shows (noun) might negatively impact the queries where the users say "show me ..." (verb). It is difficult to identify these adverse effects without a way to group and visualize similar queries.</p><p>Therefore, the need finding exercise revealed the importance of grouping or clustering the queries into semantic structures that reduces the informational overburden ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Jones et al., 2004</ref>) and ranks the failure points of the system in propor- tion to real query traffic. There are at least three benefits we have identified:</p><p>1. Software developers can access the informa- tion needed to design the most effective NLP algorithms.</p><p>2. Editors can identify bugs and patterns of log- ical errors in the deployed system.</p><p>3. Product managers can prioritize development efforts in a data-driven fashion, by easily identifying real cases that degrade user expe- rience.</p><p>Ideally, all the data should be summarized and presented through a visual interface with mini- mum cognitive burden. We sought to find an on- tology suitable for these needs. Although "topic modeling" is used as the de facto ontology for many text visualization projects ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Wei et al., 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Hoque and Carenini, 2016;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Singh et al., 2017</ref>), it is not suitable for this case because the voice queries are much shorter in length compared to the typical text documents used in topic model- ing. In addition, one of the reasons to form clusters of sentences is to visualize the systemic mistakes made by the intent understanding system. From this point of view, it appeared natural to cluster the syntactically similar queries together.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Ontology</head><p>Based on the need finding analysis, we realized that syntactic structures would be a great basis for summarizing the voice queries for the cur- rent scenario. Dependency parse trees <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Jurafsky and Martin, 2014</ref>) capture the syntactic relation- ships by representing the dependencies among the words with directed arrows. <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref> shows the dependency trees for two example sentences. No- ticeably, the dependent words (represented by ar- row heads) modify or complement their parents (e.g. watch complements want because it answers "want what?"). It is possible to summarize a num- ber of voice queries into hierarchical clusters us- ing these structures, by putting the queries con- taining the same tree fragments into the same clus- ter. Each cluster then could be divided into sub- clusters based on the structures of the subtrees within. This ontology allows the users to (1) iden- tify common patterns of error by the NLP system because syntactically similar queries are likely to all be victims of the same weaknesses, and (2) ob- serve the statistical distributions of the queries to the level of granularity they wish to see.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3">Dataset</head><p>We collected real voice queries issued by the users of Xfinity X1 TV control system within a period of seven days-totaling 32 million queries with an average length of 2.1 words. As we are in- terested in more "natural" queries, we filtered out the sentences with fewer than five words. In ad-Algorithm 1 Building the hierarchical clusters. Input: Query q, Dependency tree tree, Cluster clust Output: Updated cluster c procedure BUILD CLUST(q, tree, clust) for node in tree do Get (word, POS, dependency) triplet from node Put q in clust[word, POS, dependency] if node has subtree then BUILD CLUST(q, subtree, clust[word, POS, dependency]) dition, we used trigram language model <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Kneser and Ney, 1995)</ref> probability to obtain queries with higher natural language probabilities. The final dataset contains 1.02 million unique queries.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.4">Clustering</head><p>The algorithm for formulating the clusters is shown in Algorithm 1. For the convenience of discussion, let us consider the following two sen- tences: "I want to watch a movie" and "We want to watch football games". We extract the corre- sponding dependency tree using Google's "Syn- taxNet" <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Andor et al., 2016</ref>) parser as shown in <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref>. Representing the tree as a directed acyclic graph, each token becomes a node and each dependency relation is a directed edge be- tween two nodes.</p><p>Our clustering algorithm (Algorithm 1) is de- signed to group queries together if they have the same subpath (including the part-of-speech) in their dependency tree. Clusters are formed in a recursive manner, starting from the root. At ev- ery step, new sub-clusters are constructed based on the neighboring nodes (i.e. nodes receiving an edge from the current node). The landing node and the outgoing edge becomes the label of the sub- cluster: a triplet of the word, the part-of-speech, and the dependency relation (e.g., a/DT/det), which contains all queries with the same path starting from the root. For example, notice that both sentences in <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref>  user to jump back-and-forth between the different levels of granularity through its novel interface.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.5">Interface</head><p>The SYNTAVIZ interface is shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 2</ref>. It consists of two panes: the left pane lists la- bels of all the sub-clusters for the current clus- ter; the right pane lists all queries within the cur- rent cluster associated with other relevant informa- tion. We sort the list of sub-clusters on the left side by number of unique queries (descending)- this helps to prioritize clusters with highest im- pact. Clicking on the label of a sub-cluster allows the user to navigate deep into the clusters contain- ing increasingly (syntactically) similar queries. A breadcrumb shows the current position in the hier- archical cluster and also allows the users to navi- gate back to the upper level clusters. In the right pane, each query contains the action taken by the existing intent understanding system. This allows the users to quickly explore the failure points of the system. The queries are also accompanied by the frequencies of their occurrences in the dataset, and a list of sub-clusters that each query belongs to. Given the syntax-driven query ontology, we needed to decide the ranking of the sub-clusters (left pane) and queries (right pane) as well. In or- der to prioritize high-impact queries, we sort the list on the right side by a descending frequency of occurrences in the dataset. This arrangement provides an idea of the distribution of the queries to the user because the most prevalent ones are ranked higher in the order. In addition, a histogram of all the actions taken by the intent understanding system is shown on the upper right, which makes it possible to quickly notice any red flags in terms of system correctness.  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">User Study</head><p>We conducted quantitative, qualitative and heuris- tic experiments with the users of the SYNTAVIZ interface. There were 8 participants in the study among which four were editors/annotators from the voice NLP and the customer service project, three were developers of the voice NLP project, and one was the project manager of the customer service project. All of the participants were famil- iar with the voice queries and the existing intent understanding methods.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">Quantitative Evaluation</head><p>Several metrics were computed based on re- sponses to statements shown in <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table 1</ref> where the participants rated whether they agree, disagree, or remain neutral with respect to each statement. We use Q1 for measuring the usefulness, Q2, Q3 for usability, Q4, Q5 for efficiency, and Q6 for the practical value of the system.</p><p>The results of the evaluation are shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Fig- ure 3</ref>. Six out of eight participants agreed that SYNTAVIZ helped them to quickly find the ma- jor patterns of mistakes. This shows that SYN- TAVIZ provides useful information to achieve its intended use-finding patterns of mistakes in the existing system. Seven participants disagreed with the statement that the interface is complex (Q2) and six agreed that no help is needed to use the in- terface (Q3). The evidence that SYNTAVIZ does not cause cognitive overload or require outside help implies that it is intuitively usable. In terms of efficiency, six participants agreed that it does not take much time to learn (Q4), half of the to- tal participants seem to be confused at some point while using the interface. We analyzed this issue in the subjective evaluation which is described in the following subsection. Finally, the majority of the participants (5 out of 8) mentioned that they will use SYNTAVIZ in their regular workflow.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">Qualitative Evaluation</head><p>We asked for subjective opinions from the partic- ipants for a qualitative evaluation of SYNTAVIZ. Each participant was asked to write about the pos- itive features, negative features, important future additions, and the impact of the interface in their current workflow. These comments provided us a spectrum of information regarding the SYNTAVIZ interface which are discussed below.</p><p>Positive Aspects. A number of positive aspects of the SYNTAVIZ interface were mentioned. Almost all the participants appreciated that the combina- tion of syntactic ontology and the action histogram makes it easier to understand where the existing system is failing.</p><p>"The interface makes it clear that syn- tactic information is very useful for drilling down the long tail of VREX commands. Once I have drilled down a few levels deep, I start to see utterances where the system failed."</p><p>They also appreciated the frequency-based rank- ing scheme which helped them to "know the weight of the queries and decide priorities". In addition, every participant commented positively about the simple interaction experience.</p><p>"Simple, easy-to-learn design. Did not take long to get used to the layout and multiple sorting and drill-down features. Almost no load time. Useful and spe- cific information."</p><p>Measures for Quantitative Evaluation Q1: SYNTAVIZ allowed me to quickly find major patterns of mistakes in the deployed system Q2: The interaction was unnecessarily complex. Q3: I did not need assistance to use SYNTAVIZ. Q4: SYNTAVIZ does not take much time to learn. Q5: I never felt confused/lost while using the interface. Q6: If available, I'll use SYNTAVIZ in my regular workflow.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Measures for Qualitative Evaluation</head><p>Please write some useful aspects of SYNTAVIZ Please write some aspects of the interface that could be improved upon. Please also suggest why the proposed approach would be an improvement over the existing solution. Please enlist some possible features that should be added in the future iterations of the interface. Please also explain why. What immediate changes/benefits can this tool bring in your current workflow? Negative Aspects. The quantitative analysis re- vealed that some of the users felt confused or lost while using the interface. The underlying rea- son for such rating became clear in the qualita- tive evaluation. Many participants mentioned that the labels of the clusters are not immediately un- derstandable. The cluster names included parts- of-speech tags from Penn Treeback Project <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Santorini, 1990</ref>) (e.g. NN for Noun, JJ for Adjective), and dependency type information from Universal Dependency Project ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Nivre et al., 2016)</ref>. The par- ticipants commented that these codes might con- fuse the users. They suggested a pop-up legend or glossary would be helpful in this situation.</p><p>"I believe that the naming can be hard to understand for many people. QID is not necessarily intuitive and for anyone who operates on a higher level, they may not be aware of what a subcluster is or what the "nn root" means after the groups on the first page."</p><p>A few participants mentioned that it is problematic to navigate back to the parent clusters by clicking the back button multiple times, suggesting a Back to Home button. In addition, these comments sug- gest that the existence or use of the breadcrumb is not obvious in the interface.   Possible Future Additions. We asked the users to suggest future additions to the interface and re- ceived a number of ideas that can improve the in- terface and user experience. For example, sev- eral users asked for a search capability within the interface. Interaction on SYNTAVIZ is currently exploratory and thus the experience is similar to browsing through a tree. However, the users might need to search for a specific keyword and navigate quickly to the corresponding clusters.</p><p>"Allow the user to search for a word (or words) eg the word 'card': card NN ROOT|credit NN nn| and change VB ROOT|card NN dobj| -I wanted to find instances of 'credit card' as some of those queries may have different labels. Allow the user to filter on Action so that the user can view only queries for that action; Allow users to export queries that may need to be fixed" Participants also mentioned some other useful features; for instance, adjusting the time span for the dataset, searching and filtering for a specific action, and comparing multiple clusters. All these ideas are implementable in a future iteration while staying within the design of the proposed visual framework. Impact. Many participants mentioned that SYN- TAVIZ will allow them to identify outliers in the data or systemic errors in the deployed system, and that it will help them to identify unsupported pat- terns. This was considered useful for feature pri- oritization from a product point of view:</p><p>"Feature prioritization will be a big problem to solve from a product point of view. From research point of view this give great understanding of how the data is getting clustered among queries and find potential bugs and loop holes in our NLP system."</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3">Heuristic Evaluation</head><p>In this section, we describe a usage scenario based on the informal discussions with the de- velopers of the X1 platform: Upon studying the ranked lists, one developer noticed a cluster la- beled record/VB/ROOT, which refers to the group of 4587 unique queries that share the root verb "record". One of the largest sub-clusters is oscars/NNS/dobj, referring to the group of queries where the customers were interested in recording the Oscars event. 1 Clicking on this sub- cluster provides great insight into how customers use voice, as well as queries mishandled by the de- ployed system. The histogram on the upper right immediately revealed that around 60% of queries were categorized by the system as a SEARCH in- tent, whereas only 20% were linked to the correct (RECORD) intent. Discussions among engineers resulted in several action items to fix such issues and provide a more consistent user experience.</p><p>These errors might have seemed obvious after a short session with SYNTAVIZ, but such infor- mation is usually buried deep under the large pile of popular queries. We observed first-hand that a syntax-driven ontology is very useful at highlight- ing many other patterns in how customers use nat- ural language to query the platform.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Conclusions</head><p>In conclusion, SYNTAVIZ is a novel visualiza- tion interface for datasets with a large number of unique natural-language queries. It is based on a hierarchical clustering of all queries, designed from a syntax-driven ontology of the dataset.</p><p>Evaluation of SYNTAVIZ shows strong evi- dence that the system provides useful informa- tion for finding the errors in the existing system. Based on real needs of a major voice-enabled en- tertainment platform, our preliminary implemen- tation has shown great promise to improve soft- ware development cycles by providing useful ana- lytics that help fix bugs, as well as prioritize future efforts in a data-driven fashion.</p><p>By releasing the source code of SYNTAVIZ, we are hoping to share these benefits with many other teams across the industry. The complete source code of SyntaViz is available in https://github.com/Comcast/SyntaViz</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 1: Examples of dependency trees.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2: The complete SYNTAVIZ interface.</figDesc><graphic url="image-1.png" coords="4,73.00,62.81,382.57,147.93" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>0</head><label>0</label><figDesc></figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head>Figure 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Figure 3: Results of quantitative evaluation of the SYNTAVIZ interface.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" validated="false"><head>Table 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>All the measures for quantitative and qualita- tive evaluation of SYNTAVIZ.</figDesc><table></table></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> 2017 Oscars occurred during the week of our collected dataset.</note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Globally normalized transition-based neural networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Daniel</forename><surname>Andor</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ACL&apos;16</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2442" to="2452" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Representing and visualizing text as ontologies: A case from the patent domain</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Stamatia</forename><surname>Dasiopoulou</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">VOILA@ ISWC</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
			<biblScope unit="page">83</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Multiconvis: A visual text analytics system for exploring a collection of online conversations</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Enamul</forename><surname>Hoque</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Giuseppe</forename><surname>Carenini</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">IUI&apos;16</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="96" to="107" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Information overload and the message dynamics of online interaction spaces: A theoretical model and empirical exploration. Information systems research</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Quentin</forename><surname>Jones</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="194" to="210" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Speech and language processing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dan</forename><surname>Jurafsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>James H Martin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<editor>Prep.) Chap. 14. Pearson London</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Improved backing-off for m-gram language modeling</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Reinhard</forename><surname>Kneser</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hermann</forename><surname>Ney</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Acoustics, Speech, and Signal Processing</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>IEEE</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="181" to="184" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>International Conference on</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Universal dependencies v1: A multilingual treebank collection</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Joakim</forename><surname>Nivre</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">LREC</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Ontologyenhanced user interfaces: A survey</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Heiko</forename><surname>Paulheim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Florian</forename><surname>Probst</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">SemanticEnabled Advancements on the Web: Applications Across Industries</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="page">214</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Google i/o keynote</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Sundar Pichai</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
<note type="report_type">Presentation</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Part-of-speech tagging guidelines for the penn treebank project (3rd revision)</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Beatrice</forename><surname>Santorini</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1990" />
			<publisher>CIS</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="page">570</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
<note type="report_type">Technical Reports</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Structure-aware visualization of text corpora</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jaspreet</forename><surname>Singh</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2017 Conference on Conference Human Information Interaction and Retrieval</title>
		<meeting>the 2017 Conference on Conference Human Information Interaction and Retrieval</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="107" to="116" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">It&apos;s official: Google says more searches now on mobile than on desktop</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Greg</forename><surname>Sterling</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://searchengineland.com/its-official-google-says-more-searches-now-on-mobile-than-on-desktop-220369" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2017" to="2025" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Tiara: a visual exploratory text analytic system</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Furu</forename><surname>Wei</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 16th ACM SIGKDD international conference on Knowledge discovery and data mining</title>
		<meeting>the 16th ACM SIGKDD international conference on Knowledge discovery and data mining</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="153" to="162" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
