<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T11:36+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">APLenty: annotation tool for creating high-quality datasets using active and proactive learning</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date>October 31-November 4, 2018</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Minh-Quoc</forename><surname>Nghiem</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">School of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">National Centre for Text Mining</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">The University of Manchester</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="GB">United Kingdom</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sophia</forename><surname>Ananiadou</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">School of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">National Centre for Text Mining</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">The University of Manchester</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="GB">United Kingdom</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">APLenty: annotation tool for creating high-quality datasets using active and proactive learning</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2018 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (System Demonstrations)</title>
						<meeting>the 2018 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (System Demonstrations) <address><addrLine>Brussels; Belgium</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="108" to="113"/>
							<date type="published">October 31-November 4, 2018</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<note>108</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>In this paper, we present APLenty, an annotation tool for creating high-quality sequence labeling datasets using active and proactive learning. A major innovation of our tool is the integration of automatic annotation with active learning and proactive learning. This makes the task of creating labeled datasets easier, less time-consuming and requiring less human effort. APLenty is highly flexible and can be adapted to various other tasks.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Labeled data play a critical role in many machine learning problems. Obtaining such data is dif- ficult, time-consuming, and require a lot of hu- man effort. Many researchers have utilized active learning or proactive learning, in which a learn- ing algorithm is allowed to choose the data from which it learns <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(Settles, 2009)</ref>. The annotators, in this scenario, only have to annotate a reasonable- size set of representative and informative data. It helps reduce the human labeling effort and at the same time reduces the cost of training the machine learning models.</p><p>In recent years, there has been an increas- ing amount of libraries and systems that focus on active learning, such as the JCLAL ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Reyes et al., 2016)</ref>, the Active-Learning-Scala ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Santos and Carvalho, 2014)</ref>, or the LibAct ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">Yang et al., 2017</ref>) libraries. They implement several state- of-the-art active learning strategies in single-label and multi-label learning paradigms. These li- braries, however, have not treated sequence label- ing tasks (part-of-speech tagging, information ex- traction, . . . ) in much detail. Due to the nature of sequence labeling tasks, the learning algorithm usually gets not a single label but a sequence of labels from the annotators. Besides, to the best of our knowledge, no system offers support for proactive learning.</p><p>Up to now, far too little attention has been paid to the interaction between the annotators and the active learning algorithm. The main point of ac- tive learning is that a learning algorithm must be able to interactively query the annotators to obtain the desired outputs at new data points. The avail- able systems fail to deliver this by providing over- simplified user-interfaces for the annotators (i.e., showing the feature vector of an instance and ask- ing for the label). Such user-interfaces are not suit- able for the task since the annotators need to know the context of every instance to provide accurate annotations. Some tools provide excellent visu- alization front end, such as brat ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Stenetorp et al., 2012</ref>), PubAnnotation (Kim and Wang, 2012) or WebAnno ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Yimam et al., 2013</ref>), but unfortunately these tools provide no support for active learning.</p><p>To compensate for the lack of learning en- vironment in the well-known annotation tool, we develop APLenty (Active Proactive Learning System), a web-based system for creating anno- tated data using active/proactive learning. The main innovation of APLenty is the combination of a well-known annotation tool (brat) with ac- tive/proactive learning. Specifically:</p><p>1. Proactive learning integration: APLenty makes annotation easy, time-efficient, and re- quire less human effort by offering automatic and proactive learning.</p><p>2. An easy-to-use interface for annotators: APLenty adapts the interface of the brat rapid annotation tool, making annotation intuitive and easy to use.</p><p>3. Suitable for sequence labeling: APLenty is best used for sequence labeling tasks, al- though it can be used for other classification problems.</p><p>The remainder of this paper is organized as follows. Section 2 provides a brief overview of the related work. Section 3 presents details of APLenty. Section 4 describes a case study of using APLenty for named-entity recognition task. Sec- tion 5 concludes the paper and points to avenues for future work.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Related work</head><p>There are many tools available for active learn- ing, such as the JCLAL ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Reyes et al., 2016)</ref>, the Active-Learning-Scala ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Santos and Carvalho, 2014)</ref>, or the LibAct ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">Yang et al., 2017</ref>) libraries. Among those, JCLAL includes the most state-of- the-art strategies for active learning. Other tools such as Vowpal Wabbit 1 or TexNLP ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Baldridge and Palmer, 2009</ref>) also include some active learn- ing methods. These tools, however, do not focus on the interaction with the annotators (the user- interface).</p><p>BRAT ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Stenetorp et al., 2012</ref>) is one of the most well-known annotation tools that offer easy- to-use user-interfaces. BRAT has been developed for rich structured annotation and uses a vector graphics-based visualization component for ren- dering. BRAT can, at the same time, display many annotation layers. <ref type="bibr">WebAnno (Yimam et al., 2013</ref>) improves the annotation interface of BRAT by letting the annotators choose the annotation layer(s) for rendering. WebAnno offers a purely web-based generic annotation tool and supports distributed annotation. PubAnnotation <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Kim and Wang, 2012</ref>) also offers a web-based annotation interface but its main focus is to improve the reusability of corpora and annotations. These tools do not support active/proactive learning.</p><p>DUALIST (Settles, 2011; Settles and Zhu, 2012) and Prodigy 2 are most closely related to APLenty. DUALIST is an active learning anno- tation paradigm that offers annotation interface for semi-supervised active learning. Prodigy is a com- mercial product which provides an annotation tool powered by active learning. Unfortunately, both DUALIST and Prodigy do not support proactive learning.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">APLenty</head><p>APLenty is a web-based tool implemented in Java using Apache Wicket web framework and JavaScript. The overall architecture of APLenty is depicted in <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref>. The user interface consists of a project management page and an annotation page. Below, this section describes APLenty in detail.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Project management</head><p>In APLenty system, we have two main types of user: annotator and project manager. The annota- tors can only annotate text assigned to them while a project manager can create and customize anno- tation projects. The interface lets the project man- ager to:</p><p>1. create a project 2. upload the training, test, and unlabelled data to the web server 3. define the tagset 4. assign annotators to a project 5. choose the active/proactive learning strategy.</p><p>The system predefines some common tags, but the manager can override these by uploading a tagset file.</p><p>There are three types of data that the project manager can upload. The first one is the train- ing data, which will be used to train the machine learning model. The second one is the testing data, which will be used to test the performance of the system after each annotation step. The last one is the unlabelled data, on which the annotators will work. Training and testing data is not required, but unlabelled data is mandatory. When there is no training data, the active learning algorithm will choose the longest sentences for annotation.</p><p>APLenty currently supports data using <ref type="bibr">CoNLL2003</ref> </p><note type="other">format and XML Metadata Interchange (XMI) format. Since APLenty is based on the Apache Unstructured Information Management Architecture (UIMA) framework 3 , new formats can be supported easily. UIMA enables the appli- cation to be decomposed into components. Out of which, a collection reader component is respon- sible for reading documents in a specific format. By swapping the collection reader component, one can allow APLenty to support data in different for- mat.</note><p>The test set is optionally used to evaluate the annotation process. By providing the test set, the project manager can see the learning curve of the active learning method. This evaluation step is skipped if there is no test set.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Annotation interface</head><p>For annotation and visualization of annotated doc- uments, we adapted the WebAnno annotation in- terface, which in turn, adapted the brat rapid anno- tation tool. Since the initial purpose of APLenty is sequence labeling, the smallest unit we consider is a sentence. The annotation interface only displays one sentence to the annotator at a time. It helps the annotator to focus on the current sentence. <ref type="figure">Fig- ure 2</ref> shows the annotation interface.</p><p>When working on APLenty, the annotator se- lects a span of text on the displayed sentence and chooses a tag for that span. The annotator does not need to save the annotation since every an- notation is automatically sent to the web server (via Ajax using JSON format). The annotator has the possibility to skip annotating a sentence. By choosing skip, the algorithm marks the sentence as "skipped" and does not consider that sentence in the next annotation round for this specific annota- tor. When the annotator completed an active learn- ing iteration step, APLenty will trigger the training process with newly annotated data and update the sentences for the next annotation batch.</p><p>The annotation ends when stopping criteria are met. A project manager can have several ways to define the stopping criteria: the algorithm reaches a predefined number of iteration, or the dataset reaches a predefined number of instances, or the result on the test set reaches a predefined amount. The learning process has been completed when the stopping criteria are met. The annotators, how- ever, can stop anytime they want and resume the process later.</p><p>The project manager can increase the annota- tion speed by turning on automation. APLenty, in this case, automatically annotates certain spans of text (based on the model available from the pre- vious active learning iteration round). The anno- tators are then required to label only uncertain se- quences. This approach was proved to reduce the number of tokens to be manually annotated about 60% compared to its fully supervised counterpart, and over 80% compared to a totally passive learn- ing <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">(Tomanek and Hahn, 2009)</ref>. The project man- ager can set a threshold θ for automatic annotation. If the probability of an output sequence from the machine learning model is larger than θ, the out- put sequence is accepted as valid annotation and is used as a training instance for later active learning iterations.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3">Active learning</head><p>Depending on the project manager's settings, the system will choose a query strategy for active learning. Generally, a machine learning algorithm uses the instances in the labeled set (training set) to train a model. The system then uses the model to label the instances in the unlabeled set. Every in- stance now has a score indicating how informative or representative it is. Finally, the system aggre- gates these scores to get the score of the whole sen- tence. The system sends the most informative sen- tences to the annotators, based on the sentences' scores. When the system receives the annotations, a new iteration round starts.</p><p>Active learning for sequence labeling can use different query strategies. Most common query strategies are Least Confidence <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Culotta and McCallum, 2005</ref>), Margin Sampling ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Scheffer et al., 2001</ref>), Entropy Sampling ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Mann and McCallum, 2007</ref>), Vote Entropy ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Dagan and Engelson, 1995</ref> </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.4">Proactive learning</head><p>Active learning assumes that annotators have sim- ilar level of expertise and nobody is fallible. But in reality, different annotators have different levels of expertize in a specific domain. Proactive learn- ing has been proposed to model many types of an- notators ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Donmez and Carbonell, 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Li et al., 2017)</ref>. Proactive learning assumes that there is at least one expert and one inexperienced annotator (fallible). The expert always provides correct an- notations while the fallible annotator might pro- vide incorrect annotations in certain cases. At each iteration step, the proactive learning al- gorithm selects the sentences for the annotators based on the probabilities that the annotator will provide correct labels for a sequence in a sen- tence. A recent study by <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Li et al. (2017)</ref> esti- mated the performance of each annotator based on a benchmark dataset. The system calculates the probability that an annotator provides a correct la- bel when annotating a sentence by combining the class probability and the likelihood that the anno- tator provides a correct label for the tokens in the sentence.</p><p>In the real-time annotation scenario where speed is one of the most important factors, APLenty uses a simple threshold to distribute sentences to annotators. If the probability of an output sequence from the machine learning model is smaller than , APLenty considers the sentence a hard case and sends it to the expert annotator. Otherwise, the sentence is sent to the fallible an- notator. This reduces the cost of annotation since the time of the expert is more expensive than the time of the fallible annotator.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Case study</head><p>One use case that describes the best use of APLenty is the named entities annotation. This is a multiple span annotation task.</p><p>We used the English CoNLL-2003 named entity dataset <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">(Tjong Kim Sang and De Meulder, 2003)</ref> for the case study. The dataset contains newswire articles annotated with four entities: LOC (loca- tions), MISC (miscellaneous names), ORG (or- ganizations), and PER (persons). In the experi- ment, we used 1,200 sentences as the initial train- ing data, 3,622 sentences as test data, and the rest for unlabelled data. θ is set to 0.8, is set to 0.2, batch size is set to 100.</p><p>We compare four settings in this case study. The first one is Random Sampling: the system ran- domly chooses the next sentences for annotation. The second one is Active Learning: the system uses the output of CRF model to assign sentences to an expert. The third one is Proactive Learning: same as Active Learning, but we have two anno- tators, one expert, and one fallible annotator. The last one is Active Learning with Automation: the system automatically assigns labels for sequences based on the threshold θ. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 3</ref> shows the learning curves of the four settings. In all cases, active/proactive learning set- ting outperformed Random Sampling setting. It can be seen that the last three settings achieved peak performance when we reached 50th iteration. Combining active learning and automation lead to best performance. This result may be explained by the fact that the system got more reliable data for training after every iteration.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Conclusion and future work</head><p>We introduced APLenty, a web-based open en- vironment for constructing annotated datasets us- ing active and proactive learning while leveraging the functionalities of the popular annotation edi-  tor brat. APLenty can support the quick develop- ment of high-quality labeled data needed to train and evaluate text mining tools for different appli- cations. Existing annotation editors do not provide such an integrated environment which can quickly produce labeled data while at the same time taking into account different levels of expertise of anno- tators.</p><p>A key feature of APLenty is how it supports the automation for sequences with high confidence to be included (certain sequences), thus allowing the annotators to focus only on the uncertain ones. We have demonstrated that this feature enables anno- tators to create high-quality labeled datasets in less time than other settings.</p><p>Considerably more work will need to be done to: 1. extend our work for link annota- tion; 2. further enhance APLenty to work with other active/proactive learning criteria; 3. evaluate APLenty in a complete data creation; 4. enhance centralize repository of annotation such as PubAn- notation.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>1</head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 1: System architecture</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 2: Annotation interface</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Figure 3: Learning curve</figDesc></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="3"> https://uima.apache.org/</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>This research has been carried out with funding from BBSRC BB/P025684/1 and BB/M006891/1. We would like to thank the anonymous reviewers for their helpful comments.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">How well does active learning actually work?: Time-based evaluation of cost-reduction strategies for language documentation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jason</forename><surname>Baldridge</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alexis</forename><surname>Palmer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2009 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</title>
		<meeting>the 2009 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="296" to="305" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Reducing labeling effort for structured prediction tasks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Aron</forename><surname>Culotta</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Andrew</forename><surname>Mccallum</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">AAAI</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="746" to="751" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Committeebased sampling for training probabilistic classifiers</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ido</forename><surname>Dagan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Sean P Engelson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Machine Learning Proceedings</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Elsevier</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="150" to="157" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">From active to proactive learning methods</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Pinar</forename><surname>Donmez</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Advances in Machine Learning I</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="97" to="120" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Pubannotation: a persistent and sharable corpus and annotation repository</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jin-Dong</forename><surname>Kim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yue</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2012 Workshop on Biomedical Natural Language Processing</title>
		<meeting>the 2012 Workshop on Biomedical Natural Language Processing</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="202" to="205" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Association for Computational Linguistics</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Proactive learning for named entity recognition</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Maolin</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nhung</forename><surname>Nguyen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sophia</forename><surname>Ananiadou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="117" to="125" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Efficient computation of entropy gradient for semisupervised conditional random fields</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Gideon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Andrew</forename><surname>Mann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Mccallum</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Human Language Technologies 2007: The Conference of the North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics; Companion Volume, Short Papers</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="109" to="112" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Association for Computational Linguistics</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">CRFsuite: a fast implementation of Conditional Random Fields (CRFs)</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Naoaki</forename><surname>Okazaki</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">JCLAL: a Java framework for active learning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Oscar</forename><surname>Reyes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Eduardo</forename><surname>Pérez</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">María</forename><surname>Del Carmen Rodríguez-Hernández</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sebastián</forename><surname>Habib M Fardoun</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Ventura</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The Journal of Machine Learning Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3271" to="3275" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Comparison of active learning strategies and proposal of a multiclass hypothesis space search</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Davi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Santos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Cplf</forename><surname>André</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Carvalho</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Hybrid Artificial Intelligence Systems</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="618" to="629" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Active hidden Markov models for information extraction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tobias</forename><surname>Scheffer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christian</forename><surname>Decomain</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Stefan</forename><surname>Wrobel</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">International Symposium on Intelligent Data Analysis</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="309" to="318" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Active learning literature survey</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Burr</forename><surname>Settles</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>1648</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>University of Wisconsin-Madison</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
<note type="report_type">Computer Sciences Technical Report</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Closing the loop: Fast, interactive semi-supervised annotation with queries on features and instances</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Burr</forename><surname>Settles</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the conference on empirical methods in natural language processing</title>
		<meeting>the conference on empirical methods in natural language processing</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1467" to="1478" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Association for Computational Linguistics</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">An analysis of active learning strategies for sequence labeling tasks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Burr</forename><surname>Settles</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mark</forename><surname>Craven</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the conference on empirical methods in natural language processing</title>
		<meeting>the conference on empirical methods in natural language processing</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1070" to="1079" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Multiple-instance active learning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Burr</forename><surname>Settles</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mark</forename><surname>Craven</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Soumya</forename><surname>Ray</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Advances in neural information processing systems</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1289" to="1296" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Behavioral factors in interactive training of text classifiers</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Burr</forename><surname>Settles</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xiaojin</forename><surname>Zhu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2012 Conference of the North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics: Human Language Technologies</title>
		<meeting>the 2012 Conference of the North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics: Human Language Technologies</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="563" to="567" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Association for Computational Linguistics</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">BRAT: a web-based tool for NLP-assisted text annotation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Pontus</forename><surname>Stenetorp</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sampo</forename><surname>Pyysalo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Goran</forename><surname>Topi´ctopi´c</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tomoko</forename><surname>Ohta</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sophia</forename><surname>Ananiadou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jun&amp;apos;ichi</forename><surname>Tsujii</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Demonstrations at the 13th Conference of the European Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the Demonstrations at the 13th Conference of the European Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="102" to="107" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Association for Computational Linguistics</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Introduction to the CoNLL-2003 shared task: Language-independent named entity recognition</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Erik F Tjong Kim</forename><surname>Sang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Fien De</forename><surname>Meulder</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the seventh conference on Natural language learning at HLT-NAACL 2003</title>
		<meeting>the seventh conference on Natural language learning at HLT-NAACL 2003</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="142" to="147" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Association for Computational Linguistics</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Semisupervised active learning for sequence labeling</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Katrin</forename><surname>Tomanek</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Udo</forename><surname>Hahn</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Joint Conference of the 47th Annual Meeting of the ACL and the 4th International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing of the AFNLP</title>
		<meeting>the Joint Conference of the 47th Annual Meeting of the ACL and the 4th International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing of the AFNLP</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1039" to="1047" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">libact: Pool-based active learning in Python</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yao-Yuan</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Shao-Chuan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yu-An</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tung-En</forename><surname>Chung</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Si-An</forename><surname>Wu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hsuan-Tien</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Lin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://arxiv.org/abs/1710.00379" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">National Taiwan University. Available as arXiv preprint</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
<note type="report_type">Technical report</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">WebAnno: A flexible, web-based and visually supported system for distributed annotations</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Iryna</forename><surname>Seid Muhie Yimam</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Richard</forename><surname>Gurevych</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chris</forename><surname>Eckart De Castilho</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Biemann</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 51st Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics: System Demonstrations</title>
		<meeting>the 51st Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics: System Demonstrations</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="6" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
