<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T12:27+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Visualizing Group Dynamics based on Multiparty Meeting Understanding</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date>October 31-November 4, 2018</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ni</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tongtao</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Indrani</forename><surname>Bhattacharya</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Department of Electrical, Computer</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Systems Engineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Heng</forename><surname>Ji</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Richard</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Radke</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Department of Electrical, Computer</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Systems Engineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Visualizing Group Dynamics based on Multiparty Meeting Understanding</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2018 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (System Demonstrations)</title>
						<meeting>the 2018 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (System Demonstrations) <address><addrLine>Brussels; Belgium</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="96" to="101"/>
							<date type="published">October 31-November 4, 2018</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<note>96</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Group discussions are usually aimed at sharing opinions, reaching consensus and making good decisions based on group knowledge. During a discussion, participants might adjust their own opinions as well as tune their attitudes towards others&apos; opinions, based on the unfolding interactions. In this paper, we demonstrate a framework to visualize such dynamics ; at each instant of a conversation, the participants&apos; opinions and potential influence on their counterparts is easily visualized. We use multi-party meeting opinion mining based on bipartite graphs to extract opinions and calculate mutual influential factors, using the Lunar Survival Task as a study case.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Group meetings are pervasive in modern work- places, consuming workers' time and energy. Reaching consensus and making decisions more efficiently are major challenges. For example, dur- ing a meeting, some of the participants might in- sist on their own opinions towards the discussed items or topics, while others might rapidly change opinions and attitudes. As a meeting unfolds, we can observe developing leadership characteristics among the participants; for example, some partic- ipants may speak more assertively to drive deci- sive conclusions and steer the meeting, while oth- ers may follow the crowd and merely deliver tiny ideas.</p><p>In order to track the dynamics that reflect the change of opinions and the procedure of decision making, we require a meeting assistant that works in real time. That is, the assistant should keep track of the agenda and discussion process as a minute or note-taker, as well as record and assess the influence and contribution of each participant.</p><p>In this paper, using the NASA Lunar Survival Task 1 as a study case, we present an automatic meeting assistant with the following functionali- ties:</p><p>• The assistant detects and extracts participants' opinions from their speech and visualizes the groups' instantaneous state (ranking of items) based on current and previous utterances.</p><p>• The assistant visualizes an influence factor for each participant using current and previous ut- terances in real time. Using this information, emerging leadership in the group can be visual- ized.</p><p>The proposed assistant begins with speech recognition output, and detects the opinions from the speakers with Natural Language Processing (NLP) tools. We propose a bipartite graph formal- ism to assess participants' influence.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">System Overview</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">Study Case Introduction</head><p>The NASA Lunar Survival Task is a widely used group consensus exercise that helps encourage the development of communication, cooperation, and decision making skills <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Hall and Watson, 1970)</ref>. In small groups of 3-4, participants discuss a hy- pothetical survival scenario and rank the value of supplies that may aid in their survival and safe rendezvous with their mothership. Before the dis- cussion, each participant is asked to independently rank the items. Next, the participants are asked to reach consensus on the ranking with active verbal interaction. Each member of the group must agree upon the final ranking, which acts as the group de- cision. Influence Curves over Time <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref>: Main interface of our proposed meeting assistant. <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref> illustrates the interface of the meeting as- sistant 2 . A video window shows the meeting scene. In this window, we use red circles to denote the par- ticipants. The sizes of the circles denote the aggre- gated influence factors of participants; the larger the circle is, the more influence (i.e., contribution to the conversation) the participant possesses.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">Interface Details</head><p>Beneath the video window we provide the cur- rent speaker and speech. The raw speech is pro- cessed by IBM Watson's Speech to Text System 3 , and we use the text output to detect discus- sion/focus items and extract speakers' opinions as detailed further below.</p><p>On the right side, we place a real-time rank- ing list for items that have been discussed. As the discussion proceeds, the ranking list expands with newly involved items. We also illustrate the current focus item of each participant and her/his proposed rank of the focused item with a col- ored edge. The colors of item circles and opin-ion edges denote different rankings; greener items have higher rankings and redder items have lower rankings.</p><p>At the bottom, we illustrate curves indicating instantaneous influence factors from each partic- ipant in real time based on the current speech. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 2</ref> illustrates a series of screenshots from our proposed meeting assistant. Three participants attend the meeting and start the discussion about several items. In <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 2a</ref> and 2b, the meet- ing was in an early stage, and there is no differ- ence among the participants in terms of influence. As the discussion continues in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 2c</ref> and 2d, where more items have been discussed, the curves of influence fluctuate and imply differences in ac- tivity among participants. Moreover, the rank- ings of discussed items are adjusted according to the speech and extracted opinions as mentioned above.</p><p>Finally, as shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 2f</ref>, from the size of the red circles representing aggregated influ- ences and the historical record of the curves, we can conclude that Person 1 and Person 2 are contributing more in the discussion, while Person 3 is less active.   </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Opinion Detection and Extraction</head><p>Our system takes as input transcribed meeting speech, sentence by sentence, and outputs real- time rankings (opinion words) of the items after each participant expresses her/his thoughts.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Opinion Word Identification</head><p>In the context of the Lunar Survival Task discus- sion, we observed that participants express their opinions of item rankings in multiple ways, in- cluding 1. Explicitly mentioning an item with its rank- ing(e.g., "</p><p>In my opinion, we should put water as the second most important.") 2. Agreement or disagreement (e.g., "Yeah, I</p><p>agree.") 3. Comparison of the items by relative ranking (e.g., "Matches are less important than signal flares because they don't work on the moon.")</p><p>In the first scenario of a participant proposing an item ranking, we use the Stanford CoreNLP ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Manning et al., 2014</ref>) name tagger to extract the NUMBERs and ORDINALs mentioned in the dis- cussion ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Finkel et al., 2005</ref>). We also eliminated numbers beyond 15 and numbers that are parts of pronouns such "this one". Additionally, in this specific discussion, people use "last" or "least" to imply they are ranking the item at 15 and we also implemented this rule.</p><p>As for the second scenario, people typically express agreement/disagreement with the person who talked immediately before them ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Abu-Jbara et al., 2012</ref>). For agreement, we assume the cur- rent speaker accepts the previous speaker's stated opinion, which means we pass the weights cap- tured for the previous person to the current speaker if we find the expression of agreement in the cur- rent sentence. We found that expressions of dis- agreement are not useful since people typically ex- press their own opinion following their disagree- ment.</p><p>We currently do not deal with the third scenario of relative rankings, because no definitive ranking can be extracted from such statements.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Target Identification and Ranking</head><p>In this step, we identify discussed items in the dis- cussion. As participants must have a very con- densed discussion of these 15 items in a relatively short time, they usually mention the items with the exact words from the list they are given. Thus, we take the nouns and noun phrases as chunks and if any word matches with the nouns in the given list, it is recognized as the item in the given list.</p><p>So far, we have the opinion words and potential targets annotated in the conversation, and we want to pair them up and find the target of the ranking. It has been shown in previous work on relation ex- traction that the shortest dependency path between any two entities captures the information required to assert a relationship between them (Bunescu and <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Mooney, 2005</ref>). Based on the observation that people tend to mention items and their related ranks close to each other, we pair the item with the rank found in its shortest dependency path.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Bipartite Graph Construction</head><p>We propose an assessment method of the influ- ence factors among participants based on bipartite graphs.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">Dynamic Update of Weights and Vertices</head><p>We construct a directed bipartite graph G = (U ∪ V, E), where the vertices U represent the partic- ipants in the discussion, the vertices V represent the items, and E denotes the edges between these vertices. u i denotes the ith vertex or participants' cumulative informative score in U . v j is the jth vertex or item ranking in V .</p><p>In the Lunar Survival scenario, we observed that the information given in the conversation is very helpful in getting the right result and reaching con- sensus. To reflect this observation, we have total number of sentences so far for each speaker in the conversation as an informativeness indicator. The edges of the bipartite graph carry weights w ij , rep- resenting the relationship between vertices u i and v j , i.e., u i 's current ranking of v j . Thus, we can represent all the edge weights of the graph as a |U | × |V | matrix W = [w ij ]. With the item-rank pair extracted, we dynamically update W , and cal- culate v j as i w ij i .</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">Influence Model</head><p>We implemented an influence model (IM) ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Basu et al., 2001</ref>) to track and understand the partici- pants' opinion behaviors. We model the partici- pants' opinion shifts as a Markov chain with each state representing a user's opinion on the item. We use the coupled HMM to correlate the influence of the opinions among multiple participants. Each participant i has a chain of rankings on the items at time t denoted S i t . We assume that</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">P (S i t |S 1 t−1 , ..., S N t−1 ) = j α ij P (S i t |S j t−1 ), (1)</formula><p>where α ij (calculated from the model) can tell us how much the state transition of person i is influ- enced by the given neighbor j. This observed IM is characterized by (Φ, A), where Φ is the state transition probability matrix, and A is the influence strength vector. At any time t, we calculate the pairwise transition probabil- ity matrix P (S i t |S j t−1 ) by counting, and determine α ij using the constrained gradient ascent method to maximize per-chain likelihood.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Experiments</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.1">Dataset Construction</head><p>We curated 5 meetings and transferred the recorded voice to the texts using IBM Watson's Speech-to-Text API ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Saon et al., 2017</ref>). The con- versations are 10-15 minutes long and have an av- erage of 412 sentences. we collected the initial and final rankings of the items from each person using pre-and post-discussion questionnaires. We <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>: Information extraction measures performed the opinion extraction and target pair- ing as described in Section 3 for the 5 meetings.</p><note type="other">Team ID Precision Recall F1 score Team 1 0.53 0.21 0.31 Team 2 0.65 0.55 0.6 Team 3 0.71 0.62 0.66 Team 4 0.65 0.33 0.44 Team 5 0.59 0.70 0.64</note><p>The extraction precision and accuracy compared to human annotated ground truth is summarized in <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>. The precision is defined as the fraction of correct ranks among all ranks retrieved from the conversation, and recall is the fraction of correct ranks that have been retrieved over all the ranks supposed to be retrieved as in ground truth.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.2">Meeting Dynamics Analysis</head><p>We see that groups have very distinct opinions on the 15 items before each meeting, and that they all achieved consensus at the final stage of the meet- ing. From the playback of the meeting assistant videos, we have a very clear view of the unfold- ing speech content that influences the participants' state of mind. We observed the following patterns that corre- late with a participant's influence: 1. Approval of other people first, followed by stat- ing clearly the opinion on an item (e.g., <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Figure  3</ref>) 2. Detailed explanation of the reason to choose a specific rank (e.g., "It's a two hundred mile trek so you need some sort of sustenance for the hu- man body.") 3. Drawing attention before a statement (e.g., "OK so proposition hear me out. We're at nine now right? If we're going forward so what if we put milk powder as ten?")</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Related Work</head><p>Opinion target extraction and pairing: In our context, the targets are constrained to 15 items given beforehand, but they appear in different forms in the conversation. In the context of prod- uct review mining, ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Hu and Liu, 2004</ref>) extracted frequent nouns and noun phrases as product fea- ture candidates. Following that method, (Abu- Jbara et al., 2012) extracted frequent noun phrases As for opinion extraction, various methods were used in different contexts. <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(Kim and Hovy, 2006</ref>) collected opinion-bearing words and classified them into 3 classes. ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Ortigosa et al., 2014</ref>) also studied opinion from 3 classes. Since in our case, the opinion on an item is restricted to a ranking of 1-15, we used name tagging results to identify the ordinals and numbers mentioned in the conversa- tion.</p><p>Group dynamics studies: Most group dynam- ics studies to date of role recognition or influ- ence studies are based on non-linguistic features. ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Rienks and Heylen, 2005</ref>) used audio-only fea- tures including a collection of nonverbal and ver- bal cues to perform three-way classification of the participants dominance level. ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Beyan et al., 2018</ref>) acquired audio and visual features and predicted emergent leadership with multiple kernel learn- ing. Our group has extended the system proposed here to include non-verbal and visual cues to ac- curately predict emergent leadership and contribu- tion ( <ref type="bibr">Bhattacharya et al., 2018)</ref>.</p><p>When modeling opinion shifts, we referred to ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Chen et al., 2017</ref>) but noticed that these are less complicated in face-to-face conversation than in a social network. <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Asavathiratham, 2001</ref>) first pro- posed a simplified coupled-HMM influence model to understand the behaviors of a large number of interacting components. ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Basu et al., 2001</ref>) ex- panded the theory and proposed a gradient ascent method to learn the influence model.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7">Conclusion and future work</head><p>In this paper we demonstrate a system for meeting assistance, visualizing real-time opinion extrac- tion and group dynamics. We use the Lunar Sur- vival Task to observe how people gradually change their opinions and make decisions. With the cur- rent meeting assistant tool, we have a closed set of 15 items given in advance and a fixed set of ranks. In future work, we plan to develop infor- mation extraction systems that handle open sets and detect multiple topics in a meeting. The opin- ions extracted could be used to study group dy- namics and recognize roles in meetings, extending the scope of the meeting assistant to more general scenarios.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="8">Acknowledgements</head><p>Thanks to Mike Foley, Christoph Riedl and Brooke Foucault Welles at Northeastern Univer- sity for the experimental design. This work was supported by the U.S. National Science Founda- tion No. IIP-1631674. The views and conclusions contained in this document are those of the authors and should not be interpreted as representing the official policies, either expressed or implied, of the U.S. Government. The U.S. Government is autho- rized to reproduce and distribute reprints for Gov- ernment purposes notwithstanding any copyright notation here on.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>(</head><label></label><figDesc>a) Beginning of the conversation. (b) Different ideas about which items to rank first. (c) Adjusting the ranking of water; adding life raft. (d) Fine-tuning water and life raft.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>(</head><label></label><figDesc>e) Proceeding with other items. (f) A substantially complete list at the end of discussion.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2: Screenshots of the meeting assistant at different points in time.</figDesc><graphic url="image-6.png" coords="3,75.17,388.09,222.24,145.71" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>Figure 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Figure 3: Example of arguments with stronger influence.</figDesc><graphic url="image-8.png" coords="5,314.36,62.81,204.08,177.44" type="bitmap" /></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> https://t.co/5e56cHayji</note>

			<note place="foot" n="2"> A short video clip illustrating the meeting assistant can be viewed at https://youtu.be/3_YS0ZGQNQo. 3 https://www.ibm.com/watson/services/ speech-to-text/</note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Subgroup detection in ideological discussions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Amjad</forename><surname>Abu-Jbara</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mona</forename><surname>Diab</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Pradeep</forename><surname>Dasigi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dragomir</forename><surname>Radev</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">50th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics: Long Papers</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="399" to="409" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The Influence Model: A Tractable Representation for the Dynamics of Networked Markov Chains</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chalee</forename><surname>Asavathiratham</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>Massachusetts Institute of Technology</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
<note type="report_type">Ph.D. thesis</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Learning human interactions with the influence model</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sumit</forename><surname>Basu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tanzeem</forename><surname>Choudhury</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Brian</forename><surname>Clarkson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alex</forename><surname>Pentland</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Prediction of the leadership style of an emergent leader using audio and visual nonverbal features</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Cigdem</forename><surname>Beyan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Francesca</forename><surname>Capozzi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Cristina</forename><surname>Becchio</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Vittorio</forename><surname>Murino</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE Transactions on Multimedia</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="441" to="456" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Indrani</forename><surname>Bhattacharya</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Foley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ni</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tongtao</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christine</forename><surname>Ku</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Cameron</forename><surname>Mine</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Heng</forename><surname>Ji</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christoph</forename><surname>Riedl</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Brooke Foucault Welles</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A multimodal-sensorenabled room for unobtrusive group meeting analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Richard</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Radke</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ACM International Conference on Multimodal Interaction</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A shortest path dependency kernel for relation extraction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Razvan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Raymond J</forename><surname>Bunescu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Mooney</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Conference on Human Language Technology and Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="724" to="731" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Association for Computational Linguistics</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Exploring interpersonal influence by tracking user dynamic interactions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chengyao</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wenjie</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dehong</forename><surname>Gao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yuexian</forename><surname>Hou</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE Intelligent Systems</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">32</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="28" to="35" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Incorporating non-local information into information extraction systems by Gibbs sampling</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jenny</forename><forename type="middle">Rose</forename><surname>Finkel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Trond</forename><surname>Grenager</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christopher</forename><surname>Manning</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">43rd Annual Meeting on Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="363" to="370" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The effects of a normative intervention on group decisionmaking performance</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jay</forename><surname>Hall</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wilfred</forename><forename type="middle">Harvey</forename><surname>Watson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Human Relations</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">23</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="299" to="317" />
			<date type="published" when="1970" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Mining and summarizing customer reviews</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Minqing</forename><surname>Hu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bing</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ACM SIGKDD International Conference on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="168" to="177" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Extracting opinions, opinion holders, and topics expressed in online news media text</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Min</forename><surname>Soo-</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Eduard</forename><surname>Kim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Hovy</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Workshop on Sentiment and Subjectivity in Text</title>
		<meeting>the Workshop on Sentiment and Subjectivity in Text</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Stanford CoreNLP natural language processing toolkit</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christopher</forename><surname>Manning</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mihai</forename><surname>Surdeanu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">John</forename><surname>Bauer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jenny</forename><surname>Finkel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Steven</forename><surname>Bethard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Mcclosky</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">52nd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics: System Demonstrations</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="55" to="60" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Sentiment analysis in Facebook and its application to e-learning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alvaro</forename><surname>Ortigosa</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rosa M</forename><surname>José M Martín</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Carro</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Computers in Human Behavior</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">31</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="527" to="541" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dominance detection in meetings using easily obtainable features</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rutger</forename><surname>Rienks</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dirk</forename><surname>Heylen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">International Workshop on Machine Learning for Multimodal Interaction</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="76" to="86" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">English conversational telephone speech recognition by humans and machines</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">George</forename><surname>Saon</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of INTERSPEECH 2017</title>
		<meeting>INTERSPEECH 2017</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
