<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T12:11+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Learning Scalar Adjective Intensity from Paraphrases</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
				<availability status="unknown"><p>Copyright Association for Computational Linguistics</p>
				</availability>
				<date>October 31-November 4, 2018. 2018</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Anne</forename><surname>Cocos</surname></persName>
							<email>acocos@seas.upenn.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Department of Computer and Information Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Department of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">University of Pennsylvania</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">Brown University LIMSI</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit3">CNRS</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit4">Université Paris-Saclay</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>91403</postCode>
									<settlement>Orsay</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Veronica</forename><surname>Wharton</surname></persName>
							<email>whartonv@seas.upenn.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Department of Computer and Information Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Department of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">University of Pennsylvania</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">Brown University LIMSI</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit3">CNRS</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit4">Université Paris-Saclay</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>91403</postCode>
									<settlement>Orsay</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ellie</forename><surname>Pavlick</surname></persName>
							<email>epavlick@brown.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Department of Computer and Information Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Department of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">University of Pennsylvania</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">Brown University LIMSI</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit3">CNRS</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit4">Université Paris-Saclay</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>91403</postCode>
									<settlement>Orsay</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marianna</forename><surname>Apidianaki</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Department of Computer and Information Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Department of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">University of Pennsylvania</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">Brown University LIMSI</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit3">CNRS</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit4">Université Paris-Saclay</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>91403</postCode>
									<settlement>Orsay</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chris</forename><surname>Callison-Burch</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Department of Computer and Information Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Department of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">University of Pennsylvania</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">Brown University LIMSI</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit3">CNRS</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit4">Université Paris-Saclay</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>91403</postCode>
									<settlement>Orsay</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Learning Scalar Adjective Intensity from Paraphrases</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2018 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</title>
						<meeting>the 2018 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing <address><addrLine>Brussels, Belgium</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="1752" to="1762"/>
							<date type="published">October 31-November 4, 2018. 2018</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<note>1752</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Adjectives like warm, hot, and scalding all describe temperature but differ in intensity. Understanding these differences between adjectives is a necessary part of reasoning about natural language. We propose a new paraphrase-based method to automatically learn the relative intensity relation that holds between a pair of scalar adjectives. Our approach analyzes over 36k adjectival pairs from the Paraphrase Database under the assumption that, for example , paraphrase pair really hot ↔ scalding suggests that hot &lt; scalding. We show that combining this paraphrase evidence with existing, complementary pattern-and lexicon-based approaches improves the quality of systems for automatically ordering sets of scalar adjectives and inferring the polarity of indirect answers to yes/no questions.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Semantically similar adjectives are not fully inter- changeable in context. Although hot and scald- ing are related, the statement "the coffee was hot" does not imply the coffee was scalding. Hot and scalding are scalar adjectives that describe tem- perature, but they are not interchangeable because they vary in intensity. A native English speaker knows that their relative intensities are given by the ranking hot &lt; scalding. Understanding this distinction is important for language understand- ing tasks such as sentiment analysis <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(Pang et al., 2008)</ref>, question answering (de <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Marneffe et al., 2010)</ref>, and textual inference ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Dagan et al., 2006</ref>).</p><p>Existing lexical resources such as WordNet <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">(Miller, 1995;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Fellbaum, 1998</ref>) do not include the relative intensities of adjectives. As a result, there have been efforts to automate the process of learn- ing intensity relations (e.g. Sheinman and <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">Tokunaga (2009)</ref>, <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">de Melo and Bansal (2013)</ref>, <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">Wilkinson (2017)</ref>, etc.). Many existing approaches rely particularly pleased ↔ ecstatic quite limited ↔ restricted rather odd ↔ crazy so silly ↔ dumb completely mad ↔ crazy <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref>: Examples of paraphrases from PPDB of the form RB JJ u ↔ JJ v which can be used to infer pairwise intensity relationships (JJ u &lt; JJ v ).</p><p>on pattern-based or lexicon-based methods to pre- dict the intensity ranking of adjectives. Pattern- based approaches search large corpora for lexical patterns that indicate an intensity relationship - for example, "not just X, but Y" implies X &lt; Y.</p><p>As with pattern-based approaches for other tasks (such as hypernym discovery <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Hearst, 1992)</ref>), they are precise but have relatively sparse coverage of comparable adjectives, even when using web- scale corpora <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(de Melo and Bansal, 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Ruppenhofer et al., 2014</ref>). Lexicon-based approaches employ resources that map an adjective to a real- valued number that encodes both intensity and po- larity (e.g. good might map to 1 and phenomenal to 5, while bad maps to -1 and awful to -3). They can also be precise, but may not cover all adjec- tives of interest.</p><p>We propose paraphrases as a new source of ev- idence for the relative intensity of scalar adjec- tives. A paraphrase is a pair of words or phrases with approximately similar meaning, such as re- ally great ↔ phenomenal. Adjectival paraphrases can be exploited to uncover intensity relation- ships. A paraphrase pair of the above form, where one phrase is composed of an intensifying ad- verb and an adjective (really great) and the other is a single-word adjective (phenomenal), provides evidence that great &lt; phenomenal. By drawing this evidence from large, automatically-generated paraphrase resources like the Paraphrase Database (PPDB) 1 ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Ganitkevitch et al., 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Pavlick et al., 2015)</ref>, it is possible to obtain high-coverage pair- wise adjective intensity predictions at reasonably high accuracy.</p><p>We demonstrate the usefulness of paraphrase evidence for inferring relative adjective intensity in two tasks: ordering sets of adjectives along an intensity scale, and inferring the polarity of indi- rect answers to yes/no questions. In both cases, we find that combining the relatively noisy, but high- coverage, paraphrase evidence with more precise but low-coverage pattern-or lexicon-based evi- dence improves overall quality.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Related Work</head><p>Noting that adding adjective intensity relations to WordNet <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">(Miller, 1995;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Fellbaum, 1998</ref>) would be useful, <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Sheinman et al. (2013)</ref> propose a system for automatically extracting sets of same-attribute adjectives from WordNet 'dumbbells' -consisting of two direct antonyms at the poles and satellites of synonymous/related adjectives incident to each antonym ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Gross and Miller, 1990</ref>) -and ordering them by intensity. The annotations, however, are not in WordNet as of its latest version (3.1).</p><p>Work on adjective intensity generally focuses on two related tasks: clustering adjectives based on the attributes they modify, and ranking same- attribute adjectives by intensity. With respect to the former, common approaches involve cluster- ing adjectives by their contexts ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Hatzivassiloglou and McKeown, 1993;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Shivade et al., 2015</ref>). We do not focus on the clustering task in this paper, but concentrate on the ranking task.</p><p>Approaches to the task of ranking scalar ad- jectives by their intensity mostly fall under the paradigms of pattern-based or lexicon-based ap- proaches. Pattern-based approaches work by ex- tracting lexical <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">(Sheinman and Tokunaga, 2009;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b13">de Melo and Bansal, 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Sheinman et al., 2013</ref>) or syntactic ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Shivade et al., 2015</ref>) patterns indica- tive of an intensity relationship from large corpora. For example, the patterns "X, but not Y" and "not just X but Y" provide evidence that X is an adjec- tive less intense than Y.</p><p>Lexicon-based approaches are derived from the premise that adjectives can provide information about the sentiment of a text ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Hatzivassiloglou and McKeown, 1993)</ref>. These methods draw upon a lexicon that maps adjectives to real-valued scores encoding both sentiment polarity and intensity. The lexicon might be compiled automatically -for example, from analyzing adjectives' appearance in star-valued product or movie reviews ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">de Marneffe et al., 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b18">Rill et al., 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b21">Sharma et al., 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Ruppenhofer et al., 2014</ref>) -or manually. In our experiments we utilize the manually-compiled SO-CAL lexicon <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">(Taboada et al., 2011)</ref>.</p><p>Our paraphrase-based approach to inferring rel- ative adjective intensity is based on paraphrases that combine adjectives with adverbial modifiers. A tangentially related approach is Collex <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">(Ruppenhofer et al., 2014</ref>), which is motivated by the intuition that adjectives with extreme intensities are modified by different adverbs from adjectives with more moderate intensities: extreme adverbs like absolutely are more likely to modify extreme adjectives like brilliant than are moderate adverbs like very. Unlike Collex, which requires pre- determined sets of 'end-of-scale' and 'normal' ad- verbial modifiers, our approach learns the identity and relative importance of intensifying adverbs.</p><p>Relative intensity is just one of several dimen- sions of gradable adjective semantics. In addi- tion to intensity scales, a comprehensive model of scalar adjective semantics might also incorpo- rate notions of intensity range <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">(Morzycki, 2015)</ref>, adjective class ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Kamp and Partee, 1995)</ref>, and scale membership according to meaning <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Hatzivassiloglou and McKeown, 1993)</ref>. In this paper we take the position that relative intensity is worth studying on its own because it is an important component of adjective semantics, usable directly for some NLP tasks such as sentiment analysis <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(Pang et al., 2008)</ref>, and as part of a more com- prehensive model for other tasks like question an- swering (de Marneffe et al., 2010).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Paraphrase-based Intensity Evidence</head><p>Adjectival paraphrases provide evidence about the relative intensity of adjectives. A paraphrase of the form RB JJ u ↔ JJ v -where one phrase is com- prised of an adjective modified by an intensifying adverb (RB JJ u ), and the other is a single-word adjective (JJ v ) -is evidence that the first adjective is less intense than the second (JJ u &lt; JJ v ). We propose a new method for encoding this evidence and using it to make pairwise adjective intensity predictions. First, a graph (JJGRAPH) is formed to represent over 36k adjectival paraphrases hav- ing the specified form. Next, data in the graph are used to make pairwise adjective intensity predic- tions.</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">Round 1 very hard ↔ harder kinda hard ↔ harder so hard ↔ harder pretty hard ↔ harder ⇓ Round 2 very pleasant ↔ delightful kinda hard ↔ tricky so wonderful ↔ brilliant pretty simple ↔ plain ⇓ Round 3 more pleasant ↔ delightful really hard ↔ tricky truly wonderful ↔ brilliant quite simple ↔ plain</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Identifying Intensifying Adverbs</head><p>In JJGRAPH, nodes are adjectives, and each di- rected edge (JJ u − − → RB JJ v ) corresponds to an adjec- tival paraphrase of the form (RB JJ u ↔ JJ v ) -for example, (very tall ↔ large) -where one 'phrase' (JJ v ) is an adjective and the other (RB JJ u ) is an adjectival phrase containing an adverb and adjec- tive (see <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref> for examples). Adverbs in PPDB can be intensifying or de- intensifying. An intensifying adverb (e.g. very, totally) strengthens the adjectives it modifies. In contrast, a de-intensifying adverb (e.g. slightly, somewhat) weakens the adjectives it modifies. Since edges in JJGRAPH ideally point in the di- rection of increasing intensity, the first step in the process of creating JJGRAPH is to identify a set of adverbs that are likely intensifiers to be included as edges.</p><p>For this purpose, we generate a set R of likely intensifying adverbs within PPDB using a boot- strapping approach <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">(Figure 2</ref>). The process starts with a small seed set of adjective pairs having a known intensity relationship. The seeds are pairs (j u , j v ) from PPDB-XXL 2 such that j u is a base- form adjective (e.g. hard), and j v is its compar- ative or superlative form (e.g. harder or hard- est). Using the seeds, we identify intensifying ad-verbs by finding adjectival paraphrases in PPDB of the form (r i j u ↔ j v ); because j u &lt; j v , ad- verb r i is inferred to be intensifying (Round 1). All such r i are added to initial adverb set R 1 . The process continues by extracting paraphrases (r i j u ↔ j v ) with r i ∈ R 1 , indicating additional adjective pairs (j u , j v ) with intensity direction in- ferred by r i (Round 2). Finally, the adjective pairs extracted in this second iteration are used to iden- tify additional intensifying adverbs R 3 , which are added to the final set R = R 1 ∪ R 3 (Round 3).</p><p>In all, this process generates a set of 610 ad- verbs. Examination of the set shows that the process does capture many intensifying adverbs like very and abundantly, and excludes many de- intensifying adverbs appearing in PPDB like far less and not as. However, due to the noise in- herent in PPDB itself and in the bootstrapping process, there are also a few de-intensifying ad- verbs included in R (e.g. hardly, kind of ) as well as adverbs that are neither intensifying nor de- intensifying (e.g. ecologically). It will be impor- tant to take this noise into consideration when us- ing JJGRAPH to make pairwise intensity predic- tions.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Building JJGRAPH</head><p>JJGRAPH is built by extracting all 36,756 adjec- tival paraphrases in PPDB of the specified form, where the adverb belongs to R. The resulting graph has 3,704 unique adjective nodes. JJGRAPH is a multigraph, as there are frequently multiple intensifying relationships between pairs of adjec- tives. For example, the paraphrases (pretty hard ↔ tricky) and (really hard ↔ tricky) are both present in PPDB. There can also be contradictory or cyclic edges in JJGRAPH, as in the example depicted in the JJGRAPH subgraph in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 3</ref>, where the adverb really connects tasty to lovely and vice versa. Self-edges are allowed (e.g. (really hard ↔ hard)).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3">Pairwise Intensity Prediction</head><p>Examining the directed adverb edges between two adjectives j u and j v in JJGRAPH provides evi- dence about the relative intensity relationship be- tween them. However, it has just been noted that JJGRAPH is noisy, containing both contra- dictory/cyclic edges and adverbs that are not uni- formly intensifying. Rather than try to eliminate cycles, or manually annotate each adverb with a weight corresponding to its intensity and polarity ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">Ruppenhofer et al., 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b25">Taboada et al., 2011)</ref>, we aim to learn these weights automatically in the process of predicting pairwise intensity.</p><p>Given adjectives (j u , j v ), we build a classifier that outputs a score from 0 to 1 indicating the pre- dicted likelihood that j u &lt; j v . Its binary features correspond to adverb edges from j u to j v and from j v to j u in JJGRAPH. The feature space includes only adverbs from R that appear at least 10 times in JJGRAPH, resulting in features for m = 259 unique adverbs in each direction (i.e. from j u to j v and vice versa) for 2m = 518 binary features total. Note that while all adverb features corre- spond to predicted intensifiers from R, there are some features that are actually de-intensifying due to the noise inherent in the bootstrapping process (Section 3.1).</p><p>We train the classifier on all 36.7k edges in JJ- GRAPH, based on a simplifying assumption that all adverbs in R are indeed intensifiers. For each adjective pair (j u , j v ) with one or more direct edges from j u to j v , a positive training instance for pair (j u , j v ) and a negative training instance for pair (j v , j u ) are added to the training set. A logistic regression classifier is trained on the data, using elastic net regularization and 10-fold cross validation to tune parameters.</p><p>The model parameters output by the training process are in a feature weights vector w ∈ R 2m (with no bias term) which can be used to generate a paraphrase-based score for each adjective pair:</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">score pp (j u , j v ) = 1 1 + exp −wxuv − 0.5 (1)</formula><p>where x uv is the binary feature vector for adjec- tive pair (j u , j v ). The decision boundary 0.5 is subtracted from the sigmoid activation function so that pairs predicted to have the directed relation j u &lt; j v will have a positive score, and those pre- dicted to have the opposite directional relation will have a negative score. Pairs with no connecting edges in JJGRAPH score 0.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Other Intensity Evidence</head><p>Our experiments compare the proposed para- phrase approach with existing pattern-and lexicon-based approaches.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">Pattern-based Evidence</head><p>We experiment with the pattern-based approach of de <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Melo and Bansal (2013)</ref>. Given a pair of adjec- tives to be ranked by their intensity, de Melo and Bansal (2013) cull intensity patterns from Google n-Grams ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Brants and Franz, 2009</ref>) as evidence of their intensity order. Specifically, they identify 8 types of weak-strong patterns (e.g. "X, but not Y") and 7 types of strong-weak patterns (e.g. "not X, but still Y") that are used as evidence about the di- rectionality of the intensity relationship between adjectives. Given an adjective pair (j u , j v ), an overall pattern-based weak-strong score is calcu- lated:</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">score pat (j u , j v ) = (W u − S u ) − (W v − S v ) count(j u ) · count(j v )<label>(2)</label></formula><p>where W u and S u quantify the pattern evidence for the weak-strong and strong-weak intensity re- lations respectively for the pair (j u , j v ), and W v and S v quantify the pattern evidence for the pair (j v , j u ). W u and S u are calculated as:</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">W u = 1 P 1 p 1 ∈Pws count(p 1 (j u , j v )) S u = 1 P 2 p 2 ∈Psw count(p 2 (j u , j v ))<label>(3)</label></formula><p>W v and S v are calculated similarly by swapping the places of j u and j v . For example, given pair (good, great), W u might incorporate evidence from patterns "good, but not great" and "not only good but great", while S v might incorporate evi- dence from the pattern "not great, just good". P ws denotes the set of weak-strong patterns, P sw de- notes the set of strong-weak patterns, and P 1 and P 2 give the total counts of all occurrences of any pattern in P ws and P sw respectively. The score is normalized by the frequencies of j u and j v in or- der to avoid bias due to high-frequency adjectives.</p><p>As with the paraphrase-based scoring mechanism (Equation 1), scores output by this method can be positive or negative, with positive scores being in- dicative of a weak-strong relationship from j u to j v . Note that score(j u , j v ) = −score(j v , j u ).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">Lexicon-based Evidence</head><p>We use the manually-compiled SO-CAL 3 lexicon as our third, lexicon-based method for inferring intensity. The SO-CAL lexicon assigns an inte- ger weight in the range [−5, 5] to 2,826 adjectives. The sign of the weight encodes sentiment polar- ity (positive or negative), and the value encodes intensity (e.g. atrocious, with a weight of -5, is more intense than unlikable, with a weight of -3). SO-CAL is used to derive a pairwise intensity pre- diction for adjectives (j u ,j v ) as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_4">score socal (j u , j v ) = |L(j v )| − |L(j u )|, iff sign(j u ) = sign(j v )<label>(4)</label></formula><p>where L(j v ) gives the lexicon weight for j v . Note that score socal is computed only for adjectives having the same polarity direction in the lexicon; otherwise the score is undefined. This is because adjectives belonging to different half scales, such as freezing and steaming, are frequently incom- parable in terms of intensity (de Marneffe et al., 2010).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3">Combining Evidence</head><p>While the pattern-based and lexicon-based pair- wise intensity scores are known to be precise but low-coverage (de Melo and Bansal, 2013; Ruppenhofer et al., 2015), we expect that the paraphrase-based score will produce higher cov- erage at lower accuracy. Thus we also experiment with scoring methods that combine two or three score types. When combining two metrics x and y to generate a score for a pair (j u , j v ), we simply use the first metric x if it can be reliably calculated for the pair, and back off to metric y otherwise. More formally, the combined score for metrics x and y is given by:</p><formula xml:id="formula_5">score x+y (j u , j v ) = α x · g x (score x (j u , j v )) + (1 − α x ) · g y (score y (j u , j v ))<label>(5)</label></formula><p>where α x ∈ {0, 1} is a binary indicator corre- sponding to the condition that score x can be re- liably calculated for the adjective pair, and g x (·) is a scaling function (see below). If α x = 1, then score x is used. Otherwise, if α x = 0, then we de- fault to score y . When combining three metrics x, y, and z, the combined score is given by:</p><formula xml:id="formula_6">score x+y+z (j u , j v ) = α x · g x (score x (j u , j v )) + (1 − α x ) · score y+z (j u , j v )<label>(6)</label></formula><p>The criteria for having α x = 1 varies depend- ing on the metric type. For pattern-based evidence (x='pat'), α x = 1 when adjectives j u and j v ap- pear together in any of the intensity patterns culled from Google n-grams (e.g. "j u , but not j v " exists). For lexicon-based evidence (x='socal'), α x = 1 when both j u and j v are in the SO-CAL vocab- ulary, and have the same polarity (i.e. are both positive or both negative). For paraphrase-based evidence (x='pp'), α x = 1 when j u and j v have one or more edges directly connecting them in JJ- GRAPH.</p><p>Since the metrics to be combined may have dif- ferent ranges, we use a scaling function g x (·) to make the scores output by each metric directly comparable:</p><formula xml:id="formula_7">g x (w) = sign(w) · log(|w|) − µ x σ x + γ x<label>(7)</label></formula><p>where µ x and σ x are the estimated population mean and standard deviation of log(score x ) (es- timated over all adjective pairs in the dataset), and γ x is an offset equal to at least 5σ x .</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Ranking Adjective Sets by Intensity</head><p>The first experimental application for the differ- ent paraphrase evidence is an existing model for predicting a global intensity ordering within a set of adjectives. Global ranking models are useful for inferring intensity comparisons between adjec- tives for which there is no explicit evidence. For example, in ranking three adjectives like warm, hot, and scalding, there may be direct evidence indicating warm &lt; hot and hot &lt; scalding, but no way of directly comparing warm to scalding. Global ranking models infer that warm &lt; scalding based on evidence from the other adjective pairs in the scale.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.1">Global Ranking Model</head><p>We adopt the mixed-integer linear programming (MILP) approach of de Melo and Bansal (2013) for generating a global intensity ranking. This model takes a set of adjectives A = {a 1 , . . . , a n } Recall that all pairwise scoring metrics produce a positive score for adjective pair (j u , j v ) when it is likely that j u &lt; j v , and a negative score other- wise. Consequently, the MILP approach should result in x u &lt; x v when score(j u , j v ) is positive, and x u &gt; x v otherwise. This goal is achieved by maximizing the objective function:</p><formula xml:id="formula_8">u,v sign(x v − x u ) · score(j u , j v )<label>(8)</label></formula><p>de Melo and Bansal (2013) propose a MILP for- mulation for maximizing this objective, which we utilize in our experiments. Note that while de Melo and Bansal (2013) incorporate synonymy evidence from WordNet in their ranking method, we do not implement this part of the model.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.2">Experiments</head><p>We experiment with using each of the paraphrase-, pattern-, and lexicon-based pairwise scores as in- put to the global ranking model in isolation. To examine how the scoring methods perform when used in combination, we also test all possible com- binations of 2 and 3 scores. Experiments are run over three distinct test sets <ref type="table">(Table 1)</ref>. Each dataset contains ordered sets of scalar adjectives belonging to the same scale. In general, scalar adjectives describing the same at- tribute can be ordered along a full scale (e.g. freez- ing to sweltering), or a half scale (warm to swel- tering); all three test sets group adjectives into half scales. The three datasets are described here, and their characteristics are given in <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>. deMelo (de <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Melo and Bansal, 2013)</ref>  <ref type="bibr">4</ref> . 87 adjective sets are extracted from WordNet 'dumbbell' struc- tures ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Gross and Miller, 1990)</ref>, and partitioned into half-scale sets based on their pattern-based evidence in the Google N-Grams corpus <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Brants and Franz, 2009)</ref>. Sets are manually annotated for intensity relations (&lt;, &gt;, and =). <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">Wilkinson (Wilkinson and Oates, 2016)</ref>. Twelve adjective sets are generated by presenting crowd workers with small seed sets (e.g. huge, small, mi- croscopic), and eliciting similar adjectives. Sets are automatically cleaned for consistency, and then annotated for intensity by crowd workers. While the original dataset contains full scales, we manually sub-divide these into 21 half-scales for use in this study. Details on the modification from full-to half-scales are in the Supplemental Mate- rial. Crowd. We also crowdsourced a new set of adjec- tive scales with high coverage of the PPDB vocab- ulary. In a three-step process, we first asked crowd workers whether pairs of adjectives describe the same attribute (e.g. temperature) and therefore should belong along the same scale. Second, sets of same-scale adjectives were refined over multi- ple rounds. Finally, workers ranked the adjectives in each set by intensity. The final dataset includes 293 adjective pairs along 79 scales.</p><p>We measure the agreement between the gold standard ranking of adjectives along each scale and the predicted ranking using three commonly- used metrics: Pairwise accuracy. For each pair of adjectives along the same scale, we compare the predicted ordering of the pair after global ranking (&lt;, &gt;, or =) to the gold-standard ordering of the pair, and report overall accuracy of the pairwise predictions. Kendall's tau (τ b ). This metric computes the rank correlation between the predicted (r P (J)) and gold-standard (r G (J)) ranking permutations of each adjective scale J, incorporating a correc- tion for ties. Values for τ b range from −1 to 1, with extreme values indicating a perfect negative  <ref type="table">Table 2</ref>: Pairwise relation prediction and global ranking results for each score type in isolation, and for the best- scoring combinations of 2 and 3 score types on each dataset. For the global ranking accuracy and average τ b results, we denote with the † symbol scores for metrics incorporating paraphrase-based evidence that significantly out-perform both score pat and score socal under the paired Student's t-test, using the Anderson-Darling test to confirm that scores conform to a normal distribution <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Fisher, 1935;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Anderson and Darling, 1954;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Dror et al., 2018)</ref>. Example output is also given, with correct rankings starred.</p><p>or positive correlation, and a value of 0 indicating no correlation between predicted and gold rank- ings. We report τ b as a weighted average over scales in each dataset, where weights correspond to the number of adjective pairs in each scale. Spearman's rho (ρ). We report the Spearman's ρ rank correlation coefficient between predicted (r P (J)) and gold-standard (r G (J)) ranking per- mutations. For each dataset, we calculate this met- ric just once by treating each adjective in a partic- ular scale as a single data point, and calculating an overall ρ for all adjectives from all scales.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.3">Experimental Results</head><p>The results of the global ordering experiment, re- ported in <ref type="table">Table 2</ref>, are organized as follows: Score Accuracy pertains to performance of the scoring methods alone -prior to global ranking -while Global Ranking Results pertains to performance of each scoring method as used in the global ranking algorithm. Within Score Accuracy there are two metrics. Coverage gives the percent of unique same-scale adjective pairs from the test set that can be directly scored using the given method. For score pat , covered pairs are all those that appear together in any recognized pattern;</p><p>for score pp , covered pairs are those directly con- nected in JJGRAPH by one or more direct edges; for score socal , covered pairs are all those for which both adjectives are in the SO-CAL lexicon and the metric is defined. Pairwise Accuracy gives the accuracy of the scoring method (before global ranking) on just the covered pairs, meaning that the subset of pairs scored by each method varies. Within Global Ranking Results, we report pair- wise accuracy, weighted average τ b , and ρ calcu- lated over all pairs after ranking -including both pairs that are covered by the scoring method, and those whose pairwise intensity relationship has been inferred by the ranking algorithm.</p><p>The results indicate that the pairwise score accuracies (before ranking) for score pat and score socal are higher than those of score pp for all datasets, but that their coverage is relatively lim- ited. The one exception is the deMelo dataset, where score pat has high coverage because the dataset was compiled specifically by finding ad- jective pairs that matched lexical patterns in the corpus. For all datasets, highest coverage is achieved using one of the combined metrics that incorporates paraphrase-based evidence.</p><p>The impact of these trends is visible on the Global Ranking Results. When using pairwise intensity scores to compute the global ranking, higher coverage by a metric drives better results, as long as the metric's accuracy is reasonably high. Thus the paraphrase-based score pp , with its high coverage, gets better global ranking re- sults than the other single-method scores for two of the three datasets. Further, we find that boost- ing coverage with a combined metric that incor- porates paraphrase evidence produces the highest post-ranking pairwise accuracy scores overall for all three datasets, and the highest average τ b and ρ on the Crowd and Wilkinson datasets. We con- clude that incorporating paraphrase evidence can improve the quality of this model for ordering ad- jectives along a scale because it gives high cover- age with reasonably high quality. The performance trends on the deMelo dataset differ from those on the Crowd and Wilkinson datasets. In particular, score pp and score socal have substantially lower pre-ranking pairwise accuracy on the pairs they cover in the deMelo dataset than they do for Crowd and Wilkinson: score pp has an accuracy of just 0.458 on covered pairs in the deMelo dataset, compared with 0.676 and 0.753 on the Crowd and Wilkinson datasets, and score differences for score socal are similar. The near-random prediction accuracies of score pp and score socal on deMelo before ranking lead to near- zero correlation values on this dataset after global ranking. To explore possible reasons for these re- sults, we assessed the level of human agreement with each dataset in terms of pairwise accuracy. For each test set, we asked five crowd workers to classify the intensity direction for each adjec- tive pair (j u , j v ) in all scales as less than (&lt;), greater than (&gt;), or equal (=). We found that humans agreed with the 'gold standard' direction 65% of the time on the Bansal dataset, versus 70% of the time on the Crowd and Wilkinson datasets. It is possible that the more difficult nature of the Bansal dataset, coupled with its method of compi- lation (i.e. favoring adjective pairs that co-occur with pre-defined intensity patterns), lead to the lower coverage and lower accuracy of score pp and score socal on this dataset.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Indirect Question Answering</head><p>The second task that we address is answering indi- rect yes or no questions. de <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Marneffe et al. (2010)</ref> observed that answers to such polar questions fre- quently omit an explicit yes or no response. In some cases the implied answer depends on the rel- ative intensity of adjective modifiers in the ques- tion and answer. For example, in the exchange: Q: Was he a successful ruler? A: Oh, a tremendous ruler. the implied answer is yes, which is inferred be- cause successful ≤ tremendous in terms of relative intensity. Conversely, in the exchange: Q: Does it have a large impact? A: It has a medium-sized impact.</p><p>the implied answer is no because large &gt; medium- sized.</p><p>de <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Marneffe et al. (2010)</ref> compiled an evalua- tion set for this task by extracting 123 examples of such indirect question-answer pairs (IQAP) from dialogue corpora. In each exchange, the implied answer (annotated by crowd workers to be yes or no 5 ) depends on the relative intensity relation- ship between modifiers in the question and answer texts. In their original paper, the authors utilize an automatically-compiled lexicon to make a polarity prediction for each IQAP.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.1">Predicting Answer Polarity</head><p>Our goal is to see whether paraphrase-based scores are useful for predicting the polarity of an- swers in the IQAP dataset. As before, we com- pare the quality of predictions made using the paraphrase-based evidence with predictions made using pattern-based, lexicon-based, and combined scoring metrics.</p><p>To use the pairwise scores for inference, we em- ploy a decision procedure nearly identical to that of de <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Marneffe et al. (2010)</ref>. If j q and j a are scorable (i.e. have a scorable intensity relationship along the same half-scale), then j q ≤ j a implies the answer is yes (first example above), and j q &gt; j a implies the answer is no (second example). If the pair of adjectives is not scorable, then the pre- dicted answer is no, as the pair could be antonyms or completely unrelated. If either j q or j a is miss- ing from the scoring vocabulary, the adjectives are impossible to compare and therefore the predic- tion is uncertain. The full decision procedure is given in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 4</ref>.</p><p>Given: A dialogue exchange consisting of a polar ques- tion and answer, where the answer depends on the rel- ative intensities of distinct modifiers jq and ja in the question and answer respectively:</p><p>1. if jq or ja are missing from the score vocabulary, predict "UNCERTAIN"</p><p>2. else, if score(JJq, JJa) is undefined, predict "NO"</p><p>3. else, if score(JJq, JJa) ≥ 0, predict "YES" 4. else, predict "NO"</p><p>5. If the question or answer contains negation, map a "YES" answer to "NO and a "NO" answer to "YES" </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.2">Experiments</head><p>The decision procedure in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 4</ref> is carried out for the 123 IQAP instances in the dataset, vary- ing the score type. We report the accuracy, and macro-averaged precision, recall, and F1-score of the 85 yes and 38 no instances, in <ref type="table">Table 3</ref> along- side the percent of instances with adjectives out of vocabulary. Only the combined scores for the two best-scoring combinations, score socal+pp and score socal+pat+pp , are reported.  <ref type="table">Table 3</ref>: Accuracy and macro-averaged precision (P), recall (R), and F1-score (F) over yes and no responses on 123 question-answer pairs. The percent of pairs hav- ing one or both adjectives out of the score vocabulary is listed as %OOV.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Method</head><p>The simplest baseline of predicting all answers to be "YES" gets highest accuracy in this imbal- anced test set, but all score types perform better than the all-"YES" baseline in terms of precision and F1-score. Bouyed by its high precision, the score socal -which is derived from a manually- compiled lexicon -scored higher than score pp and score pat . But it mis-predicted 33% of pairs as uncertain because of its limited overlap with the IQAP vocabulary. Meanwhile, score pp had relatively high coverage and a mid-level F-score, while score pat scored poorly on this dataset due to its sparsity; while all modifiers in the IQAP dataset are in the Google N-grams vocabulary, most do not have observed patterns and there- fore return predictions of "NO" (item 2 in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Fig- ure 4)</ref>. As in the global ranking experiments, the paraphrase-based evidence is complementary to the lexicon-based evidence, and thus the combined score socal+pp and score socal+pat+pp produce signifi- cantly better accuracy than any score in isolation (McNemar's test, p &lt; .01), and also out-perform the original expected ranking method of de Marn- effe et al. (2010) (although they do not beat the best-reported score on this dataset, F-score=0.706 <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(Kim and de Marneffe, 2013)</ref>).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7">Conclusion</head><p>We have proposed adjectival paraphrases as a new source of evidence for predicting in- tensity relationships between scalar adjectives. While paraphrase-based intensity evidence pro- duces pairwise predictions that are less precise than those produced by pattern-or lexicon-based evidence, the coverage is substantially higher. Thus paraphrases can be successfully used as a complementary source of information for reason- ing about adjective intensity. We will publish the JJGRAPH resource, datasets, and code upon pub- lication.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2: Bootstrapping process for identifying intensifying adverbs. The adverbs found in Rounds 1 and 3 are used to build intensifying edges in JJGRAPH.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Figure 3: A subgraph of JJGRAPH, depicting its directed graph structure.</figDesc><graphic url="image-1.png" coords="4,72.00,62.81,218.26,92.92" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 4 :</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Figure 4: Decision procedure for using pairwise intensity scores for predicting polarity of an IQAP instance, based on de Marneffe et al. (2010).</figDesc></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> www.paraphrase.org</note>

			<note place="foot" n="2"> PPDB comes in six increasingly large sizes from S to XXXL; larger collections have wider coverage but lower precision. Our work uses XXL.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="3"> https://github.com/sfu-discourse-lab/ SO-CAL</note>

			<note place="foot" n="4"> http://demelo.org/gdm/intensity/</note>

			<note place="foot" n="5"> The original dataset contains two additional examples where the answer is annotated as uncertain, but de Marneffe et al. (2010) exclude them from the results and so do we.</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>This material is based in part on research spon-sored by the following organizations: the Allen Institute for Artificial Intelligence (AI2) Key Sci-entific Challenges program, the Google Ph.D. Fel-lowship program, the French National Research Agency under project ANR-16-CE33-0013, and DARPA under grant numbers FA8750-13-2-0017 (the DEFT program) and HR0011-15-C-0115 (the LORELEI program). The U.S. Government is au-thorized to reproduce and distribute reprints for Governmental purposes. The views and conclu-sions contained in this publication are those of the authors and should not be interpreted as represent-ing official policies or endorsements of DARPA and the U.S. Government.</p><p>We are grateful to our anonymous reviewers for their thoughtful and constructive comments.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A test of goodness of fit</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Theodore</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Donald A</forename><surname>Anderson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Darling</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of the American statistical association</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">49</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">268</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="765" to="769" />
			<date type="published" when="1954" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Web 1T 5gram, 10 European languages version 1. Linguistic Data Consortium</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Thorsten</forename><surname>Brants</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alex</forename><surname>Franz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<pubPlace>Philadelphia</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Revised Selected Papers, chapter The PASCAL Recognising Textual Entailment Challenge</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Oren</forename><surname>Ido Dagan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bernardo</forename><surname>Glickman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Magnini</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Machine Learning Challenges. Evaluating Predictive Uncertainty, Visual Object Classification, and Recognising Tectual Entailment: First PASCAL Machine Learning Challenges Workshop, MLCW 2005</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Southampton, UK; Berlin, Heidelberg</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer Berlin Heidelberg</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The hitchhiker&apos;s guide to testing statistical significance in natural language processing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rotem</forename><surname>Dror</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gili</forename><surname>Baumer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Segev</forename><surname>Shlomov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Roi</forename><surname>Reichart</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 56th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL)</title>
		<meeting>the 56th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1383" to="1392" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christiane</forename><surname>Fellbaum</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
			<publisher>Wiley Online Library</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The design of experiments</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ronald Aylmer</forename><surname>Fisher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1935" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">PPDB: The paraphrase database</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Juri</forename><surname>Ganitkevitch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Benjamin</forename><surname>Van Durme</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chris</forename><surname>Callison-Burch</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2013 Conference of the North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics: Human Language Technologies (NAACL HLT)</title>
		<meeting>the 2013 Conference of the North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics: Human Language Technologies (NAACL HLT)<address><addrLine>Atlanta, Georgia</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="758" to="764" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Adjectives in wordnet</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Derek</forename><surname>Gross</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Katherine</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Miller</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">International Journal of lexicography</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="265" to="277" />
			<date type="published" when="1990" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Towards the automatic identification of adjectival scales: Clustering adjectives according to meaning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Vasileios</forename><surname>Hatzivassiloglou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kathleen</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Mckeown</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 31st Annual Meeting on Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL)</title>
		<meeting>the 31st Annual Meeting on Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL)<address><addrLine>Columbus, Ohio</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="172" to="182" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Automatic acquisition of hyponyms from large text corpora</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Marti A Hearst</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 14th conference on Computational linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the 14th conference on Computational linguistics<address><addrLine>Nantes, France</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1992" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="539" to="545" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Prototype theory and compositionality</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hans</forename><surname>Kamp</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Barbara</forename><surname>Partee</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">57</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="129" to="191" />
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Deriving adjectival scales from continuous space word representations</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Joo-Kyung</forename><surname>Kim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marie-Catherine</forename><surname>De Marneffe</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2013 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP)</title>
		<meeting>the 2013 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP)<address><addrLine>Seattle, Washington</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1625" to="1630" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Learning the meaning of scalar adjectives</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marie-Catherine</forename><surname>De Marneffe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christopher</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Manning</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christopher</forename><surname>Potts</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 48th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL)</title>
		<meeting>the 48th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL)<address><addrLine>Uppsala, Sweden</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="167" to="176" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Was it good? It was provocative</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Good, great, excellent: Global inference of semantic intensities</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mohit</forename><surname>Gerard De Melo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Bansal</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Transactions of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="279" to="290" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Wordnet: A lexical database for english</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">George</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Miller</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Commun. ACM</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">38</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="39" to="41" />
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Modification</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marcin</forename><surname>Morzycki</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
			<publisher>Cambridge University Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Opinion mining and sentiment analysis. Foundations and Trends in Information Retrieval</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bo</forename><surname>Pang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lillian</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="135" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">PPDB 2.0: Better paraphrase ranking, finegrained entailment relations, word embeddings, and style classification</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ellie</forename><surname>Pavlick</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Pushpendre</forename><surname>Rastogi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Juri</forename><surname>Ganitkevitch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Benjamin</forename><surname>Van Durme</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chris</forename><surname>Callison-Burch</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 53rd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics and the 7th International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing (ACL)</title>
		<meeting>the 53rd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics and the 7th International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing (ACL)<address><addrLine>Beijing, China</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Short Papers</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="425" to="430" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A generic approach to generate opinion lists of phrases for opinion mining applications</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Sven Rill</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Johannes</forename><surname>Scheidt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Oliver</forename><surname>Drescher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dirk</forename><surname>Schütz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Florian</forename><surname>Reinel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Wogenstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the First International Workshop on Issues of Sentiment Discovery and Opinion Mining (WISDOM)</title>
		<meeting>the First International Workshop on Issues of Sentiment Discovery and Opinion Mining (WISDOM)<address><addrLine>Beijing, China</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Ordering adverbs by their scaling effect on adjective intensity</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Josef</forename><surname>Ruppenhofer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jasper</forename><surname>Brandes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Petra</forename><surname>Steiner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Wiegand</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the International Conference Recent Advances in Natural Language Processing</title>
		<meeting>the International Conference Recent Advances in Natural Language Processing<address><addrLine>Hissar, Bulgaria</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="545" to="554" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Comparing methods for deriving intensity scores for adjectives</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Josef</forename><surname>Ruppenhofer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Wiegand</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jasper</forename><surname>Brandes</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 14th Conference of the European Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics (EACL)</title>
		<meeting>the 14th Conference of the European Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics (EACL)<address><addrLine>Gothenburg, Sweden</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Adjective intensity and sentiment analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Raksha</forename><surname>Sharma</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mohit</forename><surname>Gupta</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Astha</forename><surname>Agarwal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Pushpak</forename><surname>Bhattacharyya</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2015 Conference on Empirical Methods for Natural Language Processing</title>
		<meeting>the 2015 Conference on Empirical Methods for Natural Language Processing<address><addrLine>Lisbon, Portugal</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Large, huge or gigantic? Identifying and encoding intensity relations among adjectives in WordNet. Language resources and evaluation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Vera</forename><surname>Sheinman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christiane</forename><surname>Fellbaum</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Isaac</forename><surname>Julien</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">47</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="797" to="816" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Peter Schulam, and Takenobu Tokunaga</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Adjscales: Visualizing differences between adjectives for language learners</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Vera</forename><surname>Sheinman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Takenobu</forename><surname>Tokunaga</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEICE TRANSACTIONS on Information and Systems</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">92</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1542" to="1550" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Corpus-based discovery of semantic intensity scales</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Chaitanya</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marie-Catherine</forename><surname>Shivade</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Eric</forename><surname>De Marneffe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Albert</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Fosler-Lussier</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Lai</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2015 Conference of the North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics Human Language Technologies (NAACL HLT)</title>
		<meeting>the 2015 Conference of the North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics Human Language Technologies (NAACL HLT)<address><addrLine>Denver, Colorado</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="483" to="493" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Lexicon-based methods for sentiment analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Maite</forename><surname>Taboada</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Julian</forename><surname>Brooke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Milan</forename><surname>Tofiloski</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kimberly</forename><surname>Voll</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Manfred</forename><surname>Stede</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Computational linguistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">37</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="267" to="307" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Identifying and Ordering Scalar Adjectives Using Lexical Substitution</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bryan</forename><surname>Wilkinson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
			<pubPlace>Baltimore County</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>University of Maryland</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
<note type="report_type">Ph.D. thesis</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A gold standard for scalar adjectives</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bryan</forename><surname>Wilkinson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tim</forename><surname>Oates</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Tenth International Conference on Language Resources and Evaluation (LREC)</title>
		<meeting>the Tenth International Conference on Language Resources and Evaluation (LREC)<address><addrLine>Portoro, Slovenia</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
