<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T12:41+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Out-of-domain Detection based on Generative Adversarial Network</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date>October 31-November 4, 2018</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Seonghan</forename><surname>Ryu</surname></persName>
							<email>seonghan.ryu@samsung.com</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Artificial Intelligence Center</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">Language Understanding Lab</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Samsung Research</orgName>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Computer Science and Engineering Department</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Pohang University of Science and Technology</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sangjun</forename><surname>Koo</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Computer Science and Engineering Department</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Pohang University of Science and Technology</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hwanjo</forename><surname>Yu</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Computer Science and Engineering Department</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Pohang University of Science and Technology</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gary</forename><forename type="middle">Geunbae</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Computer Science and Engineering Department</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Pohang University of Science and Technology</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Out-of-domain Detection based on Generative Adversarial Network</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2018 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</title>
						<meeting>the 2018 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing <address><addrLine>Brussels; Belgium</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="714" to="718"/>
							<date type="published">October 31-November 4, 2018</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<note>714</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>The main goal of this paper is to develop out-of-domain (OOD) detection for dialog systems. We propose to use only in-domain (IND) sentences to build a generative adversarial network (GAN) of which the dis-criminator generates low scores for OOD sentences. To improve basic GANs, we apply feature matching loss in the discriminator, use domain-category analysis as an additional task in the discriminator, and remove the biases in the generator. Thereby, we reduce the huge effort of collecting OOD sentences for training OOD detection. For evaluation, we experimented OOD detection on a multi-domain dialog system. The experimental results showed the proposed method was most accurate compared to the existing methods.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Multi-domain dialog systems <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Hakkani-Tur et al., 2016;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Jiang et al., 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Lee et al., 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Ryu et al., 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Seon et al., 2014</ref>) should detect whether an input request is out-of-domain (OOD) because users do not know the exact coverages of those systems. One important problem of building OOD detection is the huge effort required to col- lect OOD sentences. This paper focuses on devel- oping an accurate OOD detection method that re- quires only in-domain (IND) sentences for train- ing, so this paper can reduce the effort of collect- ing OOD sentences.</p><p>For OOD detection, sentences would be repre- sented in a continuous vector space in which IND cases are distinguished from OOD cases. There- fore, we use the existing sentence embedding method for OOD detection ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Ryu et al., 2017)</ref>. The authors train a recurrent neural network (RNN) for domain-category analysis task, in which one domain-category is assigned to an input sentence. Due to the similarity between OOD detection and domain-category analysis, the extracted features (i.e., representation) of the RNN contain informa- tion about domain-category. In addition, the word representations are pre-trained from a large unla- belled corpus, so the sentence embedding method has the advantage in understanding rare or un- known words that are likely to appear in OOD sen- tences.</p><p>Afterwards, we use the learned representations of IND sentences to train one-class classifiers that distinguish IND sentences from OOD sentences. We propose to use a generative adversarial net- work (GAN) ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Goodfellow et al., 2014</ref>) that con- sists of a generator G and a discriminator D. We train D that distinguishes the IND sentences from the fake sentences generated by G, so we expect D to reject OOD sentences. We apply three modifi- cations to improve basic GANs. To the best of our knowledge, this is the first study that uses GANs to solve OOD detection. <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Lane et al. (2007)</ref> proposed an in-domain verifica- tion method. The authors first build a basic binary classifier for each domain, and then build a meta classifier that takes the scores by the basic binary classifiers as input. However, in our experiment, many OOD sentences were misclassified into IND because OOD sentences were not in the negative examples of the classifiers. Therefore, the con- fidence scores of the basic binary classifiers are not sufficiently reliable evidences of OOD. Also, understanding rare or unknown words remains a problem because bag-of-words model is used. <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Ryu et al. (2017)</ref> proposed an autoencoder- based method. The authors use neural sentence embedding that has the advantage in represent- ing rare or unknown words. Based on those dis- tributed sentence representations, an autoencoder is trained on IND sentences. The autencoder will have low reconstruction errors for IND sentences, so an input sentence can be classified into either IND or OOD. However, the autoencoder-based method has a limitation in expandability. When the weights are initialized carefully and regular- ization techniques are applied, the trained autoen- coder reconstructs any input accurately. This re- sult means that the reconstruction errors by the ideal autoencoder are not reliable evidence of OOD, so in OOD detection, autoencoders have lit- tle room for improvement.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Related Work</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Methods</head><p>As we discussed in Section 1, we use the sen- tence embedding to represent sentences in an 300- dimensional continuous vector space. We propose to use a GAN to OOD detection; a GAN consists of two adversarial components: generator G and discriminator D. G generates artificial data to de- ceive D. D distinguishes real data from the artifi- cial data generated by G. GAN is an unsupervised algorithm because learning G and D does not re- quire labels. Standard GANs are trained based on the objective function V (D, G) as</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">min G max D V (D, G) = E x∼p data [log D(x)] (1) +E z∼pz(z) [log 1 − D(G(z))].</formula><p>So GAN is a minimax two-player game be- cause G minimizes V <ref type="bibr">(D, G), and D maximizes V (D, G)</ref>.</p><p>We propose to use GANs to obtain a one-class classifier for OOD detection. When we train G to generate sentences similar to IND sentences and D to classify real IND sentences and fake sen- tences generated by G, we expect D to reject OOD sentences. Therefore, we use the low confidence score by D about an input sentence as the evidence that the sentence is OOD.</p><p>Let p z (z) be a continuous uniform distribution <ref type="figure">(−1, 1)</ref>. We define G that generates fake data G(z) ∈ R m from input noise z ∼ p z (z), f that extracts features from either real data x of (x, y) ∼ p data (x, y) or G(z), and D that measures the prob- ability of either f(x) or f(G(z)) from the real data as</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">G(z) = σ h (W g z),<label>(2)</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_2">f(x) = σ h (W h x + b f ),<label>(3)</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_3">f(G(z)) = σ h (W h G(z) + b f ),<label>(4)</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_4">D(f(x)) = σ g (W d f(x) + b d ),<label>(5)</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_5">D(f(G(z))) = σ g (W d f(G(z)) + b d ), (6)</formula><p>where W g , W f , and W d are weight matrices, b f and b d are bias vectors. So we define two objective functions</p><formula xml:id="formula_6">L D = −E (x,y)∼p data (x,y) [logD(f(x))] (7) − E z∼pz(z) [log(1 − D(f(G(z))))], L G = −E z∼pz(z) [logD(f(G(z)))].<label>(8)</label></formula><p>Because G(z) continuously changes during the training, f of traditional GAN also changes. Thus we define C ∈ R |D| that computes domain- category of f(x) as</p><formula xml:id="formula_7">C(f(x)) = softmax(W c f(x) + b c ),<label>(9)</label></formula><p>where W c is a weight matrix and b c is a bias vec- tor. We expect f trained by the losses of both D and C to be more stable than f trained by the loss of only D, so we define an objective function</p><formula xml:id="formula_8">L C = E (x,y)∼p data (x,y) [H(C(f(x)), y)],<label>(10)</label></formula><p>where H(p, q) is the categorical cross entropy and y is the true domain-category. In addition, GAN suffers from a mode collapse problem in which G generates samples with a low variance. To solve the problem, we remove the biases in the generator because the G was trained to use the biases mainly instead of the weights to generate data.</p><p>Second, we apply feature matching <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Salimans et al., 2016</ref>). The authors say "Instead of directly maximizing the output of the discriminator, the new objective requires the generator to generate data that matches [sic] the statistics of the real data, where we use the discriminator only to spec- ify the statistics that we think are worth matching". So G is trained to generate high variance sentence G(z) by additional objective function</p><formula xml:id="formula_9">L f = ||E (x,y)∼p data (x,y) f(x) − E z∼pz(z) f(G(z))|| 2 2 .<label>(11)</label></formula><p>Based on our design of GAN, we train D, C, f, and G as Algorithm 1. To implement our GAN Algorithm 1 Training process of GAN for OOD detection.</p><p>for number of training iterations do Sample real data (x, y) ∼ p data (x, y).</p><formula xml:id="formula_10">Sample noise z ∼ p z (z). Update D, C, and f based on L D + L C . Sample noise z ∼ p z (z). Update G based on L G + L f . end for</formula><p>for one-class classification, we use the Tensorflow library ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Abadi et al., 2015)</ref>. We train our mod- els by using Adam ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Kingma and Ba, 2015)</ref> opti- mizer with a mini-batch size of 256 and an initial learning rate of 0.01 that is decreased linearly dur- ing 500 epochs. All weights are initialized from a zero-centered Normal distribution with standard deviation 1.0.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Experiments</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">Data Set</head><p>We experimented on a data set of 6,268 Korean sentences. We collected 706 OOD sentences about three domains: hotel, message, and smalltalk; and 5,562 IND sentences about fourteen domains: air- plane, alarm, bus, call, car navigation, diet talk, exchange, general, schedule, songfinder, time, train, and TV control. We used eighty percent of the IND sentences to train the models; we used the remaining IND sentences and all OOD sentences for testing.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">Evaluation Metrics</head><p>We use equal error rate (EER) to represent the ac- curacy of OOD detection ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Lane et al., 2007)</ref>. EER is the error rate at which false acceptance rate are equal.</p><p>We performed each experiment 20 times, and recorded the average EER of OOD detection.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3">Compared Methods</head><p>We have three variations of vanilla GAN: to re- move the biases, to add domain-category analy- We compare our method to three one-class clas- sifiers. (1) Local outlier factor ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Breunig et al., 2000</ref>) compares the local density of a point to the local densities of its neighbors, and consid- ers the point that has lower density than their neighbors as an outlier. The local density of a point is defined by the distance to its near- est neighbors. (2) One-class support vector ma- chines (One-class SVMs) ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Schölkopf et al., 2001</ref>) that treats the origin as a negative example to learn a decision function. (3) Autoencoder is explained in Section 2.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.4">Results</head><p>In the experiments <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">(Table 1)</ref>, the best EER (8.96%) was obtained by the GAN in which all three of our variations are applied (p &lt; 0.05). This result means that (1) removing the biases and using the feature matching prevented the generator from mode collapse problem and (2) using domain-category analysis as an auxiliary task stabilized the training of feature extractor. Compared to the other one-class classification methods including the autoencoder, the proposed GAN was most accurate (p &lt; 0.05), so we can say that the discriminator scores of the GAN are reliable evidence for OOD detection <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">(Table 2</ref>).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Conclusion</head><p>In this paper, we aimed at building OOD detection without OOD sentences for training. We proposed to use the discriminator of a GAN, which is trained on only IND sentences. The proposed method out- performed the existing methods in our data set. To train the GAN, we used the distributed sentence representations computed from the pre- trained sentence embeddings instead of symbolic sentences. However, we think the limitation of the pre-trained sentence embeddings can be over- come by building a GAN that generates symbolic sentences and discriminates them.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>"</head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 1: Distributed representations of IND sentences.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Figure 3: Generative adversarial network for outof-domain sentence detection.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>FAR</head><label></label><figDesc>= Number of accepted OOD sentences Number of OOD sentences (12) and false rejection rate FRR = Number of rejected ID sentences Number of ID sentences (13)</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" validated="true"><head>Table 1 : EERs [%] ± s.d. (n = 20) of OOD detec- tion.</head><label>1</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Method 
EER 

Local outlier factor 
13.33 
One-class SVM 
13.76 
Autoencoder 
9.24 ± 0.43 

GAN with biases 
15.93 ± 5.82 
GAN 
9.18 ± 0.30 
GAN with DCA task 
9.17 ± 0.40 
GAN with FM loss 
9.04 ± 0.30 
GAN with DCA task 
8.96 ± 0.34 
and FM loss 

sis (DCA) task, and to add feature matching (FM) 
loss. So we assessed five settings about GAN. 
</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" validated="true"><head>Table 2 : Average score [%] by the discriminator of the GAN.</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Data 
Score 

IND training sentences 98.69 (± 3.36) 
Fake sentences G(z) 
0.20 (± 1.70) 
IND test sentences 
88.59 (± 28.09) 
OOD test sentences 
8.04 (± 23.10) 

</table></figure>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgements</head></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">TensorFlow: Large-scale machine learning on heterogeneous distributed systems</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Martín</forename><surname>Abadi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ashish</forename><surname>Agarwal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Paul</forename><surname>Barham</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Eugene</forename><surname>Brevdo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Zhifeng</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Craig</forename><surname>Citro</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">.</forename><forename type="middle">.</forename><surname>Devin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Moore</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Warden</forename><surname>Vanhoucke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Software available from tensorflow.org</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">LOF: Identifying density-based local outliers</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Markus</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Breunig</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hans-Peter</forename><surname>Kriegel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Raymond</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Ng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jörg</forename><surname>Sander</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of ACM SIGMOD</title>
		<meeting>ACM SIGMOD</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Generative adversarial nets</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ian</forename><surname>Goodfellow</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jean</forename><surname>Pouget-Abadie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mehdi</forename><surname>Mirza</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bing</forename><surname>Xu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Warde-Farley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sherjil</forename><surname>Ozair</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Aaron</forename><surname>Courville</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yoshua</forename><surname>Bengio</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of NIPS</title>
		<meeting>NIPS</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Multi-domain joint semantic frame parsing using bi-directional RNN-LSTM</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dilek</forename><surname>Hakkani-Tur</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gokhan</forename><surname>Tur</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Asli</forename><surname>Celikyilmaz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yun-Nung</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jianfeng</forename><surname>Gao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Li</forename><surname>Deng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yeyi</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of Interspeech</title>
		<meeting>Interspeech</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Web-based multimodal multi-domain spoken dialogue system</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ridong</forename><surname>Jiang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rafael</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Banchs</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Seokhwan</forename><surname>Kim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kheng</forename><forename type="middle">Hui</forename><surname>Yeo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Arthur</forename><surname>Niswar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Haizhou</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of IWSDS</title>
		<meeting>IWSDS</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Adam: A method for stochastic optimization</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Diederik</forename><surname>Kingma</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jimmy</forename><surname>Ba</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of ICLR</title>
		<meeting>ICLR</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Out-of-domain utterance detection using classification confidences of multiple topics</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ian</forename><surname>Lane</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tatsuya</forename><surname>Kawahara</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tomoko</forename><surname>Matsui</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Satoshi</forename><surname>Nakamura</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE/ACM Trans. Audio, Speech</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="150" to="161" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
			<publisher>Language Process</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Unsupervised spoken language understanding for a multi-domain dialog system</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Donghyeon</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Minwoo</forename><surname>Jeong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kyungduk</forename><surname>Kim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Seonghan</forename><surname>Ryu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gary Geunbae</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Speech, Language Process</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">21</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2451" to="2464" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>IEEE/ACM Trans. Audio</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Neural sentence embedding using only in-domain sentences for out-of-domain sentence detection in dialog systems</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Seonghan</forename><surname>Ryu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Seokhwan</forename><surname>Kim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Junhwi</forename><surname>Choi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hwanjo</forename><surname>Yu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gary Geunbae</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Pattern Recogn. Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">88</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="26" to="32" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Detecting multiple domains from users utterance in spoken dialog system</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Seonghan</forename><surname>Ryu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jaiyoun</forename><surname>Song</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sangjun</forename><surname>Koo</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of IWSDS</title>
		<meeting>IWSDS</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Soonchoul Kwon, and Gary Geunbae Lee</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Improved techniques for training GANs</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tim</forename><surname>Salimans</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ian</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Goodfellow</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wojciech</forename><surname>Zaremba</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Vicki</forename><surname>Cheung</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alec</forename><surname>Radford</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xi</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of NIPS</title>
		<meeting>NIPS</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Estimating the support of a high-dimensional distribution</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bernhard</forename><surname>Schölkopf</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">John</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Platt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">John</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Shawetaylor</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alex</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Smola</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Robert</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Williamson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Neural Comput</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1443" to="1471" />
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Improving domain action classification in goal-oriented dialogues using a mutual retraining method</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Choong-Nyoung</forename><surname>Seon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hyunjung</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Harksoo</forename><surname>Kim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jungyun</forename><surname>Seo</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Pattern Recogn. Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page">45</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
