<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T11:04+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Developing Production-Level Conversational Interfaces with Shallow Semantic Parsing</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date>October 31-November 4, 2018</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Arushi</forename><surname>Raghuvanshi</surname></persName>
							<email>arushi@cisco.com</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Cisco Systems</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">Cisco Systems</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit3">Cisco Systems</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lucien</forename><surname>Carroll</surname></persName>
							<email>lucienc@cisco.com</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Cisco Systems</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">Cisco Systems</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit3">Cisco Systems</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Karthik</forename><surname>Raghunathan</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Cisco Systems</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">Cisco Systems</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit3">Cisco Systems</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Developing Production-Level Conversational Interfaces with Shallow Semantic Parsing</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2018 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (System Demonstrations)</title>
						<meeting>the 2018 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (System Demonstrations) <address><addrLine>Brussels; Belgium</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="157" to="162"/>
							<date type="published">October 31-November 4, 2018</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<note>157</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>We demonstrate an end-to-end approach for building conversational interfaces from prototype to production that has proven to work well for a number of applications across diverse verticals. Our architecture improves on the standard domain-intent-entity classification hierarchy and dialogue management architecture by leveraging shallow semantic parsing. We observe that NLU systems for industry applications often require more struc-tured representations of entity relations than provided by the standard hierarchy, yet without requiring full semantic parses which are often inaccurate on real-world conversational data. We distinguish two kinds of semantic properties that can be provided through shallow semantic parsing: entity groups and entity roles. We also provide live demos of conversational apps built for two different use cases: food ordering and meeting control.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Conversational interfaces are a prominent fea- ture of many consumer technology products to- day. Popular voice assistants, such as Alexa, Siri, Google Assistant, and Cortana, have been built us- ing a methodical approach of domain-intent-entity classification and dialogue management that is be- coming an industry standard <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Dialogflow, 2018;</ref><ref type="bibr">Wit.ai, 2018;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Amazon, 2018;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Microsoft, 2018)</ref>.</p><p>In this demo, we share best practices on de- veloping production conversational interfaces. We provide attendees with an interactive demo which illustrates the live classification of each model in the end-to-end pipeline for different queries and use cases. The demo systems focus on two use cases in English-food ordering and meeting control-though the architecture is broadly appli- cable to other languages and use cases.</p><p>Furthermore, we introduce two components of the pipeline that are improvements over the indus- try standard-entity grouping and entity roles- which are forms of shallow semantic parsing. We demonstrate the value of these shallow seman- tic parses, going beyond named entity recognition without exhaustive semantic or syntactic parsing, or even full relation extraction. We first give an overview of the system architecture, then describe the shallow semantic parsing problems in more de- tail and compare our approach to related systems.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Architecture</head><p>The NLP pipeline is broken down into a series of components as illustrated in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref>: Intent Clas- sifier, Entity Recognizer, Entity Resolver, Seman- tic Parser, Dialogue Manager, Question Answerer and Application Manager. For each component, the model type, features, and hyperparameters are tuned for the use case.</p><p>This architecture allows us to bootstrap appli- cations with few queries per intent-tens or hun- dreds of queries for narrow vocabulary intents and thousands of queries for open vocabulary intents-and smoothly transition as data sets in- crease. Getting a deployable version of a conver- sational assistant on small data set sizes is key, since generating conversational data is expensive, and early in development, product decisions can often change, requiring relabeling the data. Once a model is in production, dataset sizes can grow by labeling queries from user logs. This architecture scales well and continues to give robust perfor- mance as query sizes increase by orders of mag- nitude. As the dataset sizes grow, the most op- timal model type, features, and hyperparameters will change.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">Intent Classification</head><p>A Domain Classifier assigns an incoming query into one of a set of pre-defined topical buckets or domains. This is a classification model that uses text features like n-grams and gazetteer matches to determine which domain the vocabulary of the query is most likely in. In addition to these fea- tures that capture language and sentence structure, this component has access to the user context and the history of previous queries in the conversation. Different models such as logistic regression (LR), support vector machine (SVM), decision tree, or random forest can be selected for different use cases based on the data set size and distribution.</p><p>Intent Classifiers predict which of the do- main's intents is expressed in the request. It is a text classification model like the domain classifier, but trained on data to distinguish among the types of intended dialogue acts within a domain. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 2</ref> illustrates the domain and intent classi- fications for the input query "I'd like a plain bagel that's warmed up and with cream cheese" for a food ordering app. In the demo, users can try tweaking the language of the query and see how it affects the model prediction. For example, when keeping the phrase "I'd like a", but changing the rest of the query to an unrelated item (e.g. "I'd like a link to a funny video"), the domain classification changes to UNRELATED. When tweaking the lan- guage from "I'd like a bagel" to a more explicit "I want to order a bagel" increases the confidence of the ORDER intent classification.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">Entity Recognition</head><p>Entity Recognizers identify and label entities- the words and phrases that must be represented and interpreted to fulfill requests. It is a se- quence tagging model such as a Maximum En- tropy Markov Model (MEMM), Long Short-Term Memory recurrent neural network (LSTM), or a Conditional Random Field (CRF). The features depend on the model type used but can include word embeddings or gazetteer matches. The opti- mal model is dependent on dataset size. A MEMM model with gazetteer and n-gram features may be most robust when trained on a few hundred queries, but the LSTM model with character and In <ref type="figure">Figure 3</ref> we illustrate the extracted entities from an example query and the confidence of those predictions.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3">Entity Resolution</head><p>An Entity Resolver maps each identified entity to a canonical value. For example, in the food or- dering use case, the text "plain bagel" needs to be mapped to a canonical id that can be use to make an API call to place the order.</p><p>The entity resolver uses an information retrieval (IR) approach to resolve to the correct canonical form by doing text matching against an index of canonical entities. This matching uses common IR techniques of character n-gram, token n-gram, and fuzzy matching as well as tf-idf scoring. The index also contains information like synonyms for entities, so the model can correctly resolve items <ref type="figure">Figure 4</ref>: Entity resolver demo view that are semantically similar but syntactically dif- ferent. For example, "pasta with tomato sauce" can be resolved to "spaghetti marinara". In <ref type="figure">Fig- ure 4</ref>, the entity text "warmed up" is resolved to the "Warmed" (SKU: 204198) as an example.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.4">Semantic Parser</head><p>The interpretation of some queries requires a more structured representation than domains, intents and entities provide. We decompose entity rela- tion extraction into two degenerate cases: assign- ment of entity relation type or role and association of dependent 'child' entities to a head 'parent' en- tity in an entity group. Though some use cases require both kinds of information, many use cases only require one of these, and it is productive to treat them as separable problems.</p><p>Entity Role Classifiers add another level of labeling when knowing an entity's type is not enough to interpret the entity correctly. E.g., a role label can be used to classify a numerical entity as a SIZE versus a QUANTITY. In the case "I'll have the 12 oz soda", the role of the entity "12" should be SIZE, but in the case "I'll have 3 sodas", the role of the entity "3" should be a QUANTITY.</p><p>The addition of the role classification is novel to our architecture. It is an intermediate between us- ing only NER and doing a full semantic or syntac- tic parse. The benefit of doing role classification is that you can get important semantic and syntactic information in a targeted way for entities that are predefined to take multiple roles, rather than hav- ing to generate a full parse for each query. Without this learned role classification, systems often have to rely on heuristics in the dialogue manager to determine the roles of the entities. Unlike our ap- proach, the alternative of using ruled-based heuris- tics does not scale to unseen language patterns. Our role classifier can be a logistic regression, SVM, decision tree, or random forest model. The best model is selected based on the data distribu- tion and use case. Features include n-grams, bag of words, and other entities present in the query.</p><p>A Entity Group Parser finds relationships be- tween the extracted entities and groups them into a meaningful hierarchy as illustrated in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 5</ref>.</p><p>The language parser for entity grouping is an- other novel component of our architecture. A small number of configuration parameters gener- ates a weighted context-free grammar (WCFG) over entities and the words not in entities. The de- veloper can specify whether to allow parent-child attachment to the left or right, what the minimum or maximum number of dependent entities should be, and the preferred direction of attachment. The developer can also specify certain 'linking' words, whose occurrence between two entities increases the chance of the entities being in the specified head-dependent relationship. More details on the semantic parser are given in section 3.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.5">Question Answerer</head><p>A Question Answerer queries a Knowledge Base, which encompasses all of the important world knowledge for a given application use case, to find answers to user queries. The example in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Figure 6</ref> demonstrates the ranked list of relevant results for the request "what pastries are available?".</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.6">Dialogue Manager</head><p>A Dialogue Manager analyzes each processed query, executes the required logic, and returns an appropriate natural language response. The lan- guage of the response itself is often templated, but the appropriate template is selected based on the context of the target domain, intent, entities, and results from the question answerer. In the exam- ple in <ref type="figure">Figure 7</ref>, the user's query was classified as the order intent with the correct entity and op- tions filled in, so the dialogue manager prompts the user to confirm their order and informs them of the pickup time.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.7">Application Manager</head><p>An Application Manager orchestrates the query workflow. It receives requests from the client in- cluding both text queries and context information, processes the requests by passing them through each of the other components, and then returns the final response to the client endpoint.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Shallow Semantic Parsing</head><p>In conventional semantic parsing, a single tree of dependency relations is constructed to cover ap- proximately a whole sentence, enabling a transla- tion from natural language to logical form for each sentence. In the example below, the dependencies OWNER, POSSESSION and QUANTITY can be as- signed within a sentence in which a NUMBER en- tity and DRINK entity are already recognized. In contrast, entity grouping associates child enti- ties to a parent entity without specifying a rela- tion type, such as the OPTION entities to the corre- sponding DISH entities below.</p><p>a bagel with butter and warm muffin</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">DISH OPTION OPTION DISH</formula><p>Entity grouping is sufficient in cases where there is only one relation type relevant to a particular in- tent, or in cases where the relation type is fully de- termined by the associated entity types. But even when both relation type and parent-child links are required, as below, we benefit from decomposing the problem.</p><p>a bagel and two of the muffins</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">DISH NUMBER DISH QUANTITY</formula><p>In the initial stages of development, when train- ing data is limited, this allows the system to use a probabilistic model for role labeling which gener- alizes across cases with and without explicit heads, while using a simple deterministic parser for entity grouping. Once training data is sufficient, these can be smoothly transitioned to a fully probabilis- tic dependency parser, performing joint learning of entity roles and entity groups.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Evaluation of the Semantic Parser</head><p>To illustrate the trade-off in model approaches within this architecture as development matures, we provide an evaluation of different entity group- ing systems in <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>. The test data in this eval- uation is 200 food ordering queries with more than one DISH entity, and we focus on query-level accuracy-the percentage of queries with correct labels. The baseline system Nearest Head simply assigns any dependent entity to the nearest avail- able head entity. The Default WCFG system uses NLTK ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Bird et al., 2009</ref>) to construct a CFG over entities and assigns domain-general costs to se- lect a parse, while the Tuned WCFG uses prefer- ences specified by the developer for this use case (e.g. particular entities tend to associate left vs. right) to adapt the cost calculation to the use case. Tuning the WCFG on 1225 queries with multi- ple dish entities provides an acceptable 97% accu- racy. The DepP system trains the transition-based</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>System</head><p>Train # dependency parser from Spacy v. 1.9 (Honnibal and Johnson, 2015) on the entity grouping prob- lem. With only 1225 training queries, the parser is not able to learn the structure of the problem well, sometimes leaving dependent entity types unas- sociated or producing impossible tag sequences. Fixup rules that force dependent entities to asso- ciate to a head entity improve the accuracy, and adding nearly 4000 training queries that only have one DISH name allows the parser to learn the ba- sic structure better. The combination of these al- lows the DepP system to reach 98.5% accuracy. With smaller training data set sizes the DepP sys- tem is not viable, but once training data increases, we can expect more robust performance from the more powerful model.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Related Work</head><p>Our approach extends a long history of work in shallow semantics for NLU. Conceptually the most similar is work on relation extraction, as established by the Automatic Content Extraction (ACE) program <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(Doddington et al., 2004</ref>). For ex- ample, <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Culotta and Sorensen (2004)</ref>   <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">and Lapata, 2016)</ref>, and simi- lar models have the power to jointly learn role la- bels and entity groups. However, these methods only perform well with abundant training data, so while product decisions are in flux, working with simpler models facilitates the quick development of a production app on smaller data sets. Some researchers have attempted full seman- tic parsing for task-oriented systems similar to ours. <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Berant et al. (2013)</ref> induce a semantic parser from question-answer pairs, and then these parses can be used to find answers for unseen questions. <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Chen et al. (2014)</ref> combine a semantic parser with word embeddings to induce mappings from the semantic parser's relations to the slots of a task-oriented dialogue system. In customer-facing products, systems trained by unsupervised learn- ing have too high risk of misbehavior. Moreover, in our applied domains, either the relation head or the relation type is often predetermined or irrele- vant, so that information can remain undefined or implicit, leaving a simpler problem.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Conclusion</head><p>We have described a dialogue system interface for an architecture which extends the traditional NLU pipeline with entity role labeling and entity grouping, forms of shallow semantic parsing. The described methodology has allowed us to consis- tently build production-level conversational assis- tants. In this demo, we hope to share these insights in an interactive way.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: Natural language processing pipeline</figDesc><graphic url="image-1.png" coords="2,72.00,62.81,218.27,74.77" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2: Domain and intent classifier demo view</figDesc><graphic url="image-3.png" coords="2,307.28,305.13,218.26,143.15" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 5 :</head><label>5</label><figDesc>Figure 5: Semantic parser demo view</figDesc><graphic url="image-5.png" coords="3,307.28,62.81,218.26,183.56" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>Figure 6 :</head><label>6</label><figDesc>Figure 6: Question answerer demo view</figDesc><graphic url="image-7.png" coords="4,72.00,288.24,218.26,200.36" type="bitmap" /></figure>

			<note place="foot">Wit.ai. 2018. Build your first app. https://wit.ai/docs/ quickstart.</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7">Acknowledgements</head><p>The software presented in this paper has greatly benefited from the comments and code contribu-tions of Tim Tuttle, J.J. Jackson, Vijay Ramakr-ishnan, Marvin Huang, Jui-Pin Wang, Minh Tue Vo Thanh, Amrut Nagasunder, and Varsha Embar.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Create the interaction model for your skill</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Amazon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://developer.amazon.com/docs/custom-skills/create-the-interaction-model-for-your-skill.html" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Semantic parsing on freebase from question-answer pairs</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jonathan</forename><surname>Berant</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Andrew</forename><surname>Chou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Roy</forename><surname>Frostig</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Percy</forename><surname>Liang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2013 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</title>
		<meeting>the 2013 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1533" to="1544" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Natural Language Processing with Python</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Steven</forename><surname>Bird</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Edward</forename><surname>Loper</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ewan</forename><surname>Klein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<publisher>Reilly Media Inc</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A shortest path dependency kernel for relation extraction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Razvan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Raymond</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Bunescu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Mooney</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the conference on Human Language Technology and Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing-HLT &apos;05</title>
		<meeting>the conference on Human Language Technology and Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing-HLT &apos;05<address><addrLine>Morristown, NJ, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="724" to="731" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Leveraging frame semantics and distributional semantics for unsupervised semantic slot induction in spoken dialogue systems</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yun-Nung</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">William</forename><forename type="middle">Yang</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alexander</forename><forename type="middle">I</forename><surname>Rudnicky</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">2014 IEEE Spoken Language Technology Workshop (SLT)</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>IEEE</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="584" to="589" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dependency tree kernels for relation extraction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Aron</forename><surname>Culotta</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jeffrey</forename><surname>Sorensen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 42nd Annual Meeting on Association for Computational Linguistics-ACL &apos;04</title>
		<meeting>the 42nd Annual Meeting on Association for Computational Linguistics-ACL &apos;04<address><addrLine>Morristown, NJ, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
			<biblScope unit="page">423</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Association for Computational Linguistics</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Create and query your first agent</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Dialogflow</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://dialogflow.com/docs/getting-started/first-agent" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Automatic Content Extraction (ACE) Program Tasks, Data, and Evaluation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">George</forename><surname>Doddington</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alexis</forename><surname>Mitchell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mark</forename><surname>Przybocki</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lance</forename><surname>Ramshaw</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Stephanie</forename><surname>Strassel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ralph</forename><surname>Weischedel</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of LREC 2004</title>
		<meeting>LREC 2004</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="837" to="840" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">An Improved Non-monotonic Transition System for Dependency Parsing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Matthew</forename><surname>Honnibal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mark</forename><surname>Johnson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2015 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</title>
		<meeting>the 2015 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1373" to="1378" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Semantic Role Labeling: An Introduction to the Special Issue</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xavier</forename><surname>Lluís</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kenneth</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Carreras</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Suzanne</forename><surname>Litkowski</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Stevenson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Computational Linguistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">34</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="145" to="159" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Building conversations</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Microsoft</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/cortana/skills/mva32-building-conversations" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">End-to-End Relation Extraction using LSTMs on Sequences and Tree Structures</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Makoto</forename><surname>Miwa</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mohit</forename><surname>Bansal</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 54th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the 54th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1105" to="1116" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Semantic Role Labeling</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Martha</forename><surname>Palmer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Daniel</forename><surname>Gildea</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nianwen</forename><surname>Xue</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Synthesis Lectures on Human Language Technologies</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="103" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Neural Semantic Role Labeling with Dependency Path Embeddings</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Roth</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mirella</forename><surname>Lapata</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 54th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the 54th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1192" to="1202" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
