<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T12:07+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Preface by the General Chair Text Mining and Information Retrieval</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jordan</forename><surname>Boyd-Graber</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xavier</forename><surname>Carreras</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yejin</forename><surname>Choi</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Philipp</forename><surname>Koehn</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alessandro</forename><surname>Moschitti</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Slav</forename><surname>Petrov</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Massimo</forename><surname>Poesio</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kam-Fai</forename><surname>Wong</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Chiang</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Julia</forename><surname>Hockenmaier</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Junichi</forename><surname>Tsujii</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dominique</forename><surname>De Brabanter</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><roleName>Belgium</roleName><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">U</forename><surname>Leuven</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Frieda</forename><surname>Steurs</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">U</forename><surname>Leuven</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Belgium</forename><forename type="middle">Hugo</forename><surname>Van</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">U</forename><surname>Leuven</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Belgium</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Junichi</forename><surname>Tsujii</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">William</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Scott</forename><surname>Yih</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Allen</forename></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alessandro</forename><surname>Moschitti</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sophia</forename><surname>Ananiadou</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alan</forename><surname>Ritter</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Smith</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alice</forename><surname>Oh</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Kaist</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wei</forename><surname>Korea</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Xu</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">University of Notre Dame</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Jun&apos;ichi Tsujii</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Artificial Intelligence Research Center</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">Artificial Intelligence Research Center</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Illinois Urbana-Champaign</orgName>
								<address>
									<country>USA, Japan, Japan</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="department">Institute for Artificial Intelligence</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">Artificial Intelligence Research Center</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of California at Santa Barbara</orgName>
								<address>
									<country>Japan, USA, USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff3">
								<orgName type="institution">University of Trento</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="IT">Italy</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff4">
								<orgName type="institution">University of Manchester</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>United Kingdom Hsin-Hsi Chen</addrLine>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff5">
								<orgName type="department">Xiang Ren</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">National Taiwan University Marius Pasca</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Google</settlement>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff6">
								<orgName type="institution">University of Southern California</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff7">
								<orgName type="institution">Ohio State University</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff8">
								<orgName type="institution">Northeastern University</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff9">
								<orgName type="institution">Ohio State University</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff10">
								<orgName type="laboratory">Reut Tsarfaty, Open University of Isra xiii Semantics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Oslo</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Norway Emily Pitler</addrLine>
									<settlement>Google</settlement>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff11">
								<orgName type="institution">Queen Mary University of London</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="GB">United Kingdom</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff12">
								<orgName type="institution">Hebrew University of Jerusalem</orgName>
								<address>
									<country>Israel Raffaella</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff13">
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Bernardi</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">University of Trento</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="IT">Italy</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff14">
								<orgName type="institution">Michael Lewis</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Facebook</settlement>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff15">
								<orgName type="institution">Leiden University</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Netherlands Qun Liu</addrLine>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff16">
								<orgName type="institution">Dublin City University</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="IE">Ireland</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff17">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Taro Watanabe</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Danish Contractor</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">SimpleQuestions Nearly Solved: A New Upperbound and Baseline Approach</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Tsinghua University</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>China Zhaopeng Tu, Bonaventura Coppola, Gregory F. Coppola</addrLine>
									<settlement>Google, Marta</settlement>
									<region>Tencent</region>
									<country>China, Japan</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff18">
								<orgName type="department">Multi-Source Syntactic Neural Machine Translation</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory" key="lab1">Convolutional Interaction Network for Natural Language Inference</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory" key="lab2">Adversarial Evaluation of Multimodal Machine Translation</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory" key="lab3">Interpretable Emoji Prediction via Label-Wise Attention LSTMs</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Implicational Universals in Stochastic Constraint-Based Phonology</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Preface by the General Chair Text Mining and Information Retrieval</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<note>EMNLP 2018 Program Co-Chairs ix Organizing Committee General Chair Ellen Riloff, University of Utah, USA Program Committee Co-chairs David Chiang, University of Notre Dame, USA Julia Hockenmaier, University of Illinois Urbana-Champaign, USA Local Arrangements Committee Marie-Francine Moens, KU Leuven, Belgium (chair) Local Sponsorship Chair Katrien Beuls, Vrije Universiteit Brussel, Belgium Workshop Co-chairs Marieke van Erp, KNAW Humanities Cluster, Netherlands Vincent Ng, University of Texas at Dallas, USA Tutorial Co-chairs Mausam, Indian Institute of Technology Delhi, India Lu Wang, Northeastern University, USA Demos Co-chairs Eduardo Blanco, University of North Texas, USA Wei Lu, Singapore University of Technology and Design, Singapore Publications Sr Chair Preethi Raghavan, IBM, USA Publications Jr Chair Micha Elsner, Ohio State University, USA Publicity Chair Mohit Iyyer, University of Massachusetts at Amherst, USA Video Chair Bonan Min, BBN Technologies, USA Website and Conference App Chair Nitin Madnani, Educational Testing Service, USA Conference Handbook Chair Kai-Wei Chang, University of California at Los Angeles, USA xi Conference Handbook Advisor Joachim Bingel, University of Copenhagen, Denmark Handbook Proofreader He He, Stanford University, USA Student Scholarship Co-chair and Student Volunteer Coordinator Anna Rumshisky, University of Massachusetts at Lowell, USA Hugo Van hamme, KU Leuven, Belgium Childcare Policy and Grant Coordinator Swapna Somasundaran, Educational Testing Service, USA Aoife Cahill, Educational Testing Service, USA xii Program Committee Program Committee Co-chairs David Chiang, University of Notre Dame, USA Julia Hockenmaier, University of Illinois Urbana-Champaign, USA Area Chairs Information Extraction, Information Retrieval, and Question Answering Jordan Boyd-Graber, University of Maryland, USA (senior chair) Isabelle Augenstein, University of Copenhagen, Denmark Ming-Wei Chang, Google, USA Doug Downey, Northwestern University, USA Ruihong Huang, Texas A&amp;M University, USA Mausam, IIT Delhi, India Makoto Miwa, Toyota Technological Institute, Japan Social Media, Computational Social Science, and Sentiment/Opinion Analysis Kam-Fai Wong, Chinese University of Hong Kong (senior chair) Eiji Aramaki, Nara Institute of Science and Technology, Japan Mona Diab, George Washington University, USA Yulan He, Aston University, United Kingdom Dirk Hovy, Bocconi University, Italy Rada Mihalcea, University of Michigan, USA</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Welcome to EMNLP 2018 in Brussels, Belgium! I hope that EMNLP 2018 will be a memorable experience filled with exciting research presentations, outstanding keynote speakers, and many stimulating conversations with colleagues and friends, both old and new. In the evenings, I hope that you will explore the wonderful city of Brussels! Admire the historic buildings, visit great museums, and enjoy the Belgian cuisine. EMNLP 2018 will have an extensive technical program that includes 14 workshops, 6 tutorials, 3 invited speakers, 351 long paper presentations, 198 short paper presentations, 10 TACL paper presentations, and 29 demos. I want to give special thanks to the Program Co-Chairs: David Chiang, Julia Hockenmaier, and Jun&apos;ichi Tsujii. EMNLP 2018 received a record-breaking 2,231 valid submissions, a 48% increase over EMNLP 2017! Despite the massive volume of submissions, the PC chairs put tremendous care into every decision, big and small, and gracefully handled numerous inquiries and requests. Their commitment to a high-quality program was inspiring. Of course, the PC Chairs did not handle the workload alone: we all owe an enormous debt of gratitude to the 60 Area Chairs and 1,436 reviewers (yes, 1,400+ reviewers!) who took on the critical responsibilities of reviewing paper submissions and providing feedback to the program chairs. Thank you all! The Demo Co-Chairs, Eduardo Blanco and Wei Lu, also had to handle an usually high workload. EMNLP 2018 received 77 demo submissions, which was a 40% increase over EMNLP 2017. They recruited an additional 150+ reviewers to assess the demo submissions, and managed the review process seamlessly. Thank you, Eduardo and Wei! Nitin Madnani deserves special thanks for taking charge of both the EMNLP 2018 web site and conference app, and doing a fantastic job. Nitin was a pleasure to work with, and incredibly responsive, answering emails impossibly fast and accommodating every request. Thanks also to our Publicity Chair, Mohit Iyyer, for advertising the conference on social media and elsewhere, and our Video Chair, Bonan Min, for handling the video recordings. Managing the conference proceedings and compiling the handbook are extremely time-consuming and tedious jobs, but less visible to conference attendees, who only see the final products. Enormous vi thanks to the Publication Chairs, Micha Elsner (junior chair) and Preethi Raghavan (senior chair), the Conference Handbook Chair, Kai-Wei Chang, the Handbook Advisor, Joachim Bingel, and the Handbook Proofreader, He He. They were truly a fantastic team! And a huge thanks to the Local Organization Committee from KU Leuven: Marie-Francine Moens (chair), Dominique De Brabanter, Frieda Steurs, and Hugo Van hamme, as well as the Local Sponsorship Chair, Katrien Beuls from Vrije Universiteit Brussel. Their hard work and enthusiasm were key to making EMNLP 2018 a success! In addition, a large conference like EMNLP depends heavily on sponsorship, and I want to sincerely thank all of the EMNLP 2018 sponsors for their generous support! I must also thank SIGDAT for their support throughout this past year. With extra thanks to Noah Smith, the SIGDAT Secretary-Treasurer and EMNLP liaison, for his support of our new initiatives, valuable feedback, and quick responses. Finally, I owe a huge debt of gratitude to Priscilla Rasmussen, who managed so many aspects of the conference that I can&apos;t even begin to name them. A heartfelt thanks to Priscilla for her hard work, sage advice, and for patiently answering an endless stream of questions from me, and many others. And thanks to all of YOU for participating in EMNLP 2018! I hope you enjoy the conference and your time in Brussels! EMNLP 2018 General Chair Ellen Riloff, University of Utah, USA vii Preface by the Program Committee Co-Chairs Welcome to EMNLP 2018! This year&apos;s technical program consists of three invited talks, 224 oral presentations (including three papers appearing in the Transactions of the ACL), and 335 poster presentations (including seven papers appearing in TACL). To our knowledge, it&apos;s the largest NLP conference ever, and it would not have been possible without the help of our program committee members. This year, we organized the program committee into eight broad areas. For each area, one of our amazing senior area chairs () headed a team of several other area chairs (totaling 52 across all areas) and an army of reviewers (totaling 1,436 across all areas). We&apos;d like to especially thank those reviewers who agreed to review a full load of papers, which turned out to be a bit heavier than expected! 2018 appears to have been the year of experimentation with new review forms, and EMNLP was no exception. We eliminated many of the traditional numerical ratings and divided up the free-form comments into a small number of separate free-response questions. We tried to make this new structure mirror the structure of a typical review, while encouraging more comprehensive reviewing. Extrapolating exponentially from the past two years, we expected to receive about 1,800 submissions, but the eventual number exceeded our expectations at 2,231 (excluding empty and duplicate submissions). After removal of invalid submissions and some withdrawals, we sent 2,116 papers out for review. Despite the growing number of submissions, we tried to keep acceptance rates at the same level as past years. The acceptance statistics are shown below.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Long</head><p>We are delighted to have keynote addresses from three giants of our field: Johan Bos, on the future of computational semantics; Julia Hirschberg, on deception detection in speech; and Gideon Mann, on the use of NLP in finance.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>viii</head><p>In addition to our entire program committee, we would also like to give thanks to:</p><p>• Our general chair, Ellen Riloff,</p><p>• Priscilla Rasmussen,</p><p>• Last year's program chairs, Rebecca Hwa and Sebastian Riedel,</p><p>• Our local chair, Marie-Francine Moens, and the local organizing committee,</p><p>• Our web and publicity chairs, Nitin Madnani and Mohit Iyyer,</p><p>• Our publications chairs, Micha Elsner and Preethi Raghavan,</p><p>• Our handbook chair, Kai-Wei Chang,</p><p>• Rich Gerber and the technical support team at SoftConf.</p><p>Again, welcome! We hope that you enjoy this year's conference, and return home with new insights, ideas, and opportunities! Invited Speaker: Johan Bos, University of Groningen</p><p>The Moment of Meaning and the Future of Computational Semantics</p><p>Abstract: There are many recent advances in semantic parsing: we see a rising number of semantically annotated corpora and there is exciting technology (such as neural networks) to be explored. In this talk I will discuss what role computational semantics could play in future natural language processing applications (including fact checking and machine translation). I will argue that we should not just look at semantic parsing, but that things can get really interesting when we can use language-neutral meaning representations to draw (transparent) inferences. The main ideas will be exemplified by the parallel meaning bank, a new corpus comprising texts annotated with formal meaning representations for English, Dutch, German and Italian.</p><p>Bio: Johan Bos is Professor of Computational Semantics at the University of Groningen (Netherlands Abstract: Detecting deception from various forms of human behavior is a longstanding research goal which is of considerable interest to the military, law enforcement, corporate security, social services and mental health workers. However, both humans and polygraphs are very poor at this task. We describe more accurate methods we have developed to detect deception automatically from spoken lan- guage. Our classifiers are trained on the largest cleanly recorded corpus of within-subject deceptive and non-deceptive speech that has been collected. To distinguish truth from lie we make use of acoustic- prosodic, lexical, demographic, and personality features. We further examine differences in deceptive behavior based upon gender, personality, and native language (Mandarin Chinese vs. English), com- paring our systems to human performance. We extend our studies to identify cues in trusted speech vs. mistrusted speech and how these features differ by speaker and by listener. Why does a listener believe a lie? </p><formula xml:id="formula_0">Bio:</formula></div>		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl/>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
