<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T12:30+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">WikiConv: A Corpus of the Complete Conversational History of a Large Online Collaborative Community</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
				<availability status="unknown"><p>Copyright Association for Computational Linguistics</p>
				</availability>
				<date>October 31-November 4, 2018. 2018</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yiqing</forename><surname>Hua</surname></persName>
							<email>yiqing@cs.cornell.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Wikimedia Foundation</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Cornell Tech</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">Cornell University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Cristian</forename><surname>Danescu-Niculescu-Mizil</surname></persName>
							<email>cristian@cs.cornell.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Wikimedia Foundation</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Cornell Tech</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">Cornell University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dario</forename><surname>Taraborelli</surname></persName>
							<email>dtaraborelli@wikimedia.org</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Wikimedia Foundation</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Cornell Tech</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">Cornell University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nithum</forename><surname>Thain</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Wikimedia Foundation</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Cornell Tech</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">Cornell University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jeffery</forename><surname>Sorensen</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Wikimedia Foundation</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Cornell Tech</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">Cornell University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><roleName>Jigsaw, Google</roleName><forename type="first">Lucas</forename><surname>Dixon</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Wikimedia Foundation</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Cornell Tech</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">Cornell University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">WikiConv: A Corpus of the Complete Conversational History of a Large Online Collaborative Community</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2018 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</title>
						<meeting>the 2018 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing <address><addrLine>Brussels, Belgium</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="2818" to="2823"/>
							<date type="published">October 31-November 4, 2018. 2018</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<note>2818</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>We present a corpus that encompasses the complete history of conversations between contributors to Wikipedia, one of the largest online collaborative communities. By recording the intermediate states of conversations-including not only comments and replies, but also their modifications, deletions and restorations-this data offers an unprecedented view of online conversation. This level of detail supports new research questions pertaining to the process (and challenges) of large-scale online collaboration. We illustrate the corpus&apos; potential with two case studies that highlight new perspectives on earlier work. First, we explore how a person&apos;s conversational behavior depends on how they relate to the discussion&apos;s venue. Second, we show that community moderation of toxic behavior happens at a higher rate than previously estimated. Finally the reconstruction framework is designed to be language agnostic, and we show that it can extract high quality conversational data in both Chinese and English.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Compared to large-scale collections of conver- sations from social media <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Felbo et al., 2017;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Luo et al., 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Zhang et al., 2017;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Tan et al., 2016)</ref> or news comments ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Napoles et al., 2017)</ref>, Wikipedia talk pages offer a unique perspective into goal-oriented discussions between thousands of volunteer contributors coordinating to write the largest online encyclopedia. Talk page data already underpins research on social phenom- ena such as conversational behavior <ref type="bibr">(DanescuNiculescu-Mizil et al., 2012</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b2">, 2013</ref>, disputes ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Wang and Cardie, 2014b)</ref>, antisocial behavior ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Wulczyn et al., 2017;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Zhang et al., 2018</ref>) and collaboration ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Kittur et al., 2007;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Halfaker et al., 2009)</ref>. However, the scope of such studies has so far been limited by a view of the conversation that is incomplete in two crucial ways: first, it only captures a subset of all discussions; and second, it only accounts for the final form of each conversa- tion, which frequently differs from the interlocu- tors experience as the conversation develops.</p><p>In this paper, we undertake the challenge of reconstructing a complete and structured history of the conversational process in Wikipedia talk pages, containing detailed information about all the interlocutors' actions, such as adding and re- plying to comments, modifying or deleting them. To this end, we devise a methodology for identi- fying and structuring these actions, while also ad- dressing the challenges spurring from the incon- sistent formatting and the raw scale of existing records. This results in the largest public dataset of goal-oriented conversations, WikiConv, span- ning five languages. The largest component of this dataset is based on the English Wikipedia, and contains roughly 91 million conversations consist- ing of 212 million conversational actions taking place in 24 million talk pages.</p><p>By including details about how each conver- sation evolved, this corpus provides an unprece- dented view into the conversational process, as ex-perienced by the interlocutors. In fact, we find that about 40% of discussion activity would be missed by approaches that do not consider comment mod- ifications and deletions, and even more is missed when only considering the (final) static snapshots of conversations. Furthermore, a manual review of the English Wikipedia portion of the dataset re- veals that 98% of the reply structure is recovered correctly and 98% of the interlocutor's actions are categorized correctly.</p><p>Since the reconstruction pipeline does not rely on any language specific heuristics, we also ap- ply it to Chinese, German, Greek and Russian Wikipedia Talk page archives, in addition to those from English Wikipadia. A manual review of the conversations obtained from the Chinese Wikipedia Talk pages shows a similarly high re- construction accuracy with that obtained from the English Wikipedia, suggesting that it is reasonable to apply the reconstruction pipeline to different languages. To encourage further validation, refine- ments and updates, we have open sourced the code and published the datasets. <ref type="bibr">1</ref> Finally, we present two case studies illustrat- ing how the corpus can bring new insights into previously observed phenomena. We first analyze the conversational behavior of a subset of English Wikipedia contributors across the entire range of talk pages, and show that their levels of linguistic coordination vary according to where the conver- sation takes place. Second, we investigate the tox- icity of deleted comments, and show that commu- nity moderation of undesired behavior takes place at a much higher rate than previously estimated.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Further Related Work</head><p>Past efforts aimed at characterizing conversa- tions on Wikipedia talk pages have either focused on snapshots of discussion threads (Danescu- Niculescu- <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Mizil et al., 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Prabhakaran and Rambow, 2016;</ref><ref type="bibr">Wang and Cardie, 2014b,a)</ref>, or have considered text segments in talk page history as incremental comments, ignoring conversational turns and reply structures within these conversa- tions ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Wulczyn et al., 2017)</ref>. The limitations of these approaches can be seen in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 2</ref>, where, if we limit our analysis to only a snapshot of the final state of the conversation, we miss the abusive comment introduced in revision 3 and removed in revision 4, and thus miss an important part of the </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>English Wikipedia</head><p>Reconstruction interactions as a graph of actions, as illustrated in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 2</ref>. Actions are categorized into five types:</p><p>• Creation: the start of a conversation thread based on a markup section heading being added (e.g. Ac- tion 1 in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 2</ref>).</p><p>• Addition: the addition of a new comment to a thread (e.g. Actions 2 and 3).</p><p>• Modification: modification of an existing com- ment (e.g. Action 5); with the original specified as the Parent-id.</p><p>• Deletion: the removal of a comment or heading (e.g. Action 4) where the Parent-id specifies the comment or heading's most recent action.</p><p>• Restoration: a revert specifies the deleted action being undone as the Parent-id.</p><p>All action types except thread creations, thread deletions and thread restorations also include a ReplyTo-id indicating the target of the reply. From Page Revisions to Actions. Our recon- struction pipeline is a Python program written for Google Cloud Dataflow (also known as Apache Beam) <ref type="bibr">4</ref> that operates on pages in parallel and on the revisions of each page sequentially in temporal order.</p><p>Due to the large scale of Wikipedia data, we use external sorting for pages that contains too many revisions to fit in a Dataflow worker's memory.</p><p>When the number of revisions is too large for a Dataflow worker's local disk, the computation is performed in stages, a few years at a time.</p><p>Given the sorted set of a page-revisions, token- level diffs between sequential revisions are com- puted using a longest common sequence (LCS) algorithm. <ref type="bibr">5</ref> Each sequential diff is then decom- posed into the set of atomic conversation actions attributed to the user who submitted the page revi- sion. During the sequential processing of a page's revisions, two data structures are maintained: each comment's current character offset, and a list of deleted comments. The comment offsets are used to interpret the difference between modification actions (edits within the bounds of an existing ac- tion) and additions; the deleted comments are used to identify restoration of comments.</p><p>We store the most recent 100 deleted com- ments between 10 to 1000 characters long, for each page. This is used to compute when a com- ment is restored by looking up deleted comments in a trie. The token length lower bound param- eter avoids short commonly added comments- like "Thanks!"-from being interpreted as restora- tions. The upper bound ensures that occasional very long deleted comments are skipped, to bound Dataflow workers' memory usage.</p><p>Finally, reconstructed actions are processed us- ing mwparserfromhell 6 to clean the MediaWiki formating. Note that, since arbitrary page changes are allowed, some actions cannot be processed by the parser (about 1 in 200,000); in such cases, an action's raw MediaWiki markup is stored. <ref type="table">Table 1</ref> shows summary statistics of the final dataset on English and Chinese Wikipedia. The version of the raw data dumps processed were re- trieved on July 1st 2018.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Evaluation of Reconstruction Quality</head><p>We evaluate the quality of the automatic recon- struction by manually verifying a randomly drawn subset of (at least) 100 examples from each action category. For each action we verify the accuracy of (1) the assigned action type, (2) the token-level boundary of the comment, (3) the ReplyTo rela- tion and (4) the action's Parent relation.</p><p>We conduct the evaluation for both English and Chinese data <ref type="table">(Table 1)</ref>. With over 98% of actions classified correctly in both languages, the dataset exhibits a high annotation quality given its scale and detail. From the error cases in the English data, 10% result from limitations in the current technologies for HTML parsing and LCS match- ing. User behavior that we could interpret but is not yet captured by our algorithm, such as mov- ing ongoing conversations to another talk pages accounts for another 24%. The remaining errors were from edits that we were unable to interpret. By open sourcing the reconstruction code, we en- courage further refinements.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Case Studies</head><p>We now briefly present two studies on English Wikipedia that highlight the importance of <ref type="formula">(1)</ref>   <ref type="formula">(2012)</ref> studied language coordinations (i.e., in a conversation between a and b, to what degree is b systematically adopting a's language patterns when replying to a) on a conversational corpus derived from 5, 657 User Talk pages: those associated with, and managed by, a specific user. The study showed that social status mediates the amount of linguistic coordination, with contrib- utors imitating more the linguistic style of those with higher status in the community.</p><p>We now show that the coordination pattern of the page owners in the previous dataset differs sig- nificantly based on where the conversation takes place. We compare each contributor's coordina- tion patterns on their own user talk page to pat- terns exhibited on talk pages of other contribu- tors, as well as to those on article talk pages- talk pages associated with a Wikipedia article. To avoid confounding different populations (and fall into the trap of Simpson's paradox), we only in- clude in the comparison users that had a sufficient amount of contributions across all three venues. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 3</ref> shows the three aggregated coordination values computed by applying the methodology of the original paper on 4 million addition actions that occurred before 2012.</p><p>Our results show with significant difference (p &lt; 0.001 calculated by one-way ANOVA) that contributors coordinate the least when replying on other users' talk pages, and most on their own talk page. This leads us to speculate a new hypothesis: contributors have a different perception of status In a day In a week In a month In a year After one year or respect on their own page than on others. Such questions, which require more thorough investiga- tion that depends on observing how contributors interact across different discussion venues, can be studied using the WikiConv corpus. Moderation of toxic behavior. <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Wulczyn et al. (2017)</ref> measured prevalence of personal attacks in a Wikipedia talk page corpus, and evaluated the fraction of attacks that moderators follow up on with a block or warning (17.9%). However, because there was no structured history of com- ment deletion, the authors were unable to mea- sure the rate at which toxic comments are mod- erated through deletion. Using the more complete datasets provided by WikiConv we show that the fraction of problematic comments moderated by Wikipedians is significantly higher than their ini- tial estimate suggests. We used the Perspective API 7 to score the tox- icity of all addition and creation actions (which we refer to as "comments" here). 8 Each com- ment is further classified as toxic or non-toxic ac- cording to the equal error rate threshold, follow- ing the methodology of ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Wulczyn et al., 2017)</ref>, where false positives are offset by false negatives. The threshold is calculated by on the human la- bels in the Kaggle Toxicity dataset of Wikipedia comments <ref type="bibr">9</ref> . Classification at this threshold yields 86% precision and 84% recall.</p><p>We used the same method to labeled comments with the severe toxic model. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 3</ref> shows the fraction of comments deleted by Wikipedians who are not the author of the comment for different lengths of time; distinguishing between comments labeled as toxic, severely toxic, and the back- ground distribution. The key results here are that <ref type="bibr">7</ref> www.perspectiveapi.com <ref type="bibr">8</ref> We release the scores with the dataset. <ref type="bibr">9</ref> The Jigsaw Toxicity Kaggle Competition: goo.gl/ N6UGPK nearly 33% of toxic comments are removed within a day; And over 82% of severely toxic comments are deleted within a day. This complements re- sults previously reported by <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Wulczyn et al. (2017)</ref>, accounting for an additional type of community moderation that is revealed using the detailed in- formation about the history of the conversation provided by our corpus.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Conclusion and Future Work</head><p>We introduced a pipeline that extracts the com- plete conversational history of Wikipedia talk pages at a level of detail that was not previously available. We applied this pipeline to Wikipedia in multiple languages and evaluated its quality on the English and Chinese Talk page corpora, ob- taining a high reconstruction accuracy for both the Chinese and English datasets ( ˜ 98%). This level of detail and completeness opens avenues for new research, as well as revisiting and extending existing work on online conversational and col- laboration behavior. For example, while in our use cases we have focused on contributors delet- ing toxic comments, one could seek to understand why and when an editor is deleting or rewording their own comments. Beyond refining the heuris- tics and parsing methods used in our reconstruc- tion pipeline, and reducing the time needed to up- date the corpus, a significant remaining challenge is to capture conversations that happen across page boundaries.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2: Example conversation reconstruction. The action id in the ReplyTo column defines the conversation's structure; The Parent column indicates history, showing how actions change earlier actions. Note that each revision (color-coded) can introduce multiple actions.</figDesc><graphic url="image-2.png" coords="3,72.00,62.81,453.55,166.15" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>col- lecting the full history of Wikipedia across all pages and (2) capturing the various types of in- teractions. Linguistic Coordination. Danescu-Niculescu- Mizil et al.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Figure 3: (Left) Linguistic coordination depends on the discussion's venue. Error bars are estimated by bootstrap resampling. (Right) Deletion rate of content over varying time periods.</figDesc></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> github.com/conversationai/wikidetox experience of the participants. In fact, this &quot;hidden&quot; activity accounts for one third of all actions taken on talk pages in English Wikipedia. The closest dataset to our work is Bender et al. (2011) which introduces the Authority and Alignment in Wikipedia discussions corpus (AAWD), containing 365 talk page discussions. While acknowledging the complexity of conversational behaviors on Wikipedia talk pages, the AAWD work falls short of providing data on the deletions and follow-up changes to existing comments. Beyond addressing this shortcoming, the dataset we introduce in this paper is many orders of magnitude larger, containing 91 million conversations in English Wikipedia alone. Figure 1: An example Wiki markdown and its rendered form from Wikipedia Talk Page Help 2. 3 Conversation Reconstruction Technically, comments are added to Wikipedia talk pages the same way content is added to article pages: contributors simply edit the markdown of any part of the talk page without relying on any functionality specialized for structuring the conversations. Figure 1 gives an example of the discussion interface and the resulting rendered conversation. Each edit results in a revision of the whole page that is permanently stored in a public historical record. 3 Because conversations on Wikipedia have no &apos;official&apos; underlying structure, and instead are organized using indentation markup and other ad hoc visual cues, computational heuristics are necessary to interpret conversational structure. Actions. We model the conversational structure of 2 mediawiki.org/wiki/Help:Talk_pages 3 In some rare cases revisions are deleted, for example, if personal information is accidentally written into a page.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="4"> cloud.google.com/dataflow/</note>

			<note place="foot" n="5"> github.com/google/diff-match-patch 6 github.com/earwig/mwparserfromhell</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7">Acknowledgement</head><p>We thank Thomas Ristenpart, Andreas Veit for proof reading; Ben Vitale for many helpful discus-sions on building the pipeline; and all those who helped us find bugs and discussed the challenges throughout. This project is supported in part by NSF grant CNS-1558500.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Annotating social acts: Authority claims and alignment moves in Wikipedia talk pages</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Emily</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jonathan</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Bender</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Meghan</forename><surname>Morgan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mark</forename><surname>Oxley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Brian</forename><surname>Zachry</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alex</forename><surname>Hutchinson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bin</forename><surname>Marin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mari</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Ostendorf</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Workshop on Languages in Social Media</title>
		<meeting>the Workshop on Languages in Social Media</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Echoes of power: Language effects and power differences in social interaction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Cristian</forename><surname>Danescu-Niculescu-Mizil</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lillian</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bo</forename><surname>Pang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jon</forename><surname>Kleinberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of WWW</title>
		<meeting>WWW</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A computational approach to politeness with application to social factors</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Cristian</forename><surname>Danescu-Niculescu-Mizil</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Moritz</forename><surname>Sudhof</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dan</forename><surname>Jurafsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jure</forename><surname>Leskovec</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christopher</forename><surname>Potts</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of ACL</title>
		<meeting>ACL</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Using millions of emoji occurrences to learn any-domain representations for detecting sentiment, emotion and sarcasm</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bjarke</forename><surname>Felbo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alan</forename><surname>Mislove</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Anders</forename><surname>Søgaard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sune</forename><surname>Iyad Rahwan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Lehmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of EMNLP</title>
		<meeting>EMNLP</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A jury of your peers: quality, experience and ownership in Wikipedia</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Aaron</forename><surname>Halfaker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Aniket</forename><surname>Kittur</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Robert</forename><surname>Kraut</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">John</forename><surname>Riedl</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 5th International Symposium on Wikis and Open Collaboration</title>
		<meeting>the 5th International Symposium on Wikis and Open Collaboration</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">He says, she says: Conflict and coordination in Wikipedia</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Aniket</forename><surname>Kittur</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bongwon</forename><surname>Suh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ed</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Bryan A Pendleton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Chi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the SIGCHI conference on Human factors in computing systems</title>
		<meeting>the SIGCHI conference on Human factors in computing systems</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Opinion retrieval in Twitter</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Zhunchen</forename><surname>Luo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Miles</forename><surname>Osborne</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ting</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of ICWSM</title>
		<meeting>ICWSM</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Finding good conversations online: The Yahoo news annotated comments corpus</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Courtney</forename><surname>Napoles</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Joel</forename><surname>Tetreault</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Aasish</forename><surname>Pappu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Enrica</forename><surname>Rosato</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Brian</forename><surname>Provenzale</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 11th Linguistic Annotation Workshop</title>
		<meeting>the 11th Linguistic Annotation Workshop</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A corpus of wikipedia discussions: Over the years, with topic, power and gender labels</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Vinodkumar</forename><surname>Prabhakaran</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Owen</forename><surname>Rambow</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of LREC</title>
		<meeting>LREC</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Winning arguments: Interaction dynamics and persuasion strategies in good-faith online discussions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chenhao</forename><surname>Tan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Vlad</forename><surname>Niculae</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Cristian</forename><surname>Danescuniculescu-Mizil</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lillian</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of WWW</title>
		<meeting>WWW</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Improving agreement and disagreement identification in online discussions with a socially-tuned sentiment lexicon</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lu</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Claire</forename><surname>Cardie</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Workshop on Computational Approaches to Subjectivity, Sentiment and Social Media Analysis</title>
		<meeting>the Workshop on Computational Approaches to Subjectivity, Sentiment and Social Media Analysis</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A piece of my mind: A sentiment analysis approach for online dispute detection</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lu</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Claire</forename><surname>Cardie</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of ACL</title>
		<meeting>ACL</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Ex machina: Personal attacks seen at scale</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ellery</forename><surname>Wulczyn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nithum</forename><surname>Thain</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lucas</forename><surname>Dixon</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of WWW</title>
		<meeting>WWW</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Characterizing online discussion using coarse discourse sequences</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Amy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bryan</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Praveen</forename><surname>Culbertson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Paritosh</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of ICWSM</title>
		<meeting>ICWSM</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Conversations gone awry: Detecting early signs of conversational failure</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Justine</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jonathan</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Chang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Cristian</forename><surname>Danescuniculescu-Mizil</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lucas</forename><surname>Dixon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yiqing</forename><surname>Hua</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nithum</forename><surname>Thain</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dario</forename><surname>Taraborelli</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of ACL</title>
		<meeting>ACL</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
