<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T11:53+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Prediction Improves Simultaneous Neural Machine Translation</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date>October 31-November 4, 2018</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ashkan</forename><surname>Alinejad</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Simon Fraser University</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Burnaby</settlement>
									<region>BC</region>
									<country key="CA">Canada</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Maryam</forename><surname>Siahbani</surname></persName>
							<email>maryam.siahbani@ufv.ca</email>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">University of the Fraser Valley</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Abbotsford</settlement>
									<region>BC</region>
									<country key="CA">Canada</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Anoop</forename><surname>Sarkar</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Simon Fraser University</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Burnaby</settlement>
									<region>BC</region>
									<country key="CA">Canada</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Prediction Improves Simultaneous Neural Machine Translation</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2018 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</title>
						<meeting>the 2018 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing <address><addrLine>Brussels; Belgium</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="3022" to="3027"/>
							<date type="published">October 31-November 4, 2018</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<note>3022</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Simultaneous speech translation aims to maintain translation quality while minimizing the delay between reading input and incremen-tally producing the output. We propose a new general-purpose prediction action which predicts future words in the input to improve quality and minimize delay in simultaneous translation. We train this agent using reinforcement learning with a novel reward function. Our agent with prediction has better translation quality and less delay compared to an agent-based simultaneous translation system without prediction.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>One of the next significant challenges in machine translation research is to make translation ubiq- uitous using real-time translation. Simultaneous machine translation aims to address this issue by interleaving reading the input with writing the output translation. Current Simultaneous Neural Machine Translation (SNMT) systems <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Satija and Pineau, 2016;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Cho and Esipova, 2016;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Gu et al., 2017)</ref> use an AGENT to control an incremental encoder-decoder (or sequence to sequence) NMT model. Each READ adds more information to the encoder RNN, and each WRITE produces more output using the decoder RNN. In this paper, we propose adding a new action to the AGENT: a PREDICT action that predicts what words might appear in the input stream. Prediction was pre- viously proposed in simultaneous statistical ma- chine translation <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Grissom II et al., 2014</ref>) but has not been studied in the context of Neural Machine Translation (NMT). In SNMT systems, prediction of future words augments the encoder-decoder model with possible future contexts to produce output translations earlier (minimize delay) and/or produce better output translations (improve trans- lation quality). Our experiments show that predic- tion improves SNMT in both these measures.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Simultaneous Translation Framework</head><p>An agent-based framework whose actions decide whether to translate or wait for more input is a natural way to extend neural MT to simultaneous neural MT and has been explored in <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Satija and Pineau, 2016;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Gu et al., 2017</ref>) which contains two main components: The ENVIRONMENT which re- ceives the input words X = {x 1 , . . . , x N } from the source language and incrementally generates translated words W = {w 1 , . . . , w M } in the tar- get language; And the AGENT which decides an action for each time step, a t . The AGENT gen- erates an action sequence A = {a 1 , . . . , a T } to control the ENVIRONMENT.</p><p>Previous models only include two actions: READ and WRITE. We extend the model by adding the third action called PREDICT. Action READ is simply sending a new word to the EN- VIRONMENT and generating a candidate word in the target language. In action WRITE, the AGENT takes current candidate word and sends it to the output. For PREDICT, the AGENT predicts the next word in the input and treats it like a READ action. The following section explains how the ENVIRONMENT deals with different actions.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">ENVIRONMENT</head><p>The ENVIRONMENT is an attention-based Encoder-Decoder MT system ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Bahdanau et al., 2014</ref>) which is adopted to simultaneous transla- tion task. The Encoder receives the embedded representation of the input words (including predicted ones) and converts them into context vectors H ⇢ n = {h 1 , . . . , h n+⇢ } using a gated RNN (GRU) where n is the number of input words so far and ⇢ is the number of predicted words since the last READ. Whenever the AGENT decides to READ, ⇢ will be set to 0, and h n = f ENC (h n1 , x n ), where x n is the next input words (n  N ). But if the action is PREDICT, ⇢ &gt; 0, the AGENT predicts a new word x 0 ⇢ and the context vector h n+⇢ = f ENC (h n+⇢1 , x 0 ⇢ ) will be added to H ⇢ n = {h 1 , . . . , h n+⇢ }. At each time step t, the decoder uses the current context vectors (H ⇢ n ) to generate the next candi- date output (y t ):</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">c t = a ATT (z m1 , H ⇢ n ) s t = f DEC (z m1 , w m1 , c t ) p(y t |y &lt;t , H ⇢ n ) = g(w m1 , z m , c t ) y t = arg max y p(y|y &lt;t , H ⇢ n )</formula><p>where w m1 is the previous output word, and a ATT is an attention model ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Bahdanau et al., 2014</ref>), f and g are nonlinear functions, and c t is the current context vector.</p><p>If the action a t is either READ or PREDICT the current candidate y t will be ignored (wait for bet- ter predictions). But in the case of WRITE, the candidate y t is produced as the next output word w m and then the decoder state will be updated (w m y t , z m s t ). Note that as soon as the AGENT decides to READ, all the hidden vectors generated by PRE- DICT actions will be discarded (H ⇢ n = H 0 n = {h 1 , . . . , h n }). <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref> shows an example of how a sentence can be translated using our modified translation framework 1 .</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">AGENT</head><p>The AGENT is a separate component which exam- ines the ENVIRONMENT at each time step and de- cides on the actions that lead to better translation quality and lower delay. The agent in the greedy decoding framework ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Gu et al., 2017</ref>) was trained using reinforcement learning with the policy gra- dient algorithm <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(Williams, 1992)</ref>, which observes the current state of the ENVIRONMENT at time step t as o t where o t = [c t ; s t ; w m ]. A RNN with one hidden layer passed through a softmax func- tion generates the probability distribution over the actions a t at each step. Therefore, policy ⇡ ✓ will be computed as:</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">u t = f ✓ (u t1 , o t ) ⇡ ✓ (a t |a &lt; t, o  t) / g ✓ (u t )</formula><p>Where u t is the hidden state of the AGENT's RNN.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Training the AGENT with Prediction</head><p>In order to speed-up the training process, we have restricted AGENT's options by removing redun- dant operations. As illustrated in <ref type="figure">Figure 2</ref>, af- 1 The pseudo-code is available in supplementary material (Algorithm 1). ter a series of WRITE, the AGENT cannot choose to PREDICT, and after a sequence of PREDICTs, READ is not an option.</p><p>Reward Function:</p><p>The total reward at any time step is calculated as the cumulative sum of rewards for actions at each preceding step. All the evalu- ation metrics have been modified to be computed for every time step. Quality: We use a modified smoothed version of BLEU score <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Chen and Cherry, 2014</ref>) multiplied by Brevity Penalty ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Lin and Och, 2004</ref>) for evalu- ating the impact of each action on translation qual- ity. At each point in time, the reward for transla- tion quality is:</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">r Q t = ( BLEU(t) t &lt; T BLEU(W, W ⇤ ) t = T The BLEU(t)</formula><p>is the difference between BLEU score of the translated sentence at the previous time step and the current time step; BLEU(t) = BLEU(W t , W ⇤ )BLEU(W t1 , W ⇤ ); where W t is the prefix of the translated sentence at time t. Delay: The Delay reward is used to motivate the AGENT to minimize delay. We use Average Pro- portion (AP) <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Cho and Esipova, 2016)</ref> for this pur- pose, which is the average number of source words needed when translating each word. Given the source words X and translated words W , AP can be computed as:</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">d(X, W ) = 1 |X||W | X t s(t) r D t = ( 0 t &lt; T d(X, W ) t = T</formula><note type="other">Where s(t) denotes the number of source words the WRITE action uses at time step t (for any other actions, s(t) would be zero). The delay reward is smoothed using a Target Delay which is a scalar constant denoted by d ⇤ (Gu et al., 2017): r D t = bd t d ⇤ c Prediction Rewards for Quality and Delay alone do not motivate</note><p>the AGENT to choose prediction and in preliminary experiments, after a number of steps, the number of prediction actions became zero. We address this problem by defining Predic- tion Quality (PQ) which rewards the AGENT for changes in BLEU score after each prediction ac- tion. By initializing r p 0 = 0, the prediction reward can be written as:</p><formula xml:id="formula_4">r p t = 8 &gt; &lt; &gt; : BLEU(t) a t = W, a t1 = P r p t1 a t = W, a t1 6 = P 0 otherwise Final Reward</formula><p>The final reward function is cal- culated as the combination of quality, delay, and prediction rewards:</p><formula xml:id="formula_5">r t = ↵ r Q t + r D t + r p t</formula><p>(1) The trade-off between better translation quality and minimal delay is achieved by modifying the parameters ↵, , and . Reinforcement Learning is used to train the AGENT using a policy gradient algo- rithm ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Gu et al., 2017;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Williams, 1992)</ref> which searches for the maximum in J(✓) = E ⇡ ✓ h P T t=1 r t i using the gradient:</p><formula xml:id="formula_6">r ✓ J(✓) = E ⇡ ✓ [r ✓ log ⇡ ✓ (a|s)Q ⇡ ✓ (s, a)]</formula><p>where Q = P T t=1 r t . The gradient for a sentence is the cumulative sum of gradients at each time step. We pre-train the ENVIRONMENT on full sentences using log-loss log p(y|x).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Experiments</head><p>We train and evaluate our model on English- German (EN-DE) in both directions. We use WMT 2015 for training and Newstest 2013 for validation and testing. All sentences have been to- kenized and the words are segmented using byte pair encoding (BPE) ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Sennrich et al., 2016</ref>  Model Configuration For a fair comparison, we follow the settings that worked the best for the greedy decoding model in ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Gu et al., 2017</ref>) and set the target delay d ⇤ for the AGENT to 0.7. The EN- VIRONMENT consists of two unidirectional layers with 1028 GRU units for encoder and decoder. We train the network using AdaDelta optimizer, a batch of size 32 and a fixed learning rate of 0.0001 without decay. We use softmax policy via recur- rent networks with 512 GRU units and a softmax function for the AGENT and train it using Adam optimizer ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Kingma and Ba, 2014</ref>). The batch size for the AGENT is 10, and the learning rate is 2e- 6. The word predictor is a two layer RNN Lan- guage model which consists of two layers of 1024 units, followed by a softmax layer. The batch size is 64 with a learning rate of 2e-5. The predic- tor has been trained on the WMT'16 dataset and tested on Newstest'16 corpora for both languages. The perplexity of our language model is reported in <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>. We set ↵ = 1, = 0.5 and = 0.5.</p><p>We tried different settings for these hyperparame- ters during training and picked values that gave us the best Quality and Delay on the training data. Results and Analysis <ref type="figure">Figure 4</ref> shows that as the sentence length increases, prediction helps transla- tion quality due to complex reordering and multi- clausal sentences; However, for shorter samples where the structure of the sentences are simpler, the prediction action cannot improve translation quality. does not account for less delay as longer sentences are produced. A better measure than AP might be needed to emphasize delay differences. There- fore we also report the average segment length (µ), which is computed as the average number of consecutive READs in each sentence. In both EN!DE and DE!EN experiments, our model constantly decreases the segment length by around 1 word which results in less latency.</p><p>In order to evaluate the effectiveness of our proposed reward function for PREDICT action, we have explored various values for its hyper- parameters <ref type="bibr">(↵, , and )</ref>. Our empirical re- sults show that the best trade-off between quality and delay is achieved when around 20 percent of the actions are PREDICT for both EN!DE and DE!EN translation tasks <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">(Figure 3</ref>). When there is no reward for PREDICT action ( = 0), the AGENT prefers other actions, and the number of PREDICT actions turns into zero immediately af- ter training the AGENT. If the reward for predic- tion is valued too highly, the ENVIRONMENT de- pends more on predicted words and the translation quality decreases 2 .</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Related work</head><p>Early work in SNMT was done in speech, where the incoming signals were segmented based on acoustic or statistical cues ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Bangalore et al., 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Fügen et al., 2007</ref>   <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Yarmohammadi et al., 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Siahbani et al., 2014</ref>) use a separate segmentation step and incrementally translate each segment using a standard phrase-based MT system. ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Matsubara et al., 2000</ref>) applied pattern matching to predict target-side verbs in Japanese to English transla- tion. <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Grissom II et al., 2014</ref>) used reinforcement learning to predict the next word and the sentence- final verb in a statistical MT model. These mod- els reduce the delay but are not trained end-to- end like our agent-based SNMT system. ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Cho and Esipova, 2016)</ref> proposed a non-trainable heuristic agent which is not able to trade-off quality with delay. It always prefers to read more words from the input and this approach does not work well in practice. (Satija and Pineau, 2016) introduced a trainable agent which they trained using Deep Q networks ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Mnih et al., 2015)</ref>. We modified the SNMT trainable agent in ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Gu et al., 2017)</ref> and added a new non-trivial PREDICT action to the agent. We compare to their model and show better results in delay and quality.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Conclusion</head><p>We introduce a new prediction action in a train- able agent for simultaneous neural machine trans- lation. With prediction, the agent can be informed about future time steps in the input stream. Com- pared to a very strong baseline our results show that prediction can lower delay and improve the translation quality, especially for longer sentences and translating from an SOV (subject-object-verb) language (DE) to an SVO language (EN). decoding strategies for simultaneous translation. In Proceedings of the Sixth International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing, pages 1032-1036.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: A schematic of our model. The ENVIRONMENT starts with reading the 'Start of Sentence' symbol as x1 and generating y1 from the decoder. Based on the output of the network at each time step, the AGENT decides whether to READ, WRITE or PREDICT for the following time steps.</figDesc><graphic url="image-1.png" coords="2,306.45,96.83,197.44,161.53" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Figure 3: Action distribution for English to German translation in the first 25000 iterations. The numbers in each bar are the average action percentage over the previous 5000 iterations.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" validated="false"><head>Table 2 compares</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>our model with the 
Greedy Decoding (GD) model in terms of trans-
lation quality and latency. It shows that the pre-
diction mechanism outperforms the GD model in 
terms of BLEU and average proportion (AP). 
The delay evaluation measure (AP) counts 
about the same number of READs and WRITEs. It </table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3" validated="false"><head>Table 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Comparison of translation quality (BLEU), Av-

erage Proportion (AP), and average segment length (µ) for 
Greedy Decoding (GD) model with Prediction Mechanism 
(PM) model. 

et al.</table></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="2"> See Figure 6 in supplementary materials for more numerical results.</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>We would like to thank the anonymous reviewers for their helpful remarks. The research was also partially supported by the Natural Sciences and Engineering Research Council of Canada grants NSERC RGPIN-2018-06437 and RGPAS-2018-522574 and a Department of National Defence (DND) and NSERC grant DGDND-2018-00025 to the third author.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Neural machine translation by jointly learning to align and translate</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dzmitry</forename><surname>Bahdanau</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kyunghyun</forename><surname>Cho</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yoshua</forename><surname>Bengio</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>abs/1409.0473</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<publisher>CoRR</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Real-time incremental speech-tospeech translation of dialogs</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Srinivas</forename><surname>Bangalore</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Vivek</forename><surname>Kumar Rangarajan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Prakash</forename><surname>Sridhar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ladan</forename><surname>Kolan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Aura</forename><surname>Golipour</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Jimenez</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2012 Conference of the North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics: Human Language Technologies, NAACL HLT &apos;12</title>
		<meeting>the 2012 Conference of the North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics: Human Language Technologies, NAACL HLT &apos;12<address><addrLine>Stroudsburg, PA, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="437" to="445" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A systematic comparison of smoothing techniques for sentencelevel bleu</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Boxing</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Colin</forename><surname>Cherry</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">WMT</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="362" to="367" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Can neural machine translation do simultaneous translation? CoRR</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kyunghyun</forename><surname>Cho</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Masha</forename><surname>Esipova</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>abs/1606.02012</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Simultaneous translation of lectures and speeches</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christian</forename><surname>Fügen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alex</forename><surname>Waibel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Muntsin</forename><surname>Kolss</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Machine Translation</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">21</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="209" to="252" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Don&apos;t until the final verb wait: Reinforcement learning for simultaneous machine translation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alvin</forename><surname>Grissom</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><forename type="middle">I</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">He</forename><surname>He</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jordan</forename><surname>Boyd-Graber</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">John</forename><surname>Morgan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hal</forename><surname>Daumé</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Iii</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Learning to translate in real-time with neural machine translation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jiatao</forename><surname>Gu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Graham</forename><surname>Neubig</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kyunghyun</forename><surname>Cho</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Victor</forename><forename type="middle">O K</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">15th Conference of the European Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics (EACL)</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Valencia, Spain</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Adam: A method for stochastic optimization</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Diederik</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jimmy</forename><surname>Kingma</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Ba</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>abs/1412.6980</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<publisher>CoRR</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Automatic evaluation of machine translation quality using longest common subsequence and skip-bigram statistics</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chin-Yew</forename><surname>Lin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Franz Josef</forename><surname>Och</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 42Nd Annual Meeting on Association for Computational Linguistics, ACL &apos;04</title>
		<meeting>the 42Nd Annual Meeting on Association for Computational Linguistics, ACL &apos;04<address><addrLine>Stroudsburg, PA, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Simultaneous japanese-english interpretation based on early prediction of english verb</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Shigeki</forename><surname>Matsubara</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Keiichi</forename><surname>Iwashima</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nobuo</forename><surname>Kawaguchi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Katsuhiko</forename><surname>Toyama</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yasuyoshi</forename><surname>Inagaki</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 4th Symposium on Natural Languauge Processing(SNLP-2000)</title>
		<meeting>the 4th Symposium on Natural Languauge Processing(SNLP-2000)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="268" to="273" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Improving speech translation with automatic boundary prediction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Evgeny</forename><surname>Matusov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dustin</forename><surname>Hillard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mathew</forename><surname>Magimaidoss</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dilek</forename><surname>Hakkani-Tür</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mari</forename><surname>Ostendorf</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hermann</forename><surname>Ney</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Eighth Annual Conference of the International Speech Communication Association</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Human-level control through deep reinforcement learning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Volodymyr</forename><surname>Mnih</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Koray</forename><surname>Kavukcuoglu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Silver</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Andrei</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Rusu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Joel</forename><surname>Veness</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marc</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Bellemare</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alex</forename><surname>Graves</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Martin</forename><surname>Riedmiller</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Andreas</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Fidjeland</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Georg</forename><surname>Ostrovski</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Stig</forename><surname>Petersen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Charles Beattie</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">518</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">529</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
			<publisher>Shane Legg, and Demis Hassabis</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Nature</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Simultaneous machine translation using deep reinforcement learning. Abstraction in Reinforcement Learning Workshop</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Harsh</forename><surname>Satija</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Joelle</forename><surname>Pineau</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Neural Machine Translation of Rare Words with Subword Units</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rico</forename><surname>Sennrich</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Barry</forename><surname>Haddow</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alexandra</forename><surname>Birch</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 54th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the 54th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics<address><addrLine>Berlin, Germany</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Long Papers</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1715" to="1725" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Association for Computational Linguistics</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Incremental translation using hierarchichal phrase-based translation system</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Maryam</forename><surname>Siahbani</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ramtin</forename><forename type="middle">Mehdizadeh</forename><surname>Seraj</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Baskaran</forename><surname>Sankaran</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Anoop</forename><surname>Sarkar</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Spoken Language Technology Workshop (SLT)</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>IEEE</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="71" to="76" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Segmentation strategies for streaming speech translation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Vivek</forename><surname>Kumar Rangarajan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">John</forename><surname>Sridhar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Srinivas</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Bangalore</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2013 Conference of the North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics: Human Language Technologies</title>
		<meeting>the 2013 Conference of the North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics: Human Language Technologies</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="230" to="238" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Andrej Ljolje, and Rathinavelu Chengalvarayan</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Simple statistical gradientfollowing algorithms for connectionist reinforcement learning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ronald</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Williams</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Machine Learning</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1992" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="229" to="256" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Incremental segmentation and</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mahsa</forename><surname>Yarmohammadi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Vivek</forename><surname>Kumar Rangarajan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Srinivas</forename><surname>Sridhar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Baskaran</forename><surname>Bangalore</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Sankaran</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
