<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T10:37+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">WELT: Using Graphics Generation in Linguistic Fieldwork</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date>June 23-24, 2014</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Morgan</forename><surname>Ulinski</surname></persName>
							<email>mulinski@cs.columbia.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">CCLS Columbia University New York</orgName>
								<address>
									<region>NY</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Anusha</forename><surname>Balakrishnan</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">CCLS Columbia University New York</orgName>
								<address>
									<region>NY</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Daniel</forename><surname>Bauer</surname></persName>
							<email>bauer@cs.columbia.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">CCLS Columbia University New York</orgName>
								<address>
									<region>NY</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bob</forename><surname>Coyne</surname></persName>
							<email>coyne@cs.columbia.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">CCLS Columbia University New York</orgName>
								<address>
									<region>NY</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Julia</forename><surname>Hirschberg</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">CCLS Columbia University New York</orgName>
								<address>
									<region>NY</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Owen</forename><surname>Rambow</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">CCLS Columbia University New York</orgName>
								<address>
									<region>NY</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><roleName>rambow@ccls.columbia</roleName><surname>Edu</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">CCLS Columbia University New York</orgName>
								<address>
									<region>NY</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">WELT: Using Graphics Generation in Linguistic Fieldwork</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of 52nd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics: System Demonstrations</title>
						<meeting>52nd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics: System Demonstrations <address><addrLine>Baltimore, Maryland USA</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="49" to="54"/>
							<date type="published">June 23-24, 2014</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>We describe the WordsEye Linguistics tool (WELT), a novel tool for the documentation and preservation of endangered languages. WELT is based on Words-Eye (Coyne and Sproat, 2001), a text-to-scene tool that automatically generates 3D scenes from written input. WELT has two modes of operation. In the first mode, En-glish input automatically generates a picture which can be used to elicit a description in the target language. In the second mode, the linguist formally documents the grammar of an endangered language , thereby creating a system that takes input in the endangered language and generates a picture according to the grammar; the picture can then be used to verify the grammar with native speakers. We will demonstrate WELT&apos;s use on scenarios involving Arrernte and Nahuatl.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Although languages have appeared and disap- peared throughout history, today languages are facing extinction at an unprecedented pace. Over 40% of the estimated 7,000 languages in the world are at risk of disappearing. When languages die out, we lose access to an invaluable resource for studying the culture, history, and experience of peoples around the world (Alliance for Linguistic <ref type="bibr">Diversity, 2013)</ref>. Efforts to document languages and develop tools in support of collecting data on them become even more important with the in- creasing rate of extinction. <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Bird (2009)</ref> empha- sizes a particular need to make use of computa- tional linguistics during fieldwork.</p><p>To address this issue, we are developing the WordsEye Linguistics Tool, or WELT. In the first mode of operation, we provide a field linguist with tools for running custom elicitation sessions based on a collection of 3D scenes. In the second, input in an endangered language generates a picture rep- resenting the input's meaning according to a for- mal grammar.</p><p>WELT provides important advantages for elic- itation over the pre-fabricated sets of static pic- tures commonly used by field linguists today. The field worker is not limited to a fixed set of pictures but can, instead, create and modify scenes in real time, based on the informants' answers. This al- lows them to create additional follow-up scenes and questions on the fly. In addition, since the pictures are 3D scenes, the viewpoint can easily be changed, allowing exploration of linguistic de- scriptions based on different frames of reference. This will be particularly useful in eliciting spatial descriptions. Finally, since scenes and objects can easily be added in the field, the linguist can cus- tomize the images used for elicitation to be maxi- mally relevant to the current informants.</p><p>WELT also provides a means to document the semantics of a language in a formal way. Lin- guists can customize their studies to be as deep or shallow as they wish; however, we believe that a major advantage of documenting a language with WELT is that it enables such studies to be much more precise. The fully functioning text-to-scene system created as a result of this documentation will let linguists easily test the theories they de- velop with native speakers, making changes to grammars and semantics in real time. The result- ing text-to-scene system can be an important tool for language preservation, spreading interest in the language among younger generations of the com- munity and recruiting new speakers.</p><p>We will demonstrate the features of WELT for use in fieldwork, including designing elic- itation sessions, building scenes, recording au- dio, and adding descriptions and glosses to a scene. We will use examples from sessions we have conducted with a native speaker of Nahu- atl, an endangered language spoken in Mexico. We will demonstrate how to document seman- tics with WELT, using examples from Arrernte, an Australian aboriginal language spoken in Alice Springs. We will also demonstrate a basic Arrernte text-to-scene system created in WELT.</p><p>In the following sections, we will mention re- lated work (Section 2), discuss the WordsEye sys- tem that WELT is based on (Section 3), describe WELT in more detail, highlighting the functional- ity that will appear in our demonstration (Section 4), and briefly mention our future plans for WELT (Section 5).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Related Work</head><p>One of the most widely-used computer toolkits for field linguistics is SIL Fieldworks. FieldWorks is a collection of software tools; the most relevant for our research is FLEx, Fieldworks Language Explorer. FLEx includes tools for eliciting and recording lexical information, dictionary develop- ment, interlinearization of texts, analysis of dis- course features, and morphological analysis. An important part of FLEx is its "linguist-friendly" morphological parser <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Black and Simons, 2006</ref>), which uses an underlying model of morphology familiar to linguists, is fully integrated into lexicon development and interlinear text analysis, and pro- duces a human-readable grammar sketch as well as a machine-interpretable parser.</p><p>Several computational tools aim to simplify the formal documentation of syntax by eliminating the need to master particular grammar formalisms. First is the PAWS starter kit <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Black and Black, 2012)</ref>, a system that prompts linguists with a series of guided questions about the target language and uses their answers to produce a PC-PATR gram- mar <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(McConnel, 1995)</ref>. The LinGO Grammar <ref type="bibr">Matrix (Bender et al., 2002</ref>) is a similar tool de- veloped for HPSG that uses a type hierarchy to represent cross-linguistic generalizations.</p><p>The most commonly used resource for for- mally documenting semantics across languages is FrameNet ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Filmore et al., 2003)</ref>. FrameNets have been developed for many languages, includ- ing Spanish, Japanese, and Portuguese. Most start with English FrameNet and adapt it for the new language; a large portion of the frames end up being substantially the same across languages <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Baker, 2008)</ref>. <ref type="bibr">ParSem (Butt et al., 2002</ref>) is a collaboration to develop parallel semantic repre- sentations across languages, by developing seman- tic structures based on LFG. Neither of these re- sources, however, are targeted at helping non- computational linguists formally document a lan- guage, as compared to the morphological parser in FLEx or the syntactic documentation in PAWS.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">WordsEye Text-to-Scene System</head><p>WordsEye ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Coyne and Sproat, 2001</ref>) is a system for automatically converting natural language text into 3D scenes representing the meaning of that text. WordsEye supports language-based control of spatial relations, textures and colors, collec- tions, facial expressions, and poses; it handles simple anaphora and coreference resolution, al- lowing for a variety of ways of referring to ob- jects. The system assembles scenes from a library of 2,500 3D objects and 10,000 images tied to an English lexicon of about 15,000 nouns.</p><p>The system includes a user interface where the user can type simple sentences that are processed to produce a 3D scene. The user can then modify the text to refine the scene. In addition, individual objects and their parts can be selected and high- lighted with a bounding box to focus attention.</p><p>Several thousand real-world people have used WordsEye online (http://www.wordseye.com). It has also been used as a tool in education, to en- hance literacy <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(Coyne et al., 2011b)</ref>. In this paper, we describe how we are using WordsEye to create a comprehensive tool for field linguistics.</p><p>Vignette Semantics and VigNet To interpret in- put text, WordsEye uses a lexical resource called VigNet ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Coyne et al., 2011a</ref>). VigNet is inspired by and based on FrameNet ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Baker et al., 1998</ref>), a resource for lexical semantics. In FrameNet, lexical items are grouped together in frames ac- cording to their shared semantic structure. Every frame contains a number of frame elements (se- mantic roles) which are participants in this struc- ture. The English FrameNet defines the mapping between syntax and semantics for a lexical item by providing lists of valence patterns that map syntac- tic functions to frame elements.</p><p>VigNet extends FrameNet in two ways in or- der to capture "graphical semantics',' the knowl- edge needed to generate graphical scenes from language. First, graphical semantics are added to the frames by adding primitive graphical (typ- ically, spatial) relations between the frame ele-ment fillers. Second, VigNet distinguishes be- tween meanings of words that are distinguished graphically. For example, the specific objects and spatial relations in the graphical semantics for cook depend on the object being cooked and on the culture in which it is being cooked (cooking turkey in Baltimore vs. cooking an egg in Alice Springs), even though at an abstract level cook an egg in Alice Springs and cook a turkey in Bal- timore are perfectly compositional semantically. Frames augmented with graphical semantics are called vignettes.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">WordsEye Linguistics Tool (WELT)</head><p>In this section, we describe the two modes of WELT, focusing on the aspects of our system that will appear in our demonstration.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">Tools for Linguistic Fieldwork</head><p>WELT includes tools that allow linguists to elicit language with WordsEye. Each elicitation session is organized around a set of WordsEye scenes. We will demonstrate how a linguist would use WELT in fieldwork, including (1) creating an elicitation session, either starting from scratch, or by import- ing scenes from a previous session; (2) building scenes in WordsEye, saving them to a WELT ses- sion, and modifying scenes previously added to the session, either overwriting the original scene or saving the changes as a new scene; (3) adding tex- tual descriptions, glosses, and notes to a scene; and (4) recording audio, which is automatically synced to open scenes, and playingit back tto review any given scene. A screen shot of the scene annotation window is included in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref>.</p><p>To test the fieldwork capabilities of WELT, we created a set of scenes based on the Max Planck topological relations picture series <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(Bowerman and Pederson, 1992)</ref>. We used these scenes to elicit descriptions from a native Nahuatl speaker; some examples of scenes and descriptions are in- cluded in <ref type="figure">Figure 2</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">Formal Documentation of a Language</head><p>WELT also provides the means to formally doc- ument the semantics of a language and create a text-to-scene system for that language. The formal documentation allows precise description of the lexical semantics of a language. We will demon- strate both the user interface for documenting se- mantics, as well as a text-to-scene system for Ar- When a sentence is processed by WordsEye, it goes through three main stages: (1) morphological analysis and syntactic parsing, (2) semantic anal- ysis, and (3) graphical realization. We will walk through these modules in the context of WELT, discussing (a) the formal documentation required for that component, (b) the processing of an ex- ample sentence through that component, and (c) the parts of that component that will feature in our demonstration. We will use the Arrernte sentence shown in (1) as a running example.</p><p>(1) artwe le goal arrerneme man ERG goal put.nonpast The man kicks a goal.</p><p>Morphology and Syntax WELT first parses a sentence into its morphology and syntax. Since the focus of WELT is documentation of semantics, the exact mechanisms for parsing the morphology and syntax may vary. To document Arrernte, we are using XFST ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Karttunen et al., 1997</ref>) to model the morphology and XLE ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Crouch et al., 2006</ref>) to model the syntax in the LFG formalism <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">(Kaplan and Bresnan, 1982)</ref>. These are mature systems that we believe are sufficient for the formal doc- umentation of morphology and syntax. In future, we will provide interfaces to the third-party tools so that common information, like the lexicon, can We have added one additional feature to the morphology and syntax module of WELT's text- to-scene system: an interface for selecting an f- structure from multiple options produced by XLE, in case the grammar is ambiguous. This way, a linguist can use the WELT text-to-scene system to verify their semantic documentation even if the syntactic documentation is fairly rough. We will demonstrate this feature when demonstrating the Arrernte text-to-scene system.</p><p>Semantics The WELT semantics is represented using VigNet, which has been developed for WordsEye based on English. We will assume that large parts of VigNet are language-independent (for instance, the set of low-level graphical rela- tions used to express the graphical semantics is based on physics and human anatomy and does not depend on language). Therefore, it should not be necessary to create a completely new VigNet for every language that will be used in WELT. In fu- ture, we will develop tools for modifying VigNet to handle linguistic and cultural differences as they occur.</p><p>In order to use VigNet with other languages, we need to map between the formal syntax of the language being studied and the (English) lexical semantics required currently by VigNet. One in- stance showing why this is necessary occurs in our example Arrrente sentence. When discussing foot- ball in English, one would say that someone kicks a goal or makes a goal. In Arrente, one would say goal arrerneme, which translates literally to "put a goal." Although the semantics of both sentences are the same, the entry for "put" in the English VigNet does not include this meaning, but the Ar- rernte text-to-scene system needs to account for it.</p><p>To address such instances, we have created an interface for a linguist to specify a set of rules that map from syntax to semantics. The rules take syn- tactic f-structures as input and output a high-level semantic representation compatible with VigNet. The left-hand side of a rule consists of a set of con- ditions on the f-structure elements and the right- hand side consists of the semantic structure that should be returned. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 4(a)</ref> is an example of a rule mapping Arrernte syntax to semantics, cre- ated in WELT.</p><p>In addition to these rules, the linguist creates a simple table mapping lexical items into VigNet se- mantic concepts, so that nouns can be converted to graphical objects. We have created a mapping for the lexical items in the Arrernte grammar; a partial mapping is shown in <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table 1</ref>.</p><p>We now describe the semantic processing of our example Arrernte sentence, assuming a set of rules consisting solely of the one in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 4</ref>(a) and the noun mapping in <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table 1</ref>  To deter- mine the Agent, we need to find the VigNet con- cept corresponding to var-1, which occupies the subject position in the f-structure. The subject in our f-structure is artwe, and according to <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table 1</ref>, it maps to the VigNet concept PERSON.N. The re- sulting semantic representation is augmented with its graphical semantics, taken from the vignette for CAUSE MOTION.KICK (vignette definition not shown for lack of space). The final representation is shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Figure 5</ref>, with lexical semantics at the top and graphical semantics below. The Words- Eye system then builds the scene from these con- straints and renders it in 3D. WELT provides an interface for creating rules by defining the tree structures for the left-hand- side and right-hand-side of the rule. Every node on the left-hand-side can optionally contain boolean logic, if for example we want to allow the sub- ject to be [(artwe 'man' OR arhele 'woman') AND NOT ampe 'child']; so rules can be as simple or complex as desired. Rules need not specify lexical items directly; it is also possible to refer to more general semantic categories. For example, a rule could select for all verbs of motion, or specify a particular constraint on the subject or object. In <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">figure 4</ref>(a), for instance, we may want to only al- low animate subjects.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>CAUSE_MOTION.KICK</head><p>Semantic categories are chosen through a browser that allows the user to search through all the semantic categories defined in VigNet. For ex- ample, if we want to find the semantic category to use as a constraint on our example subject, we might start by searching for human. This takes us to a portion of a tree of semantic concepts cen- tered around HUMAN.N. The semantic categories are displayed one level at a time, so we initially see only the concepts directly above and directly below the word we searched for. From there, it's easy to select the concepts we are interested in, and go up or down the tree until we find the one we want. Below HUMAN.N are HUMAN-FEMALE.N and HUMAN-MALE.N, but we are more interested in the more general categories above the node. A screen shot showing the result of this search is shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 4(b)</ref>. Above HUMAN.N is HU- MANOID.N; above that, ANIMATE-BEING.N. Do- ing a quick check of further parents and chil- dren, we can see that for the subject of 'put goal,' we would probably want to choose ANIMATE- BEING.N over LIVING-THING.N.</p><p>The table mapping lexical items to VigNet con- cepts is built in a similar way; the lexicon is au- tomatically extracted from the LFG grammar, and the user can search and browse semantic concepts to find the appropriate node for each lexical item.</p><p>We will demonstrate the WELT user inter-face which supports the creation of syntax-to- semantics rules, creates the mapping between nouns in the lexicon and VigNet concepts, and ver- ifies the rules using the WELT text-to-scene sys- tem. We will show examples from our documenta- tion of Arrernte and demonstrate entering text into the Arrernte text-to-scene system to generate pic- tures.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Summary and Future Work</head><p>We have described a novel tool for linguists work- ing with endangered languages. It provides a new way to elicit data from informants, an interface for formally documenting the lexical semantics of a language, and allows the creation of a text-to- scene system for any language.</p><p>This project is in its early stages, so we are plan- ning many additional features and improvements. For both modes of WELT, we want to generate pic- tures appropriate for the target culture. To han- dle this, we will add the ability to include cus- tom objects and modify VigNet with new vignettes or new graphical semantics for existing vignettes. We also plan to build tools to import and export the work done in WELT in order to facilitate col- laboration among linguists working on similar lan- guages or cultures. Sharing sets of scenes will al- low linguists to reuse work and avoid duplicated effort. Importing different versions of VigNet will make it easier to start out with WELT on a new language if it is similar to one that has already been studied. We might expect, for instance, that other Australian aboriginal languages will require the same kinds of cultural modifications to VigNet that we make for Arrernte, or that two languages in the same family might also have similar syntax to semantics rules.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: WELT interface for annotating a scene rernte created with WELT. When a sentence is processed by WordsEye, it goes through three main stages: (1) morphological analysis and syntactic parsing, (2) semantic analysis, and (3) graphical realization. We will walk through these modules in the context of WELT, discussing (a) the formal documentation required for that component, (b) the processing of an example sentence through that component, and (c) the parts of that component that will feature in our demonstration. We will use the Arrernte sentence shown in (1) as a running example.</figDesc><graphic url="image-1.png" coords="3,315.13,62.80,202.56,281.76" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 2 :Figure 3 :</head><label>23</label><figDesc>Figure 2: Nahuatl examples elicited with WELT be shared. Running each word of the sentence through the morphological analyzer in XFST transforms the verb arrerneme into 'arrerne+NONPAST.' The other tokens in the sentence remain unchanged. Parsing the sentence with XLE gives the cstructure shown in Figure 3(a) and the f-structure shown in Figure 3(b). The f-structure will be passed on to the semantics module.</figDesc><graphic url="image-3.png" coords="4,66.98,196.92,226.78,93.04" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 4 :</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Figure 4: Syntax-semantics rule (a) and semantic category browser (b) from WELT Lexical Item artwe panikane angepe akngwelye apwerte tipwele VigNet Concept PERSON.N CUP.N CROW.N DOG.N ROCK-ITEM.N TABLE.N</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>Figure 5 :</head><label>5</label><figDesc>Figure Ground Goal Ground</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" validated="false"><head>Table 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>A mapping from nouns (lexical items) to VigNet semantic concepts 

ure 3(b) has main predicate arrerne with two ar-
guments; the object is goal. Therefore, it matches 
the left-hand-side of our rule. The output of 
the rule specifies predicate CAUSE MOTION.KICK 
with three arguments. The latter two are straight-
forward; the Theme is the VigNet object FOOTY-
BALL.N, and the Goal is FOOTYGOAL.N. </table></figure>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>This material is based upon work supported by the National Science Foundation under Grant No. 1160700.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Alliance for Linguistic Diversity</title>
		<ptr target="http://www.endangeredlanguages.com/" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">The Endangered Languages Project</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Berkeley FrameNet project</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Baker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Fillmore</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Lowe</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">36th Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics and 17th International Conference on Computational Linguistics (COLING-ACL&apos;98)</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Montréal</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="86" to="90" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">FrameNet, present and future</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Baker</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">The First International Conference on Global Interoperability for Language Resources</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="12" to="17" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Grammar Matrix</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Bender</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Flickinger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Oepen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Workshop on Grammar Engineering and Evaluation at the 19th International Conference on Computational Linguistics</title>
		<editor>J. Carroll, N. Oostdijk, and R. Sutcliffe</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Taipei, Taiwan</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="8" to="14" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Natural language processing and linguistic fieldwork</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Bird</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Computational Linguistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">35</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="469" to="474" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Grammars for the people, by the people, made easier using PAWS and XLingPaper</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Black</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Black</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Electronic Grammaticography</title>
		<editor>Sebastian Nordoff</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Honolulu</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>University of Hawaii Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="103" to="128" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The SIL FieldWorks Language Explorer approach to morphological parsing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Black</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Simons</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Computational Linguistics for Lessstudied Languages: Texas Linguistics Society</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Austin, TX</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006-11" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Topological relations picture series</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Bowerman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Pederson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">stitute for Psycholinguistics</title>
		<editor>S. Levinson</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Nijmegen. Max Planck In</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1992" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">51</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Space stimuli kit 1.2, page</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The parallel grammar project</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Butt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Dyvik</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>King</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Masuichi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Rohrer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>COLING-GEE &apos;02</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Workshop on Grammar Engineering and Evaluation</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="7" />
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Association for Computational Linguistics</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">WordsEye: An automatic text-to-scene conversion system</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Coyne</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Sproat</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<editor>SIGGRAPH</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Vignet: Grounding language in graphics using frame semantics</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Coyne</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Bauer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Rambow</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ACL Workshop on Relational Models of Semantics (RELMS)</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Portland, OR</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Evaluating a text-to-scene generation system as an aid to literacy</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Coyne</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Schudel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Bitz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Hirschberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">SlaTE (Speech and Language Technology in Education) Workshop at Interspeech</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Venice</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Crouch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Dalrymple</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Kaplan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>King</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Maxwell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Newman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://www2.parc.com/isl/groups/nltt/xle/doc/xle" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
<note type="report_type">XLE Documentation</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Background to FrameNet</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Filmore</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Johnson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Petruck</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">In International Journal of Lexicography</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="235" to="250" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Lexicalfunctional grammar: A formal system for grammatical representation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Kaplan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Bresnan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<editor>J.W. Bresnan</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1982-12" />
			<publisher>MIT Press</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Cambridge, Mass</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>The Mental Representation of Grammatical Relations</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Xerox finite-state tool</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Karttunen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Gaál</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Kempe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
			<pubPlace>Xerox Research Centre Europe, Grenoble</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
<note type="report_type">Technical report</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">PC-PATR Reference Manual. Summer Institute for Linguistics</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Mcconnel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
