<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T12:39+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Chinese Morphological Analysis with Character-level POS Tagging</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
				<availability status="unknown"><p>Copyright Association for Computational Linguistics</p>
				</availability>
				<date>June 23-25 2014. 2014</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mo</forename><surname>Shen</surname></persName>
							<email>shen@nlp.ist.i.kyoto-u.ac.jp</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hongxiao</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">School of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Fudan University</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Daisuke</forename><surname>Kawahara</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sadao</forename><surname>Kurohashi</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Graduate School of Informatics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Kyoto University</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="JP">Japan</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Chinese Morphological Analysis with Character-level POS Tagging</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 52nd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
						<meeting>the 52nd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics <address><addrLine>Baltimore, Maryland, USA</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="253" to="258"/>
							<date type="published">June 23-25 2014. 2014</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>The focus of recent studies on Chinese word segmentation, part-of-speech (POS) tagging and parsing has been shifting from words to characters. However, existing methods have not yet fully utilized the potentials of Chinese characters. In this paper, we investigate the usefulness of character-level part-of-speech in the task of Chinese morphological analysis. We propose the first tagset designed for the task of character-level POS tagging. We propose a method that performs character-level POS tagging jointly with word segmentation and word-level POS tagging. Through experiments , we demonstrate that by introducing character-level POS information, the performance of a baseline morphological analyzer can be significantly improved.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>In recent years, the focus of research on Chinese word segmentation, part-of-speech (POS) tag- ging and parsing has been shifting from words toward characters. Character-based methods have shown superior performance in these tasks compared to traditional word-based methods ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Ng and Low, 2004;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Nakagawa, 2004;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Zhao et al., 2006;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Kruengkrai et al., 2009;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Xue, 2003;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Sun, 2010)</ref>. Studies investigating the morphological- level and character-level internal structures of words, which treat character as the true atom of morphological and syntactic processing, have demonstrated encouraging results <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Li, 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Li and Zhou, 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Zhang et al., 2013)</ref>. This line of research has provided great insight in revealing the roles of characters in word formation and syntax of Chinese language.</p><p>However, existing methods have not yet fully utilized the potentials of Chinese characters. While <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Li (2011)</ref>  can productively form new words by attaching to existing words, these characters consist only a portion of all Chinese characters and appear in 35% of the words in Chinese Treebank 5.0 (CTB5) ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Xue et al., 2005</ref>). Zhang (2013) took one step further by investigating the character- level structures of words; however, the machine learning of inferring these internal structures re- lies on the character forms, which still suffers from data sparseness. In our view, since each Chinese character is in fact created as a word in origin with complete and independent meaning, it should be treated as the actual minimal morphological unit in Chinese language, and therefore should carry specific part-of-speech. For example, the character "打" (beat) is a verb and the character "破" (broken) is an adjective. A word on the other hand, is either single-character, or a compound formed by sin- gle-character words. For example, the verb "打 破" (break) can be seen as a compound formed by the two single-character words with the con- struction "verb + adjective".</p><p>Under this treatment, we observe that words with the same construction in terms of character- level POS tend to also have similar syntactic roles. For example, the words having the con-struction "verb + adjective" are typically verbs, and those having the construction "adjective + noun" are typically nouns, as shown in the fol- lowing examples:</p><p>(a) verb : verb + adjective "打破"(break) : "打"(beat) + "破"(broken) "更新"(update) : "更"(replace) + "新"(new) "漂白"(bleach) : "漂"(wash) + "白"(white)</p><p>(b) noun : adjective + noun "主题"(theme) : "主"(main) + "题"(topic) "新人"(newcomer) : "新"(new) + "人"(person) "快车"(express) : "快"(fast) + "车"(car)</p><p>This suggests that character-level POS can be used as cues in predicting the part-of-speech of unknown words. Another advantage of character-level POS is that, the sequence of character-level POS in a word can be seen as a more fine-grained version of word-level POS. An example is shown in Ta- ble 1. The five words in this table are very likely to be tagged with the same word-level POS as verb in any available annotated corpora, while it can be commonly agreed among native speakers of Chinese that the syntactic behaviors of these words are different from each other, due to their distinctions in word constructions. For example, verbs having the construction "verb + noun" (e.g. 投资) or "verb + verb" (e.g. 审查) can also be nouns in some context, while others cannot; And verbs having the constructions "verb + adjective" (e.g. 认清) require exact one object argument, while others generally do not. Therefore, com- pared to word-level POS, the character-level POS can produce information for more expres- sive features during the learning process of a morphological analyzer.</p><p>In this paper, we investigate the usefulness of character-level POS in the task of Chinese mor- phological analysis. We propose the first tagset designed for the task of character-level POS tag- ging, based on which we manually annotate the entire CTB5. We propose a method that performs character-level POS tagging jointly with word segmentation and word-level POS tagging. Through experiments, we demonstrate that by introducing character-level POS information, the performance of a baseline morphological analyz- er can be significantly improved.</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">Tag Part-of-Speech Example n noun 法案/NN (bill) v verb 发布/VV (publish) j adj./adv. 广阔/VA (vast) t numerical 三点一四/CD (3.14) m quantifier 一/CD 件/M (a piece of) d date 九五年/NT (1995) k proper noun 中美/NR (sino-US) b prefix 副市长/NN (vice mayor) e suffix 建筑业/NN (construction inductry) r transliteration 阿尔帕德/NR (Árpá d) u punctuation 查尔斯· 狄更斯/NR (Charles Dickens) f foreign chars X 射线/NN (X-ray) o onomatopoeia 隆隆/AD (rumble) s surname 王新民/NR (Wang Xinmin) p pronoun 他们/PN (they) c</formula><p>other functional 用于/VV (be used for) <ref type="table">Table 2</ref>. Tagset for character-level part-of- speech tagging. The underlined characters in the examples correspond to the tags on the left-most column. The CTB-style word-level POS are also shown for the examples.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Character-level POS Tagset</head><p>We propose a tagset for the task of character- level POS tagging. This tagset contains 16 tags, as illustrated in <ref type="table">Table 2</ref>. The tagset is designed by treating each Chinese character as a single- character word, and each (multi-character) word as a phrase of single-character words. Some of these tags are directly derived from the common- ly accepted word-level part-of-speech, such as noun, verb, adjective and adverb. It should be noted that, for single-character words, the differ- ence between adjective and adverb can almost be ignored, because for any of such words that can be used as an adjective, it usually can also be used as an adverb. Therefore, we have merged these two tags into one. On the other hand, some other tags are de- signed specifically for characters, such as trans- literation, surname, prefix and suffix. Unlike some Asian languages such as Japanese, there is no explicit character set in Chinese that are used exclusively for expressing names of foreign per- sons, places or organizations. However, some characters are used much more frequently than others in these situations. For example, in the person's name "阿尔帕德" (Árpá d), all the four characters can be frequently observed in words   <ref type="table">Table 3</ref>. Word representation with a 6-tag tagset: S, B, B 2 , B 3 , M, E of transliterations. Similarly, surnames in Chi- nese are also drawn from a set of limited number of characters. We therefore assign specific tags for this kind of character sets. The tags for pre- fixes and suffixes are motivated by the previous studies <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Li, 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Li and Zhou, 2012</ref>). We have annotated character-level POS for all words in CTB5 1 . Fortunately, character-level POS in most words are independent of context, which means it is sufficient to annotate word forms unless there is an ambiguity. The annota- tion was conducted by two persons, where each one of them was responsible for about 70% of the documents in the corpus. The redundancy was set for the purposes of style unification and quality control, on which we find that the inter- annotator agreement is 96.2%. Although the an- notation also includes the test set, we blind this portion in all the experiments. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Chinese Morphological Analysis with</head><p>Character-level POS</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">System Description</head><p>Previous studies have shown that jointly pro- cessing word segmentation and POS tagging is preferable to pipeline processing, which can propagate errors ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Nakagawa and Uchimoto, 2007;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Kruengkrai et al., 2009)</ref>. Based on these studies, we propose a word-character hybrid model which can also utilize the character-level POS information. This hybrid model constructs a lat- tice that consists of word-level and character- level nodes from a given input sentence. Word- level nodes correspond to words found in the system's lexicon, which has been compiled from training data. Character-level nodes have special tags called position-of-character (POC) that indi- cate the word-internal position <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Asahara, 2003;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Nakagawa, 2004</ref>). We have adopted the 6-tag tagset, which ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Zhao et al., 2006</ref>) reported to be optimal. This tagset is illustrated in <ref type="table">Table 3</ref>. <ref type="figure">Figure 2</ref> shows an example of a lattice for the Chinese sentence: "陈德铭答记者问" (Chen Deming answers to journalists' questions). The correct path is marked with blue bold lines. The Condition <ref type="table">Table 4</ref>. Feature templates. The "Condition" column describes when to apply the templates: and denote the previous and the current word-level node; and denote the previous and the current character-level node;</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">Baseline-unigram 〈 〉 〈 〉 〈 〉 〈 〉 〈 〉 〈 〉 〈 〉 〈 〉 〈 〉 〈 〉 〈 〉 〈 〉 〈 〉 〈 〉 〈 〉 〈 〉 〈 〉 Baseline-bigram 〈 〉 〈 〉 〈 〉 〈 〉 〈 〉 〈 〉 〈 〉 〈 〉 〈 〉 〈 〉 〈 〉 〈 〉 〈 〉 〈 〉 〈 〉 〈 〉 〈 〉 〈 〉 〈 〉 〈 〉 〈 〉 〈 〉 〈 〉 〈 〉 〈 〉 〈 〉 Otherwise Proposed-unigram 〈 〉 Proposed-bigram 〈 〉 〈 〉 〈 〉 〈 〉 〈 〉 〈 〉 〈 〉 〈 〉 〈 〉 〈 〉 〈 〉 〈 〉 〈 〉 〈 〉 〈 〉</formula><p>and denote the previous and the current node of any types. Word-level nodes represent known words that can be found in the system's lexicon.</p><p>upper part of the lattice (word-level nodes) rep- resents known words, where each node carries information such as character form, character- level POS , and word-level POS. A word that contains multiple characters is represented by a sub-lattice (the dashed rectangle in the <ref type="figure">figure)</ref>, where a path stands for a possible sequence of character-level POS for this word. For example, the word "记者" (journalist) has two possible paths of character-level POS: "verb + suffix" and "noun + suffix". Nodes that are inside a sub- lattice cannot be linked to nodes that are outside, except from the boundaries. The lower part of the lattice (character-level nodes) represents un- known words, where each node carries a posi- tion-of-character tag, in addition to other types of information that can also be found on a word- level node. A sequence of character-level nodes are considered as an unknown word if and only if the sequence of POC tags forms one of the cases listed in <ref type="table">Table 3</ref>. This table also illustrates the permitted transitions between adjacent character- level nodes. We use the standard dynamic pro- gramming technique to search for the best path in the lattice. We use the averaged perceptron <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Collins, 2002</ref>), an efficient online learning algorithm, to train the model.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Features</head><p>We show the feature templates of our model in <ref type="table">Table 4</ref>. The features consist of two categories: baseline features, which are modified from the templates proposed in ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Kruengkrai et al., 2009</ref>); and proposed features, which encode character- level POS information.</p><p>Baseline features: For word-level nodes that represent known words, we use the symbols , and to denote the word form, POS tag and length of the word, respectively. The functions and return the first and last character of . If has only one character, we omit the templates that contain or . We use the subscript indices 0 and -1 to indicate the current node and the previous node during a Viterbi search, respectively. For charac- ter-level nodes, denotes the surface character, and denotes the combination of POS and POC (position-of-character) tags.</p><p>Proposed features: For word-level nodes, the function returns the pair of the char- acter-level POS tags of the first and last charac- ters of , and returns the sequence of character-level POS tags of . If either the pair or the sequence of character-level POS is ambig- uous, which means there are multiple paths in the sub-lattice of the word-level node, then the val- ues on the current best path (with local context) during the Viterbi search will be returned. If has only one character, we omit the templates that contain . For character-level nodes, the function returns its character-level POS. The subscript indices 0 and -1 as well as other symbols stand for the same meaning as they are in the baseline features.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Evaluation</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">Settings</head><p>To evaluate our proposed method, we have con- ducted two sets of experiments on CTB5: word segmentation, and joint word segmentation and word-level POS tagging. We have adopted the same data division as in ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Jiang et al., 2008a;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Jiang et al., 2008b;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Kruengkrai et al., 2009;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Zhang and Clark, 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Sun, 2011)</ref>: the training set, dev set and test set have 18,089, 350 and 348 sentences, respectively. The models applied on all test sets are those that result in the best per- formance on the CTB5 dev set.</p><p>We have annotated character-level POS in- formation for all 508,768 word tokens in CTB5. As mentioned in section 2, we blind the annota- tion in the test set in all the experiments. To learn the characteristics of unknown words, we built the system's lexicon using only the words in the training data that appear at least 3 times. We ap- plied a similar strategy in building the lexicon for character-level POS, where the threshold we choose is 2. These thresholds were tuned using the development data.</p><p>We have used precision, recall and the F-score to measure the performance of the systems. Pre- cision ( ) is defined as the percentage of output tokens that are consistent with the gold standard test data, and recall ( ) is the percentage of to- kens in the gold standard test data that are recog- nized in the output. The balanced F-score ( ) is defined as .</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">Experimental Results</head><p>We compare the performance between a baseline model and our proposed approach. The results of the word segmentation experiment and the joint experiment of segmentation and POS tagging are shown in <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">Table 5</ref>(a) and <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">Table 5</ref>(b), respectively. Each row in these tables shows the performance of the corresponding system. "CharPos" stands for our proposed model which has been de- scribed in section 3. "Baseline" stands for the same model except it only enables features from the baseline templates.</p><p>The results show that, while the differences between the baseline model and the proposed model in word segmentation accuracies are small, the proposed model achieves significant im- provement in the experiment of joint segmentati-    <ref type="table">Table 6</ref>. Comparison with previous studies on CTB5.</p><p>on and POS tagging 2 . This suggests that our pro- posed method is particularly effective in predict- ing the word-level POS, which is consistent with our observations mentioned in section 1.</p><p>In <ref type="table">Table 6</ref> we compare our approach with morphological analyzers in previous studies. The accuracies of the systems in previous work are directly taken from the original paper. As the results show, despite the fact that the perfor- mance of our baseline model is relatively weak in the joint segmentation and POS tagging task, our proposed model achieves the second-best performance in both segmentation and joint tasks.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Conclusion</head><p>We believe that by treating characters as the true atoms of Chinese morphological and syntactic analysis, it is possible to address the out-of- vocabulary problem that word-based methods have been long suffered from. In our error analy- sis, we believe that by exploring the character- level POS and the internal word structure ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Zhang et al., 2013)</ref> at the same time, it is possible to further improve the performance of morphologi- cal analysis and parsing. We will address these issues in our future work.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1. A Word-character hybrid lattice of a Chinese sentence. Correct path is represented by blue bold lines.</figDesc><graphic url="image-1.png" coords="3,73.89,73.32,457.18,233.06" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>1</head><label></label><figDesc>http://nlp.ist.i.kyoto-u.ac.jp/EN/index.php?CharPosCN</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>(</head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" validated="false"><head>pointed out that some characters</head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Character-level 
Part-of-Speech 
Examples of Verb 

verb + noun 
投资 (invest : throw + wealth) 
noun + verb 
心疼 (feel sorry : heart + hurt) 

verb + adjective 
认清 (realize : recognize + 
clear) 
adjective + verb 痛恨 (hate : pain + hate) 

verb + verb 
审查 (inspect : examine + re-
view) 

Table 1. Character-level POS sequence as a 
more specified version of word-level POS: an 
example of verb. 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3" validated="false"><head>Table 5 .</head><label>5</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Experimental results on CTB5. 

System 
Segmentation 
Joint 
Baseline 
97.96 
93.48 
CharPOS 
98.03 
93.80 
Jiang2008a 
97.85 
93.41 
Jiang2008b 
97.74 
93.37 
Kruengkrai2009 
97.87 
93.67 
Zhang2010 
97.78 
93.67 
Sun2011 
98.17 
94.02 

</table></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="2"> in McNemar&apos;s test.</note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Corpus-based Japanese Morphological Analysis. Nara Institute of Science and Technology, Doctor&apos;s Thesis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Masayuki</forename><surname>Asahara</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Discriminative Training Methods for Hidden Markov Models: Theory and Experiments with Perceptron Algorithms</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Collins</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of EMNLP</title>
		<meeting>EMNLP</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="8" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A Cascaded Linear Model for Joint Chinese Word Segmentation and Part-of-speech Tagging</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wenbin</forename><surname>Jiang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Liang</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Qun</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yajuan</forename><surname>Lü</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of ACL</title>
		<meeting>ACL</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Word Lattice Reranking for Chinese Word Segmentation and Part-of-speech Tagging</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wenbin</forename><surname>Jiang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Haitao</forename><surname>Mi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Qun</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of COLING</title>
		<meeting>COLING</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">An Error-Driven WordCharacter Hybird Model for Joint Chinese Word Segmentation and POS Tagging</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Canasai</forename><surname>Kruengkrai</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kiyotaka</forename><surname>Uchimoto</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yiouwang</forename><surname>Jun&amp;apos;ichi Kazama</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kentaro</forename><surname>Torisawa</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hitoshi</forename><surname>Isahara</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of ACL-IJCNLP</title>
		<meeting>ACL-IJCNLP</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="513" to="521" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Parsing the Internal Structure of Words: A New Paradigm for Chinese Word Segmentation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Zhongguo</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of ACL-HLT</title>
		<meeting>ACL-HLT</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1405" to="1414" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Unified Dependency Parsing of Chinese Morphological and Syntactic Structures</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Zhongguo</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Guodong</forename><surname>Zhou</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of EMNLP</title>
		<meeting>EMNLP</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1445" to="1454" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Chinese Partof-speech Tagging: One-at-a-time or All-at-once? Word-based or Character-based?</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tou</forename><surname>Hwee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jin</forename><forename type="middle">Kiat</forename><surname>Ng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Low</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of EMNLP</title>
		<meeting>EMNLP</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="277" to="284" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Chinese and japanese word segmentation using word-level and character-level information</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tetsuji</forename><surname>Nakagawa</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of COLING</title>
		<meeting>COLING</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="466" to="472" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Hybrid Approach to Word Segmentation and Pos Tagging</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tetsuji</forename><surname>Nakagawa</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kiyotaka</forename><surname>Uchimoto</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of ACL Demo and Poster Sessions</title>
		<meeting>ACL Demo and Poster Sessions</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="217" to="220" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Word-based and Character-based Word Segmentation Models: Comparison and Combination</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Weiwei</forename><surname>Sun</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of COLING Poster Sessions</title>
		<meeting>COLING Poster Sessions</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1211" to="1219" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A Stacked Sub-word Model for Joint Chinese Word Segmentation and Part-ofspeech Tagging</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Weiwei</forename><surname>Sun</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of ACL-HLT</title>
		<meeting>ACL-HLT</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1385" to="1394" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Chinese Word Segmentation as Character Tagging</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nianwen</forename><surname>Xue</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">International Journal of Computational Linguistics and Chinese Language Processing</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Penn Chinese Treebank: Phrase Structure Annotation of a Large Corpus</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nianwen</forename><surname>Xue</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Fei</forename><surname>Xia</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Fu-Dong</forename><surname>Chiou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Martha</forename><surname>Palmer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Natural Language Engineering</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="207" to="238" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Effective Tag Set Selection in Chinese Word Segmentation via Conditional Random Field Modeling</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hai</forename><surname>Zhao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chang-Ning</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mu</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bao-Liang</forename><surname>Lu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of PACLIC</title>
		<meeting>PACLIC</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="87" to="94" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Chinese Parsing Exploiting Characters</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Meishan</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yue</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wanxiang</forename><surname>Che</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ting</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of ACL</title>
		<meeting>ACL</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="125" to="134" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A Fast Decoder for Joint Word Segmentation and POS-tagging Using a Single Discriminative Model</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yue</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Stephen</forename><surname>Clark</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of EMNLP</title>
		<meeting>EMNLP</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="843" to="852" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
