<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T12:56+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">A Linear-Time Bottom-Up Discourse Parser with Constraints and Post-Editing</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
				<availability status="unknown"><p>Copyright Association for Computational Linguistics</p>
				</availability>
				<date>June 23-25 2014. 2014</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Vanessa</forename><forename type="middle">Wei</forename><surname>Feng</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Department of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Department of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Toronto Toronto</orgName>
								<address>
									<region>ON</region>
									<country key="CA">Canada</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Graeme</forename><surname>Hirst</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">University of Toronto Toronto</orgName>
								<address>
									<region>ON</region>
									<country key="CA">Canada</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">A Linear-Time Bottom-Up Discourse Parser with Constraints and Post-Editing</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 52nd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
						<meeting>the 52nd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics <address><addrLine>Baltimore, Maryland, USA</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="511" to="521"/>
							<date type="published">June 23-25 2014. 2014</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Text-level discourse parsing remains a challenge. The current state-of-the-art overall accuracy in relation assignment is 55.73%, achieved by Joty et al. (2013). However, their model has a high order of time complexity, and thus cannot be applied in practice. In this work, we develop a much faster model whose time complexity is linear in the number of sentences. Our model adopts a greedy bottom-up approach , with two linear-chain CRFs applied in cascade as local classifiers. To enhance the accuracy of the pipeline, we add additional constraints in the Viterbi decoding of the first CRF. In addition to efficiency , our parser also significantly out-performs the state of the art. Moreover, our novel approach of post-editing, which modifies a fully-built tree by considering information from constituents on upper levels, can further improve the accuracy.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Discourse parsing is the task of identifying the presence and the type of the discourse relations between discourse units. While research in dis- course parsing can be partitioned into several di- rections according to different theories and frame- works, Rhetorical Structure Theory (RST) ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Mann and Thompson, 1988</ref>) is probably the most am- bitious one, because it aims to identify not only the discourse relations in a small local context, but also the hierarchical tree structure for the full text: from the relations relating the smallest discourse units (called elementary discourse units, EDUs), to the ones connecting paragraphs.</p><p>For example, <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref> shows a text fragment consisting of two sentences with four EDUs in total (e 1 -e 4 ). Its discourse tree representation is shown below the text, following the notation con- vention of RST: the two EDUs e 1 and e 2 are re- lated by a mononuclear relation CONSEQUENCE, where e 2 is the more salient span (called nucleus, and e 1 is called satellite); e 3 and e 4 are related by another mononuclear relation CIRCUMSTANCE, with e 4 as the nucleus; the two spans e 1:2 and e 3:4 are further related by a multi-nuclear relation SE- QUENCE, with both spans as the nucleus.</p><p>Conventionally, there are two major sub-tasks related to text-level discourse parsing: (1) EDU segmentation: to segment the raw text into EDUs, and (2) tree-building: to build a discourse tree from EDUs, representing the discourse relations in the text. Since the first sub-task is considered rela- tively easy, with the state-of-art accuracy at above 90% ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Joty et al., 2012)</ref>, the recent research focus is on the second sub-task, and often uses manual EDU segmentation.</p><p>The current state-of-the-art overall accuracy of the tree-building sub-task, evaluated on the RST Discourse Treebank (RST-DT, to be introduced in Section 8), is 55.73% by <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Joty et al. (2013)</ref>. How- ever, as an optimal discourse parser, Joty et al.'s model is highly inefficient in practice, with re- spect to both their DCRF-based local classifiers, and their CKY-like bottom-up parsing algorithm. DCRF (Dynamic Conditional Random Fields) is a generalization of linear-chain CRFs, in which each time slice contains a set of state variables and edges <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">(Sutton et al., 2007)</ref>. CKY parsing is a bottom-up parsing algorithm which searches all possible parsing paths by dynamic programming. Therefore, despite its superior performance, their model is infeasible in most realistic situations.</p><p>The main objective of this work is to develop a more efficient discourse parser, with similar or even better performance with respect to Joty et al.'s optimal parser, but able to produce parsing re- sults in real time.</p><p>Our contribution is three-fold. First, with a Figure 1: An example text fragment composed of two sentences and four EDUs, with its RST dis- course tree representation shown below.</p><p>greedy bottom-up strategy, we develop a discourse parser with a time complexity linear in the total number of sentences in the document. As a re- sult of successfully avoiding the expensive non- greedy parsing algorithms, our discourse parser is very efficient in practice. Second, by using two linear-chain CRFs to label a sequence of discourse constituents, we can incorporate contextual infor- mation in a more natural way, compared to us- ing traditional discriminative classifiers, such as SVMs. Specifically, in the Viterbi decoding of the first CRF, we include additional constraints elicited from common sense, to make more ef- fective local decisions. Third, after a discourse (sub)tree is fully built from bottom up, we perform a novel post-editing process by considering infor- mation from the constituents on upper levels. We show that this post-editing can further improve the overall parsing performance.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Related work 2.1 HILDA discourse parser</head><p>The HILDA discourse parser by <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Hernault et al. (2010)</ref> is the first attempt at RST-style text-level discourse parsing. It adopts a pipeline framework, and greedily builds the discourse tree from the bot- tom up. In particular, starting from EDUs, at each step of the tree-building, a binary SVM classifier is first applied to determine which pair of adjacent discourse constituents should be merged to form a larger span, and another multi-class SVM classi- fier is then applied to assign the type of discourse relation that holds between the chosen pair. The strength of HILDA's greedy tree-building strategy is its efficiency in practice. Also, the em- ployment of SVM classifiers allows the incorpora- tion of rich features for better data representation <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Feng and Hirst, 2012)</ref>. However, HILDA's ap- proach also has obvious weakness: the greedy al- gorithm may lead to poor performance due to local optima, and more importantly, the SVM classifiers are not well-suited for solving structural problems due to the difficulty of taking context into account.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">Joty et al.'s joint model</head><p>Joty et al. <ref type="formula">(2013)</ref> approach the problem of text- level discourse parsing using a model trained by Conditional Random Fields (CRF). Their model has two distinct features. First, they decomposed the problem of text- level discourse parsing into two stages: intra- sentential parsing to produce a discourse tree for each sentence, followed by multi-sentential pars- ing to combine the sentence-level discourse trees and produce the text-level discourse tree. Specif- ically, they employed two separate models for intra-and multi-sentential parsing. Their choice of two-stage parsing is well motivated for two rea- sons: (1) it has been shown that sentence bound- aries correlate very well with discourse bound- aries, and (2) the scalability issue of their CRF- based models can be overcome by this decompo- sition.</p><p>Second, they jointly modeled the structure and the relation for a given pair of discourse units. For example, <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 2</ref> shows their intra-sentential model, in which they use the bottom layer to rep- resent discourse units; the middle layer of binary nodes to predict the connection of adjacent dis- course units; and the top layer of multi-class nodes to predict the type of the relation between two units. Their model assigns a probability to each possible constituent, and a CKY-like parsing al- gorithm finds the globally optimal discourse tree, given the computed probabilities.</p><p>The strength of Joty et al.'s model is their joint modeling of the structure and the relation, such that information from each aspect can interact with the other. However, their model has a major defect in its inefficiency, or even infeasibility, for appli- cation in practice. The inefficiency lies in both their DCRF-based joint model, on which infer- ence is usually slow, and their CKY-like parsing algorithm, whose issue is more prominent. Due to the O(n 3 ) time complexity, where n is the number</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">R 2 S 2 U 2 U 1 R 3 S 3 U 3 R j S j U j R t-1 S t-1 U t-1</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Relation sequence</head><p>Structure sequence Unit sequence at level i of input discourse units, for large documents, the parsing simply takes too long 1 .</p><p>3 Overall work flow <ref type="figure">Figure 3</ref> demonstrates the overall work flow of our discourse parser. The general idea is that, similar to <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Joty et al. (2013)</ref>, we perform a sentence-level parsing for each sentence first, followed by a text- level parsing to generate a full discourse tree for the whole document. However, in addition to effi- ciency (to be shown in Section 6), our discourse parser has a distinct feature, which is the post- editing component (to be introduced in Section 5), as outlined in dashes.</p><p>Our discourse parser works as follows. A doc- ument D is first segmented into a list of sen- tences. Each sentence S i , after being segmented into EDUs (not shown in the <ref type="figure">figure)</ref>, goes through an intra-sentential bottom-up tree-building model M intra , to form a sentence-level discourse tree T S i , with the EDUs as leaf nodes. After that, we ap- ply the intra-sentential post-editing model P intra to modify the generated tree T S i to T p S i , by considering upper-level information.</p><p>We then combine all sentence-level discourse tree T p S i 's using our multi-sentential bottom-up tree-building model M multi to generate the text- level discourse tree T D . Similar to sentence-level parsing, we also post-edit T D using P multi to pro- duce the final discourse tree T p D . <ref type="bibr">1</ref> The largest document in the RST-DT contains over 180 sentences, i.e., n &gt; 180 for their multi-sentential CKY pars- ing. Intuitively, suppose the average time to compute the probability of each constituent is 0.01 second, then in total, the CKY-like parsing takes over 16 hours. It is possible to op- timize Joty et al.'s CKY-like parsing by replacing their CRF- based computation for upper-level constituents with some lo- cal computation based on the probabilities of lower-level con- stituents. However, such optimization is beyond the scope of this paper.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Bottom-up tree-building</head><p>For both intra-and multi-sentential parsing, our bottom-up tree-building process adopts a similar greedy pipeline framework like the HILDA dis- course parser (discussed in Section 2.1), to guar- antee efficiency for large documents. In partic- ular, starting from the constituents on the bot- tom level (EDUs for intra-sentential parsing and sentence-level discourse trees for multi-sentential parsing), at each step of the tree-building, we greedily merge a pair of adjacent discourse con- stituents such that the merged constituent has the highest probability as predicted by our structure model. The relation model is then applied to as- sign the relation to the new constituent.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">Linear-chain CRFs as Local models</head><p>Now we describe the local models we use to make decisions for a given pair of adjacent discourse constituents in the bottom-up tree-building. There are two dimensions for our local models: (1) scope of the model: intra-or multi-sentential, and (2) purpose of the model: for determining structures or relations. So we have four local models, M struct intra , M rel intra , M struct multi , and M rel multi . While our bottom-up tree-building shares the greedy framework with HILDA, unlike HILDA, our local models are implemented using CRFs. In this way, we are able to take into account the sequential information from contextual discourse constituents, which cannot be naturally repre- sented in HILDA with SVMs as local classifiers. Therefore, our model incorporates the strengths of both HILDA and Joty et al.'s model, i.e., the efficiency of a greedy parsing algorithm, and the ability to incorporate sequential information with CRFs.</p><p>As shown by <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Feng and Hirst (2012)</ref>, for a pair of discourse constituents of interest, the sequential information from contextual constituents is cru- cial for determining structures. Therefore, it is well motivated to use Conditional Random Fields (CRFs) ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Lafferty et al., 2001</ref>), which is a discrimi- native probabilistic graphical model, to make pre- dictions for a sequence of constituents surround- ing the pair of interest.</p><p>In this sense, our local models appear similar to Joty et al.'s non-greedy parsing models. How- ever, the major distinction between our models and theirs is that we do not jointly model the struc- ture and the relation; rather, we use two linear- <ref type="figure">Figure 3</ref>: The work flow of our proposed discourse parser. In the figure, M intra and M multi stand for the intra-and multi-sentential bottom-up tree-building models, and P intra and P multi stand for the intra-and multi-sentential post-editing models. chain CRFs to model the structure and the relation separately. Although joint modeling has shown to be effective in various NLP and computer vision applications ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">Sutton et al., 2007;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b21">Yang et al., 2009;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Wojek and Schiele, 2008)</ref>, our choice of using two separate models is for the following reasons:</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">D S 1 S i S n ... ... M intra M intra M intra M intra P intra ... ... ... P intra P intra P multi M multi ... ... 1 S T i S T n S T p S n T p S i T p S T 1 D T p D T</formula><p>First, it is not entirely appropriate to model the structure and the relation at the same time. For example, with respect to <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 2</ref>, it is unclear how the relation node R j is represented for a train- ing instance whose structure node S j = 0, i.e., the units U j−1 and U j are disjoint. Assume a special relation NO-REL is assigned for R j . Then, in the tree-building process, we will have to deal with the situations where the joint model yields conflicting predictions: it is possible that the model predicts S j = 1 and R j = NO-REL, or vice versa, and we will have to decide which node to trust (and thus in some sense, the structure and the relation is no longer jointly modeled).</p><p>Secondly, as a joint model, it is mandatory to use a dynamic CRF, for which exact inference is usually intractable or slow. In contrast, for linear- chain CRFs, efficient algorithms and implementa- tions for exact inference exist.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">Structure models</head><p>4.2.1 Intra-sentential structure model <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 4a</ref> shows our intra-sentential structure model M struct intra in the form of a linear-chain CRF. Similar to Joty et al.'s intra-sentential model, the first layer of the chain is composed of discourse constituents U j 's, and the second layer is com- posed of binary nodes S j 's to indicate the proba- bility of merging adjacent discourse constituents.</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">S 2 U 2 U 1 S 3 U 3 S j U j S t U t</formula><p>Structure sequence All units in sentence at level i (a) Intra-sentential structure model M struct intra .</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">S j-1 U j-1 U j-2 S j U j Structure sequence Adjacent units at level i U j+1 S j+1 S j-1 U j-3 S j+2 U j+2 C 1 C 2 C 3</formula><p>(b) Multi-sentential structure model M struct multi . C 1 , C 2 , and C 3 denote the three chains for predicting U j and U j+1 . At each step in the bottom-up tree-building pro- cess, we generate a single sequence E, consisting of U 1 ,U 2 , . . . ,U j , . . . ,U t , which are all the current discourse constituents in the sentence that need to be processed. For instance, initially, we have the sequence E 1 = {e 1 , e 2 , . . . , e m }, which are the EDUs of the sentence; after merging e 1 and e 2 on the second level, we have E 2 = {e 1:2 , e 3 , . . . , e m }; after merging e 4 and e 5 on the third level, we have E 3 = {e 1:2 , e 3 , e 4:5 , . . . , e m }, and so on. Because the structure model is the first com- ponent in our pipeline of local models, its accu- racy is crucial. Therefore, to improve its accuracy, we enforce additional commonsense constraints in its Viterbi decoding. In particular, we disallow 1- 1 transitions between adjacent labels (a discourse unit can be merged with at most one adjacent unit), and we disallow all-zero sequences (at least one pair must be merged).</p><p>Since the computation of E i does not depend on a particular pair of constituents, we can use the same sequence E i to compute structural probabili- ties for all adjacent constituents. In contrast, Joty et al.'s computation of intra-sentential sequences depends on the</p><note type="other">particular pair of constituents: the sequence is composed of the pair in question, with other EDUs in the sentence, even if those EDUs have already been merged. Thus, different CRF chains have to be formed for different pairs of con- stituents. In addition to efficiency, our use of a single CRF chain for all constituents can better capture the sequential dependencies among con- text, by taking into account the information from partially built discourse constituents, rather than bottom-level EDUs only.</note></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2.2">Multi-sentential structure model</head><p>For multi-sentential parsing, where the smallest discourse units are single sentences, as argued by <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Joty et al. (2013)</ref>, it is not feasible to use a long chain to represent all constituents, due to the fact that it takes O(T M 2 ) time to perform the forward- backward exact inference on a chain with T units and an output vocabulary size of M, thus the over- all complexity for all possible sequences in their model is O(M 2 n 3 ) 2 .</p><p>Instead, we choose to take a sliding-window approach to form CRF chains for a particular pair of constituents, as shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 4b</ref>. For exam- ple, suppose we wish to compute the structural probability for the pair U j−1 and U j , we form three chains, each of which contains two contextual constituents:</p><formula xml:id="formula_4">C 1 = {U j−3 ,U j−2 ,U j−1 ,U j }, C 2 = {U j−2 ,U j−1 ,U j ,U j+1 },</formula><p>and C 3 = {U j−1 ,U j ,U j+1 ,U j+2 }. We then find the chain C t , 1 ≤ t ≤ 3, with the highest joint probability over the entire sequence, and assign its marginal probability P(S t j = 1) to P(S j = 1). Similar to M struct intra , for M struct multi , we also include additional constraints in the Viterbi decoding, by disallowing transitions between two ones, and dis- allowing the sequence to be all zeros if it contains all the remaining constituents in the document.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3">Relation models</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3.1">Intra-sentential relation model</head><p>The intra-sentential relation model M rel intra , shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Figure 5a</ref>, works in a similar way to M struct intra , as described in Section 4.2.1. The linear-chain CRF contains a first layer of all discourse constituents U j 's in the sentence on level i, and a second layer of relation nodes R j 's to represent the relation be- tween a pair of discourse constituents. However, unlike the structure model, adjacent relation nodes do not share discourse constituents on the first layer. Rather, each relation node R j attempts to model the relation of one single con- stituent U j , by taking U j 's left and right subtrees U j,L and U j,R as its first-layer nodes; if U j is a sin- gle EDU, then the first-layer node of R j is simply U j , and R j is a special relation symbol LEAF 3 . Since we know, a priori, that the constituents in the chains are either leaf nodes or the ones that have been merged by our structure model, we never need to worry about the NO-REL issue as out- lined in Section 4.1.</p><p>In the bottom-up tree-building process, after merging a pair of adjacent constituents using M struct intra into a new constituent, say U j , we form a chain consisting of all current constituents in the sentence to decide the relation label for U j , i.e., the R j node in the chain. In fact, by perform- ing inference on this chain, we produce predic- tions not only for R j , but also for all other R nodes in the chain, which correspond to all other con- stituents in the sentence. Since those non-leaf con- stituents are already labeled in previous steps in the tree-building, we can now re-assign their rela- tions if the model predicts differently in this step. Therefore, this re-labeling procedure can compen- sate for the loss of accuracy caused by our greedy bottom-up strategy to some extent.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3.2">Multi-sentential relation model</head><p>Figure 5b shows our multi-sentential relation model. Like M rel intra , the first layer consists of adja- cent discourse units, and the relation nodes on the second layer model the relation of each constituent separately.</p><p>Similar to M struct multi introduced in Section 4.2.2, M rel multi also takes a sliding-window approach to predict labels for constituents in a local context. For a constituent U j to be predicted, we form three chains, and use the chain with the highest joint probability to assign or re-assign relations to con- stituents in that chain.   </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Post-editing</head><p>After an intra-or multi-sentential discourse tree is fully built, we perform a post-editing to con- sider possible modifications to the current tree, by considering useful information from the discourse constituents on upper levels, which is unavailable in the bottom-up tree-building process.</p><p>The motivation for post-editing is that, some particular discourse relations, such as TEXTUAL- ORGANIZATION, tend to occur on the top levels of the discourse tree; thus, information such as the depth of the discourse constituent can be quite in- dicative. However, the exact depth of a discourse constituent is usually unknown in the bottom-up tree-building process; therefore, it might be ben- eficial to modify the tree by including top-down information after the tree is fully built.</p><p>The process of post-editing is shown in Algo- rithm 1. For each input discourse tree T , which is already fully built by bottom-up tree-building models, we do the following: Lines 3 -9: Identify the lowest level of T on which the constituents can be modified according to the post-editing structure component, P struct . To do so, we maintain a list L to store the discourse constituents that need to be examined. Initially, L consists of all the bottom-level constituents in T . At each step of the loop, we consider merging the pair of adjacent units in L with the highest proba- bility predicted by P struct . If the predicted pair is not merged in the original tree T , then a possible modification is located; otherwise, we merge the pair, and proceed to the next iteration. Lines 10 -12: If modifications have been pro- posed in the previous step, we build a new tree Algorithm 1 Post-editing algorithm. Input: A fully built discourse tree T .</p><p>1: if |T | = 1 then 2:</p><p>return T Do nothing if it is a single EDU.</p><formula xml:id="formula_5">3: L ← [U 1 ,U 2 , . . . ,U t ]</formula><p>The bottom-level constituents in T . 4: while |L| &gt; 2 do <ref type="bibr">5:</ref> i ← PREDICTMERGING(L, P struct )</p><formula xml:id="formula_6">6: p ← PARENT(L[i], L[i + 1], T ) 7:</formula><p>if p = NULL then 8: </p><formula xml:id="formula_7">L ← [U 1 ,U 2 , . . . ,U t ] 12: T p ← BUILDTREE(L, P struct , P rel , T ) Output: T p</formula><p>T p using P struct as the structure model, and P rel as the relation model, from the constituents on which modifications are proposed. Otherwise, T p is built from the bottom-level constituents of T . The upper-level information, such as the depth of a discourse constituent, is derived from the initial tree T .</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.1">Local models</head><p>The local models, P {struct|rel} {intra|multi} , for post-editing is almost identical to their counterparts of the bottom-up tree-building, except that the linear- chain CRFs in post-editing includes additional features to represent information from constituents on higher levels (to be introduced in Section 7).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Linear time complexity</head><p>Here we analyze the time complexity of each com- ponent in our discourse parser, to quantitatively demonstrate the time efficiency of our model. The following analysis is focused on the bottom-up tree-building process, but a similar analysis can be carried out for the post-editing process. Since the number of operations in the post-editing process is roughly the same (1.5 times in the worst case) as in the bottom-up tree-building, post-editing shares the same complexity as the tree-building.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.1">Intra-sentential parsing</head><p>Suppose the input document is segmented into n sentences, and each sentence S k contains m k EDUs. For each sentence S k with m k EDUs, the overall time complexity to perform intra-sentential parsing is O(m 2 k ). The reason is the following. On level i of the bottom-up tree-building, we generate a single chain to represent the structure or relation for all the m k − i constituents that are currently in the sentence. The time complexity for performing forward-backward inference on the single chain is</p><formula xml:id="formula_8">O((m k − i) × M 2 ) = O(m k − i),</formula><note type="other">where the constant M is the size of the output vocabulary. Starting from the EDUs on the bottom level, we need to perform inference for one chain on each level dur- ing the bottom-up tree-building, and thus the total time complexity is Σ m</note><formula xml:id="formula_9">k i=1 O(m k − i) = O(m 2 k ).</formula><p>The total time to generate sentence-level dis- course trees for n sentences is Σ n k=1 O(m 2 k ). It is fairly safe to assume that each m k is a constant, in the sense that m k is independent of the total number of sentences in the document. There- fore, the total time complexity</p><formula xml:id="formula_10">Σ n k=1 O(m 2 k ) ≤ n × O(max 1≤ j≤n (m 2 j )) = n × O(1) = O(n), i.</formula><p>e., linear in the total number of sentences.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.2">Multi-sentential parsing</head><p>For multi-sentential models, M struct multi and M rel multi , as shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figures 4b and 5b</ref>, for a pair of con- stituents of interest, we generate multiple chains to predict the structure or the relation.</p><p>By including a constant number k of discourse units in each chain, and considering a constant number l of such chains for computing each ad- jacent pair of discourse constituents (k = 4 for M struct multi and k = 3 for M rel multi ; l = 3), we have an overall time complexity of O(n). The reason is that it takes l × O(kM 2 ) = O(1) time, where l, k, M are all constants, to perform exact inference for a given pair of adjacent constituents, and we need to perform such computation for all n − 1 pairs of adjacent sentences on the first level of the tree- building. Adopting a greedy approach, on an ar- bitrary level during the tree-building, once we de- cide to merge a certain pair of constituents, say U j and U j+1 , we only need to recompute a small number of chains, i.e., the chains which originally include U j or U j+1 , and inference on each chain takes O(1). Therefore, the total time complexity is (n − 1) × O(1) + (n − 1) × O(1) = O(n), where the first term in the summation is the complexity of computing all chains on the bottom level, and the second term is the complexity of computing the constant number of chains on higher levels.</p><p>We have thus showed that the time complexity is linear in n, which is the number of sentences in the document. In fact, under the assumption that the number of EDUs in each sentence is indepen- dent of n, it can be shown that the time complexity is also linear in the total number of EDUs 4 .</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7">Features</head><p>In our local models, to encode two adjacent units, U j and U j+1 , within a CRF chain, we use the fol- lowing 10 sets of features, some of which are mod- ified from Joty et al.'s model.</p><p>Organization features: Whether U j (or U j+1 ) is the first (or last) constituent in the sentence (for intra-sentential models) or in the document (for multi-sentential models); whether U j (or U j+1 ) is a bottom-level constituent.</p><p>Textual structure features: Whether U j con- tains more sentences (or paragraphs) than U j+1 .</p><p>N-gram features: The beginning (or end) lexi- cal n-grams in each unit; the beginning (or end) POS n-grams in each unit, where n ∈ {1, 2, 3}.</p><p>Dominance features: The PoS tags of the head node and the attachment node; the lexical heads of the head node and the attachment node; the domi- nance relationship between the two units.</p><p>Contextual features: The feature vector of the previous and the next constituent in the chain.</p><p>Substructure features: The root node of the left and right discourse subtrees of each unit.</p><p>Syntactic features: whether each unit corre- sponds to a single syntactic subtree, and if so, the top PoS tag of the subtree; the distance of each unit to their lowest common ancestor in the syntax tree (intra-sentential only).</p><p>Entity transition features: The type and the number of entity transitions across the two units.</p><p>We adopt <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Barzilay and Lapata (2008)</ref>'s entity- based local coherence model to represent a doc- ument by an entity grid, and extract local transi- tions among entities in continuous discourse con- stituents. We use bigram and trigram transitions with syntactic roles attached to each entity.</p><p>Cue phrase features: Whether a cue phrase oc- curs in the first or last EDU of each unit. The cue phrase list is based on the connectives collected by <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Knott and Dale (1994)</ref> Post-editing features: The depth of each unit in the initial tree.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="8">Experiments</head><p>For pre-processing, we use the Stanford CoreNLP ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Klein and Manning, 2003;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b3">de Marneffe et al., 2006;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Recasens et al., 2013</ref>) to syntactically parse the texts and extract coreference relations, and we use Penn2Malt 5 to lexicalize syntactic trees to ex- tract dominance features. For local models, our structure models are trained using MALLET <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">(McCallum, 2002</ref>) to in- clude constraints over transitions between adja- cent labels, and our relation models are trained using CRFSuite <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(Okazaki, 2007)</ref>, which is a fast implementation of linear-chain CRFs.</p><p>The data that we use to develop and evaluate our discourse parser is the RST Discourse Tree- bank (RST-DT) <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Carlson et al., 2001</ref>), which is a large corpus annotated in the framework of RST. The RST-DT consists of 385 documents (347 for training and 38 for testing) from the Wall Street Journal. Following previous work on the RST-DT ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Hernault et al., 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Feng and Hirst, 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Joty et al., 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Joty et al., 2013)</ref>, we use 18 coarse- grained relation classes, and with nuclearity at- tached, we have a total set of 41 distinct relations. Non-binary relations are converted into a cascade of right-branching binary relations.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="9">Results and Discussion</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="9.1">Parsing accuracy</head><p>We compare four different models using manual EDU segmentation. In <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>, the jCRF model in the first row is the optimal CRF model proposed by <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Joty et al. (2013)</ref>. gSVM FH in the second row is our implementation of HILDA's greedy parsing algorithm using <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Feng and Hirst (2012)</ref>'s enhanced feature set. The third model, gCRF, represents our greedy CRF-based discourse parser, and the last row, gCRF PE , represents our parser with the post- editing component included.</p><p>In  <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>: Performance of different models using gold-standard EDU segmentation, evaluated us- ing the constituent accuracy (%) for span, nucle- arity, and relation. For relation, we also report the macro-averaged F1-score (MAFS) for correctly retrieved constituents (before the slash) and for all constituents (after the slash). Statistical sig- nificance is verified using Wilcoxon's signed-rank test.</p><p>uation metrics, i.e., the unlabeled and labeled pre- cision, recall, and F-score 6 as defined by <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Marcu (2000)</ref>. For evaluating relations, since there is a skewed distribution of different relation types in the corpus, we also include the macro-averaged F1-score (MAFS) <ref type="bibr">7</ref> as another metric, to empha- size the performance of infrequent relation types. We report the MAFS separately for the correctly retrieved constituents (i.e., the span boundary is correct) and all constituents in the reference tree.</p><p>As demonstrated by <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>, our greedy CRF models perform significantly better than the other two models. Since we do not have the actual out- put of Joty et al.'s model, we are unable to con- duct significance testing between our models and theirs. But in terms of overall accuracy, our gCRF model outperforms their model by 1.5%. More- over, with post-editing enabled, gCRF PE signif- icantly (p &lt; .01) outperforms our initial model gCRF by another 1% in relation assignment, and this overall accuracy of 58.2% is close to 90% of human performance. With respect to the macro- averaged F1-scores, adding the post-editing com- ponent also obtains about 1% improvement.</p><p>However, the overall MAFS is still at the lower  end of 30% for all constituents. Our error anal- ysis shows that, for two relation classes, TOPIC- CHANGE and TEXTUAL-ORGANIZATION, our model fails to retrieve any instance, and for TOPIC-COMMENT and EVALUATION, our model scores a class-wise F 1 score lower than 5%. These four relation classes, apart from their infrequency in the corpus, are more abstractly defined, and thus are particularly challenging.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="9.2">Parsing efficiency</head><p>We further illustrate the efficiency of our parser by demonstrating the time consumption of different models. First, as shown in <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">Table 2</ref>, the average number of sentences in a document is 26.11, which is al- ready too large for optimal parsing models, e.g., the CKY-like parsing algorithm in jCRF, let alone the fact that the largest document contains sev- eral hundred of EDUs and sentences. Therefore, it should be seen that non-optimal models are re- quired in most cases.</p><p>In <ref type="table" target="#tab_6">Table 3</ref>, we report the parsing time 8 for the last three models, since we do not know the time of jCRF. Note that the parsing time excludes the time cost for any necessary pre-processing. As can be seen, our gCRF model is considerably faster than gSVM FH , because, on one hand, feature compu- tation is expensive in gSVM FH , since gSVM FH utilizes a rich set of features; on the other hand, in gCRF, we are able to accelerate decoding by multi-threading MALLET (we use four threads). Even for the largest document with 187 sentences, gCRF is able to produce the final tree after about 40 seconds, while jCRF would take over 16 hours assuming each DCRF decoding takes only 0.01 second. Although enabling post-editing doubles the time consumption, the overall time is still ac- ceptable in practice, and the loss of efficiency can be compensated by the improvement in accuracy.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Model</head><p>Parsing Time (seconds)  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Avg Min Max</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="10">Conclusions</head><p>In this paper, we presented an efficient text-level discourse parser with time complexity linear in the total number of sentences in the document. Our approach was to adopt a greedy bottom- up tree-building, with two linear-chain CRFs as local probabilistic models, and enforce reason- able constraints in the first CRF's Viterbi decod- ing. While significantly outperforming the state- of-the-art model by <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Joty et al. (2013)</ref>, our parser is much faster in practice. In addition, we pro- pose a novel idea of post-editing, which modifies a fully-built discourse tree by considering informa- tion from upper-level constituents. We show that, although doubling the time consumption, post- editing can further boost the parsing performance to close to 90% of human performance.</p><p>In future work, we wish to further explore the idea of post-editing, since currently we use only the depth of the subtrees as upper-level informa- tion. Moreover, we wish to study whether we can incorporate constraints into the relation models, as we do to the structure models. For example, it might be helpful to train the relation models us- ing additional criteria, such as Generalized Ex- pectation ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Mann and McCallum, 2008)</ref>, to better take into account some prior knowledge about the relations. Last but not least, as reflected by the low MAFS in our experiments, some particularly difficult relation types might need specifically de- signed features for better recognition.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2: Joty et al. (2013)'s intra-sentential Condition Random Fields.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 4 :</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Figure 4: Local structure models.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Relation</head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>Figure 5 :</head><label>5</label><figDesc>Figure 5: Local relation models.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head>Replace</head><label></label><figDesc>L[i] and L[i + 1] with p 10: if |L| = 2 then 11:</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4" validated="false"><head>Table 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Characteristics of the 38 documents in the 
test data. 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_6" validated="false"><head>Table 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>The parsing time (in seconds) for the 38 
documents in the test set of RST-DT. Time cost of 
any pre-processing is excluded from the analysis. 

</table></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="2"> The time complexity will be reduced to O(M 2 n 2 ), if we use the same chain for all constituents as in our M struct intra .</note>

			<note place="foot" n="3"> These leaf constituents are represented using a special feature vector is leaf = True; thus the CRF never labels them with relations other than LEAF.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="4"> We implicitly made an assumption that the parsing time is dominated by the time to perform inference on CRF chains. However, for complex features, the time required for feature computation might be dominant. Nevertheless, a careful caching strategy can accelerate feature computation, since a large number of multi-sentential chains overlap with each other.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="5"> http://stp.lingfil.uu.se/ ˜ nivre/ research/Penn2Malt.html.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="6"> For manual segmentation, precision, recall, and F-score are the same. 7 MAFS is the F1-score averaged among all relation classes by equally weighting each class. Therefore, we cannot conduct significance test between different MAFS.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="8"> Tested on a Linux system with four duo-core 3.0GHz processors and 16G memory.</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>We thank Professor Gerald Penn and the review-ers for their valuable advice and comments. This work was financially supported by the Natural Sciences and Engineering Research Council of Canada and by the University of Toronto.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Probabilistic head-driven parsing for discourse structure</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jason</forename><surname>Baldridge</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alex</forename><surname>Lascarides</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Ninth Conference on Computational Natural Language Learning (CoNLL-2005)</title>
		<meeting>the Ninth Conference on Computational Natural Language Learning (CoNLL-2005)<address><addrLine>Ann Arbor, Michigan, June</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="96" to="103" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Modeling local coherence: an entity-based approach</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Regina</forename><surname>Barzilay</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mirella</forename><surname>Lapata</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Computational Linguistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">34</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="34" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Building a discourse-tagged corpus in the framework of Rhetorical Structure Theory</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lynn</forename><surname>Carlson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Daniel</forename><surname>Marcu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mary</forename><forename type="middle">Ellen</forename><surname>Okurowski</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of Second SIGDial Workshop on Discourse and Dialogue</title>
		<meeting>Second SIGDial Workshop on Discourse and Dialogue</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="10" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Generating typed dependency parses from phrase structure parses</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marie-Catherine</forename><surname>De Marneffe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bill</forename><surname>Maccartney</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christopher</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Manning</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 5th International Conference on Language Resources and Evaluation (LREC</title>
		<meeting>the 5th International Conference on Language Resources and Evaluation (LREC</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Text-level discourse parsing with rich linguistic features</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wei</forename><surname>Vanessa</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Graeme</forename><surname>Feng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Hirst</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 50th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics: Human Language Technologies (ACL 2012)</title>
		<meeting>the 50th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics: Human Language Technologies (ACL 2012)<address><addrLine>Jeju, Korea</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="60" to="68" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">HILDA: A discourse parser using support vector machine classification</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hugo</forename><surname>Hernault</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Helmut</forename><surname>Prendinger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mitsuru</forename><surname>Ishizuka</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Dialogue and Discourse</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="33" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A novel discriminative framework for sentence-level discourse analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Shafiq</forename><surname>Joty</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Giuseppe</forename><surname>Carenini</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Raymond</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Ng</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2012 Joint Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing and Computational Natural Language Learning</title>
		<meeting>the 2012 Joint Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing and Computational Natural Language Learning</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="904" to="915" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Combining intra-and multisentential rhetorical parsing for document-level discourse analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Shafiq</forename><surname>Joty</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Giuseppe</forename><surname>Carenini</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Raymond</forename><surname>Ng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yashar</forename><surname>Mehdad</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 51st Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL 2013)</title>
		<meeting>the 51st Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL 2013)<address><addrLine>Sofia</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013-08" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="486" to="496" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
<note type="report_type">Bulgaria</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Accurate unlexicalized parsing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dan</forename><surname>Klein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Christopher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Manning</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 41st Annual Meeting on Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL 2003), ACL 2003</title>
		<meeting>the 41st Annual Meeting on Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL 2003), ACL 2003<address><addrLine>Stroudsburg, PA, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="423" to="430" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Using linguistic phenomena to motivate a set of coherence relations</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alistair</forename><surname>Knott</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Robert</forename><surname>Dale</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Discourse Processes</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1994" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">18</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="35" to="64" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Conditional random fields: Probabilistic models for segmenting and labeling sequence data</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">John</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Lafferty</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Andrew</forename><surname>Mccallum</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Fernando</forename><forename type="middle">C N</forename><surname>Pereira</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Eighteenth International Conference on Machine Learning</title>
		<meeting>the Eighteenth International Conference on Machine Learning<address><addrLine>San Francisco, CA, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Morgan Kaufmann Publishers Inc</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="282" to="289" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Generalized Expectation Criteria for semi-supervised learning of Conditional Random Fields</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gideon</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Mann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Andrew</forename><surname>Mccallum</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 46th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics: Human Language Technologies (ACL 2008)</title>
		<meeting>the 46th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics: Human Language Technologies (ACL 2008)<address><addrLine>Ohio</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008-06" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="870" to="878" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Columbus. Association for Computational Linguistics</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Rhetorical structure theory: Toward a functional theory of text organization</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">William</forename><surname>Mann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sandra</forename><surname>Thompson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Text</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="243" to="281" />
			<date type="published" when="1988" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The Theory and Practice of Discourse Parsing and Summarization</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Daniel</forename><surname>Marcu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
			<publisher>The MIT Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">MALLET: A machine learning for language toolkit</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Andrew Kachites</forename><surname>Mccallum</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://mallet.cs.umass.edu" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Constrained decoding for text-level discourse parsing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Philippe</forename><surname>Muller</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Stergos</forename><surname>Afantenos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Pascal</forename><surname>Denis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nicholas</forename><surname>Asher</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">The COLING 2012 Organizing Committee</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Mumbai, India</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012-12" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1883" to="1900" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Proceedings of COLING 2012</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">CRFsuite: a fast implementation of conditional random fields (CRFs)</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Naoaki</forename><surname>Okazaki</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The life and death of discourse entities: Identifying singleton mentions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marta</forename><surname>Recasens</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marie-Catherine</forename><surname>De Marneffe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christopher</forename><surname>Potts</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2013 Conference of the North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics: Human Language Technologies</title>
		<meeting>the 2013 Conference of the North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics: Human Language Technologies<address><addrLine>Atlanta, Georgia</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2013-06" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="627" to="633" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">An effective discourse parser that uses rich linguistic information</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rajen</forename><surname>Subba</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Barbara</forename><forename type="middle">Di</forename><surname>Eugenio</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of Human Language Technologies: The 2009 Annual Conference of the North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>Human Language Technologies: The 2009 Annual Conference of the North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics<address><addrLine>Boulder, Colorado</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009-06" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="566" to="574" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Association for Computational Linguistics</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dynamic conditional random fields: Factorized probabilistic models for labeling and segmenting sequence data</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Charles</forename><surname>Sutton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Andrew</forename><surname>Mccallum</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Khashayar</forename><surname>Rohanimanesh</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The Journal of Machine Learning Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="693" to="723" />
			<date type="published" when="2007-05" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A dynamic conditional random field model for joint labeling of object and scene classes</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christian</forename><surname>Wojek</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bernt</forename><surname>Schiele</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV 2008)</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Marseille, France</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="733" to="747" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Combining a two-step conditional random field model and a joint source channel model for machine transliteration</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dong</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Paul</forename><surname>Dixon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yi-Cheng</forename><surname>Pan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tasuku</forename><surname>Oonishi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Masanobu</forename><surname>Nakamura</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sadaoki</forename><surname>Furui</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2009 Named Entities Workshop: Shared Task on Transliteration (NEWS 2009)</title>
		<meeting>the 2009 Named Entities Workshop: Shared Task on Transliteration (NEWS 2009)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="72" to="75" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Suntec, Singapore, August. Association for Computational Linguistics</note>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
