<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T10:16+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Refinements to Interactive Translation Prediction Based on Search Graphs</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
				<availability status="unknown"><p>Copyright Association for Computational Linguistics</p>
				</availability>
				<date>June 23-25 2014. 2014</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Philipp</forename><surname>Koehn</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Center for Speech and Language Processing</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">The Johns Hopkins University School of Informatics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">University of Edinburgh</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chara</forename><surname>Tsoukala</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Center for Speech and Language Processing</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">The Johns Hopkins University School of Informatics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">University of Edinburgh</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Herve</forename><surname>Saint-Amand</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Center for Speech and Language Processing</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">The Johns Hopkins University School of Informatics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">University of Edinburgh</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Refinements to Interactive Translation Prediction Based on Search Graphs</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 52nd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
						<meeting>the 52nd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics <address><addrLine>Baltimore, Maryland, USA</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="574" to="578"/>
							<date type="published">June 23-25 2014. 2014</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>We propose a number of refinements to the canonical approach to interactive translation prediction. By more permissive matching criteria, placing emphasis on matching the last word of the user prefix, and dealing with predictions to partially typed words, we observe gains in both word prediction accuracy (+5.4%) and letter prediction accuracy (+9.3%).</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>As machine translation enters the workflow of professional translators, the exact nature of this human-computer interaction is currently an open challenge. Instead of tasking translators to post- edit the output of machine translation systems, a more interactive approach may be more fruitful.</p><p>One such idea is interactive translation predic- tion ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Langlais et al., 2000b</ref>): While the user writes the translation for a sentence, the system makes suggestions for sequent words. If the user di- verges from the suggestions, the system recalcu- lates its prediction, and offers new suggestions. This input modality is familiar to anybody who has used auto-complete functions in text editors, cell phones, or web applications.</p><p>The technical challenge is to come up with a method that predicts words that the user will ac- cept. The standard approach to this problem uses the search graph of the machine translation sys- tem. Such search graphs may be recomputed in a constraint decoding process restricted to the par- tial user input (called the prefix), but this is often too slow with big models and limited computing resources, so we use static word graphs.</p><p>The user prefix is matched against the search graph. If the user prefix cannot be found in the search graph, approximate string matching is used by finding a path with minimal string edit distance, i.e., a path in the graph with the minimal number of insertions, deletions and substitutions to match the user prefix. This paper presents a number of refinements to extend this approach, by allowing more per- missive matching criterion, placing emphasis on matching the last word of the user prefix, and deal- ing with predictions to partially typed words. We show improvements in word prediction accuracy from 56.1% to 60.5% and letter prediction accu- racy from 75.2% to 84.5% on a publicly available benchmark (English-Spanish news translation).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Related Work</head><p>The interactive machine translation paradigm was first explored in the TransType and TransType2 projects ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Langlais et al., 2000a;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Foster et al., 2002;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Bender et al., 2005;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Barrachina et al., 2009)</ref>. Given the computational cost and need for quick response time, most current word operates on search graphs ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Och et al., 2003)</ref>. Such search graphs can be efficiently represented and pro- cessed with finite state tools ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Civera et al., 2004</ref>). More recently, the approach has been extended to SCFG-based translation models ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">González-Rubio et al., 2013)</ref>.</p><p>There are several ways the sentence completion predictions can be presented to the user: show- ing the complete sentence prediction, only a few words, or multiple choices. User actions may be also extended to mouse actions to pinpoint the di- vergence from an acceptable translation <ref type="bibr">(SanchisTrilles et al., 2008)</ref>, or hand-writing (Alabau et al., 2011) and speech modalities ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Cubel et al., 2009</ref>).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Properties of Core Algorithm</head><p>Our implementation of the core algorithm follows closely <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Koehn (2009)</ref>. It is a dynamic program- ming solution that computes the minimal cost to reach each node in the search graph by matching parts of the user prefix. Cost is measured primar- ily in terms of string edit distance (number of dele- tions, insertions and substitutions), and secondary in terms of translation model score for the matched path in the graph. Search is done iteratively, with an increasing number of allowable edits. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Experimental Setup</head><p>Given the large number of proposed variations of the algorithm, we do not carry out user studies, but rather use a simulated setting. We predict transla- tions that were crafted by manual post-editing of machine translation output. We also use the search graphs of the system that produced the original machine translation output.</p><p>Such data has been made available by the CAS- MACAT project <ref type="bibr">1</ref> . In the project's first field trial 2 , professional translators corrected machine transla- tions of news stories from a competitive English- Spanish machine translation system <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Koehn and Haddow, 2012)</ref>. This test set consists of 24,444 word predictions and 141,662 letter predictions.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Prediction Speed</head><p>Since the interactive translation prediction process is used in an interactive setting where each key stroke of the user may trigger a new request, very fast response time is needed. According to stan- dards in usability engineering 0.1 second is about the limit for having the user feel that the system is reacting instantaneously <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Nielsen, 1993)</ref>.</p><p>So, this is the time limit we have to set ourselves to predict the next words of a translator.</p><p>What are the main factors that influence pro- cessing time in our core algorithm? See <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref> for an illustration. We plot processing time against the length of the user prefix and the string edit dis- tance between the user prefix and the search graph. The graph clearly shows that the main slowdown in processing time occurs when the edit rate in- creases.</p><p>To guarantee a response in 100ms, the algo- rithms aborts when this time is exceeded and re- lies on a prediction based on string edit distance against the best path in the graph. The larger the number of edits, the more often this occurs, as <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Fig- ure 2</ref> shows.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3">Accuracy</head><p>We are mainly interested in the accuracy of the method: How often does it predict a word that the user accepts? There is a trade-off between speed and accuracy.</p><p>One way we can balance this trade-off is by re- moving nodes from the search graph. By thresh- old pruning <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">(Sanchis-Trilles and Ortiz-Martínez, 2014</ref>), we remove nodes from the search graph that are only part of paths that are worse than the best path by a specified score difference.</p><p>See <ref type="table">Table 1</ref> how the choice of the score differ- ence threshold impacts failure rate and accuracy. A wider threshold has the potential to achieve bet- ter results (if we allows for up to 1 second of pro- cessing time), but with the constraint of 100ms re- sponse time, the optimum is with a threshold of 0.4. Wider thresholds lead to a higher failure rate, causing overall lower accuracy. </p><note type="other">Max 1000ms Max Acc. Fail Acc. Fail 0.3 55.8%</note><p>4.5% 56.9% 0.0% 0.4 56.1% 6.5% 58.0% 0.0% 0.5 55.9% 9.0% 58.8% 0.0% 0.6 55.5% 11.6% 59.4% 0.0% 0.8 54.4% 17.1% 59.4% 0.0% 1.0 52.7% 21.7% 58.6% 6.5% <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>: Impact of threshold pruning on search ac- curacy and failure rate (i.e., failure to complete search in given time and resorting to matching against best translation).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Refinements</head><p>We now introduce a number of refinements over the core method. Given the constraints established in the previous section (maximum response time of 100ms, pruning threshold 0.4), we set out to improve accuracy.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">Matching Last Word</head><p>The first idea is that it is more important to match the last word of the user prefix than having mis- matches in earlier words. We attempt to find the last word in the predicted path either before or after the optimal matching position according to string edit distance. We combine the matched path in the prefix with the optimal suffix, and search for the last user pre- fix word within a window. This means that we either move words from the suffix to the prefix or the other way around, without changing the over- all string along the path. <ref type="table">Table 2</ref> shows the impact on accuracy for differ- ent window sizes. While we expected some gains by checking for the word somewhere around the optimal position in the predicted path, we do see significant gains by not placing any restrictions to where the word can be found, except for a bias to less distant positions. For instance, examining a window of up to 3 words gives us a word pre- diction accuracy of 57.2% versus the 56.1% base- line. Finding the last word anywhere boosts per- formance to 59.1%.</p><p>The table also reports accuracy numbers when we allow the process to run up to 1 second - which is basically an exhaustive search but not practically useful. These numbers shed some light on why an unlimited window size in matching the last word helps: the gains come partially from the cases where the initial search fails. Finding the last user word anywhere in the machine transla- Window 100ms Max 1000ms Max baseline 56.1% 58.0% 1 word 56.6% 58.4% 2 words 56.9% 58.6% 3 words 57.2% 58.9% 5 words 57.8% 59.3% anywhere 59.1% 59.5% <ref type="table">Table 2</ref>: Search for the last prefix word in a win- dow around the predicted position in the matched path.</p><p>Word Matching 100ms Max 1000ms Max baseline 59.1% 59.5% case-insensitive 58.7% 59.4% <ref type="table">Table 3</ref>: Search with case-insensitive word match- ing (say, University and university).</p><p>tion output is a better fallback than computing op- timal string edit distance. Analysis of the data suggests that gains mainly come from large length mismatches between user translation and machine translation, even in the case of first pass searches.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">Case-Insensitive Matching</head><p>Some mismatches between words matter less than others. For instance, if the user prefix differs only in casing from the machine translation (say, Uni- versity instead of university), then we may still want to treat that as a word match in our al- gorithm. However, as <ref type="table">Table 3</ref> shows, allowing case-insensitive matching leads to lower accuracy (58.7% vs. 59.1%). A major reason is computational cost. The most inner loop in the algorithm compares words. This is optimized by representing words as integers. However, if we allow case-insensitive matching, this simple method does not work anymore. We do precompute approximate word matches and store matching words identifiers in a hash map, but still the ratio of searches that do not complete in 100ms increases from 6.5% to 9.7%. By extending the al- lowable time to 1 second, the accuracy gap is re- duced to 0.1%.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3">Approximate Word Matching</head><p>When a word in the user translation differs from a word in the decoder search graph only by a few letters, then it should be considered a lesser error than substitutions of completely different words. Such word differences may be due to casing, mor- phological variants, or spelling inconsistencies.</p><p>We compute word dissimilarity by computing Max. Dissimilarity 100ms Max. 1000ms Max. baseline 59.1% 59.5% 30% 60.2% 61.0% 20% 60.4% 61.3% 10% 60.6% 61.5%  <ref type="table">Table 5</ref>: Counting substitutions between morpho- logical variants as half an error. Morphological variance is approximated by requiring a minimum number of initial letters to match and a maximum of final letters to differ.</p><p>the ratio of letter edit operations to the length of the shorter word. <ref type="bibr">3</ref> We now set a threshold for maximum dissimilarity, under which mismatched words are considered only half the edit cost of other edit operations. <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table 4</ref> shows that we get significantly higher word prediction accuracy than with the baseline approach (up to 60.6% vs. 59.1%), and the best performance with a 10% threshold. We observe the same computational problem as in the previous section (about 9.2% first pass failures, vs. 6.5%), reflected in a higher accuracy gap for 100ms and 1000ms time limits.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.4">Stemmed Matching</head><p>We suspected that the main benefit of approximate word matching is the better handling of morpho- logical variants. In Spanish, this mainly consti- tutes itself as different word endings. Thus, we re- define our word dissimilarity measure by consider words similar, if they agree in at least a number of leading letters (presumably the stem), and may differ in at most a number of trailing letters (pre- sumably the morpheme). <ref type="table">Table 5</ref> shows that this is successful in increas- ing the word prediction rate (59.5% vs. 59.1%) but not as much as with the more general approx- imate word matching in the previous section (re- call: 60.6%).</p><p>= .75.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head># Method</head><p>Word Acc. Letter Acc. 1 baseline 56.0% 75.2% 2 1+matching last word 59.0% 80.6% 3 2+case insensitive 58.7% 80.4% 4 2+dissimilarity 10% 60.5% 80.6% 5 2+stem 2/3 59.4% 80.5% 6 4+desperate 60.5% 84.5% <ref type="table">Table 6</ref>: Extending the approach to word com- pletion. Impact of refinements of letter prediction accuracy with additional desperate word matching against the entire vocabulary.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Word Completion</head><p>Besides word prediction, word completion is also a useful feature in an interactive translation tool. When the machine translation system decides for college over university, but the user types the letter u, it should change its prediction.</p><p>To enable word completion in the canonical al- gorithm, we allow matching of the final user word (if not followed by a space character) as a prefix of any word as a zero cost operation. The predicted suffix that is returned to the user then starts with the remaining letters of the word in the path. <ref type="table">Table 6</ref> shows that the refinements that helped sentence completion also benefit word comple- tion. From a baseline accuracy of 75.2% correctly predicted letters, we reach up to 80.6%. Note that the baseline word prediction accuracy is slightly lower (56.0% vs. 56.1%) than in the previous ex- periments, since the previously correctly matched last word may be mistaken as the prefix of another word.</p><p>We add an additional refinement to this task: If the potentially incomplete final word of the user prefix cannot be found in the predicted path, then we explore the entire vocabulary from the un- pruned search graph for completions. If multiple words match, the one with the highest path score is used. This desperate word completion method gives significant gains (84.5% over 80.6%).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Conclusion and Future Work</head><p>We observe most improvements by a focus on the last word of the user prefix and approximate word matching. This suggests that there may be additional gains by a stronger focus on the tail of the user prefix. Also, the findings from the time/productivity tradeoffs indicate that more time efficient algorithms and implementations should be explored.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>577</head></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: Average response time of baseline method based on length of the prefix and number of edits: The main bottleneck is the string edit distance between prefix and path.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2: Ratio of prefix matching processes abandoned due to exceeding the 100ms time limit (showing only curves with a minimum of 5 edits).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" validated="false"><head>Table 4 :</head><label>4</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Counting substitutions between similar 
words as half an error. Dissimilarity is measured 
as letter edit distance 

Min Stem / Max Suffix 100ms 1000ms 
baseline 
59.1% 
59.5% 
4 / 3 
59.4% 
60.1% 
3 / 3 
59.5% 
60.2% 
2 / 3 
59.5% 
60.3% 

</table></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> http://www.casmacat.eu/ 2 http://www.casmacat.eu/uploads/Deliverables/d6.1.pdf</note>

			<note place="foot" n="3"> For instance, if a 6 letter word and a 4 letter word can be matched with two deletions and one substitution, then the dissimilarity score is 3 4</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgements</head><p>This work was supported under the CASMACAT project (grant agreement N o 287576) by the European Union 7 th Framework Programme <ref type="bibr">(FP7/2007</ref><ref type="bibr">(FP7/-2013</ref>).</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Improving on-line handwritten recognition using translation models in multimodal interactive machine translation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Alabau</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Sanchis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Casacuberta</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 49th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics: Human Language Techologies</title>
		<meeting>the 49th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics: Human Language Techologies<address><addrLine>Portland, Oregon, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="389" to="394" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Association for Computational Linguistics</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Statistical approaches to computer-assisted translation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Barrachina</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Bender</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Casacuberta</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Civera</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Cubel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Khadivi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Lagarda</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Ney</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Tomás</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Vidal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J.-M</forename><surname>Vilar</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Computational Linguistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">35</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Comparison of generation strategies for interactive machine translation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Bender</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Hasan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Vilar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Zens</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Ney</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 10th Conference of the European Association for Machine Translation (EAMT)</title>
		<meeting>the 10th Conference of the European Association for Machine Translation (EAMT)<address><addrLine>Budapest</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">From machine translation to computer assisted translation using finite-state models</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Civera</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Cubel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Lagarda</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Picó</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>González</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Vidal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Casacuberta</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Vilar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Barrachina</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of EMNLP 2004</title>
		<editor>Lin, D. and Wu, D.</editor>
		<meeting>EMNLP 2004<address><addrLine>Barcelona, Spain</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="349" to="356" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Statistical approaches to computer-assisted translation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Cubel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Khadivi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Lagarda</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Ney</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Toms</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Vidal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J.-M</forename><surname>Vilar</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Computational Linguistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">35</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Userfriendly text prediction for translators</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Foster</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Langlais</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lapalme</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP)</title>
		<meeting>the Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP)<address><addrLine>Philadelphia</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="148" to="155" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Interactive machine translation using hierarchical translation models</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>González-Rubio</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Ortíz-Martinez</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Benedí</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Casacuberta</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2013 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</title>
		<meeting>the 2013 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing<address><addrLine>Seattle, Washington, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="244" to="254" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A process study of computer-aided translation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Koehn</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Machine Translation</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">23</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="241" to="263" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Towards effective use of training data in statistical machine translation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Koehn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Haddow</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<monogr>
				<title level="m">Proceedings of the Seventh Workshop on Statistical Machine Translation</title>
		<meeting>the Seventh Workshop on Statistical Machine Translation<address><addrLine>Montreal, Canada</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="363" to="367" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Transtype: a computer-aided translation typing system</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Langlais</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Foster</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lapalme</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the ANLP-NAACL 2000 Workshop on Embedded Machine Translation Systems</title>
		<meeting>the ANLP-NAACL 2000 Workshop on Embedded Machine Translation Systems</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Unit completion for a computer-aided translation typing system</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Langlais</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Foster</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lapalme</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of Annual Meeting of the North American Chapter of the Association of Computational Linguistics (NAACL)</title>
		<meeting>Annual Meeting of the North American Chapter of the Association of Computational Linguistics (NAACL)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Usability Engineering</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Nielsen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
			<publisher>Morgan Kaufmann</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Efficient search for interactive statistical machine translation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Och</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Zens</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Ney</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of Meeting of the European Chapter of the Association of Computational Linguistics (EACL)</title>
		<meeting>Meeting of the European Chapter of the Association of Computational Linguistics (EACL)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Efficient wordgraph pruning for interactive translation prediction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Sanchis-Trilles</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Ortiz-Martínez</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Annual Conference of the European Association for Machine Translation (EAMT)</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Improving interactive machine translation via mouse actions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Sanchis-Trilles</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Ortiz-Martínez</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Civera</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Casacuberta</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Vidal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Hoang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2008 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</title>
		<meeting>the 2008 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing<address><addrLine>Honolulu, Hawaii</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="485" to="494" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
