<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T11:35+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Unsupervised Alignment of Privacy Policies using Hidden Markov Models</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
				<availability status="unknown"><p>Copyright Association for Computational Linguistics</p>
				</availability>
				<date>June 23-25 2014. 2014</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rohan</forename><surname>Ramanath</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">School of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Carnegie Mellon University Pittsburgh</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>15213</postCode>
									<region>PA</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Fei</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">School of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Carnegie Mellon University Pittsburgh</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>15213</postCode>
									<region>PA</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Norman</forename><surname>Sadeh</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">School of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Carnegie Mellon University Pittsburgh</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>15213</postCode>
									<region>PA</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Noah</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Smith</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">School of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Carnegie Mellon University Pittsburgh</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>15213</postCode>
									<region>PA</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Unsupervised Alignment of Privacy Policies using Hidden Markov Models</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 52nd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
						<meeting>the 52nd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics <address><addrLine>Baltimore, Maryland, USA</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="605" to="610"/>
							<date type="published">June 23-25 2014. 2014</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>To support empirical study of online privacy policies, as well as tools for users with privacy concerns, we consider the problem of aligning sections of a thousand policy documents, based on the issues they address. We apply an unsupervised HMM; in two new (and reusable) evaluations, we find the approach more effective than clustering and topic models.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Privacy policy documents are verbose, often eso- teric legal documents that many people encounter as clients of companies that provide services on the web. <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">McDonald and Cranor (2008)</ref> showed that, if users were to read the privacy policies of every website they access during the course of a year, they would end up spending a substantial amount of their time doing just that and would often still not be able to answer basic questions about what these policies really say. Unsurpris- ingly, many people do not read them <ref type="bibr">(Federal Trade Commission, 2012)</ref>.</p><p>Such policies therefore offer an excellent op- portunity for NLP tools that summarize or ex- tract key information that (i) helps users under- stand the implications of agreeing to these poli- cies and (ii) helps legal analysts understand the contents of these policies and make recommenda- tions on how they can be improved or made more clear. Past applications of NLP have sought to parse privacy policies into machine-readable rep- resentations ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Brodie et al., 2006</ref>) or extract sub- policies from larger documents ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Xiao et al., 2012)</ref>. Machine learning has been applied to assess cer- tain attributes of policies ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Costante et al., 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Ammar et al., 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Costante et al., 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Zimmeck and Bellovin, 2013)</ref>. This paper instead analyzes policies in aggre- gate, seeking to align sections of policies. This task is motivated by an expectation that many poli- cies will address similar issues, 1 such as collec- tion of a user's contact, location, health, and fi- nancial information, sharing with third parties, and deletion of data. This expectation is supported by recommendation by privacy experts <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Gellman, 2014)</ref> and policymakers <ref type="bibr">(Federal Trade Commission, 2012)</ref>; in the financial services sector, the Gramm-Leach-Bliley Act requires these institu- tions to address a specific set of issues. Aligning policy sections is a first step toward our aforemen- tioned summarization and extraction goals.</p><p>We present the following contributions: • A new corpus of over 1,000 privacy policies gathered from widely used websites, manually segmented into subtitled sections by crowdwork- ers ( §2).</p><p>• An unsupervised approach to aligning the policy sections based on the issues they discuss. For example, sections that discuss "user data on the company's server" should be grouped together. The approach is inspired by the application of hidden Markov models to sequence alignment in computational biology ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Durbin et al., 1998;</ref><ref type="bibr">§3)</ref>. • Two reusable evaluation benchmarks for the re- sulting alignment of policy sections ( §4). We demonstrate that our approach outperforms na¨ıvena¨ıve methods ( §5). Our corpus and benchmarks are available at http://usableprivacy.org/data.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Data Collection</head><p>We collected 1,010 unique privacy policy documents from the top websites ranked by Alexa.com. <ref type="bibr">2</ref>  of Alexa.com's seventeen categories <ref type="table">(Table 1)</ref>. <ref type="bibr">3</ref> Finding a website's policy is not trivial. Though many well-regulated commercial websites provide a "privacy" link on their homepages, not all do. We found university websites to be exceptionally unlikely to provide such a link. Even once the pol- icy's URL is identified, extracting the text presents the usual challenges associated with scraping doc- uments from the web. Since every site is differ- ent in its placement of the document (e.g., buried deep within the website, distributed across several pages, or mingled together with Terms of Service) and format (e.g., HTML, PDF, etc.), and since we wish to preserve as much document structure as possible (e.g., section labels), full automation was not a viable solution.</p><p>We therefore crowdsourced the privacy policy document collection using Amazon Mechanical Turk. For each website, we created a HIT in which a worker was asked to copy and paste the following privacy policy-related information into text boxes: (i) privacy policy URL; (ii) last up- dated date (or effective date) of the current privacy policy; (iii) privacy policy full text; and (iv) the section subtitles in the top-most layer of the pri- vacy policy. To identify the privacy policy URL, workers were encouraged to go to the website and search for the privacy link. Alternatively, they could form a search query using the website name and "privacy policy" (e.g., "Amazon.com privacy policy") and search in the returned results for the most appropriate privacy policy URL. Given the privacy policy full text and the section subtitles, we partition the full privacy document into differ- ent sections, delimited by the section subtitles. A privacy policy is then converted into XML.</p><p>Each HIT was completed by three workers, paid $0.05, for a total cost of $380 (including Ama- zon's surcharge).</p><p>Given the corpus of privacy policies described in §2, we designed a model to efficiently infer an alignment of policy sections. While we expect that different kinds of websites will likely address dif- ferent privacy issues, we believe that many poli- cies will discuss roughly the same set of issues.</p><p>Aligning the policies is a first step in a larger effort to (i) automatically analyze policies to make them less opaque to users and (ii) support legal experts who wish to characterize the state of privacy on- line and make recommendations ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Costante et al., 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Ammar et al., 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Costante et al., 2013</ref>). We are inspired by multiple sequence alignment methods in computational biology ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Durbin et al., 1998)</ref> and by <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Barzilay and Lee (2004)</ref>, who de- scribed a hidden Markov model (HMM) for doc- ument content where each state corresponds to a distinct topic and generates sentences relevant to that topic according to a language model. We estimate an HMM-like model on our corpus, ex- ploiting similarity across privacy policies to the extent it is evident in the data. In our formula- tion, each hidden state corresponds to an issue or topic, characterized by a distribution over words and bigrams appearing in privacy policy sections addressing that issue. The transition distribution captures tendencies of privacy policy authors to organize these sections in similar orders, though with some variation.</p><p>The generative story for our model is as follows. Let S denote the set of hidden states. 1. Choose a start state y 1 from S according to the start-state distribution. 2. For t = 1, 2, . . ., until y t is the stopping state:</p><p>(a) Sample the tth section of the document by drawing a bag of terms, o t , according to the emission multinomial distribution for state y t . Note the difference from traditional HMMs, in which a single observation symbol is drawn at each time step. o t is generated by repeat- edly sampling from a distribution over terms that includes all unigrams and bigrams except those that occur in fewer than 5% of the doc- uments and in more than 98% of the docu- ments. This filtering rule was designed to eliminate uninformative stopwords as well as company-specific terms (e.g., the name of the company). <ref type="bibr">4</ref> Websites with Unique privacy Unique privacy Ave. sections  (b) Sample the next state, y t+1 , according to the transition distribution over S. This model can nearly be understood as a hid- den semi-Markov model ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Baum and Petrie, 1966)</ref>, though we treat the section lengths as observable. Indeed, our model does not even generate these lengths, since doing so would force the states to "explain" the length of each section, not just its content. The likelihood function for the model is shown in <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref>.</p><p>The parameters of the model are almost iden- tical to those of a classic HMM (start state dis- tribution, emission distributions, and transition distributions), except that emissions are char- acterized by multinomial rather than a cate- gorical distributions.</p><p>These are learned us- ing Expectation-Maximization, with a forward- backward algorithm to calculate marginals (E- step) and smoothed maximum likelihood estima- tion for the M-step <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(Rabiner, 1989)</ref>. After learn- ing, the most probable assignment of a policy's sections to states can be recovered using a variant of the Viterbi algorithm.</p><p>We consider three HMM variants. "Vanilla" al- lows all transitions. The other two posit an order- ing on the states S = {s 1 , s 2 , . . . , s K }, and re- strict the set of transitions that are possible, impos- ing bias on the learner. "All Forward" only allows models (e.g., a bigram may be generated by as many as three draws from the emission distribution: once for each unigram it contains and once for the bigram). s k to transition to {s k , s k+1 , . . . , s K }. "Strict For- ward" only allows s k to transition to s k or s k+1 .</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Evaluation</head><p>Developing a gold-standard alignment of privacy policies would either require an interface that al- lows each annotator to interact with the entire cor- pus of previously aligned documents while read- ing the one she is annotating, or the definition (and likely iterative refinement) of a set of categories for manually labeling policy sections. These were too costly for us to consider, so we instead pro- pose two generic methods to evaluate models for sequence alignment of a collection of docu- ments with generally similar content. Though our model (particularly the restricted variants) treats the problem as one of alignment, our evaluations consider groupings of policy sections. In the se- quel, a grouping on a set X is defined as a collec- tion of subsets X i ⊆ X; these may overlap (i.e., there might be x ∈ X i ∩ X j ) and need not be ex- haustive (i.e., there might be x ∈ X \ i X i ).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">Evaluation by Human QA</head><p>This study was carried out as part of a larger col- laboration with legal scholars who study privacy.</p><p>In that work, we have formulated a set of nine mul- tiple choice questions about a single policy that ask about collection of contact, location, health, and financial information, sharing of each with</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">P π,η,γ (y t , o t n t=1 | t n t=1 ) = π(y 1 ) n t=1 t i=1 η(o t,i | y i )</formula><p>γ(y t+1 | y t ) <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref>: The likelihood function for the alignment model (one privacy policy). yt is the hidden state for the tth section, ot is the bag of unigram and bigram terms observed in that section, and t is the size of the bag. Start-state, emission, and transition distributions are denoted respectively by π, η, and γ. yn+1 is the silent stopping state.</p><p>third parties, and deletion of data. <ref type="bibr">5</ref> The questions were inspired primarily by the substantive interest of these domain experts-not by this particular al- gorithmic study.</p><p>For thirty policies, we obtained answers from each of six domain experts who were not involved in designing the questions. For the purposes of this study, the experts' answers are not important. In addition to answering each question for each pol- icy, we also asked each expert to copy and paste the text of the policy that contains the answer. Experts were allowed to select as many sections for each question as they saw fit, since answering some questions may require synthesizing informa- tion from different sections.</p><p>For each of the nine questions, we take the union of all policy sections that contain text se- lected by any annotator as support for her answer. This results in nine groups of policy sections, which we call answer-sets denoted A 1 , . . . , A 9 . Our method allows these to overlap (63% of the sections in any A i occurred in more than one A i ), and they are not exhaustive (since many sections of the policies were not deemed to contain answers to any of the nine questions by any expert).</p><p>Together, these can be used as a gold standard grouping of policy sections, against which we can compare our system's output. To do this, we define the set of section pairs that are grouped together in answer sets, G = |{{a, b | ∃A i a, b}|, and a similar set of pairs H from a model's grouping. From these sets, we calculate estimates of preci- sion (|G ∩ H|/|H|) and recall (|G ∩ H|/|G|).</p><p>One shortcoming of this approach, for which the second evaluation seeks to compensate, is that a very small, and likely biased, subset of the policy sections is considered.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">Evaluation by Direct Judgment</head><p>We created a separate gold standard of judgments of pairs of privacy policy sections. The data se- lected for judgment was a sample of pairs stratified by a simple measure of text similarity. We derived unigram tfidf vectors for each section in each of 50 randomly sampled policies per category. We then binned pairs of sections by cosine similarity (into four bins bounded by 0.25, 0.5, and 0.75). We sampled 994 section pairs uniformly across the 15 categories' four bins each.</p><p>Crowdsourcing was used to determine, for each pair, whether the two sections should be grouped together. A HIT consisted of a pair of policy sec- tions and a multiple choice question, "After read- ing the two sections given below, would you say that they broadly discuss the same topic?" The possible answers were: 1. Yes, both the sections essentially convey the same message in a privacy policy. 2. Although, the sections do not convey the same message, the broadly discuss the same topic.</p><p>(For ease of understanding, some examples of content on "the same topic" were included.) 3. No, the sections discuss two different topics. The first two options were considered a "yes" for the majority voting and for defining a gold stan- dard. Every section-pair was annotated by at least three annotators (as many as 15, increased until an absolute majority was reached). Turkers with an acceptance rate greater than 95% with an ex- perience of at least 100 HITs were allowed and paid $0.03 per annotation. The total cost includ- ing some initial trials was $130. 535 out of the 994 pairs were annotated to be similar in topic. An example is shown in <ref type="figure">Figure 2</ref>.</p><p>As in §4.1, we calculate precision and recall on pairs. This does not penalize the model for group- ing together a "no" pair; we chose it nonetheless because it is interpretable.</p><p>Section 5 of classmates.com: [46 words] . . . You may also be required to use a password to access certain pages on the Services where certain types of your personal information can be changed or deleted. . . . [113 words] Section 2 of 192.com: [50 words] . . . This Policy sets out the means by which You can have Your Personal Information removed from the Service. 192.com is also committed to keeping Personal Information of users of the Service secure and only to use it for the purposes set out in this Policy and as agreed by You. . . . [24 words] <ref type="figure">Figure 2</ref>: Selections from sections that discuss the issue of "deletion of personal information" and were labeled as discussing the same issue by crowdworkers. Both na¨ıvena¨ıve grouping and LDA put them in two different groups, but the Strict Forward variant of our model correctly groups them together.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Precision</head><p>Recall  Baselines. Our first baseline is a greedy divisive clustering algorithm 6 to partition the policy sec- tions into ten clusters. In this method, the de- sired K-way clustering solution is computed by performing a sequence of bisections. The imple- mentation uses unigram features and cosine simi- larity. Our second baseline is latent Dirichlet allo- cation (LDA; <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Blei et al., 2003)</ref>, with ten topics and online variational Bayes for inference <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(Hoffman et al., 2010)</ref>. <ref type="bibr">7</ref> To more closely match our models, LDA is given access to the same unigram and bi- gram tokens.</p><p>Results. <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">Table 3</ref> shows the results. For LDA and the HMM variants (which use random initial- ization), we report mean and standard deviation across ten independent runs. All three variants of the HMM improve over the baselines on both tasks, in terms of F 1 . In the human QA evalu- ation, this is mostly due to recall improvements (i.e., more pairs of sections relevant to the same policy question were grouped together). The three variants of the model performed sim- ilarly on average, though Strict Forward had very high variance. Its maximum performance across <ref type="bibr">6</ref> As implemented in CLUTO, http://glaros.dtc. umn.edu/gkhome/cluto/cluto/overview <ref type="bibr">7</ref> As implemented in gensim <ref type="bibr">( ˇ Rehůřek and Sojka, 2010).</ref> ten runs was very high (67% and 53% F 1 on the two tasks), suggesting the potential benefits of good initialization or model selection.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Conclusion</head><p>We considered the task of aligning sections of a collection of roughly similarly-structured legal documents, based on the issues they address. We introduced an unsupervised model for this task along with two new (and reusable) evaluations. Our experiments show the approach to be more ef- fective than clustering and topic models. The cor- pus and evaluation data have been made available at http://usableprivacy.org/data . In future work, policy section alignments will be used in automated analysis to extract useful infor- mation for users and privacy scholars.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" validated="false"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>These policies were collected during a period of six weeks during December 2013 and January 2014. They are a snapshot of privacy policies of mainstream websites covering fifteen</figDesc><table>Business Computers 

Games 
Health 
Home 
News 
Recreation Shopping 
Arts 
Kids and Teens Reference Regional 
Science 
Society 
Sports 

Table 1: Fifteen website categories provided by Alexa.com. 
We collect privacy policies from the top 100 websites in each. 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" validated="false"><head>Table 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Statistics of each website category, including (i) the number of websites with an identified privacy policy link; (ii) 
number of unique privacy policies in each category (note that in rare cases, multiple unique privacy policies were identified 
for the same website, e.g., a website that contains links to both new and old versions of its privacy policy); (iii) number of 
websites with an identified privacy modification date; (iv) average number of sections per policy; (v) average number of tokens 
per policy. 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4" validated="false"><head>Table 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Evaluation by human QA (above) and direct judg-
ment (below), aggregated across ten independent runs where 
appropriate (see text). Vanilla, All F(orward), and Strict 
F(orward) are three variants of our HMM. 

</table></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> Personal communication, Joel Reidenberg. 2 http://www.alexa.com</note>

			<note place="foot" n="3"> The &quot;Adult&quot; category was excluded; the &quot;World&quot; category was excluded since it contains mainly popular websites in different languages, and we opted to focus on policies in English in this first stage of research, though mulitlingual policy analysis presents interesting challenges for future work.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="4"> The emission distributions are not a proper language</note>

			<note place="foot" n="5"> The questions are available in an online appendix at http://usableprivacy.org/data.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="5"> Experiment In this section, we evaluate the three HMM variants described in §3, and two baselines, using the methods in §4. All of the methods require the specification of the number of groups or hidden states, which we fix to ten, the average number of sections per policy.</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>The authors gratefully acknowledge helpful com-ments from Lorrie Cranor, Joel Reidenberg, Flo-rian Schaub, and several anonymous reviewers. This research was supported by NSF grant SaTC-1330596.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Automatic categorization of privacy policies: A pilot study</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Waleed</forename><surname>Ammar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Shomir</forename><surname>Wilson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Norman</forename><surname>Sadeh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Noah</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Smith</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>CMU-LTI-12-019</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>Carnegie Mellon University</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
<note type="report_type">Technical Report</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Catching the drift: Probabilistic content models, with applications to generation and summarization</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Regina</forename><surname>Barzilay</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lillian</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of HLTNAACL</title>
		<meeting>of HLTNAACL</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Statistical inference for probabilistic functions of finite state Markov chains</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Leonard</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Baum</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ted</forename><surname>Petrie</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Annals of Mathematical Statistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">37</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1554" to="1563" />
			<date type="published" when="1966" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>David</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Blei</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Andrew</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michael I Jordan</forename><surname>Ng</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Latent Dirichlet allocation. the Journal of machine Learning research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="993" to="1022" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">An empirical study of natural language parsing of privacy policy rules using the SPARCLE policy workbench</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Carolyn</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Brodie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Clare-Marie</forename><surname>Karat</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">John</forename><surname>Karat</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of the Symposium on Usable Privacy and Security</title>
		<meeting>of the Symposium on Usable Privacy and Security</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A machine learning solution to assess privacy policy completeness</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Elisa</forename><surname>Costante</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yuanhao</forename><surname>Sun</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Milan</forename><surname>Petkovi´cpetkovi´c</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jerry</forename><surname>Hartog</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of the ACM Workshop on Privacy in the Electronic Society</title>
		<meeting>of the ACM Workshop on Privacy in the Electronic Society</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">What websites know about you</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Elisa</forename><surname>Costante</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jerry</forename><surname>Hartog</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Milan</forename><surname>Petkovi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Data Privacy Management and Autonomous Spontaneous Security</title>
		<editor>Roberto Pietro, Javier Herranz, Ernesto Damiani, and Radu State</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">7731</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="146" to="159" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Heidelberg</forename><surname>Springer Berlin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Richard</forename><surname>Durbin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sean</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Eddy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Anders</forename><surname>Krogh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Graeme</forename><surname>Mitchison</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Biological Sequence Analysis: Probabilistic Models of Proteins and Nucleic Acids</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Cambridge University Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Protecting consumer privacy in an era of rapid change: Recommendations for businesses and policymakers</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Federal Trade Commission</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Fair information practices: a basic history (v. 2.11)</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Robert</forename><surname>Gellman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://www.bobgellman.com/rg-docs/rg-FIPShistory.pdf" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Available at</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Online learning for latent Dirichlet allocation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Matthew D Hoffman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Francis R</forename><surname>Blei</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Bach</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">NIPS</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The cost of reading privacy policies. I/S: A</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Aleecia</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Mcdonald</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lorrie</forename><forename type="middle">Faith</forename><surname>Cranor</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Law and Policy for the Information Society</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A tutorial on hidden Markov models and selected applications in speech recognition</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lawrence</forename><surname>Rabiner</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the IEEE</title>
		<meeting>the IEEE</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1989" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">77</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="257" to="286" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Software framework for topic modelling with large corpora</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Petr</forename><surname>Radimřehůřekradimˇradimřehůřek</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Sojka</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of the LREC Workshop on New Challenges for NLP Frameworks</title>
		<meeting>of the LREC Workshop on New Challenges for NLP Frameworks</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Automated extraction of security policies from natural-language software documents</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xusheng</forename><surname>Xiao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Amit</forename><surname>Paradkar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Suresh</forename><surname>Thummalapenta</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tao</forename><surname>Xie</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of the ACM SIGSOFT International Symposium on the Foundations of Software Engineering</title>
		<meeting>of the ACM SIGSOFT International Symposium on the Foundations of Software Engineering</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Machine learning for privacy policy</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sebastian</forename><surname>Zimmeck</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Steven</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Bellovin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
