<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T10:12+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Learning to Automatically Solve Algebra Word Problems</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
				<availability status="unknown"><p>Copyright Association for Computational Linguistics</p>
				</availability>
				<date>June 23-25 2014. 2014</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nate</forename><surname>Kushman</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Computer Science &amp; Engineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">Articial Intelligence Laboratory</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Massachusetts Institute of Technology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">University of Washington</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yoav</forename><surname>Artzi</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Computer Science &amp; Engineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">Articial Intelligence Laboratory</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Massachusetts Institute of Technology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">University of Washington</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Luke</forename><surname>Zettlemoyer</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Computer Science &amp; Engineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">Articial Intelligence Laboratory</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Massachusetts Institute of Technology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">University of Washington</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Regina</forename><surname>Barzilay</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Computer Science &amp; Engineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">Articial Intelligence Laboratory</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Massachusetts Institute of Technology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">University of Washington</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Learning to Automatically Solve Algebra Word Problems</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 52nd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
						<meeting>the 52nd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics <address><addrLine>Baltimore, Maryland, USA</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="271" to="281"/>
							<date type="published">June 23-25 2014. 2014</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>We present an approach for automatically learning to solve algebra word problems. Our algorithm reasons across sentence boundaries to construct and solve a system of linear equations, while simultaneously recovering an alignment of the variables and numbers in these equations to the problem text. The learning algorithm uses varied supervision, including either full equations or just the final answers. We evaluate performance on a newly gathered corpus of algebra word problems, demonstrating that the system can correctly answer almost 70% of the questions in the dataset. This is, to our knowledge, the first learning result for this task.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Algebra word problems concisely describe a world state and pose questions about it. The described state can be modeled with a system of equations whose solution specifies the questions' answers. For example, <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref> shows one such problem. The reader is asked to infer how many children and adults were admitted to an amusement park, based on constraints provided by ticket prices and overall sales. This paper studies the task of learning to automatically solve such problems given only the natural language. <ref type="bibr">1</ref> Solving these problems requires reasoning across sentence boundaries to find a system of equations that concisely models the described se- mantic relationships. For example, in <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref>, the total ticket revenue computation in the second equation summarizes facts about ticket prices and total sales described in the second, third, and fifth <ref type="bibr">1</ref> The code and data for this work are available at http://groups.csail.mit.edu/rbg/code/ wordprobs/.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Word problem</head><p>An amusement park sells 2 kinds of tickets. Tickets for children cost $1.50. Adult tickets cost $4. On a certain day, 278 people entered the park. On that same day the admission fees collected totaled $792. How many children were admitted on that day? How many adults were admitted? Figure 1: An example algebra word problem. Our goal is to map a given problem to a set of equations representing its algebraic meaning, which are then solved to get the problem's answer.</p><p>sentences. Furthermore, the first equation models an implicit semantic relationship, namely that the children and adults admitted are non-intersecting subsets of the set of people who entered the park. Our model defines a joint log-linear distribu- tion over full systems of equations and alignments between these equations and the text. The space of possible equations is defined by a set of equa- tion templates, which we induce from the train- ing examples, where each template has a set of slots. Number slots are filled by numbers from the text, and unknown slots are aligned to nouns. For example, the system in <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref> is gener- ated by filling one such template with four spe- cific numbers (1.5, 4, 278, and 792) and align- ing two nouns ("Tickets" in "Tickets for children", and "tickets" in "Adult tickets"). These inferred correspondences are used to define cross-sentence features that provide global cues to the model. For instance, in our running example, the string pairs ("$1.50", "children") and ("$4","adults") both surround the word "cost," suggesting an out- put equation with a sum of two constant-variable products.</p><p>We consider learning with two different levels of supervision. In the first scenario, we assume ac- cess to each problem's numeric solution (see <ref type="figure">Fig- ure 1)</ref> for most of the data, along with a small set of seed examples labeled with full equations. During learning, a solver evaluates competing hy- potheses to drive the learning process. In the sec- ond scenario, we are provided with a full system of equations for each problem. In both cases, the available labeled equations (either the seed set, or the full set) are abstracted to provide the model's equation templates, while the slot filling and align- ment decisions are latent variables whose settings are estimated by directly optimizing the marginal data log-likelihood.</p><p>The approach is evaluated on a new corpus of 514 algebra word problems and associated equa- tion systems gathered from Algebra.com. Pro- vided with full equations during training, our al- gorithm successfully solves over 69% of the word problems from our test set. Furthermore, we find the algorithm can robustly handle weak supervi- sion, achieving more than 70% of the above per- formance when trained exclusively on answers.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Related Work</head><p>Our work is related to three main areas of research: situated semantic interpretation, information ex- traction, and automatic word problem solvers.</p><p>Situated Semantic Interpretation There is a large body of research on learning to map nat- ural language to formal meaning representations, given varied forms of supervision. Reinforcement learning can be used to learn to read instructions and perform actions in an external world <ref type="bibr">(Branavan et al., 2009;</ref><ref type="bibr">Branavan et al., 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr">Vogel and Jurafsky, 2010)</ref>. Other approaches have re- lied on access to more costly annotated logical forms ( <ref type="bibr">Zelle and Mooney, 1996;</ref><ref type="bibr">Thompson and Mooney, 2003;</ref><ref type="bibr">Wong and Mooney, 2006;</ref><ref type="bibr">Zettlemoyer and Collins, 2005;</ref><ref type="bibr">Kwiatkowski et al., 2010)</ref>. These techniques have been generalized more recently to learn from sentences paired with indirect feedback from a controlled application. Examples include question answering <ref type="bibr">(Clarke et al., 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr">Cai and Yates, 2013a;</ref><ref type="bibr">Cai and Yates, 2013b;</ref><ref type="bibr">Berant et al., 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr">Kwiatkowski et al., 2013)</ref>, dialog systems ( <ref type="bibr">Artzi and Zettlemoyer, 2011)</ref>, robot instruction ( <ref type="bibr">Chen and Mooney, 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr">Chen, 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr">Kim and Mooney, 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr">Matuszek et al., 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr">Artzi and Zettlemoyer, 2013)</ref>, and pro- gram executions <ref type="bibr">(Kushman and Barzilay, 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr">Lei et al., 2013)</ref>. We focus on learning from varied supervision, including question answers and equa- tion systems, both can be obtained reliably from annotators with no linguistic training and only ba- sic math knowledge.</p><p>Nearly all of the above work processed sin- gle sentences in isolation. Techniques that con- sider multiple sentences typically do so in a se- rial fashion, processing each in turn with limited cross-sentence reasoning <ref type="bibr">(Branavan et al., 2009;</ref><ref type="bibr">Zettlemoyer and Collins, 2009;</ref><ref type="bibr">Chen and Mooney, 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr">Artzi and Zettlemoyer, 2013)</ref>. We focus on analyzing multiple sentences simultaneously, as is necessary to generate the global semantic rep- resentations common in domains such as algebra word problems.</p><p>Information Extraction Our approach is related to work on template-based information extraction, where the goal is to identify instances of event templates in text and extract their slot fillers. Most work has focused on the supervised case, where the templates are manually defined and data is la- beled with alignment information, e.g. ( <ref type="bibr">Grishman et al., 2005;</ref><ref type="bibr">Maslennikov and Chua, 2007;</ref><ref type="bibr">Ji and Grishman, 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr">Reichart and Barzilay, 2012)</ref>. However, some recent work has studied the au- tomatic induction of the set of possible templates from data ( <ref type="bibr">Chambers and Jurafsky, 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr">Ritter et al., 2012</ref>). In our approach, systems of equations are relatively easy to specify, providing a type of template structure, and the alignment of the slots in these templates to the text is modeled primar- ily with latent variables during learning. Addition- ally, mapping to a semantic representation that can be executed allows us to leverage weaker supervi- sion during learning.</p><p>Automatic Word Problem Solvers Finally, there has been research on automatically solving vari- ous types of mathematical word problems. The dominant existing approach is to hand engineer rule-based systems to solve math problem in spe- cific domains <ref type="bibr">(Mukherjee and Garain, 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr">Lev et al., 2004</ref>). Our focus is on learning a model for the end-to-end task of solving word problems given only a training corpus of questions paired with equations or answers.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Derivation 1</head><p>Word problem An amusement park sells 2 kinds of tickets. Tickets for children cost $ 1.50 . Adult tickets cost $ 4 . On a certain day, 278 people entered the park. On that same day the admission fees collected totaled $ 792 . How many children were admitted on that day? How many adults were admitted? </p><formula xml:id="formula_0">Aligned template u 1 1 + u 1 2 − n 1 = 0 n 2 × u 2 1 + n 3 × u 2</formula><formula xml:id="formula_1">n 1 × u 1 1 + n 2 × u 1 2 − n 3 = 0 n 4 × u 2 1 + n 5 × u 2 2 − n 6 = 0 Instantiated equations 2x + 3y − 252 = 0 4x + 1y − 244 = 0 Answer x = 48 y = 52</formula><p>Figure 2: Two complete derivations for two different word problems. Derivation 1 shows an alignment where two instances of the same slot are aligned to the same word (e.g., u 1 1 and u 2 1 both are aligned to "Tickets"). Derivation 2 includes an alignment where four identical nouns are each aligned to different slot instances in the template (e.g., the first "speed" in the problem is aligned to u 1 1 ).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Mapping Word Problems to Equations</head><p>We define a two step process to map word prob- lems to equations. First, a template is selected to define the overall structure of the equation sys- tem. Next, the template is instantiated with num- bers and nouns from the text. During inference we consider these two steps jointly. <ref type="figure">Figure 2</ref> shows both steps for two derivations. The template dictates the form of the equations in the system and the type of slots in each: u slots represent unknowns and n slots are for numbers that must be filled from the text. In Derivation 1, the selected template has two unknown slots, u 1 and u 2 , and four number slots, n 1 to n 4 . Slots can be shared between equations, for example, the unknown slots u 1 and u 2 in the example appear in both equations. A slot may have different in- stances, for example u 1 1 and u 2 1 are the two in- stances of u 1 in the example.</p><p>We align each slot instance to a word in the problem. Each number slot n is aligned to a num- ber, and each unknown slot u is aligned to a noun. For example, Derivation 1 aligns the number 278 to n 1 , 1.50 to n 2 , 4 to n 3 , and 792 to n 4 . It also aligns both instances of u 1 (e.g., u 1 1 and u 2 1 ) to "Tickets", and both instances of u 2 to "tickets". In contrast, in Derivation 2, instances of the same unknown slot (e.g. u 1</p><p>1 and u 2 1 ) are aligned to two different words in the problem (different occur- rences of the word "speed"). This allows for a tighter mapping between the natural language and the system template, where the words aligned to the first equation in the template come from the first two sentences, and the words aligned to the second equation come from the third.</p><p>Given an alignment, the template can then be instantiated: each number slot n is replaced with the aligned number, and each unknown slot u with a variable. This output system of equations is then automatically solved to generate the final answer.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Derivations</head><p>Definitions Let X be the set of all word problems. A word problem x ∈ X is a sequence of k words w 1 , . . . w k . Also, define an equation template t to be a formula A = B, where A and B are expres- sions. An expression A is one of the following:</p><p>• A number constant f .</p><p>• A number slot n.</p><p>• An unknown slot u.</p><p>• An application of a mathematical relation R to two expressions (e.g., n 1 × u 1 ).</p><p>We define a system template T to be a set of l equation templates {t 0 , . . . , t l }. T is the set of all system templates. A slot may occur more than once in a system template, to allow variables to be reused in different equations. We denote a spe- cific instance i of a slot, u for example, as u i . For brevity, we omit the instance index when a slot ap- pears only once. To capture a correspondence be- tween the text of x and a template T , we define an alignment p to be a set of pairs (w, s), where w is a token in x and s is a slot instance in T . Given the above definitions, an equation e can be constructed from a template t where each num- ber slot n is replaced with a real number, each un- known slot u is replaced with a variable, and each number constant f is kept as is. We call the pro- cess of turning a template into an equation tem- plate instantiation. Similarly, an equation system E is a set of l equations {e 0 , . . . , e l }, which can be constructed by instantiating each of the equa- tion templates in a system template T . Finally, an answer a is a tuple of real numbers.</p><p>We define a derivation y from a word problem to an answer as a tuple (T, p, a), where T is the se- lected system template, p is an alignment between T and x, and a is the answer generated by instan- tiating T using x through p and solving the gener- ated equations. Let Y be the set of all derivations.</p><p>The Space of Possible Derivations We aim to map each word problem x to an equation system E. The space of equation systems considered is defined by the set of possible system templates T and the words in the original problem x, that are available for filling slots. In practice, we gener- ate T from the training data, as described in Sec- tion 4.1. Given a system template T ∈ T , we create an alignment p between T and x. The set of possible alignment pairs is constrained as fol- An amusement park sells 2 kinds of tickets. Tickets for children cost $ 1.50 . Adult tick- ets cost $ 4 . On a certain day, 278 people entered the park. On that same day the ad- mission fees collected totaled $ 792 . How many children were admitted on that day? How many adults were admitted?</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">u 1 1 + u 1 2 − n 1 = 0 n 2 × u 2 1 + n 3 × u 2 2 − n 4 = 0 Figure 3:</formula><p>The first example problem and selected system template from <ref type="figure">Figure 2</ref> with all potential aligned words marked. Nouns (boldfaced) may be aligned to unknown slot instances u j i , and num- ber words (highlighted) may be aligned to number slots n i .</p><p>lows: each number slot n ∈ T can be aligned to any number in the text, a number word can only be aligned to a single slot n, and must be aligned to all instances of that slot. Additionally, an un- known slot instance u ∈ T can only be aligned to a noun word. A complete derivation's alignment pairs all slots in T with words in x. <ref type="figure">Figure 3</ref> illustrates the space of possible align- ments for the first problem and system template from <ref type="figure">Figure 2</ref>. Nouns (shown in boldface) can be aligned to any of the unknown slot instances in the selected template (u 1 1 , u 2 1 , u 1 2 , and u 2 2 for the template selected). Numbers (highlighted) can be aligned to any of the number slots (n 1 , n 2 , n 3 , and n 4 in the template).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Probabilistic Model</head><p>Due to the ambiguity in selecting the system tem- plate and alignment, there will be many possible derivations y ∈ Y for each word problem x ∈ X . We discriminate between competing analyses us- ing a log-linear model, which has a feature func- tion φ : X × Y → R d and a parameter vector θ ∈ R d . The probability of a derivation y given a problem x is defined as:</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">p(y|x; θ) = e θ·φ(x,y)</formula><p>y ∈Y e θ·φ(x,y ) Section 6 defines the full set of features used.</p><p>The inference problem at test time requires us to find the most likely answer a given a problem x, assuming the parameters θ are known:</p><formula xml:id="formula_4">f (x) = arg max a p(a|x; θ)</formula><p>Here, the probability of the answer is marginalized over template selection and alignment:</p><formula xml:id="formula_5">p(a|x; θ) = y∈Y s.t. AN(y)=a p(y|x; θ)<label>(1)</label></formula><p>where AN(y) extracts the answer a out of deriva- tion y. In this way, the distribution over deriva- tions y is modeled as a latent variable. We use a beam search inference procedure to approximately compute Equation 1, as described in Section 5.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Learning</head><p>To learn our model, we need to induce the struc- ture of system templates in T and estimate the model parameters θ.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">Template Induction</head><p>It is possible to generate system templates T when provided access to a set of n training examples {(x i , E i ) : i = 1, . . . , n}, where x i is a word problem and E i is a set of equations. We general- ize each E to a system template T by (a) replacing each variable with an unknown slot, and (b) re- placing each number mentioned in the text with a number slot. Numbers not mentioned in the prob- lem text remain in the template as constants. This allows us to solve problems that require numbers that are implied by the problem semantics rather than appearing directly in the text, such as the per- cent problem in <ref type="figure">Figure 4</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">Parameter Estimation</head><p>For parameter estimation, we assume access to n training examples {(x i , V i ) : i = 1, . . . , n}, each containing a word problem x i and a val- idation function V i . The validation function V : Y → {0, 1} maps a derivation y ∈ Y to 1 if it is correct, or 0 otherwise. We can vary the validation function to learn from different types of supervision. In Sec- tion 8, we will use validation functions that check whether the derivation y has either (1) the cor- rect system of equations E, or (2) the correct an- swer a. Also, using different types of validation functions on different subsets of the data enables semi-supervised learning. This approach is related to <ref type="bibr">Artzi and Zettlemoyer (2013)</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Word problem</head><p>A chemist has a solution that is 18 % alco- hol and one that is 50 % alcohol. He wants to make 80 liters of a 30 % solution. How many liters of the 18 % solution should he add? How many liters of the 30 % solution should he add?</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Labeled equations</head><p>18 × 0.01 × x + 50 × 0.01 × y = 30 × 0.01 × 80</p><p>x + y = 80</p><p>Induced template system</p><formula xml:id="formula_6">n1 × 0.01 × u 1 1 + n2 × 0.01 × u 1 2 = n3 × 0.01 × n4 u 2 1 + u 2 2 = n5</formula><p>Figure 4: During template induction, we automat- ically detect the numbers in the problem (high- lighted above) to generalize the labeled equations to templates. Numbers not present in the text are considered part of the induced template.</p><p>We estimate θ by maximizing the conditional log-likelihood of the data, marginalizing over all valid derivations:</p><formula xml:id="formula_7">O = i y∈Y s.t. V i (y)=1 log p(y|x i ; θ)</formula><p>We use L-BFGS ( <ref type="bibr">Nocedal and Wright, 2006</ref>) to optimize the parameters. The gradient of the indi- vidual parameter θ j is given by:</p><formula xml:id="formula_8">∂O ∂θ j = i E p(y|x i ,V i (y)=1;θ) [φ j (x i , y)] − E p(y|x i ;θ) [φ j (x i , y)]<label>(2)</label></formula><p>Section 5 describes how we approximate the two terms of the gradient using beam search.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Inference</head><p>Computing the normalization constant for Equa- tion 1 requires summing over all templates and all possible ways to instantiate them. This results in a search space exponential in the number of slots in the largest template in T , the set of available system templates. Therefore, we approximate this computation using beam search. We initialize the beam with all templates in T and iteratively align slots from the templates in the beam to words in the problem text. For each template, the next slot to be considered is selected according to a pre- defined canonicalized ordering for that template. After each iteration we prune the beam to keep the top-k partial derivations according to the model score. When pruning the beam, we allow at most l partial derivations for each template, to ensure that a small number of templates don't monopolize the beam. We continue this process until all templates in the beam are fully instantiated.</p><p>During learning we compute the second term in the gradient (Equation 2) using our beam search approximation. Depending on the available vali- dation function V (as defined in Section 4.2), we can also accurately prune the beam for the com- putation of the first half of the gradient. Specifi- cally, when assuming access to labeled equations, we can constrain the search to consider only par- tial hypotheses that could possibly be completed to produce the labeled equations.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Model Details</head><p>Template Canonicalization There are many syn- tactically different but semantically equivalent ways to express a given system of equations. For example, the phrase "John is 3 years older than Bill" can be written as j = b + 3 or j − 3 = b. To avoid such ambiguity, we canonicalize tem- plates into a normal form representation. We per- form this canonicalization by obtaining the sym- bolic solution for the unknown slots in terms of the number slots and constants using the mathe- matical solver Maxima <ref type="bibr">(Maxima, 2014)</ref>.</p><p>Slot Signature In a template like s 1 +s 2 = s 3 , the slot s 1 is distinct from the slot s 2 , but we would like them to share many of the features used in de- ciding their alignment. To facilitate this, we gener- ate signatures for each slot and slot pair. The sig- nature for a slot indicates the system of equations it appears in, the specific equation it is in, and the terms of the equation it is a part of. Pairwise slot signatures concatenate the signatures for the two slots as well as indicating which terms are shared. This allows, for example, n 2 and n 3 in Derivation 1 in <ref type="figure">Figure 2</ref> to have the same signature, while the pairs n 2 , u 1 and n 3 , u 1 have different ones. To share features across templates, slot and slot-pair signatures are generated for both the full template, as well as for each of the constituent equations.</p><p>Features The features φ(x, y) are computed for a derivation y and problem x and cover all deriva- tion decisions, including template and alignment selection. When required, we use standard tools to generate part-of-speech tags, lematizations, and dependency parses to compute features. <ref type="bibr">2</ref> For each number word in y we also identify the closest noun in the dependency parse. For example, the noun for 278 in Derivation 1, <ref type="figure">Figure 2</ref> would be "peo- ple." The features are calculated based on these nouns, rather than the number words. We use four types of features: document level features, features that look at a single slot entry, features that look at pairs of slot entries, and fea- tures that look at the numeric solutions. <ref type="table">Table 1</ref> lists all the features used. Unless otherwise noted, when computing slot and slot pair features, a sep- arate feature is generated for each of the signature types discussed earlier.</p><p>Document level features Oftentimes the natural language in x will contain words or phrases which are indicative of a certain template, but are not as- sociated with any of the words aligned to slots in the template. For example, the word "chemist" might indicate a template like the one seen in <ref type="figure">Fig- ure 4</ref>. We include features that connect each tem- plate with the unigrams and bigrams in the word problem. We also include an indicator feature for each system template, providing a bias for its use.</p><p>Single Slot Features The natural language x al- ways contains one or more questions or commands indicating the queried quantities. For example, the first problem in <ref type="figure">Figure 2</ref> asks "How many children were admitted on that day?" The queried quanti- ties, the number of children in this case, must be represented by an unknown in the system of equa- tions. We generate a set of features which look at both the word overlap and the noun phrase overlap between slot words and the objects of a question or command sentence. We also compute a feature in- dicating whether a slot is filled from a word in a question sentence. Additionally, algebra problems frequently use phrases such as "2 kinds of tickets" (e.g., <ref type="figure">Figure 2</ref>). These numbers do not typically appear in the equations. To account for this, we add a single feature indicating whether a number is one or two. Lastly, many templates contain con- stants which are identifiable from words used in nearby slots. For example, in <ref type="figure">Figure 4</ref> the con- stant 0.01 is related to the use of "%" in the text. To capture such usage, we include a set of lexical- ized features which concatenate the word lemma with nearby constants in the equation. These fea- tures do not include the slot signature.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Slot Pair Features</head><p>The majority of features we compute account for relationships between slot words. This includes features that trigger for various equivalence relations between the words themselves, as well as features of the dependency path between them. We also include features that look at the numerical relationship of two num- bers, where the numeric values of the unknowns are generated by solving the system of equations. This helps recognize that, for example, the total of a sum is typically larger than each of the (typically positive) summands.</p><p>Additionally, we also have a single feature look- ing at shared relationships between pairs of slots. For example, in <ref type="figure">Figure 2</ref> the relationship between "tickets for children" and "$1.50" is "cost". Sim- ilarly the relationship between "Adult tickets" and "$4" is also "cost". Since the actual nature of this relationship is not important, this feature is not lexicalized, instead it is only triggered for the pres- ence of equality. We consider two cases: subject- object relationships where the intervening verb is equal, and noun-to-preposition object relation- ships where the intervening preposition is equal.</p><note type="other"># problems 514 # sentences 1616 # words 19357 Vocabulary size 2352 Mean words per problem 37 Mean sentences per problem 3.1 Mean nouns per problem 13.4 # unique equation systems 28 Mean slots per system 7 Mean derivations per problem 4M</note><p>Solution Features By grounding our semantics in math, we are able to include features which look at the final answer, a, to learn which answers are reasonable for the algebra problems we typically see. For example, the solution to many, but not all, of the problems involves the size of some set of objects which must be both positive and integer.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7">Experimental Setup</head><p>Dataset We collected a new dataset of alge- bra word problems from Algebra.com, a crowd- sourced tutoring website. The questions were posted by students for members of the community to respond with solutions. Therefore, the problems are highly varied, and are taken from real prob- lems given to students. We heuristically filtered the data to get only linear algebra questions which did not require any explicit background knowl- edge. From these we randomly chose a set of 1024 questions. As the questions are posted to a web forum, the posts often contained additional comments which were not part of the word prob- lems and the solutions are embedded in long free- form natural language descriptions. To clean the data we asked Amazon Mechanical Turk workers to extract from the text: the algebra word prob- lem itself, the solution equations, and the numeric answer. We manually verified both the equations and the numbers to ensure they were correct. To ensure each problem type is seen at least a few times in the training data, we removed the infre- quent problem types. Specifically, we induced the system template from each equation system, as de- scribed in Section 4.1, and removed all problems for which the associated system template appeared less than 6 times in the dataset. This left us with 514 problems. <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Table 2</ref> provides the data statistics.</p><p>Forms of Supervision We consider both semi- supervised and supervised learning. In the semi- supervised scenario, we assume access to the nu- merical answers of all problems in the training cor- pus and to a small number of problems paired with full equation systems. To select which problems to annotate with equations, we identified the five most common types of questions in the data and annotated a randomly sampled question of each type. 5EQ+ANS uses this form of weak supervi- sion. To show the benefit of using the weakly su- pervised data, we also provide results for a base- line scenario 5EQ, where the training data includes only the five seed questions annotated with equa- tion systems. In the fully supervised scenario ALLEQ, we assume access to full equation sys- tems for the entire training set.</p><p>Evaluation Protocol We run all our experiments using 5-fold cross-validation. Since our model generates a solution for every problem, we report only accuracy. We report two metrics: equation accuracy to measure how often the system gener- ates the correct equation system, and answer accu- racy to evaluate how often the generated numerical answer is correct. When comparing equations, we avoid spurious differences by canonicalizing the equation system, as described in Section 6. To compare answer tuples we disregard the ordering and require each number appearing in the refer- ence answer to appear in the generated answer.</p><p>Parameters and Solver In our experiments we set k in our beam search algorithm (Section 5) to 200, and l to 20. We run the L-BFGS computation for 50 iterations. We regularize our learning objec- tive using the L 2 -norm and a λ value of 0.1. The set of mathematical relations supported by our im- plementation is {+, −, ×, /}.Our implementation uses the Gaussian Elimination function in the Effi- cient Java Matrix Library (EJML) <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Abeles, 2014)</ref> to generate answers given a set of equations.</p><p>8 Results   results in performance which is almost 70% of ALLEQ, demonstrating the value of weakly super- vised data. In contrast, 5EQ, which cannot use this weak supervision, performs much worse.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="8.1">Impact of Supervision</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="8.2">Performance and Template Frequency</head><p>To better understand the results, we also measured equation accuracy as a function of the frequency of each equation template in the data set. <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">Table 4</ref> reports results for ALLEQ after grouping the prob- lems into four different frequency bins. We can see that the system correctly answers more than 85% of the question types which occur frequently while still achieving more than 50% accuracy on those that occur relatively infrequently. We do not include template frequency results for 5EQ+ANS since in this setup our system is given only the top five most common templates. This limited set of templates covers only those questions in the &gt; 20 bin, or about 52% of the data. However, on this subset 5EQ+ANS performs very well, answering 88% of them correctly, which is approximately the same as the 86% achieved by ALLEQ. Thus while the weak supervision is not helpful in generating the space of possible equations, it is very helpful in learning to generate the correct answer when given an appropriate space of equations.  performance when two groups of features are ab- lated together. We can see that all of the features contribute to the overall performance, and that the pair features are the most important followed by the document and solution features. We also see that the pair features can compensate for the ab- sence of other features. For example, the perfor- mance drops only slightly when either the docu- ment or solution features are removed in isolation. However, the drop is much more dramatic when they are removed along with the pair features.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="8.3">Ablation Analysis</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="8.4">Qualitative Error Analysis</head><p>We examined our system output on one fold of ALLEQ and identified two main classes of errors. The first, accounting for approximately one- quarter of the cases, includes mistakes where more background or world knowledge might have helped. For example, Problem 1 in <ref type="figure">Figure 5</ref> re- quires understanding the relation between the di- mensions of a painting, and how this relation is maintained when the painting is printed, and Prob- lem 2 relies on understanding concepts of com- merce, including cost, sale price, and profit. While these relationships could be learned in our model with enough data, as it does for percentage prob- lems (e.g., <ref type="figure">Figure 4</ref>), various outside resources, such as knowledge bases (e.g. Freebase) or distri- butional statistics from a large text corpus, might help us learn them with less training data.</p><p>The second category, which accounts for about half of the errors, includes mistakes that stem from compositional language. For example, the second sentence in Problem 3 in <ref type="figure">Figure 5</ref> could generate the equation 2x − y = 5, with the phrase "twice of one of them" generating the expression 2x. Given the typical shallow nesting, it's possible to learn templates for these cases given enough data, and in the future it might also be possible to develop new, cross-sentence semantic parsers to enable better generalization from smaller datasets.</p><p>(1) A painting is 10 inches tall and 15 inches wide. A print of the painting is 25 inches tall, how wide is the print in inches?</p><p>A textbook costs a bookstore 44 dollars, and the store sells it for 55 dollars. Find the amount of profit based on the selling price.</p><p>(3)</p><p>The sum of two numbers is 85. The dif- ference of twice of one of them and the other one is 5. Find both numbers.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>(4)</head><p>The difference between two numbers is 6. If you double both numbers, the sum is 36. Find the two numbers. <ref type="figure">Figure 5</ref>: Examples of problems our system does not solve correctly.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="9">Conclusion</head><p>We presented an approach for automatically learn- ing to solve algebra word problems. Our algorithm constructs systems of equations, while aligning their variables and numbers to the problem text. Using a newly gathered corpus we measured the effects of various forms of weak supervision on performance. To the best of our knowledge, we present the first learning result for this task. There are still many opportunities to improve the reported results, and extend the approach to related domains. We would like to develop tech- niques to learn compositional models of mean- ing for generating new equations. Furthermore, the general representation of mathematics lends it- self to many different domains including geome- try, physics, and chemistry. Eventually, we hope to extend the techniques to synthesize even more complex structures, such as computer programs, from natural language.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>A</head><label></label><figDesc>motorist drove 2 hours at one speed and then for 3 hours at another speed. He covered a distance of 252 kilometers. If he had traveled 4 hours at the first speed and 1 hour at the second speed , he would have covered 244 kilometers. Find two speeds? Aligned template</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" validated="false"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Document level Unigrams Bigrams Single slot Has the same lemma as a question object Is a question object Is in a question sentence Is equal to one or two (for numbers) Word lemma X nearby constant Slot pair Dep. path contains: Word Dep. path contains: Dep. Type Dep. path contains: Word X Dep. Type Are the same word instance Have the same lemma In the same sentence In the same phrase Connected by a preposition Numbers are equal One number is larger than the other Equivalent relationship Solution Features Is solution all positive Is solution all integer Table 1: The features divided into categories.</figDesc><table></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" validated="false"><head>Table 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Dataset statistics. 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" validated="false"><head>Table 3 summarizes</head><label>3</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>the results. As expected, hav-
ing access to the full system of equations (ALLEQ) 
at training time results in the best learned model, 
with nearly 69% accuracy. However, training 
from primarily answer annotations (5EQ+ANS) 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3" validated="false"><head>Table 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Cross-validation accuracy results for var-
ious forms of supervision. 

Equation Answer % of 
accuracy accuracy data 
≤ 10 
43.6 
50.8 
25.5 
11 − 15 
46.6 
45.1 
10.5 
16 − 20 
44.2 
52.0 
11.3 
&gt; 20 
85.7 
86.1 
52.7 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4" validated="false"><head>Table 4 :</head><label>4</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Performance on different template fre-
quencies for ALLEQ. 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_5" validated="false"><head>Table 5 shows</head><label>5</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>ablation results for each group of 
features. The results along the diagonal show the 
performance when a single group of features is 
ablated, while the off-diagonal numbers show the </table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_6" validated="false"><head>Table 5 :</head><label>5</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Cross-validation accuracy results with 
different feature groups ablated for ALLEQ. Re-
sults are for answer accuracy which is 68.7% with-
out any features ablated. 

</table></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="2"> In our experiments these are generated using the Stanford parser (de Marneffe et al., 2006)</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>The authors acknowledge the support of Battelle Memorial Institute (PO#300662) and NSF (grant IIS-0835652). We thank Nicholas FitzGerald, the MIT NLP group, the UW NLP group and the ACL reviewers for their suggestions and com-ments. Any opinions, findings, conclusions, or recommendations expressed in this paper are those of the authors, and do not necessarily reflect the views of the funding organizations.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>281</head></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Efficient java matrix library</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Peter</forename><surname>Abeles</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://code.google.com/p/efficient-java-matrix-library/" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
