<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T12:33+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">An Extension of BLANC to System Mentions</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
				<availability status="unknown"><p>Copyright Association for Computational Linguistics</p>
				</availability>
				<date>June 23-25 2014. 2014</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xiaoqiang</forename><surname>Luo</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sameer</forename><surname>Pradhan</surname></persName>
							<email>sameer.pradhan@childrens.harvard.edu</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marta</forename><surname>Recasens</surname></persName>
							<email>recasens@google.com</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Eduard</forename><surname>Hovy</surname></persName>
							<email>hovy@cmu.edu</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Harvard Medical School</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Google Inc</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>111 8th Ave, 300 Longwood Ave</addrLine>
									<postCode>10011, 02115</postCode>
									<settlement>New York, Boston</settlement>
									<region>NY, MA</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">Google Inc</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>1600 Amphitheatre Pkwy, Mountain View</addrLine>
									<postCode>94043</postCode>
									<region>CA</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="institution">Carnegie Mellon University</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>5000 Forbes Ave. Pittsburgh</addrLine>
									<postCode>15213</postCode>
									<region>PA</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">An Extension of BLANC to System Mentions</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 52nd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
						<meeting>the 52nd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics <address><addrLine>Baltimore, Maryland, USA</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="24" to="29"/>
							<date type="published">June 23-25 2014. 2014</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>BLANC is a link-based coreference evaluation metric for measuring the quality of coreference systems on gold mentions. This paper extends the original BLANC (&quot;BLANC-gold&quot; henceforth) to system mentions, removing the gold mention assumption. The proposed BLANC falls back seamlessly to the original one if system mentions are identical to gold mentions , and it is shown to strongly correlate with existing metrics on the 2011 and 2012 CoNLL data.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Coreference resolution aims at identifying natu- ral language expressions (or mentions) that refer to the same entity. It entails partitioning (often imperfect) mentions into equivalence classes. A critically important problem is how to measure the quality of a coreference resolution system. Many evaluation metrics have been proposed in the past two decades, including the MUC measure ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Vilain et al., 1995)</ref>, B-cubed ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Bagga and Baldwin, 1998)</ref>, CEAF ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Luo, 2005</ref>) and, more recently, BLANC- gold ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Recasens and Hovy, 2011</ref>). B-cubed and CEAF treat entities as sets of mentions and mea- sure the agreement between key (or gold standard) entities and response (or system-generated) enti- ties, while MUC and BLANC-gold are link-based.</p><p>In particular, MUC measures the degree of agreement between key coreference links (i.e., links among mentions within entities) and re- sponse coreference links, while non-coreference links (i.e., links formed by mentions from different entities) are not explicitly taken into account. This leads to a phenomenon where coreference systems outputting large entities are scored more favorably than those outputting small entities ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Luo, 2005)</ref>. BLANC ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Recasens and Hovy, 2011</ref>), on the other hand, considers both coreference links and non- coreference links. It calculates recall, precision and F-measure separately on coreference and non- coreference links in the usual way, and defines the overall recall, precision and F-measure as the mean of the respective measures for coreference and non-coreference links.</p><p>The BLANC-gold metric was developed with the assumption that response mentions and key mentions are identical. In reality, however, men- tions need to be detected from natural language text and the result is, more often than not, im- perfect: some key mentions may be missing in the response, and some response mentions may be spurious-so-called "twinless" mentions by <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Stoyanov et al. (2009)</ref>. Therefore, the identical- mention-set assumption limits BLANC-gold's ap- plicability when gold mentions are not available, or when one wants to have a single score mea- suring both the quality of mention detection and coreference resolution. The goal of this paper is to extend the BLANC-gold metric to imperfect re- sponse mentions.</p><p>We first briefly review the original definition of BLANC, and rewrite its definition using set nota- tion. We then argue that the gold-mention assump- tion in Recasens and Hovy (2011) can be lifted without changing the original definition. In fact, the proposed BLANC metric subsumes the origi- nal one in that its value is identical to the original one when response mentions are identical to key mentions.</p><p>The rest of the paper is organized as follows. We introduce the notions used in this paper in Section 2. We then present the original BLANC- gold in Section 3 using the set notation defined in Section 2. This paves the way to generalize it to imperfect system mentions, which is presented in Section 4. The proposed BLANC is applied to the CoNLL 2011 and 2012 shared task participants, and the scores and its correlations with existing metrics are shown in Section 5.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Notations</head><p>To facilitate the presentation, we define the nota- tions used in the paper.</p><p>We use key to refer to gold standard mentions or entities, and response to refer to system mentions or entities. The collection of key entities is denoted</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">by K = {k i } |K| i=1</formula><p>, where k i is the i th key entity; accordingly, R = {r j } |R| j=1 is the set of response entities, and r j is the j th response entity. We as- sume that mentions in {k i } and {r j } are unique; in other words, there is no duplicate mention.</p><p>Let C k (i) and C r (j) be the set of coreference links formed by mentions in k i and r j :</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">C k (i) = {(m1, m2) : m1 ∈ ki, m2 ∈ ki, m1 = m2} Cr(j) = {(m1, m2) : m1 ∈ rj, m2 ∈ rj, m1 = m2}</formula><p>As can be seen, a link is an undirected edge be- tween two mentions, and it can be equivalently represented by a pair of mentions. Note that when an entity consists of a single mention, its corefer- ence link set is empty.</p><p>Let N k (i, j) (i = j) be key non-coreference links formed between mentions in k i and those in k j , and let N r (i, j) (i = j) be response non- coreference links formed between mentions in r i and those in r j , respectively:</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">N k (i, j) = {(m1, m2) : m1 ∈ ki, m2 ∈ kj} Nr(i, j) = {(m1, m2) : m1 ∈ ri, m2 ∈ rj}</formula><p>Note that the non-coreference link set is empty when all mentions are in the same entity.</p><p>We use the same letter and subscription with- out the index in parentheses to denote the union of sets, e.g.,</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">C k = ∪iC k (i), N k = ∪ i =j N k (i, j) Cr = ∪jCr(j), Nr = ∪ i =j Nr(i, j)</formula><p>We use T k = C k ∪ N k and T r = C r ∪ N r to denote the total set of key links and total set of response links, respectively. Clearly, C k and N k form a partition of</p><formula xml:id="formula_4">T k since C k ∩ N k = ∅, T k = C k ∪ N k . Likewise, C r and N r form a partition of T r .</formula><p>We say that a key link l 1 ∈ T k equals a response link l 2 ∈ T r if and only if the pair of mentions from which the links are formed are identical. We write l 1 = l 2 if two links are equal. It is easy to see that the gold mention assumption-same set of response mentions as the set of key mentions- can be equivalently stated as T k = T r (this does not necessarily mean that C k = C r or N k = N r ).</p><p>We also use | · | to denote the size of a set.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Original BLANC</head><p>BLANC-gold is adapted from Rand Index <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Rand, 1971)</ref>, a metric for clustering objects. Rand Index is defined as the ratio between the number of cor- rect within-cluster links plus the number of correct cross-cluster links, and the total number of links. When T k = T r , Rand Index can be applied di- rectly since coreference resolution reduces to a clustering problem where mentions are partitioned into clusters (entities):</p><formula xml:id="formula_5">Rand Index = |C k ∩ Cr| + |N k ∩ Nr| 1 2 |T k |(|T k | − 1)<label>(1)</label></formula><p>In practice, though, the simple-minded adoption of Rand Index is not satisfactory since the number of non-coreference links often overwhelms that of coreference links (Recasens and Hovy, 2011), or, |N k | |C k | and |N r | |C r |. Rand Index, if used without modification, would not be sensitive to changes of coreference links. BLANC-gold solves this problem by averaging the F-measure computed over coreference links and the F-measure over non-coreference links. Using the notations in Section 2, the recall, pre- cision, and F-measure on coreference links are:</p><formula xml:id="formula_6">R (g) c = |C k ∩ Cr| |C k ∩ Cr| + |C k ∩ Nr| (2) P (g) c = |C k ∩ Cr| |Cr ∩ C k | + |Cr ∩ N k | (3) F (g) c = 2R (g) c P (g) c R (g) c + P (g) c ;<label>(4)</label></formula><p>Similarly, the recall, precision, and F-measure on non-coreference links are computed as:</p><formula xml:id="formula_7">R (g) n = |N k ∩ Nr| |N k ∩ Cr| + |N k ∩ Nr|<label>(5)</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_8">P (g) n = |N k ∩ Nr| |Nr ∩ C k | + |Nr ∩ N k | (6) F (g) n = 2R (g) n P (g) n R (g) n + P (g) n .<label>(7)</label></formula><p>25 Finally, the BLANC-gold metric is the arithmetic average of F (g) c and F (g) n :</p><formula xml:id="formula_9">BLANC (g) = F (g) c + F (g) n 2 .<label>(8)</label></formula><p>Superscript g in these equations highlights the fact that they are meant for coreference systems with gold mentions. Eqn. <ref type="formula" target="#formula_9">(8)</ref> indicates that BLANC-gold assigns equal weight to F (g) c , the F-measure from coref- erence links, and F (g) n , the F-measure from non- coreference links. This avoids the problem that |N k | |C k | and |N r | |C r |, should the original Rand Index be used.</p><p>In Eqn. <ref type="formula">(2)</ref> - <ref type="formula">(3)</ref> and Eqn. (5) -(6), denominators are written as a sum of disjoint subsets so they can be related to the contingency table in ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Recasens and Hovy, 2011</ref>). Under the assumption that</p><formula xml:id="formula_10">T k = T r , it is clear that C k = (C k ∩ C r ) ∪ (C k ∩ N r ), C r = (C k ∩ C r ) ∪ (N k ∩ C r )</formula><p>, and so on.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">BLANC for Imperfect Response Mentions</head><p>Under the assumption that the key and response mention sets are identical (which implies that T k = T r ), Equations (2) to (7) make sense. For example, R c is the ratio of the number of correct coreference links over the number of key corefer- ence links; P c is the ratio of the number of cor- rect coreference links over the number of response coreference links, and so on. However, when response mentions are not iden- tical to key mentions, a key coreference link may not appear in either C r or N r , so Equations (2) to (7) cannot be applied directly to systems with im- perfect mentions. For instance, if the key entities are {a,b,c} {d,e}; and the response entities are {b,c} {e,f,g}, then the key coreference link (a,b) is not seen on the response side; sim- ilarly, it is possible that a response link does not appear on the key side either: (c,f) and (f,g) are not in the key in the above example.</p><p>To account for missing or spurious links, we ob- serve that</p><p>• C k \ T r are key coreference links missing in the response;</p><p>• N k \ T r are key non-coreference links miss- ing in the response;</p><p>• C r \ T k are response coreference links miss- ing in the key;</p><p>• N r \ T k are response non-coreference links missing in the key, and we propose to extend the coreference F- measure and non-coreference F-measure as fol- lows. Coreference recall, precision and F-measure are changed to:</p><formula xml:id="formula_11">Rc = |C k ∩ Cr| |C k ∩ Cr| + |C k ∩ Nr| + |C k \ Tr| (9) Pc = |C k ∩ Cr| |Cr ∩ C k | + |Cr ∩ N k | + |Cr \ T k |<label>(10)</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_12">Fc = 2RcPc Rc + Pc<label>(11)</label></formula><p>Non-coreference recall, precision and F-measure are changed to:</p><formula xml:id="formula_13">Rn = |N k ∩ Nr| |N k ∩ Cr| + |N k ∩ Nr| + |N k \ Tr| (12) Pn = |N k ∩ Nr| |Nr ∩ C k | + |Nr ∩ N k | + |Nr \ T k |<label>(13)</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_14">Fn = 2RnPn Rn + Pn .<label>(14)</label></formula><p>The proposed BLANC continues to be the arith- metic average of F c and F n :</p><formula xml:id="formula_15">BLANC = F c + F n 2 .<label>(15)</label></formula><p>We observe that the definition of the proposed BLANC, Equ. (9)-(14) subsume the BLANC- gold (2) to (7) due to the following proposition:</p><formula xml:id="formula_16">If T k = T r , then BLAN C = BLAN C (g) .</formula><p>Proof. We only need to show that R c = R</p><formula xml:id="formula_17">(g) c , P c = P (g) c , R n = R (g)</formula><p>n , and P n = P (g) n . We prove the first one (the other proofs are similar and elided due to space limitations). Since T k = T r and C k ⊂ T k , we have C k ⊂ T r ; thus C k \T r = ∅, and</p><formula xml:id="formula_18">|C k ∩ T r | = 0. This establishes that R c = R (g) c .</formula><p>Indeed, since C k is a union of three disjoint sub- sets:</p><formula xml:id="formula_19">C k = (C k ∩ C r ) ∪ (C k ∩ N r ) ∪ (C k \ T r ), R (g)</formula><p>c and R c can be unified as |C k ∩Cr| |C K | . Unification for other component recalls and precisions can be done similarly. So the final definition of BLANC can be succinctly stated as:</p><formula xml:id="formula_20">Rc = |C k ∩ Cr| |C k | , Pc = |C k ∩ Cr| |Cr| (16) Rn = |N k ∩ Nr| |N k | , Pn = |N k ∩ Nr| |Nr| (17) Fc = 2|C k ∩ Cr| |C k | + |Cr| , Fn = 2|N k ∩ Nr| |N k | + |Nr|<label>(18)</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_21">BLANC = Fc + Fn 2<label>(19)</label></formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">Boundary Cases</head><p>Care has to be taken when counts of the BLANC definition are 0. This can happen when all key (or response) mentions are in one cluster or are all singletons: the former case will lead to N k = ∅ (or N r = ∅); the latter will lead to C k = ∅ (or C r = ∅). Observe that as long as <ref type="formula" target="#formula_5">(18)</ref> is well-defined; as long as |N k |+|N r | &gt; 0, F n in <ref type="formula" target="#formula_5">(18)</ref> is well-defined. So we only need to augment the BLANC definition for the following cases:</p><formula xml:id="formula_22">|C k | + |C r | &gt; 0, F c in</formula><p>(1) If C k = C r = ∅ and N k = N r = ∅, then BLANC = I(M k = M r ), where I(·) is an in- dicator function whose value is 1 if its argument is true, and 0 otherwise. M k and M r are the key and response mention set. This can happen when a document has no more than one mention and there is no link.</p><p>(2) If C k = C r = ∅ and |N k | + |N r | &gt; 0, then BLANC = F n . This is the case where the key and response side has only entities consisting of singleton mentions. Since there is no coreference link, BLANC reduces to the non-coreference F- measure F n .</p><p>(3) If N k = N r = ∅ and |C k | + |C r | &gt; 0, then BLANC = F c . This is the case where all mentions in the key and response are in one entity. Since there is no non-coreference link, BLANC reduces to the coreference F-measure F c .</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">Toy Examples</head><p>We walk through a few examples and show how BLANC is calculated in detail. In all the examples below, each lower-case letter represents a mention; mentions in an entity are closed in {}; two letters in () represent a link. Example 1. Key entities are {abc} and {d}; re- sponse entities are {bc} and {de}. Obviously,</p><formula xml:id="formula_23">C k = {(ab), (bc), (ac)}; N k = {(ad), (bd), (cd)}; C r = {(bc), (de)}; N r = {(bd), (be), (cd), (ce)}. Therefore, C k ∩ C r = {(bc)}, N k ∩ N r = {(bd), (cd)}, and R c = 1 3 , P c = 1 2 , F c = 2 5 ; R n = 2</formula><p>3 , P n = 2 4 , F n = 4 7 . Finally, BLANC = 17 35 . Example 2. Key entity is {a}; response entity is {b}. This is boundary case (1): BLANC = 0.</p><p>Example 3. Key entities are {a}{b}{c}; re- sponse entities are {a}{b}{d}. This is boundary case (2): there are no coreference links. Since N k = {(ab), (bc), (ca)},  <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>: The proposed BLANC scores of the CoNLL-2011 shared task participants.</p><formula xml:id="formula_24">N r = {(ab), (bd), (ad)}, we have N k ∩ N r = {(ab)}, and R n = 1 3 , P n = 1 3 . So BLANC = F n = 1 3 . Example 4</formula><p>. Key entity is {abc}; response entity is {bc}. This is boundary case <ref type="formula">(3)</ref>: there are no non-coreference links. Since C k = {(ab), (bc), (ca)}, and C r = {(bc)}, we have C k ∩ C r = {(bc)}, and R c = 1 3 , P c = 1, So BLANC = F c = 2 4 = 1 2 .</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Results</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.1">CoNLL-2011/12</head><p>We have updated the publicly available CoNLL coreference scorer 1 with the proposed BLANC, and used it to compute the proposed BLANC scores for all the CoNLL 2011 (Pradhan et al., 2011) and 2012 (Pradhan et al., 2012) participants in the official track, where participants had to au- tomatically predict the mentions. <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">Tables 1 and 2</ref> report the updated results. <ref type="bibr">2</ref>       other measures along R, P and F1 ( <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">Table 3)</ref>, showing that BLANC is able to capture most entity-based similarities measured by B-cubed and CEAF. However, the CoNLL data sets come from OntoNotes ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Hovy et al., 2006</ref>), where singleton entities are not annotated, and BLANC has a wider dynamic range on data sets with singletons <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Recasens and Hovy, 2011</ref>). So the correlations will likely be lower on data sets with singleton entities.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.2">Correlation with Other Measures</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Conclusion</head><p>The original BLANC-gold (Recasens and Hovy, 2011) requires that system mentions be identical to gold mentions, which limits the metric's utility since detected system mentions often have missing key mentions or spurious mentions. The proposed BLANC is free from this assumption, and we have shown that it subsumes the original BLANC- gold. Since BLANC works on imperfect system mentions, we have used it to score the CoNLL 2011 and 2012 coreference systems. The BLANC scores show strong correlation with existing met- rics, especially B-cubed and CEAF-m.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 shows</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1 shows how the proposed BLANC measure works when compared with existing metrics such as MUC, B-cubed and CEAF, using the BLANC and F1 scores. The proposed BLANC is highly positively correlated with the</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Participant</head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: Correlation plot between the proposed BLANC and the other measures based on the CoNLL 2011/2012 results. All values are F1 scores.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" validated="false"><head>Table 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>The proposed BLANC scores of the 
CoNLL-2012 shared task participants. 

R 
P 
F1 

MUC 
0.975 
0.844 
0.935 
B-cubed 
0.981 
0.942 
0.966 
CEAF-m 
0.941 
0.923 
0.966 
CEAF-e 
0.797 
0.781 
0.919 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3" validated="false"><head>Table 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Pearson's r correlation coefficients be-
tween the proposed BLANC and the other coref-
erence measures based on the CoNLL 2011/2012 
results. All p-values are significant at &lt; 0.001. 

</table></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> http://code.google.com/p/reference-coreference-scorers 2 The order is kept the same as in Pradhan et al. (2011) and Pradhan et al. (2012) for easy comparison.</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>We would like to thank the three anonymous re-viewers for their invaluable suggestions for im-proving the paper. This work was partially sup-ported by grants R01LM10090 from the National Library of Medicine.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Algorithms for scoring coreference chains</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Amit</forename><surname>Bagga</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Breck</forename><surname>Baldwin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Linguistic Coreference Workshop at The First International Conference on Language Resources and Evaluation (LREC&apos;98)</title>
		<meeting>the Linguistic Coreference Workshop at The First International Conference on Language Resources and Evaluation (LREC&apos;98)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="563" to="566" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">OntoNotes: The 90% solution</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Eduard</forename><surname>Hovy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mitchell</forename><surname>Marcus</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Martha</forename><surname>Palmer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lance</forename><surname>Ramshaw</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ralph</forename><surname>Weischedel</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Human Language Technology Conference of the NAACL, Companion Volume: Short Papers</title>
		<meeting>the Human Language Technology Conference of the NAACL, Companion Volume: Short Papers<address><addrLine>New York City, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2006-06" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="57" to="60" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">On coreference resolution performance metrics</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xiaoqiang</forename><surname>Luo</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of Human Language Technology (HLT)/Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP)</title>
		<meeting>of Human Language Technology (HLT)/Empirical Methods in Natural Language essing (EMNLP)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">CoNLL-2011 shared task: Modeling unrestricted coreference in OntoNotes</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lance</forename><surname>Sameer Pradhan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mitchell</forename><surname>Ramshaw</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Martha</forename><surname>Marcus</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ralph</forename><surname>Palmer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nianwen</forename><surname>Weischedel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Xue</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Fifteenth Conference on Computational Natural Language Learning: Shared Task</title>
		<meeting>the Fifteenth Conference on Computational Natural Language Learning: Shared Task<address><addrLine>Portland, Oregon, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2011-06" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="27" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">CoNLL2012 shared task: Modeling multilingual unrestricted coreference in OntoNotes</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alessandro</forename><surname>Sameer Pradhan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nianwen</forename><surname>Moschitti</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Olga</forename><surname>Xue</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yuchen</forename><surname>Uryupina</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Joint Conference on EMNLP and CoNLL-Shared Task</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Jeju Island, Korea</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012-07" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="40" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Association for Computational Linguistics</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Objective criteria for the evaluation of clustering methods</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Rand</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of the American Statistical Association</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">66</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">336</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="846" to="850" />
			<date type="published" when="1971" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">BLANC: Implementing the Rand index for coreference evaluation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Recasens</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Hovy</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Natural Language Engineering</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="485" to="510" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Conundrums in noun phrase coreference resolution: Making sense of the stateof-the-art</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Veselin</forename><surname>Stoyanov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nathan</forename><surname>Gilbert</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Claire</forename><surname>Cardie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ellen</forename><surname>Riloff</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Joint Conference of the 47th Annual Meeting of the ACL and the 4th International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing of the AFNLP</title>
		<meeting>the Joint Conference of the 47th Annual Meeting of the ACL and the 4th International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing of the AFNLP<address><addrLine>Stroudsburg, PA, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="656" to="664" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>ACL &apos;09</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A model-theoretic coreference scoring scheme</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Vilain</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Burger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Aberdeen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Connolly</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Hirschman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of MUC6</title>
		<meeting>of MUC6</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="45" to="52" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
