<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T11:46+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">The Excitement Open Platform for Textual Inferences</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
				<availability status="unknown"><p>Copyright Association for Computational Linguistics</p>
				</availability>
				<date>June 23-24. 2014. 2014</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bernardo</forename><surname>Magnini</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Roberto</forename><surname>Zanoli</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ido</forename><surname>Dagan</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">•</forename></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kathrin</forename><surname>Eichler</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>¨ Unter Neumann</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tae-Gil</forename><surname>Noh</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sebastian</forename><surname>Pado</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Asher</forename><surname>Stern</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Omer</forename><surname>Levy</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Stuttgart Univ</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Heidelberg</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">Bar Ilan University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">The Excitement Open Platform for Textual Inferences</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of 52nd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics: System Demonstrations</title>
						<meeting>52nd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics: System Demonstrations <address><addrLine>Baltimore, Maryland USA</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="43" to="48"/>
							<date type="published">June 23-24. 2014. 2014</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>This paper presents the Excitement Open Platform (EOP), a generic architecture and a comprehensive implementation for tex-tual inference in multiple languages. The platform includes state-of-art algorithms, a large number of knowledge resources, and facilities for experimenting and testing innovative approaches. The EOP is distributed as an open source software.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>In the last decade textual entailment ( ) has been a very active topic in Computa- tional Linguistics, providing a unifying framework for textual inference. Several evaluation exercises have been organized around Recognizing Textual Entailment (RTE) challenges and many method- ologies, algorithms and knowledge resources have been proposed to address the task. However, re- search in textual entailment is still fragmented and there is no unifying algorithmic framework nor software architecture.</p><p>In this paper, we present the Excitement Open Platform (EOP), a generic architecture and a com- prehensive implementation for multilingual textual inference which we make available to the scien- tific and technological communities. To a large extent, the idea is to follow the successful experi- ence of the Moses open source platform ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Koehn et al., 2007</ref>) in Machine Translation, which has made a substantial impact on research in that field. The EOP is the result of a two-year coordinated work under the international project EXCITEMENT. <ref type="bibr">1</ref> A consortium of four academic partners has defined the EOP architectural specifications, implemented the functional interfaces of the EOP components, imported existing entailment engines into the EOP 1 http://www.excitement-project.eu and finally designed and implemented a rich envi- ronment to support open source distribution.</p><p>The goal of the platform is to provide function- ality for the automatic identification of entailment relations among texts. The EOP is based on a modu- lar architecture with a particular focus on language- independent algorithms. It allows developers and users to combine linguistic pipelines, entailment al- gorithms and linguistic resources within and across languages with as little effort as possible. For ex- ample, different entailment decision approaches can share the same resources and the same sub- components in the platform. A classification-based algorithm can use the distance component of an edit-distance based entailment decision approach, and two different approaches can use the same set of knowledge resources. Moreover, the platform has various multilingual components for languages like English, German and Italian. The result is an ideal software environment for experimenting and testing innovative approaches for textual inferences. The EOP is distributed as an open source software 2 and its use is open both to users interested in using inference in applications and to developers willing to extend the current functionalities.</p><p>The paper is structured as follows. Section 2 presents the platform architecture, highlighting how the EOP component-based approach favors interoperability. Section 3 provides a picture of the current population of the EOP in terms of both entailment algorithms and knowledge resources. Section 4 introduces expected use cases of the plat- form. Finally, Section 5 presents the main features of the open source package.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Architecture</head><p>The EOP platform takes as input two text portions, the first called the Text (abbreviated with T), the second called the Hypothesis (abbreviated with H). The output is an entailment judgement, either "En- tailment" if T entails H, or "NonEntailment" if the relation does not hold. A confidence score for the decision is also returned in both cases.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Linguis'c)Analysis</head><p>The EOP architecture <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Padó et al., 2014</ref>) is based on the concept of modularization with pluggable and replaceable components to enable extension and customization. The overall structure is shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref> and consists of two main parts. The Linguistic Analysis Pipeline (LAP) is a series of linguistic annotation components. The Entailment Core (EC) performs the actual entailment recog- nition. This separation ensures that (a) the com- ponents in the EC only rely on linguistic analysis in well-defined ways and (b) the LAP and EC can be run independently of each other. Configuration files are the principal means of configuring the EOP. In the rest of this section we first provide an intro- duction to the LAP, then we move to the EC and finally describe the configuration files.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">Linguistic Analysis Pipeline (LAP)</head><p>The Linguistic Analysis Pipeline is a collection of annotation components for Natural Language Pro- cessing (NLP) based on the Apache UIMA frame- work. <ref type="bibr">3</ref> Annotations range from tokenization to part of speech tagging, chunking, Named Entity Recognition and parsing. The adoption of UIMA enables interoperability among components (e.g., substitution of one parser by another one) while ensuring language independence. Input and output of the components are represented in an extended version of the DKPro type system based on UIMA Common Analysis Structure (CAS) <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Gurevych et al., 2007;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Noh and Padó, 2013</ref>).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">Entailment Core (EC)</head><p>The Entailment Core performs the actual entail- ment recognition based on the preprocessed text made by the Linguistic Analysis Pipeline. It con- sists of one or more Entailment Decision Algo- rithms (EDAs) and zero or more subordinate com- ponents. An EDA takes an entailment decision (i.e., "entailment" or "no entailment") while com- ponents provide static and dynamic information for the EDA.</p><p>Entailment Decision Algorithms are at the top level in the EC. They compute an entailment deci- sion for a given Text/Hypothesis (T/H) pair, and can use components that provide standardized al- gorithms or knowledge resources. The EOP ships with several EDAs (cf. Section 3).</p><p>Scoring Components accept a Text/Hypothesis pair as an input, and return a vector of scores. Their output can be used directly to build minimal classifier-based EDAs forming complete RTE sys- tems. An extended version of these components are the Distance Components that can produce normal- ized and unnormalized distance/similarity values in addition to the score vector.</p><p>Annotation Components can be used to add dif- ferent annotations to the Text/Hypothesis pairs. An example of such a type of component is one that produces word or phrase alignments between the Text and the Hypothesis.</p><p>Lexical Knowledge Components describe se- mantic relationships between words. In the EOP, this knowledge is represented as directed rules made up of two word-POS pairs, where the LHS (left-hand side) entails the RHS (right- hand side), e.g., (shooting star, N oun) =⇒ (meteorite, N oun). Lexical Knowledge Compo- nents provide an interface that allows for (a) listing all RHS for a given LHS; (b) listing all LHS for a given RHS; and (c) checking for an entailment relation for a given LHS-RHS pair. The interface also wraps all major lexical knowledge sources cur- rently used in RTE research, including manually constructed ontologies like WordNet, and encyclo- pedic resources like Wikipedia.</p><p>Syntactic Knowledge Components capture en- tailment relationships between syntactic and lexical-syntactic expressions. We represent such relationships by entailment rules that link (option- ally lexicalized) dependency tree fragments that can contain variables as nodes. For example, the rule fall of X =⇒ X falls, or X sells Y to Z =⇒ Z buys Y from X express general paraphrasing pat- terns at the predicate-argument level that cannot be captured by purely lexical rules. Formally, each syntactic rule consists of two dependency tree frag- ments plus a mapping from the variables of the LHS tree to the variables of the RHS tree. <ref type="bibr">4</ref> </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3">Configuration Files</head><p>The EC components can be combined into actual inference engines through configuration files which contain information to build a complete inference engine. A configuration file completely describes an experiment. For example, it specifies the re- sources that the selected EDA has to use and the data set to be analysed. The LAP needed for data set preprocessing is another parameter that can be configured too. The platform ships with a set of predefined configuration files accompanied by sup- porting documentation.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Entailment Algorithms and Resources</head><p>This section provides a description of the Entail- ment Algorithms and Knowledge Resources that are distributed with the EOP.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Entailment Algorithms</head><p>The current version of the EOP platform ships with three EDAs corresponding to three different ap- proaches to RTE: an EDA based on transformations between T and H, an EDA based on edit distance algorithms, and a classification based EDA using features extracted from T and H.</p><p>Transformation-based EDA applies a sequence of transformations on T with the goal of making it identical to H. If each transformation preserves (fully or partially) the meaning of the original text, then it can be concluded that the modified text (which is actually the Hypothesis) can be inferred from the original one. Consider the following sim- ple example where the text is "The boy was located by the police" and the Hypothesis is "The child was found by the police". Two transformations for "boy" → "child" and "located" → "found" do the job.</p><p>In the EOP we include a transformation based inference system that adopts the knowledge based transformations of <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Bar-Haim et al. (2007)</ref>, while in- corporating a probabilistic model to estimate trans- formation confidences. In addition, it includes a search algorithm which finds an optimal sequence of transformations for any given T/H pair ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Stern et al., 2012</ref>).</p><p>Edit distance EDA involves using algorithms casting textual entailment as the problem of map- ping the whole content of T into the content of H. Mappings are performed as sequences of editing operations (i.e., insertion, deletion and substitu- tion) on text portions needed to transform T into H, where each edit operation has a cost associated with it. The underlying intuition is that the probability of an entailment relation between T and H is related to the distance between them; see <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Kouylekov and Magnini (2005)</ref> for a comprehensive experimental study.</p><p>Classification based EDA uses a Maximum En- tropy classifier to combine the outcomes of sev- eral scoring functions and to learn a classification model for recognizing entailment. The scoring functions extract a number of features at various linguistic levels (bag-of-words, syntactic dependen- cies, semantic dependencies, named entities). The approach was thoroughly described in <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Wang and Neumann (2007)</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Knowledge Resources</head><p>As described in Section 2.2, knowledge resources are crucial to recognize cases where T and H use different textual expressions (words, phrases) while preserving entailment. The EOP platform includes a wide range of knowledge resources, including lex- ical and syntactic resources, where some of them are grabbed from manual resources, like dictionar- ies, while others are learned automatically. Many EOP resources are inherited from pre-existing RTE systems migrated into the EOP platform, but now use the same interfaces, which makes them acces- sible in a uniform fashion.</p><p>There are about two dozen lexical (e.g. word- nets) and syntactic resources for three languages (i.e. English, Italian and German). However, since there is still a clear predominance of En- glish resources, the platform includes lexical and syntactic knowledge mining tools to bootstrap re- sources from corpora, both for other languages and  <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Transformation-based English RTE-3  67.13%  Transformation-based English RTE-6</ref> 49.55% Edit-Distance English RTE-3 64.38% Edit-Distance German RTE-3 59.88% Edit-Distance Italian RTE-3 63.50% <ref type="table">Classification-based English RTE-3  65.25%  Classification-based German RTE-3</ref> 63.75% Median of RTE-3 (English) submissions 61.75% Median of RTE-6 (English) submissions 33.72%  <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">and Pantel, 2002</ref>) and Lin similarity(Lin, 1998).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3">EOP Evaluation</head><p>Results for the three EDAs included in the EOP platform are reported in <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table 1</ref>. Each line rep- resents an EDA, the language and the dataset on which the EDA was evaluated. For brevity, we omit here the knowledge resources used for each EDA, even though knowledge configuration clearly affects performance. The evaluations were performed on RTE-3 dataset ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Giampiccolo et al., 2007)</ref>, where the goal is to maximize accuracy. We (manually) translated it to German and Italian for evaluations: in both cases the results fix a refer- ence for the two languages. The two new datasets for German and English are available both as part of the EOP distribution and independently <ref type="bibr">5</ref> . The transformation-based EDA was also evaluated on RTE-6 dataset ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Bentivogli et al., 2010)</ref>, in which the goal is to maximize the F1 measure.</p><p>The results of the included EDAs are higher than median values of participated systems in RTE-3, and they are competing with state-of-the-arts in RTE-6 results. To the best of our knowledge, the results of the EDAs as provided in the platform are the highest among those available as open source systems for the community.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Use Cases</head><p>We see four primary use cases for the EOP. Their requirements were reflected in our design choices.</p><p>Use Case 1: Applied Textual Entailment. This category covers users who are not interested in the details of RTE but who are interested in an NLP task in which textual entailment can take over part of or all of the semantic processing, such as Ques- tion Answering or Intelligent Tutoring. Such users require a system that is as easy to deploy as possi- ble, which motivates our offer of the EOP platform as a library. They also require a system that pro- vides good quality at a reasonable efficiency as well as guidance as to the best choice of parame- ters. The latter point is realized through our results archive in the official EOP Wiki on the EOP site.</p><p>Use Case 2: Textual Entailment Development. This category covers researchers who are interested in Recognizing Textual Entailment itself, for exam- ple with the goal of developing novel algorithms for detecting entailment. In contrast to the first category, this group need to look "under the hood" of the EOP platform and access the source code of the EOP. For this reason, we have spent substantial effort to provide the code in a well-structured and well-documented form.</p><p>A subclass of this group is formed by researchers who want to set up a RTE infrastructure for lan- guages in which it does not yet exist (that is, al- most all languages). The requirements of this class of users comprises clearly specified procedures to replace the Linguistic Analysis Pipeline, which are covered in our documentation, and simple methods to acquire knowledge resources for these languages (assuming that the EDAs themselves are largely language-independent). These are provided by the language-independent knowledge acquisition tools which we offer alongside the platform (cf. Section 3.2).</p><p>Use Case 3: Lexical Semantics Evaluation. A third category consists of researchers whose pri- mary interest is in (lexical) semantics.</p><p>As long as their scientific results can be phrased in terms of semantic similarities or inference rules, the EOP platform can be used as a simple and stan- dardized workbench for these results that indicates the impact that the semantic knowledge under con- sideration has on deciding textual entailment. The main requirement for this user group is the simple integration of new knowledge resources into the EOP platform. This is catered for through the defi- nition of the generic knowledge component inter- faces (cf. Section 2.2) and detailed documentation on how to implement these interfaces.</p><p>Use Case 4: Educational Use. The fourth and final use case is as an educational tool to support academic courses and projects on Recognizing Tex- tual Entailment and inference more generally. This use case calls, in common with the others, for easy usability and flexibility. Specifically for this use case, we have also developed a series of tutorials aimed at acquainting new users with the EOP plat- form through a series of increasingly complexity exercises that cover all areas of the EOP. We are also posting proposals for projects to extend the EOP on the EOP Wiki.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">EOP Distribution</head><p>The EOP infrastructure follows state-of-the-art soft- ware engineering standards to support both users and developers with a flexible, scalable and easy to use software environment. In addition to communi- cation channels, like the mailing list and the issue tracking system, the EOP infrastructure comprises the following set of facilities.</p><p>Version Control System: We use GitHub, 6 a web-based hosting service for code and documen- tation storage, development, and issue tracking.</p><p>Web Site: The GitHub Automatic Page Genera- tor was used to build the EOP web site and Wiki, containing a general introduction to the software platform, the terms of its license, mailing lists to contact the EOP members and links to the code releases.</p><p>Documentation: Both user and developer docu- mentation is available from Wiki pages; the pages are written with the GitHub Wiki Editor and hosted on the GitHub repository. The documentation in- cludes a Quick Start guide to start using the EOP platform right away, and a detailed step by step tutorial.</p><p>Results Archive: As a new feature for commu- nity building, EOP users can, and are encouraged to, share their results: the platform configuration files used to produce results as well as contact infor- mation can be saved and archived into a dedicated page on the EOP GitHub repository. That allows other EOP users to replicate experiments under the same condition and/or avoid doing experiments that have already been done.</p><p>Build Automation Tool: The EOP has been de- veloped as a Maven 7 multi-modules project, with all modules sharing the same Maven standard struc- ture, making it easier to find files in the project once one is used to Maven.</p><p>Maven Artifacts Repository: Using a Maven repository has a twofold goal: (i) to serve as an internal private repository of all software libraries used within the project (libraries are binary files and should not be stored under version control sys- tems, which are intended to be used with text files); (ii) to make the produced EOP Maven artifacts available (i.e., for users who want to use the EOP as a library in their own code). We use Artifactory 8 repository manager to store produced artifacts.</p><p>Continuous Integration: The EOP uses Jenk- ins 9 for Continuous Integration, a software develop- ment practice where developers of a team integrate their work frequently (e.g., daily).</p><p>Code Quality Tool: Ensuring the quality of the produced software is one of the most important aspects of software engineering. The EOP uses tools like PMD 10 that can automatically be run during development to help the developers check the quality of their software.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.1">Project Repository</head><p>The EOP Java source code is hosted on the EOP Github repository and managed using Git. The repository consists of three main branches: the release branch contains the code that is supposed to be in a production-ready state, whereas the master branch contains the code to be incorporated into the next release. When the source code in the master branch reaches a stable point and is ready to be released, all of the changes are merged back into release. Finally, the gh-pages branch contains the web site pages.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.2">Licensing</head><p>The software of the platform is released under the terms of General Public License (GPL) version 3. <ref type="bibr">11</ref> The platform contains both components and resources designed by the EOP developers, as well as others that are well known and freely available in the NLP research community. Additional com- ponents and resources whose license is not compat- ible with the EOP license have to be downloaded and installed separately by the user.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Conclusion</head><p>This paper has presented the main characteristics of Excitement Open Platform platform, a rich envi- ronment for experimenting and evaluating textual entailment systems. On the software side, the EOP is a complex endeavor to integrate tools and re- sources in Computational Linguistics, including pipelines for three languages, three pre-existing entailment engines, and about two dozens of lex- ical and syntactic resources. The EOP assumes a clear and modular separation between linguistic annotations, entailment algorithms and knowledge resources which are used by the algorithms. A relevant benefit of the architectural design is that a high level of interoperability is reached, provid- ing a stimulating environment for new research in textual inferences.</p><p>The EOP platform has been already tested in sev- eral pilot research projects and educational courses, and it is currently distributed as open source soft- ware under the GPL-3 license. To the best of our knowledge, the entailment systems and their con- figurations provided in the platform are the best systems available as open source for the commu- nity. As for the future, we are planning several initiatives for the promotion of the platform in the research community, as well as its active experi- mentation in real application scenarios.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: EOP architecture</figDesc><graphic url="image-1.png" coords="2,123.47,63.24,155.36,180.22" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" validated="false"><head>Table 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>EDAs results 

for specific domains. Particularly, the EOP plat-
form includes a language independent tool to build 
Wikipedia resources (Shnarch et al., 2009), as well 
as a language-independent framework for building 
distributional similarity resources like DIRT (Lin 
</table></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="2"> http://hltfbk.github.io/ Excitement-Open-Platform/</note>

			<note place="foot" n="3"> http://uima.apache.org/</note>

			<note place="foot" n="4"> Variables of the LHS may also map to null, when material of the LHS must be present but is deleted in the inference step.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="5"> http://www.excitement-project.eu/ index.php/results</note>

			<note place="foot" n="6"> https://github.com/</note>

			<note place="foot" n="7"> http://maven.apache.org/ 8 http://www.jfrog.com/ 9 http://jenkins-ci.org/ 10 http://pmd.sourceforge.net 11 http://www.gnu.org/licenses/gpl.html</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>This work was partially supported by the EC-funded project EXCITEMENT (FP7ICT-287923).</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Semantic inference at the lexicalsyntactic level</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Roy</forename><surname>Bar-Haim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ido</forename><surname>Dagan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Iddo</forename><surname>Greental</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Eyal</forename><surname>Shnarch</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of AAAI</title>
		<meeting>AAAI<address><addrLine>Vancouver, BC</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="871" to="876" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Sixth PASCAL Recognizing Textual Entailment Challenge</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Luisa</forename><surname>Bentivogli</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Peter</forename><surname>Clark</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ido</forename><surname>Dagan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hoa</forename><forename type="middle">Trang</forename><surname>Dang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Danilo</forename><surname>Giampiccolo</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of TAC</title>
		<meeting>TAC<address><addrLine>Gaithersburg, MD</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Recognizing textual entailment: Rational, evaluation and approaches</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bill</forename><surname>Ido Dagan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bernardo</forename><surname>Dolan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dan</forename><surname>Magnini</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Roth</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Natural Language Engineering</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="i" to="xvii" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Third PASCAL Recognising Textual Entailment Challenge</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Danilo</forename><surname>Giampiccolo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bernardo</forename><surname>Magnini</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ido</forename><surname>Dagan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bill</forename><surname>Dolan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the ACL-PASCAL Workshop on Textual Entailment and Paraphrasing</title>
		<meeting>the ACL-PASCAL Workshop on Textual Entailment and Paraphrasing<address><addrLine>Prague, Czech Republic</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Darmstadt knowledge processing repository based on UIMA</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Iryna</forename><surname>Gurevych</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Max</forename><surname>Mühlhäuser</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christof</forename><surname>Müller</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jürgen</forename><surname>Steimle</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Markus</forename><surname>Weimer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Torsten</forename><surname>Zesch</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the First Workshop on Unstructured Information Management Architecture</title>
		<meeting>the First Workshop on Unstructured Information Management Architecture<address><addrLine>Tübingen, Germany</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Moses: Open Source Toolkit for Statistical Machine Translation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Philipp</forename><surname>Koehn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hieu</forename><surname>Hoang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alexandra</forename><surname>Birch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chris</forename><surname>Callison-Burch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marcello</forename><surname>Federico</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nicola</forename><surname>Bertoldi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Brooke</forename><surname>Cowan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wade</forename><surname>Shen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christine</forename><surname>Moran</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Richard</forename><surname>Zens</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chris</forename><surname>Dyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ondrej</forename><surname>Bojar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alexandra</forename><surname>Constantin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Evan</forename><surname>Herbst</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the ACL demo session</title>
		<meeting>the ACL demo session<address><addrLine>Prague, Czech Republic</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="177" to="180" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Recognizing textual entailment with tree edit distance algorithms</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Milen</forename><surname>Kouylekov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bernardo</forename><surname>Magnini</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the First PASCAL Challenges Workshop on Recognising Textual Entailment</title>
		<meeting>the First PASCAL Challenges Workshop on Recognising Textual Entailment<address><addrLine>Southampton, UK</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="17" to="20" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Discovery of Inference Rules for Question Answering</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dekang</forename><surname>Lin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Patrick</forename><surname>Pantel</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Natural Language Engineering</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="343" to="360" />
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Automatic retrieval and clustering of similar words</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dekang</forename><surname>Lin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of ACL/COLING</title>
		<meeting>ACL/COLING<address><addrLine>Montréal, Canada</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="768" to="774" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Using UIMA to structure an open platform for textual entailment</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gil</forename><surname>Tae-</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sebastian</forename><surname>Noh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Padó</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 3rd Workshop on Unstructured Information Management Architecture</title>
		<meeting>the 3rd Workshop on Unstructured Information Management Architecture</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Design and realization of a modular architecture for textual entailment</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sebastian</forename><surname>Padó</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tae-Gil</forename><surname>Noh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Asher</forename><surname>Stern</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rui</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Roberto</forename><surname>Zanoli</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="doi">doi:10.1017/S1351324913000351</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Natural Language Engineering</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Extracting lexical reference rules from Wikipedia</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Eyal</forename><surname>Shnarch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Libby</forename><surname>Barak</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ido</forename><surname>Dagan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of ACL-IJCNLP</title>
		<meeting>ACL-IJCNLP</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="450" to="458" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Singapore</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Efficient search for transformation-based inference</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Asher</forename><surname>Stern</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Roni</forename><surname>Stern</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ido</forename><surname>Dagan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ariel</forename><surname>Felner</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of ACL</title>
		<meeting>ACL<address><addrLine>Jeju Island, South Korea</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="283" to="291" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Recognizing textual entailment using a subsequence kernel method</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rui</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Günter</forename><surname>Neumann</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of AAAI</title>
		<meeting>AAAI<address><addrLine>Vancouver, BC</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="937" to="945" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
