<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T10:02+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Cross-language and Cross-encyclopedia Article Linking Using Mixed-language Topic Model and Hypernym Translation</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date>June 23-25</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yu-Chun</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chun-Kai</forename><surname>Wu</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Richard</forename><surname>Tzong</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Han</forename><surname>Tsai</surname></persName>
							<email>thtsai@csie.ncu.edu.tw</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Department of CSIE</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Department of CSIE National</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">National Taiwan University Taipei</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="TW">Taiwan</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Department of CSIE</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Tsinghua University Hsinchu</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="TW">Taiwan</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="institution">National Central University Chungli</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="TW">Taiwan</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Cross-language and Cross-encyclopedia Article Linking Using Mixed-language Topic Model and Hypernym Translation</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 52nd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (Short Papers)</title>
						<meeting>the 52nd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (Short Papers) <address><addrLine>Baltimore, Maryland, USA</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="586" to="591"/>
							<date type="published">June 23-25</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Creating cross-language article links among different online encyclopedias is now an important task in the unification of multilingual knowledge bases. In this paper, we propose a cross-language article linking method using a mixed-language topic model and hypernym translation features based on an SVM model to link English Wikipedia and Chinese Baidu Baike, the most widely used Wiki-like encyclopedia in China. To evaluate our approach, we compile a data set from the top 500 Baidu Baike articles and their corresponding English Wiki articles. The evaluation results show that our approach achieves 80.95% in MRR and 87.46% in recall. Our method does not heavily depend on linguistic characteristics and can be easily extended to generate cross-language article links among different online encyclopedias in other languages.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Online encyclopedias are among the most fre- quently used Internet services today.</p><p>One of the largest and best known online encyclopedias is Wikipedia. Wikipedia has many language ver- sions, and articles in one language contain hyper- links to corresponding pages in other languages. However, the coverage of different language ver- sions of Wikipedia is very inconsistent. However, there are alternatives to Wikipedia for some languages. In China, for example Baidu Baike and Hudong are the largest encyclopedia sites, containing more than 6.2 and 7 million Chi- nese articles respectively. Similarly, in Korea, Naver Knowledge Encyclopedia has a large pres- ence.</p><p>Since alternative encyclopedias like Baidu Baike are larger (by article count) and growing faster than the Chinese Wikipedia, it is worth- while to investigate creating cross-language links among different online encyclopedias. Several works have focused on creating cross-language links between Wikipedia language versions ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Oh et al., 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Sorg and Cimiano, 2008)</ref> or find- ing a cross-language link for each entity mention in a Wikipedia article, namely Cross-Language Link Discovery (CLLD) ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Tang et al., 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b4">McNamee et al., 2011</ref>). These works were able to exploit the link structure and metadata common to all Wikipedia language versions. However, when linking between different online encyclope- dia platforms this is more difficult as many of these structural features are different or not shared. To date, little research has been done into linking be- tween encyclopedias on different platforms.</p><p>Title translation is an effective and widely used method of creating cross-language links between encyclopedia articles. ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Wang et al., 2012</ref>; Adafre and de <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Rijke, 2005</ref>) However, title translation alone is not always sufficient. In some cases, for example, the titles of corresponding articles in dif- ferent languages do not even match. Other meth- ods must be used along with title translation to cre- ate a more robust linking tool.</p><p>In this paper, we propose a method compris- ing title and hypernym translation and mixed- language topic model methods to select and link related articles between the English Wikipedia and Baidu Baike online encyclopedias. We also com- pile a suitable dataset from the above two ency- clopedias to evaluate the linking accuracy of our method.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Method</head><p>Cross-language article linking between different encyclopedias can be formulated as follows: For each encyclopedia K, a collection of human- written articles, can be defined as</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">K = {a i } n i=1</formula><p>, where a i is an article in K and n is the size of K. Article linking can then be defined as fol- lows: Given two encyclopedia K 1 and K 2 , cross- language article linking is the task of finding the corresponding equivalent article a j from encyclo- pedia K 2 for each article a i from encyclopedia K 1 . Equivalent articles are articles that describe the same topic in different languages.</p><p>Our approach to cross-language article linking comprises two stages: candidate selection, which produces a list of candidate articles, and candidate ranking, which ranks that list.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">Candidate Selection</head><p>Since knowledge bases (KB) may contain millions of articles, comparison between all possible pairs in two knowledge bases is time-consuming and sometimes impractical. To avoid brute-force com- parison, we first select plausible candidate articles on which to focus our efforts. To extract possible candidates, two similarity calculation methods are carried out: title matching and title similarity.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1.1">Title Matching</head><p>In our title matching method, we formulate can- didate selection as an English-Chinese cross- language information retrieval (CLIR) problem <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Schönhofen et al., 2008)</ref>, in which every English article's title is treated as a query and all the arti- cles in the Chinese encyclopedia are treated as the documents. We employ the two main CLIR meth- ods: query translation and document translation.</p><p>In query translation, we translate the title of ev- ery English article into Chinese and then use these translated titles as queries to retrieve articles from the Chinese encyclopedia. In document transla- tion, we translate the contents of the entire Chinese encyclopedia into English and then search them using the original English titles. The top 100 re- sults for the query-translation and the top 100 re- sults for document-translation steps are unionized. The resulting list contains our title-matching can- didates.</p><p>For the query-and document-translation steps, we use the Lucene search engine with similar- ity scores calculated by the Okapi BM25 ranking function ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Beaulieu et al., 1997</ref>). We separate all words in the translated and original English article titles with the "OR" operator before submission to the search engine. For all E-C and C-E translation tasks, we use Google Translate.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1.2">Title Similarity</head><p>In the title similarity method, every Chinese arti- cle title is represented as a vector, and each dis- tinct character in all these titles is a dimension of all vectors. The title of each English article is translated into Chinese and represented as a vec- tor. Then, cosine similarity between this vector and the vector of each Chinese title is measured as title similarity.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">Candidate Ranking</head><p>The second stage of our approach is to score each viable candidate using a supervised learning method, and then sort all candidates in order of score from high to low as final output.</p><p>Each article x i in KB K 1 can be represented by a feature vector</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">x i = (f 1 (x i ), f 2 (x i ), . . . , f n (x i )).</formula><p>Also, we have y j = (f 1 (y j ), f 2 (y j ), . . . , f n (y j )) for a candidate article y j in KB K 2 . Then, individual feature functions F k (x i , y j ) are based on the feature properties of both article a i and a j . The top pre- dicted corresponding article y j in the knowledge base K 2 for an input article x i in K 1 should receive a higher score than any other entity in K 2 , a m ∈ K 2 , m = j. We use the support vector machine (SVM) approach to determine the probability of each pair (x i , y j ) being equivalent. Our SVM model's features are described below.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Title Matching and Title Similarity Feature (Baseline)</head><p>We use the results of title matching and title sim- ilarity from the candidate selection stage as two features for the candidate ranking stage. The sim- ilarity values generated by title matching and title similarity are used directly as real value features in the SVM model.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Mixed-language Topic Model Feature (MTM)</head><p>For a linked English-Chinese article pair, the dis- tribution of words used in each usually shows some convergence. The two semantically corre- sponding articles often have many related terms, which results in clusters of specific words. If two articles do not describe the same topic, the distri- bution of terms is often scattered. ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Misra et al., 2008</ref>) Thus, the distribution of terms is good mea- surement of article similarity.</p><p>Because the number of all possible words is too large, we adopt a topic model to gather the words into some latent topics. For this feature, we use the Latent Dirichlet Allocation (LDA) ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Blei et al., 2003)</ref>. LDA can be seen as a typical probabilistic approach to latent topic computation. Each topic is represented by a distribution of words, and each word has a probability score used to measure its contribution to the topic. To train the LDA model, the pair English and Chinese articles are concate- nated into a single document. English and Chinese terms are all regarded as terms of the same lan- guage and the LDA topic model, namely mixed- language topic model, generates both English and Chinese terms for each latent topic. Then, for each English article and Chinese candidate pair in test- ing, the LDA model provides the distribution of the latent topics. Next, we can use entropy to mea- sure the distribution of topics. The entropy of the estimated topic distribution of a related article is expected to be lower than that of an unrelated ar- ticle. We can calculate the entropy of the distribu- tion as a value for SVM. The entropy is defined as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">H = − T j=1 θ dj log θ dj</formula><p>where T is the number of latent topics, θ dj is the topic distribution of a given topic j.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Hypernym Translation Feature (HT)</head><p>The first sentence of an encyclopedia article usu- ally contains the title of the article. It may also contain a hypernym that defines the category of the article. For example, the first sentence of the "iPad" article in the English Wikipedia begins, "iPad is a line of tablet computers designed and marketed by Apple Inc. . ." In this sentence, the term "tablet computers" is the hypernym of iPad. These extracted hypernyms can be treated as arti- cle categories. Therefore, articles containing the same hypernym are likely to belong to the same category.</p><p>In this study, we only carry out title hypernym extraction on the first sentences of English articles due to the looser syntactic structure of Chinese. To generate dependency parse trees for the sentences, we adopt the Stanford Dependency Parser. Then, we manually designed seven patterns to extract hy- pernyms from the parse tree structures. To demon- strate this idea, let us take the English article "The Hunger Games" for example. The first sentence of this article is "The Hunger Games is a 2008 young adult novel by American writer Suzanne Collins." Since article titles may be named entities or com- pound nouns, the dependency parser may mislabel them and thus output an incorrect parse tree. To avoid this problem, we first replace all instances of an article's title in the first sentence with pronouns. For example, the previous sentence is rewritten as "It is a 2008 young adult novel by American writer Suzanne Collins." Then, the dependency parser generates the following parse tree: Next, we apply our predefined syntactic patterns to extract the hypernym. (Hearst, 1992) If any pat- tern matches the structure of the dependency parse tree, the hypernym can be extracted. In the above example, the following pattern is matched:</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>NN</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>It</head><p>is NN nsubj cop nn <ref type="bibr">[target]</ref> In this pattern, the rightmost leaf is the hyper- nym target. Thus, we can extract the hypernym "novel" from the previous example. The term "novel" is the extracted hypernym of the English article "The Hunger Games".</p><p>After extracting the hypernym of the English ar- ticle, the hypernym is translated into Chinese. The value of this feature in the SVM model is calcu- lated as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">F hypernym (h) = log count(translated(h))</formula><p>where h is the hypernym, translated(h) is the Chinese translation of the term h.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>English Title Occurrence Feature (ETO)</head><p>In a Baidu Baike article, the first sentence may contain a parenthetical translation of the main ti- tle. For example, the first sentence of the Chinese article on San Francisco is "旧金山（San Fran- cisco），又译'圣弗朗西斯科'、'三藩市'。". We regard the appearance of the English title in the first sentence of a Baidu Baike article as a bi- nary feature: If the English title appears in the first sentence, the value of this feature is 1; otherwise, the value is 0.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Evalutaion</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Evaluation Dataset</head><p>In order to evaluate the performance of cross- language article linking between English Wikiep- dia and Chinese Baidu Baike, we compile an English-Chinese evaluation dataset from Wikipedia and Baidu Baike online encyclopedias. First, our spider crawls the entire contents of En- glish Wikipedia and Chinese Baidu Baike. Since the two encyclopedias' article formats differ, we copy the information in each article (title, content, category, etc.) into a standardized XML structure. In order to generate the gold standard evalua- tion sets of correct English and Chinese article pairs, we automatically collect English-Chinese inter-language links from Wikipedia. For pairs that have both English and Chinese articles, the Chinese article title is regarded as the translation of the English one. Next, we check if there is a Chinese article in Baidu Baike with exactly the same title as the one in Chinese Wikipedia. If so, the corresponding English Wikipedia article and the Baidu Baike article are paired in the gold standard.</p><p>To evaluate the performance of our method on linking different types of encyclopedia articles, we compile a set containing the most popular articles. We select the top 500 English-Chinese article pairs with the highest page view counts in Baidu Baike. This set represents the articles people in China are most interested in.</p><p>Because our approach uses an SVM model, the data set should be split into training and test sets. For statistical generality, each data set is randomly split 4:1 (training:test) 30 times. The final evalua- tion results are calculated as the mean of the aver- age of these 30 evaluation sets.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Evaluation Metrics</head><p>To measure the quality of cross-language entity linking, we use the following three metrics. For each English article queries, ten output Baidu Baike candidates are generated in a ranked list. To define the metrics, we use following notations: N is the number of English query; r i,j is j-th correct Chinese article for i-th English query; c i,k is k-th candiate the system output for i-th English query.</p><p>Top-k Accuracy (ACC) ACC measures the correctness of the first candi- date in the candidate list. ACC = 1 means that all top candidates are correctly linked (i.e. they match one of the references), and ACC = 0 means that none of the top candidates is correct.</p><formula xml:id="formula_4">ACC = 1 N N i=1 1 if ∃r i,j : r i,j = c i,k 0 otherwise Mean Reciprocal Rank (MRR)</formula><p>Traditional MRR measures any correct answer produced by the system from among the candi- dates. 1/MRR approximates the average rank of the correct transliteration. An MRR closer to 1 im- plies that the correct answer usually appears close to the top of the n-best lists.</p><formula xml:id="formula_5">RR i = min j 1 j if ∃r i,j , c i,k : r i,j = c i,k 0 otherwise M RR = 1 N N i=1 RR i</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Recall</head><p>Recall is the fraction of the retrieved articles that are relevant to the given query. Recall is used to measure the performance of the candidate selec- tion method. If the candidate selection method can actually select the correct Chinese candidate, the recall will be high.</p><p>Recall = |relevant articles| ∩ |retrieved articles| |relevant articles|</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3">Evaluation Results</head><p>The overall results of our method achieves 80.95% in MRR and 87.46% in recall. <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref> shows the top-k ACC from the top 1 to 5. These results show that our method is very effective in linking articles in English Wikipedia to those in Baidu Baike. In order to show the benefits of each feature used in the SVM model, we conduct a experiment to test the performance of different feature combi- nations. Because title similarity of the articles is a widely used method, we choose English and Chi- nese title similarity as the baseline. Then, another feature is added to each configuration until all the features have been added.  In the results, we can observe that mix-language topic model, hypernym, and English title oc- curence features all noticeably improve the perfor- mance. Combining two of these three feature has more improvement and the combination of all the features achieves the best.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Discussion</head><p>Although our method can effectively generate cross-language links with high accuracy, some correct candidates are not ranked number one. Af- ter examining the results, we can divide errors into several categories:</p><p>The first kind of error is due to large literal dif- ferences between the English and Chinese titles. For example, for the English article "Nero", our approach ranks the Chinese candidate "尼禄王" ("King Nero") as number one, instead of the cor- rect answer "尼禄·克劳狄乌斯·德鲁苏斯·日耳 曼尼库斯" (the number two candidate). The title of the correct Chinese article is the full name of the Roman Emperor Nero (Nero Claudius Drusus Germanicus). The false positive "尼禄王" is a his- torical novel about the life of the Emperor Nero. Because of the large difference in title lengths, the value of the title similarity feature between the En- glish article "Nero" and the corresponding Chi- nese article is low. Such length differences may cause the SVM model to rank the correct answer lower when the difference of other features are not so significant because the contents of the Chinese candidates are similar.</p><p>The second error type is caused by articles that have duplicates in Baidu Baike. For example, for the English article "Jensen Ackles", our approach generates a link to the Chinese article "Jensen" in Baidu Baike. However, there is another Baidu article "詹森·阿克斯" ("Jensen Ackles"). These two articles both describe the actor Jensen Ackles. In this case, our approach still generates a correct link, although it is not the one in the gold standard.</p><p>The third error type is translation errors. For ex- ample, the English article "Raccoon" is linked to the Baidu article "狸" (raccoon dog), though the correct one is "浣熊" (raccoon). The reason is that Google Translate provides the translation "狸" in- stead of "浣熊".</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Conclusion</head><p>Cross-language article linking is the task of creat- ing links between online encyclopedia articles in different languages that describe the same content. We propose a method based on article hypernym and topic model to link English Wikipedia articles to corresponding Chinese Baidu Baike articles. Our method comprises two stages: candidate se- lection and candidate ranking. We formulate can- didate selection as a cross-language information retrieval task based on the title similarity between English and Chinese articles. In candidate rank- ing, we employ several features of the articles in our SVM model. To evaluate our method, we com- pile a dataset from English Wikipedia and Baidu Baike, containing the 500 most popular Baidu ar- ticles. Evaluation results of our method show an MRR of up to 80.95% and a recall of 87.46%. This shows that our method is effective in generating cross-language links between English Wikipedia and Baidu Baike with high accuracy. Our method does not heavily depend on linguistic characteris- tics and can be easily extended to generate cross- language article links among different encyclope- dias in other languages.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" validated="false"><head>Table 1 shows</head><label>1</label><figDesc>the statistics of inter-language link pages in the English and Chinese editions in February 2014. The total number of Chinese articles is about one-quarter of English ones, and only 2.3% of English articles have inter-language links to their Chinese versions. * corresponding author</figDesc><table>Articles 
Inter-language Links Ratio 
zh 755,628 zh2en 
486,086 
64.3% 
en 4,470,246 en2zh 
106,729 
2.3% 

Table 1: Inter-Language Links in Wikipedia 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" validated="false"><head>Table 2 shows</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>the final 
results of different feature combinations. </table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3" validated="false"><head>Table 2 : MRRs of Feature Combinations</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table></table></figure>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Discovering missing links in wikipedia</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Sisay Fissaha Adafre And Maarten De Rijke</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 3rd international workshop on Link discovery (LinkKDD &apos;05)</title>
		<meeting>the 3rd international workshop on Link discovery (LinkKDD &apos;05)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Okapi at TREC5</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Beaulieu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Gatford</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Robertson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Walker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Williams</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the fifth Text REtrieval Conference (TREC-5)</title>
		<meeting>the fifth Text REtrieval Conference (TREC-5)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="143" to="166" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Latent dirichlet allocation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Blei</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Andrew</forename><forename type="middle">Y</forename><surname>Ng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michael</forename><forename type="middle">I</forename><surname>Jordan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Machine Learning Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4-5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="993" to="1022" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Automatic acquisition of hyponyms from large text corpora</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marti</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Hearst</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 14th conference on Computational linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the 14th conference on Computational linguistics</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1992" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Crosslanguage entity linking</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Paul</forename><surname>Mcnamee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">James</forename><surname>Mayfield</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dawn</forename><surname>Lawrie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Douglas</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Oard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David S</forename><surname>Doermann</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of International Joint Con-ference on Natural Language Processing (IJCNLP)</title>
		<meeting>International Joint Con-ference on Natural Language Processing (IJCNLP)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="255" to="263" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Using lda to detect semantically incoherent documents</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hemant</forename><surname>Misra</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Olivier</forename><surname>Cappe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">François</forename><surname>Yvon</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Twelfth Conference on Computational Natural Language Learning (CoNLL &apos;08)</title>
		<meeting>the Twelfth Conference on Computational Natural Language Learning (CoNLL &apos;08)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Enriching multilingual language resources by discovering missing cross-language links in wikipedia</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jong-Hoon</forename><surname>Oh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Daisuke</forename><surname>Kawahara</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kiyotaka</forename><surname>Uchimoto</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kentaro</forename><surname>Jun&amp;apos;ichi Kazama</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Torisawa</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the</title>
		<meeting>the</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
			</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ACM International Conference on Web Intelligence and Intelligent Agent Technology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="322" to="328" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Cross-language retrieval with wikipedia. Advances in Multilingual and Multimodal Information Retrieval</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P`</forename><surname>Eter Schönhofen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Andràs</forename><surname>Benczùr</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Istvàn B` Irò</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Csalogàny</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Lecture Notes in Computer Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5152</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="72" to="79" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Enriching the crosslingual link structure of wikipedia-a classification-based approach</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Philipp</forename><surname>Sorg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Philipp</forename><surname>Cimiano</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the AAAI 2008 Workshop on Wikipedia and Artifical Intelligence</title>
		<meeting>the AAAI 2008 Workshop on Wikipedia and Artifical Intelligence</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="49" to="54" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Overview of the ntcir-10 cross-lingual link discovery task</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ling-Xiang</forename><surname>Tang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">In-Su</forename><surname>Kang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Fuminori</forename><surname>Kimura</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yihsun</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Andrew</forename><surname>Trotman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Shlomo</forename><surname>Geva</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yue</forename><surname>Xu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Tenth NTCIR Workshop Meeting</title>
		<meeting>the Tenth NTCIR Workshop Meeting</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Cross-lingual knowledge linking across wiki knowledge bases</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Zhichun</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Juanzi</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Zhigang</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jie</forename><surname>Tang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 21st international conference on World Wide Web</title>
		<meeting>the 21st international conference on World Wide Web</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>WWW</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
