<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T10:42+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Strategies for Contiguous Multiword Expression Analysis and Dependency Parsing</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
				<availability status="unknown"><p>Copyright Association for Computational Linguistics</p>
				</availability>
				<date>June 23-25 2014. 2014</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marie</forename><surname>Candito</surname></persName>
							<email>marie.candito@ linguist.univ-paris-diderot.fr</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Alpage Paris Diderot Univ INRIA</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">Université Paris-Est LIGM CNRS</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Matthieu</forename><surname>Constant</surname></persName>
							<email>Matthieu.Constant@ u-pem.fr</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Alpage Paris Diderot Univ INRIA</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">Université Paris-Est LIGM CNRS</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Strategies for Contiguous Multiword Expression Analysis and Dependency Parsing</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 52nd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
						<meeting>the 52nd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics <address><addrLine>Baltimore, Maryland, USA</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="743" to="753"/>
							<date type="published">June 23-25 2014. 2014</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>In this paper, we investigate various strategies to predict both syntactic dependency parsing and contiguous multiword expression (MWE) recognition, testing them on the dependency version of French Tree-bank (Abeillé and Barrier, 2004), as instantiated in the SPMRL Shared Task (Seddah et al., 2013). Our work focuses on using an alternative representation of syntactically regular MWEs, which captures their syntactic internal structure. We obtain a system with comparable performance to that of previous works on this dataset, but which predicts both syntactic dependencies and the internal structure of MWEs. This can be useful for capturing the various degrees of semantic composi-tionality of MWEs.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>A real-life parsing system should comprise the recognition of multi-word expressions (MWEs 1 ), first because downstream semantic-oriented ap- plications need some marking in order to dis- tinguish between regular semantic composition and the typical semantic non-compositionality of MWEs. Second, MWE information, is intuitively supposed to help parsing.</p><p>That intuition is confirmed in a classical but non-realistic setting in which gold MWEs are pre- grouped ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Arun and Keller, 2005;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Nivre and Nilsson, 2004;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b14">EryiˇgitEryiˇgit et al., 2011</ref>). But the situation is much less clear when switching to automatic MWE prediction. While <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Cafferkey et al. (2007)</ref> report a small improvement on the pure parsing <ref type="bibr">1</ref> Multiword expressions can be roughly defined as con- tinuous or discontinuous sets of tokens, which either do not exhibit full freedom in lexical selection or whose meaning is not fully compositional. We focus in this paper on contiguous multiword expressions, also known as "words with spaces". task when using external MWE lexicons to help English parsing,  report re- sults on the joint MWE recognition and parsing task, in which errors in MWE recognition allevi- ate their positive effect on parsing performance.</p><p>While the realistic scenario of syntactic pars- ing with automatic MWE recognition (either done jointly or in a pipeline) has already been investi- gated in constituency parsing <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">(Green et al., 2011;</ref>, the French dataset of the SPMRL 2013 Shared Task (  only recently provided the opportunity to evaluate this scenario within the framework of dependency syntax. <ref type="bibr">2</ref> In such a sce- nario, a system predicts dependency trees with marked groupings of tokens into MWEs. The trees show syntactic dependencies between se- mantically sound units (made of one or several tokens), and are thus particularly appealing for downstream semantic-oriented applications, as de- pendency trees are considered to be closer to predicate-argument structures.</p><p>In this paper, we investigate various strate- gies for predicting from a tokenized sentence both MWEs and syntactic dependencies, using the French dataset of the SPMRL 13 Shared Task. We focus on the use of an alternative representation for those MWEs that exhibit regular internal syn- tax. The idea is to represent these using regular syntactic internal structure, while keeping the se- mantic information that they are MWEs.</p><p>We devote section 2 to related work. In sec- tion 3, we describe the French dataset, how MWEs are originally represented in it, and we present and motivate an alternative representation. Sec- tion 4 describes the different architectures we test for predicting both syntax and MWEs. Section 5 presents the external resources targeted to improve MWE recognition. We describe experiments and discuss their results in section 6 and conclude in section 7.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Related work</head><p>We gave in introduction references to previous work on predicting MWEs and constituency pars- ing. To our knowledge, the first works 3 on predict- ing both MWEs and dependency trees are those presented to the SPMRL 2013 Shared Task that provided scores for French (which is the only dataset containing MWEs). <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Constant et al. (2013)</ref> proposed to combine pipeline and joint systems in a reparser ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">Sagae and Lavie, 2006</ref>), and ranked first at the Shared Task. Our contribution with respect to that work is the representation of the internal syntactic structure of MWEs, and use of MWE-specific features for the joint system. The system of <ref type="bibr">Björkelund et al. (2013)</ref> ranked second on French, though with close UAS/LAS scores. It is a less language-specific system that reranks n- best dependency parses from 3 parsers, informed with features from predicted constituency trees. It uses no feature nor treatment specific to MWEs as it focuses on the general aim of the Shared Task, namely coping with prediction of morphological and syntactic analysis.</p><p>Concerning related work on the representa- tion of MWE internal structure, we can cite the Prague Dependency Bank, which captures both regular syntax of non-compositional MWEs and their MWE status, in two distinct annotation lay- ers <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Bejček and Stranak, 2010)</ref>. Our represen- tation also resembles that of light-verb construc- tions (LVC) in the hungarian dependency treebank ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">Vincze et al., 2010)</ref>: the construction has regular syntax, and a suffix is used on labels to express it is a LVC ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Vincze et al., 2013</ref>).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Data: MWEs in Dependency Trees</head><p>The data we use is the SPMRL 13 dataset for French, in dependency format. It contains pro- jective dependency trees that were automatically derived from the latest status of the French Tree- bank ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Abeillé and Barrier, 2004</ref>), which con- sists of constituency trees for sentences from the newspaper Le Monde, manually annotated with phrase structures, morphological information, and grammatical functional tags for dependents of verbs. The Shared Task used an enhanced version of the constituency-to-dependency conversion of , with different handling of MWEs. The dataset consists of 18535 sentences, split into 14759, 1235 and 2541 sentences for training, development, and final evaluation respec- tively.</p><p>We describe below the flat representation of MWEs in this dataset, and the modified represen- tation for regular MWEs that we propose.  <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref>: French dependency tree for L'abus de biens sociaux fut dénoncé en vain (literally the misuse of assets social was denounced in vain, meaning The misuse of corporate assets was de- nounced in vain), containing two MWEs (in red). Top: original flat representation. Bottom: Tree af- ter regular MWEs structuring.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">MWEs in Gold Data: Flat representation</head><p>In gold data, the MWEs appear in an expanded flat format: each MWE bears a part-of-speech and consists of a sequence of tokens (hereafter the "components" of the MWE), each having their proper POS, lemma and morphological features.</p><p>In the dependency trees, there is no "node" for a MWE as a whole, but one node per MWE com- ponent (more generally one node per token). The first component of a MWE is taken as the head of the MWE. All subsequent components of the MWE depend on the first one, with the special label dep_cpd (hence the name flat represen-tation). Furthermore, the first MWE component bears a feature mwehead equal to the POS of the MWE. An example is shown in <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref>. The MWE en vain (pointlessly) is an adverb, contain- ing a preposition and an adjective. The latter de- pends on former, which bears mwehead=ADV+. The algorithm to recover MWEs is: any node having dependents with the dep_cpd label forms a MWE with such dependents.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Alternative representation for regular MWEs</head><p>In the alternative representation we propose, ir- regular MWEs are unchanged and appear as flat MWEs (e.g. en vain in <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref> has pattern prepo- sition+adjective, which is not considered regular for an adverb, and is thus unchanged). Regular MWEs appear with 'structured' syntax: we mod- ify the tree structure to recover the regular syn- tactic dependencies. For instance, in the bottom tree of the figure, biens is attached to the prepo- sition, and the adjective sociaux is attached to bi- ens, with regular labels. Structured MWEs can- not be spotted using the tree topology and la- bels only. Features are added for that purpose: the syntactic head of the structured MWE bears a regmwehead for the POS of the MWE (abus in <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref>), and the other components of the MWE bear a regcomponent feature (the orange tokens in <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref>). <ref type="bibr">4</ref> With this representation, the algorithm to recover regular MWEs is: any node bearing regmwehead forms a MWE with the set of direct or indirect dependents bearing a regcomponent feature.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2.1">Motivations</head><p>Our first motivation is to increase the quantity of information conveyed by the dependency trees, by distinguishing syntactic regularity and seman- tic regularity. Syntactically regular MWEs (here- after regular MWEs) show various degrees of se- mantic non-compositionality. For instance, in the French Treebank, population active (lit. active population, meaning 'working population') is a partially compositional MWE. Furthermore, some sequences are both syntactically and semantically regular, but encoded as MWE due to frozen lexi- cal selection. This is the case for déficit budgétaire (lit. budgetary deficit, meaning 'budget deficit'), because it is not possible to use déficit du bud- get (budget deficit). Our alternative representa- tion distinguishes between syntactic internal reg- ularity and semantic regularity. This renders the syntactic description more uniform and it provides an internal structure for regular MWEs, which is meaningful if the MWE is fully or partially com- positional. For instance, it is meaningful to have the adjective sociaux attach to biens instead of on the first component abus. Moreover, such a dis- tinction opens the way to a non-binary classifica- tion of MWE status: the various criteria leading to classify a sequence as MWE could be annotated separately and using nominal or scaled categories for each criteria. For instance, déficit budgétaire could be marked as fully compositional, but with frozen lexical selection. Further, annotation is of- ten incoherent for the MWEs with both regular syntax and a certain amount of semantic compo- sitionality, the same token sequence (with same meaning) being sometimes annotated as MWE and sometimes not.</p><p>More generally, keeping a regular representa- tion would allow to better deal with the interac- tion between idiomatic status and regular syntax, such as the insertion of modifiers on MWE sub- parts (e.g. make a quick decision).</p><p>Finally, using regular syntax for MWEs pro- vides a more uniform training set. For instance for a sequence N1 preposition N2, though some exter- nal attachments might vary depending on whether the sequence forms a MWE or not, some may not, and the internal dependency structure (N1 → (preposition → N2)) is quite regular. One objec- tive of the current work is to investigate whether this increased uniformity eases parsing or whether it is mitigated by the additional difficulty of find- ing the internal structure of a MWE.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Total</head><p>Nb of regular MWEs nb of  <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>: Total number of MWEs and number of regular MWEs in training, development and test set (and broken down by POS of MWE).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2.2">Implementation</head><p>We developed an ad hoc program for structur- ing the regular MWEs in gold data. MWEs are first classified as regular or irregular, using reg- ular expressions over the sequence of parts-of- speech within the MWE. To define the regular expressions, we grouped gold MWEs according to the pair [global POS of the MWE + sequence of POS of the MWE components], and designed regular expressions to match the most frequent patterns that looked regular according to our lin- guistic knowledge. The internal structure for the matching MWEs was built deterministically, us- ing heuristics favoring local attachments. 5 <ref type="table">Table 1</ref> shows the proportions of MWEs classified as regu- lar, and thus further structured. About half MWEs are structured, and about two thirds of structured MWEs are nouns. For predicted parses with structured MWEs, we use an inverse transformation of structured MWEs into flat MWEs, for evaluation against the gold data. When a predicted structured MWE is flat- tened, all the dependents of any token of the MWE that are not themselves belonging to the MWE are attached to the head component of the MWE.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3">Integration of MWE features into labels</head><p>In some experiments, we make use of alterna- tive representations, which we refer later as "la- beled representation", in which the MWE features are incorporated in the dependency labels, so that MWE composition and/or the POS of the MWE be totally contained in the tree topology and labels, and thus predictable via dependency parsing. <ref type="figure">Fig- ure</ref> shows the labeled representation for the sen- tence of <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref>.</p><p>For flat MWEs, the only missing information is the MWE part-of-speech: we concatenate it to the dep_cpd labels. For instance, the arc from en to vain is relabeled dep_cpd_ADV. For struc- tured MWEs, in order to get full MWE account within the tree structure and labels, we need to in- corporate both the MWE POS, and to mark it as <ref type="bibr">5</ref> The six regular expressions that we obtained cover nomi- nal, prepositional, adverbial and verbal compounds. We man- ually evaluated both the regular versus irregular classification and the structuring of regular MWEs on the first 200 MWEs of the development set. 113 of these were classified as regu- lar, and we judged that all of them were actually regular, and were correctly structured. Among the 87 classified as irregu- lar, 7 should have been tagged as regular and structured. For 4 of them, the classification error is due to errors on the (gold) POS of the MWE components.  <ref type="figure">Figure 2</ref>: Integration of all MWE information into labels for the example of <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref>.</p><p>belonging to a MWE. The suffixed label has the form FCT_r_POS. For instance, in bottom tree of <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref>, arcs pointing to the non-head compo- nents (de, biens, sociaux) are suffixed with _r to mark them as belonging to a structured MWE, and with _N since the MWE is a noun.</p><p>In both cases, this label suffixing is translated back into features for evaluation against gold data.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Architectures for MWE Analysis and Parsing</head><p>The architectures we investigated vary depending on whether the MWE status of sequences of to- kens is predicted via dependency parsing or via an external tool (described in section 5), and this di- chotomy applies both to structured MWEs and flat MWEs. More precisely, we consider the following alternative for irregular MWEs:</p><p>• IRREG-MERGED: gold irregular MWEs are merged for training; for parsing, irregular MWEs are predicted externally, merged into one token at parsing time, and re-expanded into several tokens for evaluation;</p><p>• IRREG-BY-PARSER: the MWE status, flat topology and POS are all predicted via de- pendency parsing, using representations for training and parsing, with all information for irregular MWEs encoded in topology and la- bels (as for in vain in <ref type="figure">Figure 2</ref>).</p><p>For regular MWEs, their internal structure is al- ways predicted by the parser. For instance the un- labeled dependencies for abus de biens sociaux are the same, independently of predicting whether it forms a MWE or not. But we use two kinds of predictions for their MWE status and POS:</p><p>• REG-POST-ANNOTATION: the regular</p><p>MWEs are encoded/predicted as shown for abus de biens sociaux in bottom tree of <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref>, and their MWE status and POS is predicted after parsing, by an external tool.</p><p>• REG-BY-PARSER: all regular MWE infor- mation (topology, status, POS) is predicted via dependency parsing, using representa- tions with all information for regular MWEs encoded in topology and labels <ref type="figure">(Figure 2</ref>).  We obtain four architectures, schematized in ta- ble 2. We describe more precisely two of them, the other two being easily inferable:</p><p>JOINT-REG architecture:</p><p>• training set: irregular MWEs merged into one token, regular MWEs are structured, and integration of regular MWE information into the labels (FCT_r_POS). </p><note type="other">not distinguished: Uniform joint architecture: The joint systems perform syntactic parsing and MWE analysis via a single dependency parser, using representations as in 3.3.</note></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Uniform pipeline architecture:</head><p>• training set: MWEs merged into one token • parsing: (i) MWE analysis, (ii) merge of pre- dicted MWEs, (iii) tagging and morphologi- cal prediction, (iv) parsing For each architecture, we apply the appropriate normalization procedures on the predicted parses, in order to evaluate against (i) the pseudo-gold data in structured representation, and (ii) the gold data in flat representation.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Use of external MWE resources</head><p>In order to better deal with MWE prediction, we use external MWE resources, namely MWE lexi- cons and an MWE analyzer. Both resources help to predict MWE-specific features (section 5.3) to guide the MWE-aware dependency parser. More- over, in some of the architectures, the external MWE analyzer is used either to pre-group irreg- ular MWEs (for the architectures using IRREG- MERGED), or to post-annotate regular MWEs.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.1">MWE lexicons</head><p>MWE lexicons are exploited as sources of fea- tures for both the dependency parser and the ex- ternal MWE analyzer. In particular, two large- coverage general-language lexicons are used: the Lefff 6 lexicon <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">(Sagot, 2010)</ref>, which contains ap- proximately half a million inflected word forms, among which approx. 25, 000 are MWEs; and the DELA 7 <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Courtois, 2009;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Courtois et al., 1997</ref>) lexicon, which contains approx. one million in- flected forms, among which about 110, 000 are MWEs. These resources are completed with spe- cific lexicons freely available in the platform Uni- tex 8 : the toponym dictionary Prolex ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">Piton et al., 1999</ref>) and a dictionary of first names. Note that the lexicons do not include any information on the ir- regular or the regular status of the MWEs. In order to compare the MWEs present in the lexicons and those encoded in the French treebank, we applied the following procedure (hereafter called lexicon <ref type="bibr">6</ref> We use the version available in the POS tagger MElt <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(Denis and Sagot, 2009)</ref>. <ref type="bibr">7</ref> We use the version in the platform Unitex (http://igm.univ-mlv.fr/˜unitex). We had to convert the DELA POS tagset to that of the French Treebank.</p><p>8 http://igm.univ-mlv.fr/˜unitex lookup): in a given sentence, the maximum num- ber of non overlapping MWEs according to the lexicons are systematically marked as such. We obtain about 70% recall and 50% precision with respect to MWE spanning.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.2">MWE Analyzer</head><p>The MWE analyzer is a CRF-based sequential la- beler, which, given a tokenized text, jointly per- forms MWE segmentation and POS tagging (of simple tokens and of MWEs), both tasks mutu- ally helping each other <ref type="bibr">9</ref> . The MWE analyzer inte- grates, among others, features computed from the external lexicons described in section 5.1, which greatly improve POS tagging <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(Denis and Sagot, 2009)</ref> and MWE segmentation <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Constant and Tellier, 2012</ref>). The MWE analyzer also jointly classi- fies its predicted MWEs as regular or irregular (the distinction being learnt on gold training set, with structured MWEs cf. section 3.2).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.3">MWE-specific features</head><p>We introduce information from the external MWE resources in different ways: Flat MWE features: MWE information can be integrated as features to be used by the de- pendency parser. We tested to incorporate the MWE-specific features as defined in the gold flat representation (section 3.1): the mwehead=POS feature for the MWE head token, POS being the part-of-speech of the MWE; the component=y feature for the non-first MWE component. Switch: instead or on top of using the mwehead feature, we use the POS of the MWE instead of the POS of the first component of a flat MWE. For in- stance in <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref>, the token en gets pos=ADV in- stead of pos=P. The intuition behind this feature is that for an irregular MWE, the POS of the lin- early first component, which serves as head, is not always representative of the external distribution of the MWE. For regular MWEs, the usefulness of such a trick is less obvious. The first component of a regular MWE is not necessarily its head (for instance for a nominal MWE with internal pattern adjective+noun), so the switch trick could be detri- mental in such cases. 10 <ref type="bibr">9</ref> Note that in our experiments, we use this analyzer for MWE analysis only, and discard the POS tagging predic- tion. Tagging is performed along with lemmatization with the Morfette tool (section 6.1). <ref type="bibr">10</ref> We also experimented to use POS of MWE plus suffixes to force disjoint tagsets for single words, irregular MWEs and</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Experiments</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.1">Settings and evaluation metrics</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>MWE Analysis and Tagging:</head><p>For the MWE analyzer, we used the tool lgtagger 11 (version 1.1) with its default set of feature templates, and a 10-fold jackknifing on the training corpus.</p><p>Parser: We used the second-order graph-based parser available in Mate-tools 12 <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Bohnet, 2010)</ref>. We used the Anna3.3 version, in projective mode, with default feature sets and parameters proposed in the documentation, augmented or not with MWE-specific features, depending on the experiments.</p><p>Morphological prediction: Predicted lemmas, POS and morphology features are computed with Morfette version 0.3.5 ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Chrupała et al., 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b21">Seddah et al., 2010)</ref>  <ref type="bibr">13</ref> , using 10 iterations for the tagging perceptron, 3 iterations for the lemmatization perceptron, default beam size for the decoding of the joint prediction, and the Lefff (Sagot, 2010) as external lexicon used for out-of-vocabulary words. We performed a 10-fold jackknifing on the training corpus.</p><p>Evaluation metrics: we evaluate our parsing sys- tems by using the standard metrics for depen- dency parsing: Labeled Attachment Score (LAS) and Unlabeled Attachment Score (UAS), com- puted using all tokens including punctuation. To evaluate statistical significance of parsing perfor- mance differences, we use eval07.pl <ref type="bibr">14</ref> with -b op- tion, and then Dan Bikel's comparator. <ref type="bibr">15</ref> For MWEs, we use the Fmeasure for recognition of untagged MWEs (hereafter FUM) and for recog- nition of tagged MWEs (hereafter FTM).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.2">MWE-specific feature prediction</head><p>In all our experiments, for the switch trick (section 5.3), the POS of MWE is always predicted using the MWE analyzer. For the flat MWE features, we experimented both with features predicted by the MWE analyzer, and with features predicted using the external lexicons mentioned in section 5.1 (us- ing the lexicon lookup procedure  <ref type="table">Table 3</ref>: Baseline and best results for the four MWE+parsing architectures on the dev set (see text for statistical significance evaluation). The UAS for the structured representation is the same as the one for the labeled representation, and is not repeated.</p><p>prediction lead to fairly comparable results, so in all the following, the MWE features, when used, are predicted using the external lexicons.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.3">Tuning features for each architecture</head><p>We ran experiments for all value combinations of the following parameters: (i) the architecture, (ii) whether MWE features are used, whether the switch trick is applied or not (iii) for irregular MWEs and (iv) for regular MWEs. We performed evaluation of the predicted parses using the three representations described in sec- tion 3, namely flat, structured and labeled repre- sentations. In the last two cases, the evaluation is performed against an instance of the gold data automatically transformed to match the represen- tation type. Moreover, for the "labeled representa- tion" evaluation, though the MWE information in the predicted parses is obtained in various ways, depending on the architecture, we always map all this information in the dependency labels, to ob- tain predicted parses matching the "labeled repre- sentation". While the evaluation in flat represen- tation is the only one comparable to other works on this dataset, the other two evaluations provide useful information. In the "labeled representation" evaluation, the UAS provides a measure of syn- tactic attachments for sequences of words, inde- pendently of the (regular) MWE status of subse- quences. For the sequence abus de biens sociaux, suppose that the correct internal structure is pre- dicted, but not the MWE status. The UAS for labeled representation will be maximal, whereas for the flat representation, the last two tokens will count as incorrect for UAS. For LAS, in both cases the three last tokens will count as incorrect if the wrong MWE status is predicted. So to sum up on the "labeled evaluation", we obtain a LAS eval- uation for the whole task of parsing plus MWE recognition, but an UAS evaluation that penalizes less errors on MWE status, while keeping a rep- resentation that is richer: predicted parses contain not only the syntactic dependencies and MWE in- formation, but also a classification of MWEs into regular and irregular, and the internal syntactic structure of regular MWEs.</p><p>The evaluation on "structured representation" can be interpreted as an evaluation of the parsing task plus the recognition of irregular MWEs only: both LAS and UAS are measured independently of errors on regular MWE status (note the UAS is exactly the same than in the "labeled" case).</p><p>For each architecture, <ref type="table">Table 3</ref> shows the results for two systems: first the baseline system without any MWE features nor switches and immediately below the best settings for the architecture. The JOINT baseline corresponds to a "pure" joint sys- tem without external MWE resources (hence the minus sign for the first three columns). For each architecture except the PIPELINE one, differences between the baseline and the best setting are sta- tistically significant (p &lt; 0.01). Differences be- tween best PIPELINE and best JOINT-REG are not. Best JOINT has statistically significant dif- ference (p &lt; 0.01) over both best JOINT-REG and best PIPELINE. The situation for best JOINT- IRREG with respect to the other three is borderline (with various p-values depending on the metrics).</p><p>Concerning the tuning of parameters, it appears that the best setting is to use MWE-features, and switch for both regular and irregular MWEs, ex- cept for the pipeline architecture for which results without MWE features are slightly better. So over- all, informing the parser with independently pre-  <ref type="table">Table 4</ref>: Final results on test set for baseline and the best system for each architecture.</p><p>dicted POS of MWE has positive impact. The best architectures are JOINT and JOINT-IRREG, with the former slightly better than the latter for parsing metrics, though only some of the differ- ences are significant between the two. It can be noted though, that JOINT-IRREG performs over- all better on MWEs (last two columns of table 3), whereas JOINT performs better on irregular MWEs: the latter seems to be beneficial for pars- ing, but is less efficient to correctly spot the regular MWEs.</p><p>Concerning the three distinct representations, evaluating on structured representation (hence without looking at regular MWE status) leads to a rough 2 point performance increase for the LAS and a one point increase for the UAS, with respect to the evaluation against flat representation. This quantifies the additional difficulty of deciding for a regular sequence of tokens whether it forms a MWE or not. The evaluation on the labeled rep- resentation provides an evaluation of the full task (parsing, regular/irregular MWE recognition and regular MWEs structuring), with a UAS that is less impacted by errors on regular MWE status, while LAS reflects the full difficulty of the task. <ref type="bibr">16</ref> </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.4">Results on test set and comparison</head><p>We provide the final results on the test set in table 4. We compare the baseline JOINT sys- tem with the best system for all four reg/irreg architectures (cf. section 6.3). We observe the same general trend as in the development corpus, but with tinier differences. JOINT and JOINT- IRREG significantly outperform the baseline and the PIPELINE, on labeled representation and flat representation. We can see that there is no sig- nificant difference between JOINT and JOINT- <ref type="bibr">16</ref> The slight differences in LAS between the labeled and the flat representations are due to side effects of errors on MWE status: some wrong reattachments performed to obtain flat representation decrease the UAS, but also in some cases the LAS.  IRREG and between JOINT-REG and JOINT- IRREG. JOINT slightly outperforms JOINT-REG (p &lt; 0.05). On the structured representation, the two best systems (JOINT and JOINT-IRREG) sig- nificantly outperform the other systems (p &lt; 0.01 for all; p &lt; 0.05 for JOINT-REG). Moreover, we provide in table 5 a comparison of our best architecture with reg/irregular MWE distinction with other architectures that do not make this distinction, namely the two best com- parable systems designed for the SPMRL Shared Task ( : the pipeline sim- ple parser based on Mate-tools of <ref type="bibr">Constant et al. (2013) (Const13)</ref> and the Mate-tools system (without reranker) of <ref type="bibr">Björkelund et al. (2013) (Bjork13)</ref>. We also reimplemented and improved the uniform joint architecture of <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Constant et al. (2013)</ref>, by adding MWE features and switch. Re- sults can only be compared on the flat representa- tion, because the other systems output poorer lin- guistic information. We computed statistical sig- nificance of differences between our systems and Const13. On dev, the best system is the enhanced uniform joint, but differences are not significant between that and the best reg/irreg joint (1st row) and the Const13 pipeline. But on the test corpus (which is twice bigger), the best system is Const13  <ref type="table">Table 6</ref>: Comparison with simpler tasks on the flat representation of the development set.</p><p>pipeline, with statistically significant differences over our joint systems. So the first observation is that our architectures that distinguish between reg/irreg MWEs do not outperform uniform ar- chitectures. But we note that the differences are slight, and the output we obtain is enhanced with regular MWE internal structure. It can thus be noted that the increased syntactic uniformity ob- tained by our MWE representation is mitigated so far by the additional complexity of the task. The second observation is that currently the best sys- tem on this dataset is a pipeline system, as results on test set show (and somehow contrary to results on dev set). The joint systems that integrate MWE information in the labels seem to suffer from in- creased data sparseness.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.5">Evaluating the double task with respect to simpler tasks</head><p>In this section, we propose to better evaluate the difficulty of combining the tasks of MWE analy- sis and dependency parsing by comparing our sys- tems with systems performing simpler tasks: i.e. MWE recognition without parsing, and parsing with no or limited MWE recognition, simulated by using gold MWEs. We also provide a finer eval- uation of the MWE recognition task, in particular with respect to their regular/irregular status. We first compare our best system with a parser where all MWEs have been perfectly pre-grouped, in order to quantify the difficulty that MWEs add to the parsing task. We also compare the per- formance on MWEs of our best system with that achieved by the CRF-based analyzer described in section 5.2. Next, we compare the best JOINT- REG system with the one based on the same ar- chitecture but where the irregular MWEs are per- fectly pre-identified, in order to quantify the dif- ficulty added by the irregular MWEs. Results are given in table 6. Without any surprise, the task is much easier without considering MWE recog- nition. We can see that without considering MWE analysis the parsing accuracy is about 2.5 points better in terms of LAS. In the JOINT-REG ar- chitecture, assuming gold irregular MWE identi- fication, increases LAS by 1.3 point. In terms of MWE recognition, as compared with the CRF- based analyzer, our best system is around 2 points below. But the situation is quite different when breaking the evaluation by MWE type. Our sys- tem is 1 point better than the CRF-based analyzer for irregular MWEs. This shows that considering a larger syntactic context helps recognition of ir- regular MWEs. The "weak point" of our system is therefore the identification of regular MWEs.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7">Conclusion</head><p>We experimented strategies to predict both MWE analysis and dependency structure, and tested them on the dependency version of French Tree- bank ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Abeillé and Barrier, 2004</ref>), as instantiated in the SPMRL Shared Task ( . Our work focused on using an alternative repre- sentation of syntactically regular MWEs, which captures their syntactic internal structure. We ob- tain a system with comparable performance to that of previous works on this dataset, but which pre- dicts both syntactic dependencies and the internal structure of MWEs. This can be useful for captur- ing the various degrees of semantic composition- ality of MWEs. The main weakness of our system comes from the identification of regular MWEs, a property which is highly lexical. Our current use of external lexicons does not seem to suffice, and the use of data-driven external information to bet- ter cope with this identification can be envisaged.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>• parsing: (i)</head><label></label><figDesc>MWE analysis with classifica- tion of MWEs into regular or irregular, (ii) merge of predicted irregular MWEs, (iii) tag- ging and morphological prediction, (iv) pars- ing JOINT-IRREG architecture: • training set: flat representation of irregu- lar MWEs, with label suffixing (dep_cpd_ POS), structured representation of regular MWEs without label suffixing. • parsing: (i) MWE analysis and classifica- tion into regular or irregular, used for MWE- specific features, (ii) tagging and morpholog- ical prediction, (iii) parsing, We compare these four architectures between them and also with two simpler architectures used by (Constant et al., 2013) within the SPMRL 13 Shared Task, in which regular and irregular MWEs are</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" validated="false"><head>c . Labeled representation:</head><label>c</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>L' 
abus 
de 
biens 
sociaux 
fut 
dénoncé 
en 
vain 

suj 

d e t 
d e p 

r N 

o b j. p 

r N 

m 
o d 
r N 

a u x 

t p s 

m o d 

d e p c p d A D V 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3" validated="false"><head>Table 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>The four architectures, depending on how 
regular and irregular MWEs are predicted. 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4" validated="false"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>). Both kinds of regular MWEs, but this showed comparable results.</figDesc><table>LABELED 

STRUCTURED 
FLAT 
REPRES. 
REPRESENTATION 
REPRESENTATION 
MWE swi. swi. 
LAS UAS 
LAS FUM FTM 
LAS UAS FUM FTM 
ARCHI 
feats 
irreg 
reg 
irreg 
irreg 
bsline 
-
-
-
84.5 
89.3 
87.0 
83.6 
80.6 
84.2 
88.1 
73.5 
70.7 
JOINT 
best 
+ 
+ 
+ 
85.3 
89.7 
87.5 
85.4 
82.6 
85.2 88.8 
77.6 
74.5 
JOINT-bsline 
-
-
-
84.7 
89.4 
87.0 
83.5 
80.3 
84.5 
88.0 
78.3 
75.9 
IRREG 
best 
+ 
+ 
+ 
85.1 
89.8 
87.4 
85.0 
81.6 
84.9 
88.3 
79.0 
76.5 
JOINT-bsline 
-
NA 
-
84.2 
89.1 
86.7 
84.2 
80.8 
84.0 
88.0 
73.3 
70.3 
REG 
best 
+ 
NA 
+ 
84.7 
89.3 
86.9 
84.1 
80.7 
84.6 
88.3 
76.3 
73.2 
PIPE 
bsline 
-
NA 
-
84.6 
89.2 
86.9 
84.1 
80.7 
84.5 
87.9 
78.8 
76.3 
LINE 
best 
-
NA 
+ 
84.7 
89.4 
87.0 
84.2 
80.8 
84.6 
88.1 
78.8 
76.3 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_7" validated="false"><head>Table 5 :</head><label>5</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Comparison on dev set of our best archi-
tecture with reg/irregular MWE distinction (first 
row), with the single-parser architectures of (Con-
stant et al., 2013) (Const13) and (Björkelund et 
al., 2013) (Bjork13). Uniform joint is our reimple-
mentation of Const13 joint, enhanced with mwe-
features and switch. 

</table></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="2"> The main focus of the Shared Task was on predicting both morphological and syntactic analysis for morphologically-rich languages. The French dataset is the only one containing MWEs: the French treebank has the particularity to contain a high ratio of tokens belonging to a MWE (12.7% of non numerical tokens).</note>

			<note place="foot" n="3"> Concerning non contiguous MWEs, we can cite the work of Vincze et al. (2013), who experimented joint dependency parsing and light verb construction identification.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="4"> The syntactic head of a structured MWE may not be the first token, whereas the head token of a flat MWE is always the first one.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="11"> http://igm.univ-mlv.fr/˜mconstan 12 http://code.google.com/p/mate-tools/ 13 https://sites.google.com/site/morfetteweb/ 14 http://nextens.uvt.nl/depparse-wiki/SoftwarePage 15 The compare.pl script, formerly available at www.cis.upenn.edu/ dbikel/</note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Enriching a french treebank</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Anne</forename><surname>Abeillé</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nicolas</forename><surname>Barrier</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of LREC</title>
		<meeting>LREC<address><addrLine>Lisbon, Portugal</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Lexicalization in crosslinguistic probabilistic parsing: The case of french</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Abhishek</forename><surname>Arun</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Frank</forename><surname>Keller</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of ACL 2005</title>
		<meeting>ACL 2005<address><addrLine>Ann Arbor, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Annotation of multiword expressions in the prague dependency treebank. Language Resources and Evaluation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Eduard</forename><surname>Bejček</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Pavel</forename><surname>Stranak</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">44</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="7" to="21" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Richárdand Müller, and Wolfgang Seeker. 2013. (re)ranking meets morphosyntax: State-of-the-art results from the spmrl 2013 shared task</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Anders</forename><surname>Björkelund</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Thomas</forename><surname>Ozlem C ¸ Etinoˇgluetinoˇglu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Farkas</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 4th Workshop on Statistical Parsing of Morphologically Rich Languages: Shared Task</title>
		<meeting>the 4th Workshop on Statistical Parsing of Morphologically Rich Languages: Shared Task<address><addrLine>Seattle, WA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Top accuracy and fast dependency parsing is not a contradiction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bernd</forename><surname>Bohnet</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of COLING 2010</title>
		<meeting>COLING 2010<address><addrLine>Beijing, China</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Multi-word units in treebank-based probabilistic parsing and generation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Conor</forename><surname>Cafferkey</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Deirdre</forename><surname>Hogan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Josef</forename><surname>Van Genabith</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 10th International Conference on Recent Advances in Natural Language Processing (RANLP&apos;07)</title>
		<meeting>the 10th International Conference on Recent Advances in Natural Language Processing (RANLP&apos;07)<address><addrLine>Borovets, Bulgaria</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Statistical french dependency parsing : Treebank conversion and first results</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marie</forename><surname>Candito</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Benoit</forename><surname>Crabbé</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Pascal</forename><surname>Denis</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of LREC 2010</title>
		<meeting>LREC 2010<address><addrLine>Valletta, Malta</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Learning morphology with morfette</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Grzegorz</forename><surname>Chrupała</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Georgiana</forename><surname>Dinu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Josef</forename><surname>Van Genabith</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of LREC 2008</title>
		<meeting>LREC 2008<address><addrLine>Marrakech, Morocco. ELDA/ELRA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Evaluating the impact of external lexical resources into a crf-based multiword segmenter and part-of-speech tagger</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Matthieu</forename><surname>Constant</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Isabelle</forename><surname>Tellier</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of LREC 2012</title>
		<meeting>LREC 2012<address><addrLine>Istanbul, Turkey</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Discriminative strategies to integrate multiword expression recognition and parsing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Matthieu</forename><surname>Constant</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Anthony</forename><surname>Sigogne</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Patrick</forename><surname>Watrin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of ACL 2012</title>
		<meeting>ACL 2012<address><addrLine>Stroudsburg, PA, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The ligm-alpage architecture for the spmrl 2013 shared task: Multiword expression analysis and dependency parsing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Matthieu</forename><surname>Constant</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marie</forename><surname>Candito</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Djamé</forename><surname>Seddah</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 4th Workshop on Statistical Parsing of Morphologically Rich Languages: Shared Task</title>
		<meeting>the 4th Workshop on Statistical Parsing of Morphologically Rich Languages: Shared Task<address><addrLine>Seattle, WA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">DictionnairéDictionnairé electronique DELAC : les mots composés binaires</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Blandine</forename><surname>Courtois</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gaston</forename><surname>Myì Ene Garrigues</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Maurice</forename><surname>Gross</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">René</forename><surname>Gross</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Jung</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Technical Report</title>
		<editor>Mathieu-Colas Michel, Anne Monceaux, Anne Poncet-Montange, Max Silberztein, and Robert Vivés</editor>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">56</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Un système de dictionnairesélectroniques dictionnaires´dictionnairesélectroniques pour les mots simples du français</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Blandine</forename><surname>Courtois</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Langue Française</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">87</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="11" to="22" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Coupling an annotated corpus and a morphosyntactic lexicon for state-of-the-art POS tagging with less human effort</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Pascal</forename><surname>Denis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Benoˆıtbenoˆıt</forename><surname>Sagot</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 23rd Pacific Asia Conference on Language, Information and Computation (PACLIC&apos;09)</title>
		<meeting>the 23rd Pacific Asia Conference on Language, Information and Computation (PACLIC&apos;09)<address><addrLine>Hong Kong</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Multiword expressions in statistical dependency parsing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gülsgüls¸en</forename><surname>Eryiˇgiteryiˇgit</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tugay</forename><surname>Ilbay</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ozan Arkan</forename><surname>Can</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the IWPT Workshop on Statistical Parsing of Morphologically-Rich Languages (SPMRL&apos;11)</title>
		<meeting>the IWPT Workshop on Statistical Parsing of Morphologically-Rich Languages (SPMRL&apos;11)<address><addrLine>Dublin, Ireland</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Multiword expression identification with tree substitution grammars: A parsing tour de force with french</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Spence</forename><surname>Green</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marie-Catherine</forename><surname>De Marneffe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">John</forename><surname>Bauer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christofer</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Manning</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of EMNLP 2011</title>
		<meeting>EMNLP 2011<address><addrLine>Edinburgh, Scotland</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Parsing models for identifying multiword expressions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Spence</forename><surname>Green</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marie-Catherine</forename><surname>De Marneffe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christopher D</forename><surname>Manning</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Computational Linguistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">39</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="195" to="227" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Multiword units in syntactic parsing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Joakim</forename><surname>Nivre</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jens</forename><surname>Nilsson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the LREC Workshop : Methodologies and Evaluation of Multiword Units in Real-World Applications (MEMURA)</title>
		<meeting>the LREC Workshop : Methodologies and Evaluation of Multiword Units in Real-World Applications (MEMURA)<address><addrLine>Lisbon, Portugal</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The prolex data base : Toponyms and gentiles for nlp</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Odile</forename><surname>Piton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Denis</forename><surname>Maurel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Claude</forename><surname>Belleil</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Third International Workshop on Applications of Natural Language to Data Bases (NLDB&apos;99)</title>
		<meeting>the Third International Workshop on Applications of Natural Language to Data Bases (NLDB&apos;99)<address><addrLine>Klagenfurt, Austria</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Parser combination by reparsing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kenji</forename><surname>Sagae</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alon</forename><surname>Lavie</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of NAACL/HLT 2006, Companion Volume: Short Papers</title>
		<meeting>NAACL/HLT 2006, Companion Volume: Short Papers<address><addrLine>Stroudsburg, PA, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The lefff, a freely available, accurate and large-coverage lexicon for french</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Benoˆıtbenoˆıt</forename><surname>Sagot</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of LREC 2010</title>
		<meeting>LREC 2010<address><addrLine>Valletta, Malta</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Lemmatization and statistical lexicalized parsing of morphologically-rich languages</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Djamé</forename><surname>Seddah</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Grzegorz</forename><surname>Chrupała</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ozlem</forename><surname>Cetinoglu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Josef</forename><surname>Van Genabith</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marie</forename><surname>Candito</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the NAACL/HLT Workshop on Statistical Parsing of Morphologically Rich Languages (SPMRL 2010)</title>
		<meeting>the NAACL/HLT Workshop on Statistical Parsing of Morphologically Rich Languages (SPMRL 2010)<address><addrLine>Los Angeles, CA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Wolfgang Seeker, Yannick Versley, Veronika Vincze, Marcin Woli´nskiWoli´nski, Alina Wróblewska, and Eric Villemonte de la Clérgerie</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Djamé</forename><surname>Seddah</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Reut</forename><surname>Tsarfaty</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Sandra</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marie</forename><surname>´ &amp;apos;ubler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jinho</forename><surname>Candito</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Richárd</forename><surname>Choi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jennifer</forename><surname>Farkas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Iakes</forename><surname>Foster</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Koldo</forename><surname>Goenaga</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yoav</forename><surname>Gojenola</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Spence</forename><surname>Goldberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nizar</forename><surname>Green</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marco</forename><surname>Habash</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wolfgang</forename><surname>Kuhlmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Joakim</forename><surname>Maier</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Adam</forename><surname>Nivre</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ryan</forename><surname>Przepiorkowski</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Roth</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 4th Workshop on Statistical Parsing of Morphologically Rich Languages: Shared Task</title>
		<meeting>the 4th Workshop on Statistical Parsing of Morphologically Rich Languages: Shared Task<address><addrLine>Seattle, WA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Overview of the spmrl 2013 shared task: A cross-framework evaluation of parsing morphologically rich languages</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Hungarian dependency treebank</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Veronika</forename><surname>Vincze</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dóra</forename><surname>Szauter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Attila</forename><surname>Almási</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">György</forename><surname>Móra</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Zoltán</forename><surname>Alexin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">János</forename><surname>Csirik</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of LREC 2010</title>
		<meeting>LREC 2010<address><addrLine>Valletta, Malta</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dependency parsing for identifying hungarian light verb constructions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Veronika</forename><surname>Vincze</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">János</forename><surname>Zsibrita</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Istvàn</forename><surname>Nagy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing</title>
		<meeting>International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing<address><addrLine>Nagoya, Japan</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>IJCNLP 2013</note>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
