<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T10:22+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Real-Time Detection, Tracking, and Monitoring of Automatically Discovered Events in Social Media</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date>June 23-24, 2014</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Miles</forename><surname>Osborne</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<address>
									<settlement>Loughborough, Aston, Aston</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><roleName>Edinburgh</roleName><forename type="first">Sean</forename><surname>Moran</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<address>
									<settlement>Loughborough, Aston, Aston</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Edinburgh</forename><surname>Richard</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<address>
									<settlement>Loughborough, Aston, Aston</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mccreadie</forename><surname>Glasgow</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<address>
									<settlement>Loughborough, Aston, Aston</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alexander</forename><surname>Lunen</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<address>
									<settlement>Loughborough, Aston, Aston</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Martin</forename><forename type="middle">Sykora</forename><surname>Loughborough</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<address>
									<settlement>Loughborough, Aston, Aston</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Elizabeth</forename><surname>Cano</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<address>
									<settlement>Loughborough, Aston, Aston</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Neil</forename><forename type="middle">Ireson</forename><surname>Sheffield</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<address>
									<settlement>Loughborough, Aston, Aston</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Craig</forename><surname>Macdonald</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<address>
									<settlement>Loughborough, Aston, Aston</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Glasgow</forename><surname>Iadh</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<address>
									<settlement>Loughborough, Aston, Aston</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ounis</forename><surname>Glasgow</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<address>
									<settlement>Loughborough, Aston, Aston</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yulan</forename><surname>He</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<address>
									<settlement>Loughborough, Aston, Aston</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tom</forename><surname>Jackson</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<address>
									<settlement>Loughborough, Aston, Aston</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Loughborough</forename><surname>Fabio</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<address>
									<settlement>Loughborough, Aston, Aston</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ciravegna</forename><surname>Sheffield</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<address>
									<settlement>Loughborough, Aston, Aston</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ann</forename><surname>O&amp;apos;</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<address>
									<settlement>Loughborough, Aston, Aston</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Brien</forename><surname>Loughborough</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<address>
									<settlement>Loughborough, Aston, Aston</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Real-Time Detection, Tracking, and Monitoring of Automatically Discovered Events in Social Media</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of 52nd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics: System Demonstrations</title>
						<meeting>52nd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics: System Demonstrations <address><addrLine>Baltimore, Maryland USA</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="37" to="42"/>
							<date type="published">June 23-24, 2014</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>We introduce ReDites, a system for real-time event detection, tracking, monitoring and visualisation. It is designed to assist Information Analysts in understanding and exploring complex events as they unfold in the world. Events are automatically detected from the Twitter stream. Then those that are categorised as being security-relevant are tracked, geolo-cated, summarised and visualised for the end-user. Furthermore, the system tracks changes in emotions over events, signalling possible flashpoints or abatement. We demonstrate the capabilities of ReD-ites using an extended use case from the September 2013 Westgate shooting incident. Through an evaluation of system la-tencies, we also show that enriched events are made available for users to explore within seconds of that event occurring.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction and Challenges</head><p>Social Media (and especially Twitter) has become an extremely important source of real-time infor- mation about a massive number of topics, ranging from the mundane (what I had for breakfast) to the profound (the assassination of Osama Bin Laden).</p><p>The use of social media message streams for event detection poses a number of opportunities and challenges as these streams are: very high in volume, often contain duplicated, incomplete, im- precise and incorrect information, are written in informal style (i.e. short, unedited and conver- sational), generally concern the short-term zeit- geist; and finally relate to unbounded domains. These characteristics mean that while massive and timely information sources are available, domain- relevant information may be mentioned very infre- quently. The scientific challenge is therefore the detection of the signal within that noise. This chal- lenge is exacerbated by the typical requirement that documents must be processed in (near) real- time, such that events can be promptly acted upon.</p><p>The ReDites system meets these requirements and performs event detection, tracking, summari- sation, categorisation and visualisation. To the best of our understanding, it is the first published, large-scale, (near) real-time Topic Detection and Tracking system that is tailored to the needs of in- formation analysts in the security sector. Novel as- pects of ReDites include the first large-scale treat- ment of spuriously discovered events and tailoring the event stream to the security domain. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Related Work</head><p>A variety of event exploration systems have previ- ously been proposed within the literature. For in- stance, Trend Miner 1 enables the plotting of term times series, drawn from Social Media <ref type="bibr">(Preot¸iucPreot¸iucPietro and Cohn, 2013)</ref>. It has a summarisation component and is also multilingual. In contrast, our system is focussed instead upon documents (Tweets) and is more strongly driven by real- time considerations. The Social Sensor ( <ref type="bibr">Aiello et al., 2013</ref>) system facilitates the tracking of pre- defined events using social streams.</p><p>In contrast, we track all automatically discov- ered events we find in the stream. The Twitci- dent ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Abel et al., 2012</ref>) project deals with user- driven searching through Social Media with re- spect to crisis management. However, unlike ReDites, these crises are not automatically dis- covered. The LRA Crisis Tracker 2 has a similar purpose as ReDites. However, while LRA uses crowdsourcing, our ReDites system is fully auto- matic.</p><p>3 System Overview and Architecture <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref> gives a high-level system description. The system itself is loosely coupled, with ser- vices from different development teams coordi- nating via a Thrift interface. An important as- pect of this decoupled design is that it enables ge- ographically dispersed teams to coordinate with each other. Event processing is comprised of the following main 4 steps: 1) New events are detected. An event is described by the first Tweet that we find discussing it and is defined as something that is captured within a single Tweet ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Petrovic et al., 2010</ref>).</p><p>1 http://www.trendminer-project.eu/ 2 http://www.lracrisistracker.com/ 2) When an event is first discovered it may initially have little information associated with it. Further- more, events evolve over time. Hence, the sec- ond step involves tracking the event -finding new posts relating to it as they appear and maintaining a concise updated summary of them. 3) Not all events are of interest to our intended audience, so we organise them. In particular, we determine whether an event is security-related (or otherwise), geolocate it, and detect how prominent emotions relating to that event evolve. 4) Finally, we visualise the produced stream of summarised, categorised and geolocated events for the analyst(s), enabling them to better make sense of the mass of raw information present within the original Twitter stream. Section 6 further describes these four steps.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Data and Statistics</head><p>For the deployment of ReDites, we use the Twit- ter 1% streaming sample. This provides approx- imately four million Tweets per day, at a rate of about 50 Tweets a second. <ref type="table">Table 1</ref> gives some illustrative statistics on a sample of data from September 2013 to give a feel for the rate of data and generated events we produce. <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Table 2</ref> gives timing information, corresponding with the major components of our system: time to process and time to transfer to the next component, which is usually a service on another machine on the in- ternet. The latency of each step is measured in seconds over a 1000 event sample. 'Transfer' la- tencies is the time between one step completing and the output arriving at the next step to be pro- cessed (Thrift transfer time). Variance is the aver- age deviation from the mean latency over the event sample.</p><p>When processing the live stream, we ingest data at an average rate of 50 Tweets per second and de- tect an event (having geolocated and filtered out non-English or spam Tweets) with a per-Tweet la- tency of 0.6±0.55 seconds. <ref type="figure">Figure 2</ref> gives laten- cies for the various major components of the sys- tem. All processing uses commodity machines.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">The Westgate Shopping Mall Attack</head><p>As an illustrative example of a complex recent event, we considered a terrorist attack on the 21st of <ref type="bibr">September, 2013. 3</ref> This event is used to demon- strate how our system can be used to understand it.  In summary, a shopping Mall in Kenya was at- tacked from the 21st of September until the 24th of September. This event was covered by tradi- tional newswire, by victims caught up in it as well as by terrorist sympathisers, often in real-time.</p><note type="other">Measure Event Detection Tracking and Summ Emotion Ident Security</note><p>As we later show, even though we only operate over 1% of the Twitter Stream, we are still able to find many (sub) events connected with this attack. There were 6657 mentions of Westgate in Septem- ber 2013 in our 1% of sample Tweets.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Major Components</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.1">Event Detection</head><p>Building upon an established Topic Detection and Tracking (TDT) methodology, which assumes that each new event corresponds with seeing some novel document. the event detection component uses a hashing approach that finds novel events 4 in constant time ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Petrovic et al., 2010)</ref>. To make it scale and process thousands of documents each second, it can optionally be distributed over a clus- ter of machines (via Storm 5 ) ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">McCreadie et al., 2013</ref>). The system favours recall over precision and has been shown to have high recall, but a low precision ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Petrovic et al., 2013)</ref>. Given that we are presenting discovered events to a user and we do not want to overload them with false positives, we need to take steps to increase precision (ie present fewer false positives).</p><p>We use a content categoriser to determine whether a discovered event is worth reporting. Using more than 100k automatically discovered events from the Summer of 2011, we created a training set and manually labelled each Tweet: was it content bearing (what you might want to read about in traditional newswire) or irrelevant / not useful. With this labelled data, we used a Passive-Aggressive algorithm to build a con- tent classifier. Features were simply unigrams in Tweets. This dramatically improves precision, to 70%, with a drop in recall to 25% (when tested on 73k unseen events, manually labelled by two annotators). We can change the precision-recall boundary as needed by adjusting the associated decision boundary. We do not consider non- English language Tweets in this work and they are filtered out <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Lui and Baldwin, 2012)</ref>.</p><p>Geolocation is important, as we are particu- larly interested in events that occur at a spe- cific location. We therefore additionally geolo- cate any Tweets that were not originally ge- olocated. To geotag those Tweets that do not have any geo-location information we use the Tweet text and additional Tweet metadata (lan- guage, city/state/country name, user description etc), to learn a L 1 penalised least squares regres- sor (LASSO) to predict the latitude and longitude. The model is learnt on nearly 20 million geo- located Tweets collected from 2010-2014. Exper- iments on a held-out test dataset show we can lo- calise Tweets to within a mean distance of 433 km of their true location. This performance is based on the prediction of individual tweet location and not, as in most previous work, on the location of a user who is represented by a set of tweets. Further- more we are not restricted to a single, well-defined area (such as London) and we also evaluate over a very large set of unfiltered tweets.</p><p>Turning to the Westgate example, the first men- tion of it in our data was at 10:02 UTC. There were 57 mentions of Westgate in discovered events, of which 42 mentioned Kenya and 44 mentioned Nairobi. The first mention itself in Twitter was at 09:38 UTC. We declared it an event (having seen enough evidence and post-processing it) less than one second later:</p><p>Westgate under siege. Armed thugs. Gun- shots reported. Called the managers, phones are off/busy. Are cops on the way?</p><p>We also captured numerous informative sub-events covering different aspects and sides of the central Westgate siege event, four of these are il- lustrated below: </p><formula xml:id="formula_0">Post</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.2">Tracking and Summarisation</head><p>The second component of the event exploration system is Tracking and Summarisation (TaS). The second TaS sub-component is event sum- marisation. This sub-component takes as input the Tweet ranking produced above and performs ex- tractive summarisation <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Nenkova and McKeown, 2012</ref>) upon it, i.e. it selects a subset of the ranked Tweets to form a summary of the event. The goals of event summarisation are two-fold. First, to re- move any Tweets from the above ranking that are not relevant to the event (e.g. Tweet 5 in the exam- ple above). Indeed when an event is first detected, there may be few relevant Tweets yet posted. The second goal is to remove redundancy from within the selected Tweets, such as Tweets 2 and 3 in the above example, thereby focussing the produced summary on novelty. To tackle the first of these goals, we leverage the score distribution of Tweets within the ranking to identify those Tweets that are likely background noise. When an event is first detected, few relevant Tweets will be retrieved, hence the mean score over the Tweets is indicative of non-relevant Tweets. Tweets within the rank- ing whose scores diverge from the mean score in the positive direction are likely to be on-topic. We therefore, make an include/exclude decision for each Tweet t in the ranking R:</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">include(t, R) =            1 if score(t) − SD(R) &gt; 0 and |SD(R) − score(t)| &gt; θ · 1 |R| t ∈R |SD(R) − score(t )| 0 otherwise</formula><p>(1) where SD(R) is the standard deviation of scores in R, score(t) is the retrieval score for Tweet t and θ is a threshold parameter that describes the mag- nitude of the divergence from the mean score that a Tweet must have before it is included within the summary. Then, to tackle the issue of redundancy, we select Tweets in a greedy time-ordered man- ner (earliest first). A similarity (cosine) threshold between the current Tweet and each Tweet previ- ously selected is used to remove those that are tex- tually similar, resulting in the following extractive summary: Finally, the TaS component can be used to track events over time. In this case, instead of tak- ing a new event as input from the event detec- tion component, a previously summarised event can be used as a surrogate. For instance, a user might identify an event that they want to track. The real-time search sub-component retrieves new Tweets about the event posted since that event was last summarised. The event summarisation sub- component then removes non-relevant and redun- dant Tweets with respect to those contained within the previous summary, producing a new updated summary.</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">ID</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.3">Organising Discovered Events</head><p>The events we discover are not targeted at infor- mation analysts. For example, they contain sports updates, business acquisitions as well as those that are genuinely relevant and can bear various opin- ions and degrees of emotional expression. We therefore take steps to filter and organise them for our intended audience: we predict whether they have a specific security-focus and finally predict an emotional label for events (which can be useful when judging changing viewpoints on events and highlighting extreme emotions that could possibly motivate further incidents).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.3.1">Security-Related Event Detection</head><p>We are particularly interested in security-related events such as violent events, natural disasters, or emergency situations. Given a lack of in-domain labelled data, we resort to a weakly supervised Bayesian modelling approach based on the previ- ously proposed Violence Detection Model (VDM) ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Cano et al., 2013</ref>) for identifying security events. In order to differentiate between security and non-security related events, we extract words re- lating to security events from existing knowledge sources such as DBpedia and incorporate them as priors into the VDM model learning. It should be noted that such a word lexicon only provides ini- tial prior knowledge into the model. The model will automatically discover new words describing security-related events.</p><p>We trained the VDM model on a randomly sampled 10,581 Tweets from the TREC Mi- croblog 2011 corpus ( ) and tested the model on 1,759 manually labelled Tweets which consist of roughly the same num- ber of security-related and non-security related Tweets. Our results show that the VDM model achieved 85.8% in F-measure for the identification of security-related Tweets, which is not far from the F-measure of 90% obtained using the super- vised Naive Bayes classifier despite using no la- belled data in the model.</p><p>Here, we derived word priors from a total of 32,174 documents from DBpedia and ex- tracted 1,612 security-related words and 1,345 non-security-related words based on the measure- ment of relative word entropy. We then trained the VDM model by setting the topic number to 50 and using 7,613 event Tweets extracted from the Tweets collected during July-August 2011 and September 2013 in addition to 10,581 Tweets from the TREC Microblog 2011 corpus. In the afore- mentioned Westgate example, we classify 24% of Tweets as security-related out of a total of 7,772 summary Tweets extracted by the TaS component. Some of the security-related Tweets are listed be- low 8 : </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.3.2">Emotion</head><p>Security-related events can be fraught, with emo- tionally charged posts possibly evolving over time, reflecting ongoing changes in underlying events. Eight basic emotions, as identified in the psychol- ogy literature (see <ref type="bibr">(Sykora et al., 2013a</ref>) for a de- tailed review of this literature) are covered, specif- ically; anger, confusion, disgust, fear, happiness, sadness, shame and surprise. Extreme values -as well as their evolution-can be useful to an ana- lyst ( <ref type="bibr">Sykora et al., 2013b</ref>). We detect enotions in Tweets and support faceted browing. The emotion component assigns labels to Tweets representing these emotions. It is based upon a manually con- structed ontology, which captures the relationships between these emotions and terms <ref type="bibr">(Sykora et al., 2013a</ref>). We sampled the summarised Tweets of the Westgate attack, starting from the event detection and following the messages over a course of seven days. In the relevant Tweets, we detected that 8.6% had emotive terms in them, which is in line with the aforementioned literature. Some example expressions of emotion include: For Westgate, the emotions of sadness, fear and surprise dominated. Very early on the emotions of fear and sadness were expressed, as Twitter users were terrified by the event and saddened by the loss of lives. Sadness and fear were -over time - the emotions that were stated most frequently and constantly, with expressions of surprise, as users were shocked about what was going on, and some happiness relating to when people managed to escape or were rescued from the mall. Generally speaking, factual statements in the Tweets were more prominent than emotive ones. This coincides with the emotive Tweets that represented fear and surprise in the beginning, as it was not clear what had happened and Twitter users were upset and tried to get factual information about the event.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.4">Visual Analytics</head><p>The visualisation component is designed to facili- tate the understanding and exploration of detected events. It offers faceted browsing and multiple vi- sualisation tools to allow an information analyst to gain a rapid understanding of ongoing events. An analyst can constrain the detected events us- ing information both from the original Tweets (e.g. hashtags, locations, user details) and from the up- dated summaries derived by ReDites. The ana- lyst can also view events using facet values, loca- tions/keywords in topic maps and time/keywords in multiple timelines. By combining informa- tion dimensions, the analyst can determine pat- terns across dimensions to determine if an event should be acted upon -e.g the analyst can choose to view Tweets, which summarise highly emotive events, concerning middle eastern countries.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7">Discussion</head><p>We have presented ReDites, the first published system that carries out large-scale event detection, tracking summarisation and visualisation for the security sector. Events are automatically identified and those that are relevant to information analysts are quickly made available for ongoing monitor- ing. We showed how the system could be used to help understand a complex, large-scale security event. Although our system is initially specialised to the security sector, it is easy to repurpose it to other domains, such as natural disasters or smart cities. Key aspects of our approach include scala- bility and a rapid response to incoming data.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: System Diagram</figDesc><graphic url="image-1.png" coords="2,91.08,54.30,180.11,141.24" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" validated="true"><head>Table 2 : Event exploration timing and timing variance (seconds)</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Data 
Rate 
Tweets 
35 Million 
Detected events 
533k 
Categorised (security-related) events 5795 

Table 1: Data statistics, 1st September -30th 
September 2013 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3" validated="false"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>The aim of this component is to use the underlying Tweet stream to produce an overview for each event produced by the event detection stage, up- dating this overview as the event evolves. Track- ing events is important when dealing with live, on- going disasters, since new information can rapidly emerge over time. TaS takes as input a Tweet representing an event and emits a list of Tweets summarising that event in more detail. TaS is comprised of two dis- tinct sub-components, namely: real-time tracking; and event summarisation. The real-time track- ing component maintains a sliding window of Tweets from the underlying Tweet stream. As an event arrives, the most informative terms con- tained 6 form a search query that is used to retrieve new Tweets about the event. For example, tak- ing the Tweet about the Westgate terrorist attack used in the previous section as input on September 21st 2013 at 10:15am, the real-time tracking sub- component retrieved the following related Tweets from the Twitter Spritzer (1%) steam 7 (only 5/100 are shown):</figDesc><table>ID Post Time Tweet 
Score 
1 
10:05am 
Westgate under siege. Armed thugs. Gun-
shots reported. Called the managers, phones are 
off/busy. Are cops on the way? 

123.7 

2 
10:13am 
DO NOT go to Westgate Mall. Gunshots and 
mayhem, keep away until further notice. 
22.9 

3 
10:13am 
RT DO NOT go to Westgate Mall. Gunshots 
and mayhem, keep away until further notice. 
22.9 

4 
10:10am 
Good people please avoid Westgate Mall. @Po-
liceKE @IGkimaiyo please act ASAP, reports 
of armed attack at #WestgateMall 

22.2 

5 
10:07am 
RT @steve enzo: @kirimiachieng these thugs 
won't let us be 
11.5 </table></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="3"> https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Westgate shopping mall shooting</note>

			<note place="foot" n="4"> An event is defined as something happening at a given time and place. Operationally, this means something that can be described within a Tweet. 5 http://storm.incubator.apache.org/</note>

			<note place="foot" n="6"> Nouns, adjectives, verbs and cardinal numbers 7 https://dev.twitter.com/docs/streamingapis/streams/public</note>

			<note place="foot" n="8"> Note some Tweets happen on following days.</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgements</head><p>This work was funded by EPSRC grant EP/L010690/1. MO also acknowledges sup-port from grant ERC Advanced Fellowship 249520 GRAMPLUS.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Semantics + filtering + search = twitcident. exploring information in social web streams</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Abel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G.-J</forename><surname>Hauff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Houben</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Stronkman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of HT</title>
		<meeting>of HT</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Aiello</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">A. Jaimes Sensing trending topics in Twitter. Transactions on Multimedia Journal</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A weakly supervised bayesian model for violence detection in social media</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Cano</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>He</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Zhao</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of IJCNLP</title>
		<meeting>of IJCNLP</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">py: An off-the-shelf language identification tool</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Lui</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Baldwin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Langid</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of ACL</title>
		<meeting>of ACL</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Scalable distributed event detection for twitter</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Mccreadie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Macdonald</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Ounis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Osborne</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Petrovic</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of Big Data</title>
		<meeting>of Big Data</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">On building a reusable Twitter corpus</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Mccreadie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Soboroff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Lin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Macdonald</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Ounis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Mccullough</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of SIGIR</title>
		<meeting>of SIGIR</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A survey of text summarization techniques</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Nenkova</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Mckeown</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Mining Text Data Journal</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Streaming first story detection with application to Twitter</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Petrovic</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Osborne</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Lavrenko</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of NAACL</title>
		<meeting>of NAACL</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Can Twitter replace newswire for breaking news?</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Petrovic</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Osborne</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Mccreadie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Macdonald</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Ounis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Shrimpton</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of WSM</title>
		<meeting>of WSM</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A temporal model of text periodicities using gaussian processes</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Preot¸iucpreot¸iuc-Pietro</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Cohn</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of EMNLP</title>
		<meeting>of EMNLP</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Emotive ontology: Extracting fine-grained emotions from terse, informal messages</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Sykora</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Jackson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>O&amp;apos;brien</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Elayan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Computer Science and Information Systems Journal</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">National security and social media monitoring</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Sykora</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Jackson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>O&amp;apos;brien</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Elayan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of EISIC</title>
		<meeting>of EISIC</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
