<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T10:58+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Vector spaces for historical linguistics: Using distributional semantics to study syntactic productivity in diachrony</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
				<availability status="unknown"><p>Copyright Association for Computational Linguistics</p>
				</availability>
				<date>June 23-25 2014. 2014</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Florent</forename><surname>Perek</surname></persName>
							<email>fperek@princeton.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Princeton University Princeton</orgName>
								<address>
									<region>NJ</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Vector spaces for historical linguistics: Using distributional semantics to study syntactic productivity in diachrony</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 52nd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
						<meeting>the 52nd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics <address><addrLine>Baltimore, Maryland, USA</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="309" to="314"/>
							<date type="published">June 23-25 2014. 2014</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>This paper describes an application of dis-tributional semantics to the study of syntactic productivity in diachrony, i.e., the property of grammatical constructions to attract new lexical items over time. By providing an empirical measure of semantic similarity between words derived from lexical co-occurrences, distributional semantics not only reliably captures how the verbs in the distribution of a construction are related, but also enables the use of visualization techniques and statistical modeling to analyze the semantic development of a construction over time and identify the semantic determinants of syntactic productivity in naturally occurring data.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Language change does not exclusively consist of drastic shifts in 'core' aspects of grammar, such as changes in word order. Variation in usage, which can occur in no more than a few decades, is much more common, and to many linguists constitutes linguistic change in the making. Among these as- pects of language use that are subject to diachronic change, this paper is concerned with the productiv- ity of syntactic constructions, i.e., the range of lex- ical items with which a construction can be used. A given construction might occur with very differ- ent distributions at different points in time, even when the function it conveys remains the same. This is what <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Israel (1996)</ref> finds for the pattern "Verb one's way Path", commonly called the way- construction <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Goldberg, 1995)</ref>, exemplified by (1) and (2) below.</p><p>(1) They hacked their way through the jungle. (2) She typed her way to a promotion.</p><p>As reported by Israel, examples like (1), in which the main verb describes the physical means whereby motion towards a goal is enabled, are at- tested as early as the 16 th century, but it was not until the 19 th century that examples like (2) started to appear, in which the action depicted by the verb provides a more indirect (and abstract) way of at- taining the agent's goal.</p><p>The productivity of a construction may appear partly arbitrary, but a growing body of evidence suggests that it is tied to the previous experience of speakers with that construction <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Barðdal, 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Bybee and Eddington, 2006;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Suttle and Goldberg, 2011</ref>). More specifically, previous research points to a strong semantic component, in that the pos- sibility of a novel use depends on how it seman- tically relates to prior usage. Along these lines, <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Suttle and</ref><ref type="bibr">Goldberg (2011, 1254</ref>) posit a criterion of coverage, defined as "the degree to which at- tested instances 'cover' the category determined jointly by attested instances together with the tar- get coinage". Coverage relates to how the seman- tic domain of a construction is populated in the vicinity of a given target coinage, and in particular to the density of the semantic space.</p><p>The importance of semantics for syntactic pro- ductivity implies that the meaning of lexical items must be appropriately taken into account when studying the distribution of constructions, which calls for an empirical operationalization of seman- tics. Most existing studies rely either on the se- mantic intuitions of the analyst, or on semantic norming studies <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Bybee and Eddington, 2006</ref>). In this paper, I present a third alternative that takes advantage of advances in computational linguis- tics and draws on a distributionally-based measure of semantic similarity. On the basis of a case study of the construction "V the hell out of NP", I show how distributional semantics can profitably be ap- plied to the study of syntactic productivity.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">The hell-construction</head><p>The case study presented in this paper considers the syntactic pattern "V the hell out of NP", as ex- emplified by the following sentences from the Cor- pus of Contemporary American English (COCA; Davies The construction generally conveys an in- tensifying function (very broadly defined). Thus, scare/surprise the hell out of means "scare/surprise very much", and kick the hell out of means "kick very hard". The particular aspect that is intensified may be highly specific to the verb and depend to some extent on the context. Scare and beat are the most typical verbs in that construction (and arguably the two that first come to mind), but a wide and diverse range of other verbs can also be found, such that avoid in (6), drive (a car) in (7) and even an intransitive verb (listen) in <ref type="formula">(8)</ref> To examine how the construction evolved over time, I used diachronic data from the Corpus of Historical American English (COHA; Davies 2010), which contains about 20 million words of written American English for each decade be- tween 1810 and 2009 roughly balanced for genre (fiction, magazines, newspapers, non-fiction). In- stances of the hell-construction were filtered out manually from the results of the query "[v*] the hell out of", mostly ruling out locative construc- tions like get the hell out of here. The diachronic evolution of the verb slot in terms of token and type frequency is plotted in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 1</ref>. Since the corpus size varies slightly in each decade, the to- ken frequencies are normalized per million words.</p><p>The construction is first attested in the corpus in the 1930s. Since then, it has been steadily in- creasing in token frequency (to the exception of a sudden decrease in the 1990s). Also, more and more different verbs are attested in the construc- tion, as shown by the increase in type frequency. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Distributional measure of semantic similarity</head><p>Drawing on the observation that words occurring in similar contexts tend to have related mean- ings <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Miller and Charles, 1991)</ref>, distributional ap- proaches to semantics seek to capture the mean- ing of words through their distribution in large text corpora <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(Lenci, 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Turney and Pantel, 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Erk, 2012)</ref>. One benefit of the distributional se- mantics approach is that it allows semantic sim- ilarity between words to be quantified by mea- suring the similarity in their distribution. This is achieved by means of a vector-space model that assigns an array of numerical values (i.e., a vector) derived from distributional information to each word. A wide range of distributional informa- tion can be employed in vector-based models; the present study uses the 'bag of words' approach, which is based on the frequency of co-occurrence of words within a given context window. Accord- ing to <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Sahlgren (2008)</ref>, this kind of model cap- tures to what extent words can be substituted for each other, which is a good measure of semantic similarity between verbs. As it turns out, even this relatively coarse model captures semantic distinc- tions in the distribution of the hell-construction that make intuitive sense.</p><p>All instances of the relevant verbs were ex- tracted from the COCA 1 with their context of oc- currence. In order to make sure that enough dis- tributional information is available to reliably as- sess semantic similarity, verbs with less than 2,000 occurrences were excluded, which left 92 usable items (out of 105). The words in the sentence con- texts extracted from the COCA were lemmatized and annotated for part-of-speech using TreeTag- ger <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">(Schmid, 1994)</ref>. The part-of-speech annotated lemma of each collocate within a 5-word window was extracted from the COCA data to build the co- occurrence matrix recording the frequency of co- occurrence of each verb with its collocates. Only the nouns, verbs, adjectives, and adverbs listed among the 5,000 most frequent words in the cor- pus were considered (to the exclusion of be, have, and do), thus ignoring function words (articles, prepositions, conjunctions, etc.) and all words that did not make the top 5,000.</p><p>The co-occurrence matrix was transformed by applying a Point-wise Mutual Information weight- ing scheme, using the DISSECT toolkit ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Dinu et al., 2013)</ref>, to turn the raw frequencies into weights that reflect how distinctive a collocate is for a given target word with respect to the other tar- get words under consideration. The resulting ma- trix, which contains the distributional information (in 4,683 columns) for 92 verbs occurring in the hell-construction, constitutes the semantic space under consideration in this case study. Pairwise distances between the target verbs were calculated using the cosine distance. The rest of the analysis was conducted on the basis of this distance matrix in the R environment (R Development Core Team, 2013). <ref type="bibr">1</ref> The COCA contains 464 million words of American En- glish consisting of the same amount of spoken, fiction, mag- azine, newspaper, and academic prose data for each year between 1990 and 2012. Admittedly, a more ecologically valid choice would have been to use data from a particular time frame to build a vector-space model for the same time frame, but even the twenty-odd million words per decade of the COHA did not prove sufficient to achieve that purpose. This is, however, not as problematic as it might sound, since the meaning of the verbs under consideration are not likely to have changed considerably within the time frame of this study. Besides, using the same data presents the advantage that the distribution is modeled with the same semantic space in all time periods, which makes it easier to visualize changes.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Application of the vector-space model 4.1 Semantic plots</head><p>One of the advantages conferred by the quantifi- cation of semantic similarity is that lexical items can be precisely considered in relation to each other, and by aggregating the similarity informa- tion for all items in the distribution, we can pro- duce a visual representation of the structure of the semantic domain of the construction in order to observe how verbs in that domain are related to each other, and to immediately identify the re- gions of the semantic space that are densely pop- ulated (with tight clusters of verbs), and those that are more sparsely populated (fewer and/or more scattered verbs). Multidimensional scaling (MDS) provides a way both to aggregate similarity infor- mation and to represent it visually. This technique aims to place objects in a space with two (or more) dimensions such that the between-object distances are preserved as much as possible.</p><p>The pairwise distances between verbs were sub- mitted to multidimensional scaling into two di- mensions. <ref type="bibr">2</ref> To visualize the semantic development of the hell-construction over time, the diachronic data was divided into four successive twenty-year periods <ref type="bibr">: 1930-1949, 1950-1969, 1970-1989, and 1990-2009</ref>. The semantic plots corresponding to the distribution of the construction in each period are presented in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Figure 2</ref>. For convenience and ease of visualization, the verbs are color-coded according to four broad semantic groupings that were identified inductively by means of hierarchi- cal clustering (using Ward's criterion). <ref type="bibr">3</ref> By comparing the plots in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Figure 2</ref>, we can follow the semantic development of the hell- construction. The construction is strikingly cen- tered around two kinds of verbs: mental verbs (in red: surprise, please, scare, etc.) and verbs of hitting (most verbs in green: smash, kick, whack, etc.), a group that is orbited by other kinds of forceful actions (such as pinch, push, and tear). These two types of verbs account for most of the distribution at the onset, and they continue to weigh heavily throughout the history of the con- struction. These two classes also correspond to the regions of the semantic domain that attract the most new members, and they constantly do so in all periods. Outside of these two clusters, the se- mantic space is much more sparsely populated. In the first period <ref type="bibr">(1930)</ref><ref type="bibr">(1931)</ref><ref type="bibr">(1932)</ref><ref type="bibr">(1933)</ref><ref type="bibr">(1934)</ref><ref type="bibr">(1935)</ref><ref type="bibr">(1936)</ref><ref type="bibr">(1937)</ref><ref type="bibr">(1938)</ref><ref type="bibr">(1939)</ref><ref type="bibr">(1940)</ref><ref type="bibr">(1941)</ref><ref type="bibr">(1942)</ref><ref type="bibr">(1943)</ref><ref type="bibr">(1944)</ref><ref type="bibr">(1945)</ref><ref type="bibr">(1946)</ref><ref type="bibr">(1947)</ref><ref type="bibr">(1948)</ref><ref type="bibr">(1949)</ref>, only a few peripheral members are found. They are joined by other dis- tantly related items in later periods, although by no more than a handful in each. In other words, the construction is markedly less productive in these outer domains, which never form proper clusters of verbs.</p><p>In sum, the semantic plots show that densely populated regions of the semantic space appear to be the most likely to attract new members. Out- side of the two identified domains of predilection, other classes never become important, assumedly because they do not receive a "critical mass" of items, and therefore attract new members more slowly.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">Statistical analysis</head><p>With the quantification of semantic similarity pro- vided by the distributional semantic model, it is also possible to properly test the hypothesis that productivity is tied to the structure of the seman- tic space. On the reasonable assumption that the semantic contribution of the construction did not change, and therefore that all verbs ever attested in it are equally plausible from a semantic point of view, the fact that some verbs joined the dis- tribution later than others is in want of an expla- nation. In view of the observations collected on the semantic plots and in line with previous re- search (especially Suttle and Goldberg's notion of coverage), I suggest that the occurrence of a new item in the construction in a given period is related to the density of the semantic space around that item in the previous period. If the semantic space around the novel item is dense, i.e., if there is a high number of similar items, the coinage will be very likely. The sparser the semantic space around a given item, the less likely this item can be used.</p><p>The measure of density used in this study con- siders the set of the N nearest neighbors of a given item in the semantic space, and is defined by the following formula:</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">Density V,N = 1 − N n=1 d(V, V n ) N where d(V, V n )</formula><p>is the distance between a verb V and its n th nearest neighbor. In plain language, density equals one minus the mean distance to the N nearest neighbors. The latter value decreases with space density (i.e., if there are many close neighbors), and is therefore technically a measure of sparsity; since cosine distances are between 0 and 1, subtracting the mean distance from one re- turns a measure of density within the same bound- aries. This measure of density was used as a factor in logistic regression to predict the first occurrence of a verb in the construction, coded as the binary variable OCCURRENCE, set to 1 for the first pe- riod in which the verb is attested in the construc- tion, and to 0 for all preceding periods (later pe- riods were discarded). For each VERB-PERIOD- OCCURRENCE triplet, the density of the semantic space around the verb in the immediately preced- ing period was calculated. Six different versions of the density measure, with the number of neigh- bors under consideration (N) varying between 3 and 8, were used to fit six mixed effects regres- sion models with OCCURRENCE as the dependent variable, DENSITY as a fixed effect, and random by-verb intercepts and slopes <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Bates et al., 2011</ref>). The results of these models are summarized in <ref type="table">Ta- ble</ref>  For all values of N, we find a positive effect of DENSITY, i.e., there is a positive relation between the measure of density and the probability of first occurrence of a verb in the construction. However, the effect is only significant for N ≥ 7; hence, the hypothesis that space density increases the odds of a coinage occurs in the construction is supported for measures of density based on these values of N.</p><p>More generally, the p-value decreases as N in- creases, which means that the positive relation be- tween DENSITY and OCCURRENCE is less sys- tematic when DENSITY is measured with fewer neighbors. This is arguably because a higher N helps to better discriminate between dense clusters where all items are close together from looser ones that consist of a few 'core' items surrounded by more distant neighbors. This result illustrates the role of type frequency in syntactic productivity: a measure of density that is supported by a higher number of types makes better prediction than a measure supported by fewer types. This means that productivity not only hinges on how the exist- ing semantic space relates to the novel item, it also occurs more reliably when this relation is attested by more items. These finding support the view that semantic density and type frequency, while they both positively influence syntactic productiv- ity, do so in different ways: density defines the necessary conditions for a new coinage to occur, while type frequency increases the confidence that this coinage is indeed possible.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Conclusion</head><p>This paper reports the first attempt at using a dis- tributional measure of semantic similarity derived from a vector-space model for the study of syn- tactic productivity in diachrony. On the basis of a case study of the construction "V the hell out of NP" from 1930 to 2009, the advantages of this approach were demonstrated. Not only does dis- tributional semantics provide an empirically-based measure of semantic similarity that appropriately captures semantic distinctions, it also enables the use of methods for which quantification is neces- sary, such as data visualization and statistical anal- ysis. Using multidimensional scaling and logis- tic regression, it was shown that the occurrence of new items throughout the history of the con- struction can be predicted by the density of the se- mantic space in the neighborhood of these items in prior usage. In conclusion, this work opens new perspectives for the study of syntactic productivity in line with the growing synergy between compu- tational linguistics and other fields.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>, 2008): (3) Snakes just scare the hell out of me. (4) It surprised the hell out of me when I heard what he's been accused of. (5) You might kick the hell out of me like you did that doctor.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>: (6) I [...] avoided the hell out of his presence. (7) But you drove the hell out of it! (8) I've been listening the hell out of your tape.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: Diachronic development of the hellconstruction in terms of normalized token frequency and type frequency</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>Figure 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2: Semantic plots of the hell-construction in four time periods.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" validated="false"><head>1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>N Effect of DENSITY p-value 
3 
0.7211 
0.195 
4 
0.8836 
0.135 
5 
1.0487 
0.091 (.) 
6 
1.2367 
0.056 (.) 
7 
1.4219 
0.034 (*) 
8 
1.6625 
0.017 (*) 

Table 1: Summary of logistic regression results 
for different values of N. Model formula: OC-
CURRENCE ∼ DENSITY + (1 + DENSITY|VERB). 
Marginally significant effects are marked with a 
period (.), significant effects with a star (*). 

</table></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="2"> Non-metric MDS was employed (Kruskal, 1964), using the function isoMDS from the R package MASS. 3 Another benefit of combining clustering and MDS stems from the fact that the latter often distorts the data when fitting the objects into two dimensions, in that some objects might have to be slightly misplaced if not all distance relations can be simultaneously complied with. Since cluster analysis operates with all 4,683 dimensions of the distributional space, it is more reliable than MDS, although it lacks the visual appeal of the latter.</note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Productivity: Evidence from Case and Argument Structure in Icelandic</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Johana</forename><surname>Barðdal</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">John Benjamins</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">lme4: Linear mixedeffects models using S4 classes. R package</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Douglas</forename><surname>Bates</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Martin</forename><surname>Maechler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ben</forename><surname>Bolker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Steven</forename><surname>Walker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://CRAN.R-project.org/package=lme4" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Language, Usage and Cognition</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Joan</forename><surname>Bybee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<publisher>Cambridge University Press</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Cambridge</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">A usagebased approach to Spanish verbs of &apos;becoming&apos;. Language</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Joan</forename><surname>Bybee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Eddington</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">82</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="323" to="355" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The Corpus of Contemporary American English: 450 million words, 1990-present</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mark</forename><surname>Davies</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://corpus.byu.edu/coca/" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The Corpus of Historical American English: 400 million words</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mark</forename><surname>Davies</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://corpus.byu.edu/coha/" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1810" to="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">DISSECT: DIStributional SEmantics Composition Toolkit</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Georgiana</forename><surname>Dinu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nghia</forename><surname>The</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marco</forename><surname>Pham</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Baroni</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the System Demonstrations of ACL 2013 (51st Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the System Demonstrations of ACL 2013 (51st Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Vector Space Models of Word Meaning and Phrase Meaning: A Survey</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Katrin</forename><surname>Erk</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Language and Linguistics Compass</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="635" to="653" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Constructions: A construction grammar approach to argument structure</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Adele</forename><surname>Goldberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
			<publisher>University of Chicago Press</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Chicago</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The way constructions grow</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Israel</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Conceptual structure, discourse and language</title>
		<editor>Adele E. Goldberg</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Stanford, CA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="217" to="230" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Multidimensional scaling by optimizing goodness of fit to a nonmetric hypothesis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Joseph</forename><surname>Kruskal</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychometrika</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">29</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="27" />
			<date type="published" when="1964" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Distributional semantics in linguistic and cognitive research</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alessandro</forename><surname>Lenci</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Rivista di Linguistica</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="31" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Contextual correlates of semantic similarity</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">George</forename><surname>Miller</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Walter</forename><surname>Charles</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Language and Cognitive Processes</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="28" />
			<date type="published" when="1991" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">R: A language and environment for statistical computing. R Foundation for Statistical Computing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Development Core</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Team</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://www.R-project.org/" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<pubPlace>Vienna</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The distributional hypothesis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Magnus</forename><surname>Sahlgren</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Rivista di Linguistica</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="33" to="53" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Probabilistic Part-of-Speech Tagging Using Decision Trees</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Helmut</forename><surname>Schmid</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of International Conference on New Methods in Language Processing</title>
		<meeting>International Conference on New Methods in Language Processing<address><addrLine>Manchester, UK</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1994" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The partial productivity of constructions as induction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Laura</forename><surname>Suttle</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Adele</forename><surname>Goldberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Linguistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">49</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1237" to="1269" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">From Frequency to Meaning: Vector Space Models of Semantics</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Peter</forename><surname>Turney</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Patrick</forename><surname>Pantel</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Artificial Intelligence Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">37</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="141" to="188" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
