<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T11:02+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Negation Focus Identification with Contextual Discourse Information</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
				<availability status="unknown"><p>Copyright Association for Computational Linguistics</p>
				</availability>
				<date>June 23-25 2014. 2014</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bowei</forename><surname>Zou</surname></persName>
							<email>zoubowei@gmail.com, {qmzhu, gdzhou}@suda.edu.cn</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">School of Computer Science and Technology</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">Natural Language Processing Lab</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Soochow University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>215006</postCode>
									<settlement>Suzhou</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Qiaoming</forename><surname>Zhu</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">School of Computer Science and Technology</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">Natural Language Processing Lab</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Soochow University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>215006</postCode>
									<settlement>Suzhou</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Guodong</forename><surname>Zhou</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">School of Computer Science and Technology</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">Natural Language Processing Lab</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Soochow University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>215006</postCode>
									<settlement>Suzhou</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Negation Focus Identification with Contextual Discourse Information</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 52nd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
						<meeting>the 52nd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics <address><addrLine>Baltimore, Maryland, USA</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="522" to="530"/>
							<date type="published">June 23-25 2014. 2014</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Negative expressions are common in natural language text and play a critical role in information extraction. However, the performances of current systems are far from satisfaction , largely due to its focus on intra-sentence information and its failure to consider inter-sentence information. In this paper, we propose a graph model to enrich intra-sentence features with inter-sentence features from both lexical and topic perspectives. Evaluation on the *SEM 2012 shared task corpus indicates the usefulness of contextual discourse information in negation focus identification and justifies the effectiveness of our graph model in capturing such global information. *</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Negation is a grammatical category which com- prises various kinds of devices to reverse the truth value of a proposition <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">(Morante and Sporleder, 2012)</ref>. For example, sentence (1) could be interpreted as it is not the case that he stopped.</p><p>(1) He didn't stop.</p><p>Negation expressions are common in natural language text. According to the statistics on bio- medical literature genre ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">Vincze et al., 2008)</ref>, 19.44% of sentences contain negative expres- sions. The percentage rises to 22.5% on Conan Doyle stories <ref type="bibr">(Morante and Daelemans, 2012)</ref>. It is interesting that a negative sentence may have both negative and positive meanings. For exam- ple, sentence (2) could be interpreted as He stopped, but not until he got to Jackson Hole with positive part he stopped and negative part until he got to Jackson Hole. Moreover, a nega- * Corresponding author tive expression normally interacts with some special part in the sentence, referred as negation focus in linguistics. Formally, negation focus is defined as the special part in the sentence, which is most prominently or explicitly negated by a negative expression. Hereafter, we denote nega- tive expression in boldface and negation focus underlined.</p><p>(2) He didn't stop until he got to Jackson Hole.</p><p>While people tend to employ stress or intona- tion in speech to emphasize negation focus and thus it is easy to identify negation focus in speech corpora, such stress or intonation infor- mation often misses in the dominating text cor- pora. This poses serious challenges on negation focus identification. Current studies (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Blanco and Moldovan, 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b18">Rosenberg and Bergler, 2012</ref>) sort to various kinds of intra-sentence in- formation, such as lexical features, syntactic fea- tures, semantic role features and so on, ignoring less-obvious inter-sentence information. This largely defers the performance of negation focus identification and its wide applications, since such contextual discourse information plays a critical role on negation focus identification. Take following sentence as an example.</p><p>(3) Helen didn't allow her youngest son to play the violin.</p><p>In sentence (3), there are several scenarios on identification of negation focus, with regard to negation expression n't, given different contexts: Scenario A: Given sentence But her husband did as next sentence, the negation focus should be Helen, yielding interpretation the person who didn't allow the youngest son to play the violin is Helen but not her husband. Scenario B: Given sentence She thought that he didn't have the artistic talent like her eldest son as next sentence, the negation focus should be the youngest son, yielding interpretation Helen thought that her eldest son had the talent to play the violin, but the youngest son didn't. Scenario C: Given sentence Because of her neighbors' protests as previous sentence, the ne- gation focus should be play the violin, yielding interpretation Helen didn't allow her youngest son to play the violin, but it didn't show whether he was allowed to do other things.</p><p>In this paper, to well accommodate such con- textual discourse information in negation focus identification, we propose a graph model to en- rich normal intra-sentence features with various kinds of inter-sentence features from both lexical and topic perspectives. Besides, the standard PageRank algorithm is employed to optimize the graph model. Evaluation on the *SEM 2012 shared task corpus <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">(Morante and Blanco, 2012)</ref> justifies our approach over several strong base- lines.</p><p>The rest of this paper is organized as follows. Section 2 overviews the related work. Section 3 presents several strong baselines on negation fo- cus identification with only intra-sentence fea- tures. Section 4 introduces our topic-driven word-based graph model with contextual dis- course information. Section 5 reports the exper- imental results and analysis. Finally, we con- clude our work in Section 6.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Related Work</head><p>Earlier studies of negation were almost in lin- guistics (e.g. <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Horn, 1989;</ref><ref type="bibr">van der Wouden, 1997)</ref>, and there were only a few in natural lan- guage processing with focus on negation recog- nition in the biomedical domain. For example, <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Chapman et al. (2001)</ref> developed a rule-based negation recognition system, NegEx, to deter- mine whether a finding mentioned within narra- tive medical reports is present or absent. Since the release of the BioScope corpus ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">Vincze et al., 2008)</ref>, a freely available resource consisting of medical and biological texts, machine learning approaches begin to dominate the research on negation recognition (e.g. <ref type="bibr">Morante et al., 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Li et al., 2010)</ref>.</p><p>Generally, negation recognition includes three subtasks: cue detection, which detects and identi- fies possible negative expressions in a sentence, scope resolution, which determines the grammat- ical scope in a sentence affected by a negative expression, and focus identification, which iden- tifies the constituent in a sentence most promi- nently or explicitly negated by a negative expres- sion. This paper concentrates on the third subtask, negation focus identification.</p><p>Due to the increasing demand on deep under- standing of natural language text, negation recognition has been drawing more and more attention in recent years, with a series of shared tasks and workshops, however, with focus on cue detection and scope resolution, such as the Bi- oNLP 2009 shared task for negative event detec- tion ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Kim et al., 2009</ref>) and the ACL 2010 Work- shop for scope resolution of negation and specu- lation (Morante and Sporleder, 2010), followed by a special issue of Computational Linguistics (Morante and Sporleder, 2012) for modality and negation.</p><p>The research on negation focus identification was pioneered by <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Blanco and Moldovan (2011)</ref>, who investigated the negation phenomenon in semantic relations and proposed a supervised learning approach to identify the focus of a nega- tion expression. However, although <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Morante and Blanco (2012)</ref> proposed negation focus identifi- cation as one of the *SEM'2012 shared tasks, only one team ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">Rosenberg and Bergler, 2012</ref>) 1 participated in this task. They identified negation focus using three kinds of heuristics and achieved 58.40 in F1-measure. This indicates great expectation in negation focus identification.</p><p>The key problem in current research on nega- tion focus identification is its focus on intra- sentence information and large ignorance of in- ter-sentence information, which plays a critical role in the success of negation focus identifica- tion. For example, Ding (2011) made a qualita- tive analysis on implied negations in conversa- tion and attempted to determine whether a sen- tence was negated by context information, from the linguistic perspective. Moreover, a negation focus is always associated with authors' intention in article. This indicates the great challenges in negation focus identification. examples for verbal negations, please refer to <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Blanco and Moldovan (2011)</ref>.</p><p>For comparison, we choose the state-of-the-art system described in <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Blanco and Moldovan (2011)</ref>, which employed various kinds of syntac- tic features and semantic role features, as one of our baselines. Since this system adopted C4.5 for training, we name it as Baseline C4.5 . In order to provide a stronger baseline, besides those fea- tures adopted in Baseline C4.5 , we added more re- fined intra-sentence features and adopted ranking Support Vector Machine (SVM) model for train- ing. We name it as Baseline SVM .</p><p>Following is a list of features adopted in the two baselines, for both Baseline C4.5 and Base- line SVM ,  Basic features: first token and its part-of- speech (POS) tag of the focus candidate; the number of tokens in the focus candidate; relative position of the focus candidate among all the roles present in the sentence; negated verb and its POS tag of the negative expression;  Syntactic features: the sequence of words from the beginning of the governing VP to the negated verb; the sequence of POS tags from the beginning of the governing VP to the negated verb; whether the governing VP contains a CC; whether the governing VP contains a RB.  Semantic features: the syntactic label of se- mantic role A1; whether A1 contains POS tag DT, JJ, PRP, CD, RB, VB, and WP, as defined in Blanco and Moldovan (2011); whether A1 contains token any, anybody, an- ymore, anyone, anything, anytime, anywhere, certain, enough, full, many, much, other, some, specifics, too, and until, as defined in <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Blanco and Moldovan (2011)</ref>; the syntactic label of the first semantic role in the sentence; the semantic label of the last semantic role in the sentence; the thematic role for A0/A1/A2/A3/A4 of the negated predicate. and for Baseline SVM only,  Basic features: the named entity and its type in the focus candidate; relative position of the focus candidate to the negative expression (before or after).  Syntactic features: the dependency path and its depth from the focus candidate to the neg- ative expression; the constituent path and its depth from the focus candidate to the nega- tive expression;</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Exploring Contextual Discourse In- formation for Negation Focus Identi- fication</head><p>While some of negation focuses could be identi- fied by only intra-sentence information, others must be identified by contextual discourse in- formation. Section 1 illustrates the necessity of such contextual discourse information in nega- tion focus identification by giving three scenarios of different discourse contexts for negation ex- pression n't in sentence (3). For better illustration of the importance of contextual discourse information, <ref type="table">Table 1</ref> shows the statistics of intra-and inter-sentence infor- mation necessary for manual negation focus identification with 100 instances randomly ex- tracted from the held-out dataset of *SEM'2012 shared task corpus. It shows that only 17 instanc- es can be identified by intra-sentence information. It is surprising that inter-sentence information is indispensable in 77 instances, among which 42 instances need only inter-sentence information and 35 instances need both intra-and inter- sentence information. This indicates the great importance of contextual discourse information on negation focus identification. It is also inter- esting to note 6 instances are hard to determine even given both intra-and inter-sentence infor- mation.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Info</head><p>Number #Intra-Sentence Only 17 #Inter-Sentence Only 42 #Both 35 #Hard to Identify 6 (Note: "Hard to Identify" means that it is hard for a human being to identify the negation focus even given both intra-and inter-sentence information.) <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>. Statistics of intra-and inter-sentence information on negation focus identification.</p><p>Statistically, we find that negation focus is al- ways related with what authors repeatedly states in discourse context. This explains why contex- tual discourse information could help identify negation focus. While inter-sentence information provides the global characteristics from the dis- course context perspective and intra-sentence information provides the local features from lex- ical, syntactic and semantic perspectives, both have their own contributions on negation focus identification.</p><p>In this paper, we first propose a graph model to gauge the importance of contextual discourse information. Then, we incorporate both intra- and inter-sentence features into a machine learn- ing-based framework for negation focus identifi- cation.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">Graph Model</head><p>Graph models have been proven successful in many NLP applications, especially in represent- ing the link relationships between words or sen- tences ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Wan and Yang, 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Li et al., 2009</ref>). Generally, such models could construct a graph to compute the relevance between document theme and words.</p><p>In this paper, we propose a graph model to represent the contextual discourse information from both lexical and topic perspectives. In par- ticular, a word-based graph model is proposed to represent the explicit relatedness among words in a discourse from the lexical perspective, while a topic-driven word-based model is proposed to enrich the implicit relatedness between words, by adding one more layer to the word-based graph model in representing the global topic distribu- tion of the whole dataset. Besides, the PageRank algorithm ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Page et al., 1998</ref>) is adopted to opti- mize the graph model.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Word-based Graph Model:</head><p>A word-based graph model can be defined as G word <ref type="bibr">(W, E)</ref>, where W={w i } is the set of words in one document and E={e ij |w i , w j ∈W} is the set of directed edges between these words, as shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref>. In the word-based graph model, word node w i is weighted to represent the correlation of the word with authors' intention. Since such correla- tion is more from the semantic perspective than the grammatical perspective, only content words are considered in our graph model, ignoring functional words (e.g., the, to,…). Especially, the content words limited to those with part-of- speech tags of JJ, NN, PRP, and VB. For sim- plicity, the weight of word node w i is initialized to 1.</p><p>In addition, directed edge e ij is weighted to represent the relatedness between word w i and word w j in a document with transition probability P(j|i) from i to j, which is normalized as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">| ,, ∑ ,,<label>(1)</label></formula><p>where k represents the nodes in discourse, and Sim(w i ,w j ) denotes the similarity between w i and w j . In this paper, two kinds of information are used to calculate the similarity between words. One is word co-occurrence (if word w i and word w j occur in the same sentence or in the adjacent sentences, Sim(w i ,w j ) increases 1), and the other is WordNet <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(Miller, 1995)</ref> based similarity. Please note that Sim(w i ,w i ) = 0 to avoid self- transition, and Sim(w i ,w j ) and Sim(w j ,w i ) may not be equal.</p><p>Finally, the weights of word nodes are calcu- lated using the PageRank algorithm as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">1 ∑ | 1 (2)</formula><p>where d is the damping factor as in the PageRank algorithm.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Topic-driven Word-based Graph Model</head><p>While the above word-based graph model can well capture the relatedness between content words, it can only partially model the focus of a negation expression since negation focus is more directly related with topic than content. In order to reduce the gap, we propose a topic-driven word-based model by adding one more layer to refine the word-based graph model over the global topic distribution, as shown in <ref type="figure">Figure 2</ref>. <ref type="figure">Figure 2</ref>. Topic-driven word-based graph model.</p><p>Here, the topics are extracted from all the doc- uments in the *SEM 2012 shared task using the LDA Gibbs Sampling algorithm <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Griffiths, 2002</ref>). In the topic-driven word-based graph model, the first layer denotes the relatedness among content words as captured in the above word-based graph model, and the second layer denotes the topic distribution, with the dashed lines between these two layers indicating the word-topic model re- turn by LDA.</p><p>Formally, the topic-driven word-based two- layer graph is defined as G topic (W, T, E w , E t ), where W={w i } is the set of words in one docu- ment and T={t i } is the set of topics in all docu- ments; E w ={ew ij |w i , w j ∈W} is the set of directed edges between words and E t ={et ij |w i ∈W, t j ∈T} is the set of undirected edges between words and topics; transition probability P w (j|i) of ew ij is de- fined as the same as P(j|i) of the word-based graph model. Besides, transition probability P t (i,m) of et ij in the word-topic model is defined as:</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">, ,, ∑ ,,<label>(3)</label></formula><p>where Rel(w i , t m ) is the weight of word w i in top- ic t m calculated by the LDA Gibbs Sampling al- gorithm. On the basis, the transition probability P w (j|i) of ew ij is updated by calculating as fol- lowing:</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">′ | θ • | 1 1 θ • , , ∑ , ,<label>(4)</label></formula><p>where k represents all topics linked to both word w i and word w j , and θ∈ <ref type="bibr">[0,</ref><ref type="bibr">1]</ref> is the coefficient controlling the relative contributions from the lexical information in current document and the topic information in all documents.</p><p>Finally, the weights of word nodes are calcu- lated using the PageRank algorithm as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_4">1 ∑ ′ | 1 (5)</formula><p>where d is the damping factor as in the PageRank algorithm.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">Negation Focus Identification via Graph Model</head><p>Given the graph models and the PageRank opti- mization algorithm discussed above, four kinds of contextual discourse information are extracted as inter-sentence features <ref type="table">(Table 2</ref>).</p><p>In particular, the total weight and the max weight of words in the focus candidate are calcu- lated as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_5">∑ (6)</formula><p>max <ref type="formula">(7)</ref> where i represents the content words in the focus candidate. These two kinds of weights focus on different aspects about the focus candidate with the former on the contribution of content words, which is more beneficial for a long focus candi- date, and the latter biased towards the focus can- didate which contains some critical word in a discourse.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>No</head><p>Feature 1</p><p>Total weight of words in the focus candi- date using the co-occurrence similarity.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>2</head><p>Max weight of words in the focus candi- date using the co-occurrence similarity.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>3</head><p>Total weight of words in the focus candi- date using the WordNet similarity.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>4</head><p>Max weight of words in the focus candi- date using the WordNet similarity. <ref type="table">Table 2</ref>. Inter-sentence features extracted from graph model.</p><p>For evaluating the contribution of contextual discourse information on negation focus identifi- cation directly, we incorporate the four inter- sentence features from the topic-driven word- based graph model into a negation focus identifi- er.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Experimentation</head><p>In this section, we describe experimental settings and systematically evaluate our negation focus identification approach with focus on exploring the effectiveness of contextual discourse infor- mation.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.1">Experimental Settings</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Dataset</head><p>In all our experiments, we employ the *SEM'2012 shared task corpus (Morante and Blanco, 2012) 2 . As a freely downloadable re- source, the *SEM shared task corpus is annotated on top of PropBank, which uses the WSJ section of the Penn TreeBank. In particular, negation focus annotation on this corpus is restricted to verbal negations (with corresponding mark MNEG in PropBank). On 50% of the corpus an- notated by two annotators, the inter-annotator agreement was 0.72 ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Blanco and Moldovan, 2011)</ref>. Along with negation focus annotation, this corpus also contains other annotations, such as POS tag, named entity, chunk, constituent tree, dependency tree, and semantic role.</p><p>In total, this corpus provides 3,544 instances of negation focus annotations. For fair compari- son, we adopt the same partition as *SEM'2012 shared task in all our experiments, i.e., with 2,302 for training, 530 for development, and 712 for testing. Although for each instance, the cor- pus only provides the current sentence, the pre- vious and next sentences as its context, we sort to the Penn TreeBank 3 to obtain the corresponding document as its discourse context.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Evaluation Metrics</head><p>Same as the *SEM'2012 shared task, the evalua- tion is made using precision, recall, and F1-score. Especially, a true positive (TP) requires an exact match for the negation focus, a false positive (FP) occurs when a system predicts a non-existing negation focus, and a false negative (FN) occurs when the gold annotations specify a negation focus but the system makes no prediction. For each instance, the predicted focus is considered correct if it is a complete match with a gold an- notation.</p><p>Beside, to show whether an improvement is significant, we conducted significance testing using z-test, as described in <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Blanco and Moldovan (2011)</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Toolkits</head><p>In our experiments, we report not only the de- fault performance with gold additional annotated features provided by the *SEM'2012 shared task corpus and the Penn TreeBank, but also the per- formance with various kinds of features extracted automatically, using following toolkits:  Syntactic Parser: We employ the Stanford Parser 4 ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Klein and Manning, 2003;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b2">De Marneffe et al., 2006</ref>) for tokenization, constituent and dependency parsing.  Named Entity Recognizer: We employ the Stanford NER 5 ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Finkel et al., 2005</ref>) to obtain named entities.</p><p> Semantic Role Labeler: We employ the se- mantic role labeler, as described in Punyaka- nok et al <ref type="bibr">(2008)</ref>.  Topic Modeler: For estimating transition probability Pt(i,m), we employ GibbsLDA++ 6 , an LDA model using Gibbs Sampling technique for parameter estimation and inference.  Classifier: We employ SVM Light 7 with default parameters as our classifier.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.2">Experimental Results</head><p>With Only Intra-sentence Information <ref type="table">Table 3</ref> shows the performance of the two base- lines, the decision tree-based classifier as in Blanco and Moldovan (2011) and our ranking SVM-based classifier. It shows that our ranking SVM-based baseline slightly improves the F1- measure by 2.52% over the decision tree-based baseline, largely due to the incorporation of more refined features.  <ref type="table">Table 3</ref>. Performance of baselines with only intra-sentence information.</p><formula xml:id="formula_6">System P(%) R(%) F1</formula><p>Error analysis of the ranking SVM-based baseline on development data shows that 72% of them are caused by the ignorance of inter- sentence information. For example, among the 42 instances listed in the category of "#Inter- Sentence Only" in <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>, only 7 instances can be identified correctly by the ranking SVM- based classifier. With about 4 focus candidates in one sentence on average, this percentage is even lower than random.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>With Only Inter-sentence Information</head><p>For exploring the usefulness of pure contextual discourse information in negation focus identifi- cation, we only employ inter-sentence features into ranking SVM-based classifier. First of all, we estimate two parameters for our topic-driven word-based graph model: topic number T for topic model and coefficient θ between P w (j|i) and P t (i,m) in Formula 4.</p><p>Given the LDA Gibbs Sampling model with parameters α = 50/T and β = 0.1, we vary T from 20 to 100 with an interval of 10 to find the opti-mal T. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 3</ref> shows the experiment results of varying T (with θ = 0.5) on development data. It shows that the best performance is achieved when T = 50 with 51.11 in F1). Therefore, we set T as 50 in our following experiments. For parameter θ, a trade-off between the tran- sition probability P w (j|i) (word to word) and the transition probability P t (i,m) (word and topic) to update P' w (j|i), we vary it from 0 to 1 with an interval of 0.1. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 4</ref> shows the experiment results of varying θ (with T=50) on development data. It shows that the best performance is achieved when θ = 0.6, which are adopted here- after in all our experiments. This indicates that direct lexical information in current document contributes more than indirect topic information in all documents on negation focus identification. It also shows that direct lexical information in current document and indirect topic information in all documents are much complementary on negation focus identification. using topic-driven word- based graph model 54.59 50.76 52.61 <ref type="table">Table 4</ref>. Performance with only inter-sentence information. <ref type="table">Table 4</ref> shows the performance of negation focus identification with only inter-sentence fea- tures. It also shows that the system with inter- sentence features from the topic-driven word- based graph model significantly improves the F1-measure by 8.86 over the system with inter- sentence features from the word-based graph model, largely due to the usefulness of topic in- formation.</p><p>In comparison with <ref type="table">Table 3</ref>, it shows that the system with only intra-sentence features achieves better performance than the one with only inter- sentence features (59.64 vs. 52.61 in F1- measure).</p><p>With both Intra-and Inter-sentence In- formation <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">Table 5</ref> shows that enriching intra-sentence fea- tures with inter-sentence features significantly (p&lt;0.01) improve the performance by 9.85 in F1- measure than the better baseline. This indicates the usefulness of such contextual discourse in- formation and the effectiveness of our topic- driven word-based graph model in negation fo- cus identification.   <ref type="table">Table 6</ref>. Performance comparison of systems on negation focus identification with automatically extracted features.</p><formula xml:id="formula_7">System P(%) R(%) F1</formula><p>Besides, <ref type="table">Table 6</ref> shows the performance of our best system with all features automatically extracted using the toolkits as described in Sec- tion 5.1. Compared with our best system employ- ing gold additional annotated features (the last line in <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">Table 5</ref>), the homologous system with automatically extracted features (the last line in <ref type="table">Table 6</ref>) only decrease of less than 4 in F1- measure. This demonstrates the achievability of our approach.</p><p>In comparison with the best-reported perfor- mance on the *SEM'2012 shared task <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">(Rosenberg and Bergler, 2012)</ref>, our system performs better by about 11 in F-measure.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.3">Discussion</head><p>While this paper verifies the usefulness of con- textual discourse information on negation focus identification, the performance with only inter- sentence features is still weaker than that with only intra-sentence features. There are two main reasons. On the one hand, the former employs an unsupervised approach without prior knowledge for training. On the other hand, the usefulness of inter-sentence features depends on the assump- tion that a negation focus relates to the meaning of which is most relevant to authors' intention in a discourse. If there lacks relevant information in a discourse context, negation focus will become difficult to be identified only by inter-sentence features.</p><p>Error analysis also shows that some of the ne- gation focuses are very difficult to be identified, even for a human being. Consider the sentence (3) in Section 1, if given sentence because of her neighbors' protests, but her husband doesn't think so as its following context, both Helen and to play the violin can become the negation focus. Moreover, the inter-annotator agreement in the first round of negation focus annotation can only reach 0.72 ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Blanco and Moldovan, 2011</ref>). This indicates inherent difficulty in negation focus identification.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Conclusion</head><p>In this paper, we propose a graph model to enrich intra-sentence features with inter-sentence fea- tures from both lexical and topic perspectives. In this graph model, the relatedness between words is calculated by word co-occurrence, WordNet- based similarity, and topic-driven similarity. Evaluation on the *SEM 2012 shared task corpus indicates the usefulness of contextual discourse information on negation focus identification and our graph model in capturing such global infor- mation.</p><p>In future work, we will focus on exploring more contextual discourse information via the graph model and better ways of integrating intra- and inter-sentence information on negation focus identification.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1. Word-based graph model.</figDesc><graphic url="image-1.png" coords="4,81.21,499.92,198.84,141.66" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 3 .</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Figure 3. Performance with varying T.</figDesc><graphic url="image-3.png" coords="7,73.23,139.50,214.80,135.24" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 4 .</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Figure 4. Performance with varying θ. System P(%) R(%) F1 using word-based graph model 45.62 42.02 43.75</figDesc><graphic url="image-4.png" coords="7,72.03,501.12,221.64,143.64" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" validated="false"><head>Table 5 .</head><label>5</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Performance comparison of systems on 
negation focus identification. 

System 
P(%) R(%) 
F1 
Baseline C4.5 with intra 
feat. only (auto) 
60.94 44.62 51.52 

Baseline SVM with intra 
feat. Only (auto) 
53.81 51.67 52.72 

Ours with Both feat. 
using word-based GM 
(auto) 

58.77 57.19 57.97 

Ours with Both feat. 
using topic-driven 
word-based GM (auto) 

66.74 64.53 65.62 

</table></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="3"> Baselines Negation focus identification in *SEM&apos;2012 shared tasks is restricted to verbal negations annotated with MNEG in PropBank, with only the constituent belonging to a semantic role selected as negation focus. Normally, a verbal negation expression (not or n&apos;t) is grammatically associated with its corresponding verb (e.g., He didn&apos;t stop). For details on annotation guidelines and 1 In *SEM&apos;2013, the shared task is changed with focus on &quot;Semantic Textual Similarity&quot;.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="2"> http://www.clips.ua.ac.be/sem2012-st-neg/</note>

			<note place="foot" n="3"> http://www.cis.upenn.edu/~treebank/ 4 http://nlp.stanford.edu/software/lex-parser.shtml 5 http://nlp.stanford.edu/ner/</note>

			<note place="foot" n="6"> http://gibbslda.sourceforge.net/ 7 http://svmlight.joachims.org</note>

			<note place="foot">Roser Morante and Walter Daelemans. 2012. Conan Doyle-neg: Annotation of negation cues and their scope in Conan Doyle stories. In Proceedings of LREC 2012, Istambul.</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Semantic Representation of Negation Using Focus Detection</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Eduardo</forename><surname>Blanco</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dan</forename><surname>Moldovan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 49th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the 49th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics<address><addrLine>Portland, Oregon</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011-06-19" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="581" to="589" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A simple algorithm for identifying negated findings and diseases in discharge summaries</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wendy</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Chapman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Will</forename><surname>Bridewell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Paul</forename><surname>Hanbury</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gregory</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Cooper</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bruce</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Buchanan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Biomedical Informatics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">34</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="301" to="310" />
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Generating Typed Dependency Parses from Phrase Structure Parses</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marie-Catherine De</forename><surname>Marneffe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bill</forename><surname>Maccartney</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Christopher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Manning</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of LREC</title>
		<meeting>LREC</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Implied Negation in Discourse</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yun</forename><surname>Ding</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Theory and Practice in Language Studies</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="44" to="51" />
			<date type="published" when="2011-01" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Incorporating non-local information into information extraction systems by gibbs sampling</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jenny</forename><forename type="middle">Rose</forename><surname>Finkel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Trond</forename><surname>Grenager</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christopher</forename><surname>Manning</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 43rd Annual Meeting on Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the 43rd Annual Meeting on Association for Computational Linguistics<address><addrLine>Stroudsburg, PA, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="363" to="370" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Gibbs sampling in the generative model of Latent Dirichlet Allocation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tom</forename><surname>Griffiths</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
			<pubPlace>Stanford University</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
<note type="report_type">Tech. rep.</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">A Natural History of Negation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Laurence R Horn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1989" />
			<publisher>Chicago University Press</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Chicago, IL</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Answering Opinion Questions with Random Walks on Graphs</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Fangtao</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yang</forename><surname>Tang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Minlie</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xiaoyan</forename><surname>Zhu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 47th Annual Meeting of the ACL and the 4th IJCNLP of the AFNLP</title>
		<meeting>the 47th Annual Meeting of the ACL and the 4th IJCNLP of the AFNLP<address><addrLine>Suntec, Singapore</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009-08" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2" to="7" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Learning the Scope of Negation via Shallow Semantic Parsing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Junhui</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Guodong</forename><surname>Zhou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hongling</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Qiaoming</forename><surname>Zhu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 23rd International Conference on Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the 23rd International Conference on Computational Linguistics<address><addrLine>Stroudsburg, PA, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="671" to="679" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Association for Computational Linguistics</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Overview of BioNLP&apos;09 Shared Task on Event Extraction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jin-Dong</forename><surname>Kim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tomoko</forename><surname>Ohta</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sampo</forename><surname>Pyysalo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yoshinobu</forename><surname>Kano</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jun&amp;apos;ichi</forename><surname>Tsujii</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the BioNLP&apos;2009 Workshop Companion Volume for Shared Task</title>
		<meeting>the BioNLP&apos;2009 Workshop Companion Volume for Shared Task<address><addrLine>Stroudsburg, PA, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="9" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>: Association for Computational Linguistics</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Accurate Unlexicalized Parsing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dan</forename><surname>Klein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christopher</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Manning</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 41st Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the 41st Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="423" to="430" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Wordnet: a lexical database for english</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">George</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Miller</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Commun. ACM</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">38</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="39" to="41" />
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Learning the Scope of Negation in Biomedical Texts</title>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2008 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</title>
		<editor>Roser Morante, Anthony Liekens and Walter Daelemans</editor>
		<meeting>the 2008 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing<address><addrLine>Honolulu, October</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="715" to="724" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<monogr>
				<title level="m">Proceedings of the Workshop on Negation and Speculation in Natural Language Processing. University of Antwerp</title>
		<editor>Roser Morante and Caroline Sporleder</editor>
		<meeting>the Workshop on Negation and Speculation in Natural Language Processing. University of Antwerp<address><addrLine>Uppsala, Sweden</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">*SEM 2012 Shared Task: Resolving the Scope and Focus of Negation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Roser</forename><surname>Morante</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Eduardo</forename><surname>Blanco</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the First Joint Conference on Lexical and Computational Semantics (*SEM)</title>
		<meeting>the First Joint Conference on Lexical and Computational Semantics (*SEM)<address><addrLine>Montreal, Canada</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012-06-78" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="265" to="274" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Modality and Negation: An Introduction to the Special Issue</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Roser</forename><surname>Morante</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Caroline</forename><surname>Sporleder</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Computational Linguistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">38</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="223" to="260" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The pagerank citation ranking: Bringing order to the web</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lawrence</forename><surname>Page</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sergey</forename><surname>Brin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rajeev</forename><surname>Motwani</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Terry</forename><surname>Winograd</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>Stanford University</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
<note type="report_type">Technical report</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The importance of syntactic parsing and inference in semantic role labeling</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Vasin</forename><surname>Punyakanok</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dan</forename><surname>Roth</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wen-Tau</forename><surname>Yih</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Computational Linguistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">34</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="257" to="287" />
			<date type="published" when="2008-06" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">UConcordia: CLaC Negation Focus Detection at *Sem</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sabine</forename><surname>Rosenberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sabine</forename><surname>Bergler</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the First Joint Conference on Lexical and Computational Semantics (*SEM)</title>
		<meeting>the First Joint Conference on Lexical and Computational Semantics (*SEM)<address><addrLine>Montreal, Canada; London</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="294" to="300" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Negative Contexts: Collocation, Polarity, and Multiple Negation. Routledge</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The BioScope corpus: biomedical texts annotated for uncertainty,negation and their scopes</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Veronika</forename><surname>Vincze</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">György</forename><surname>Szarvas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Richárd</forename><surname>Farkas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">György</forename><surname>Móra</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">János</forename><surname>Csirik</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">BMC Bioinformatics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">9</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Suppl</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Multidocument summarization using cluster-based link analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xiaojun</forename><surname>Wan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jianwu</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 31st annual international ACM SIGIR conference on Research and development in information retrieval</title>
		<meeting>the 31st annual international ACM SIGIR conference on Research and development in information retrieval</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="299" to="306" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
