<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T12:10+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Citation Resolution: A method for evaluating context-based citation recommendation systems</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
				<availability status="unknown"><p>Copyright Association for Computational Linguistics</p>
				</availability>
				<date>June 23-25 2014. 2014</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Daniel</forename><surname>Duma</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">University of Edinburgh D.C.Duma@sms</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">University of Edinburgh</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ewan</forename><surname>Klein</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">University of Edinburgh D.C.Duma@sms</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">University of Edinburgh</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Citation Resolution: A method for evaluating context-based citation recommendation systems</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 52nd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
						<meeting>the 52nd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics <address><addrLine>Baltimore, Maryland, USA</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="358" to="363"/>
							<date type="published">June 23-25 2014. 2014</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Wouldn&apos;t it be helpful if your text editor automatically suggested papers that are relevant to your research? Wouldn&apos;t it be even better if those suggestions were contextually relevant? In this paper we name a system that would accomplish this a context-based citation recommendation (CBCR) system. We specifically present Citation Resolution, a method for the evaluation of CBCR systems which exclusively uses readily-available scientific articles. Exploiting the human judgements that are already implicit in available resources, we avoid purpose-specific annotation. We apply this evaluation to three sets of methods for representing a document, based on a) the contents of the document, b) the surrounding contexts of citations to the document found in other documents, and c) a mixture of the two.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Imagine that you were working on a draft paper which contained a sentence like the following: <ref type="bibr">1</ref> A variety of coherence theories have been developed over the years ... and their principles have found application in many symbolic text generation sys- tems (e.g.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>[CITATION HERE])</head><p>Wouldn't it be helpful if your editor automat- ically suggested some references that you could cite here? This is what a citation recommenda- tion system ought to do. If the system is able to take into account the context in which the citation occurs -for example, that papers relevant to our example above are not only about text generation <ref type="bibr">1</ref> Adapted from the introduction to <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Barzilay and Lapata (2008)</ref> systems, but specifically mention applying coher- ence theories -then this would be much more informative. So we define a context-based citation recommendation (CBCR) system as one that assists the author of a draft document by suggesting other documents with content that is relevant to a partic- ular context in the draft.</p><p>Our longer term research goal is to provide sug- gestions that satisfy the requirements of specific expository or rhetorical tasks, e.g. provide support for a particular argument, acknowledge previous work that uses the same methodology, or exem- plify work that would benefit from the outcomes of the author's work. However, our current pa- per has more modest aims: we present initial re- sults using existing IR-based approaches and we introduce an evaluation method and metric. CBCR systems are not yet widely available, but a num- ber of experiments have been carried out that may pave the way for their popularisation, e.g. <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">He et al. (2010)</ref>, <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Schäfer and Kasterka (2010)</ref> and <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">He et al. (2012)</ref>. It is within this early wave of experiments that our work is framed.</p><p>A main problem we face is that evaluating the performance of these systems ultimately requires human judgement. This can be captured as a set of relevance judgements for candidate citations over a corpus of documents, which is an arduous ef- fort that requires considerable manual input and very careful preparation. In designing a context- based citation recommendation system, we would ideally like to minimise these costs.</p><p>Fortunately there is already an abundance of data that meets our requirements: every scientific paper contains human "judgements" in the form of citations to other papers which are contextually appropriate: that is, relevant to specific passages of the document and aligned with its argumenta- tive structure. Citation Resolution is a method for evaluating CBCR systems that is exclusively based on this source of human judgements.</p><p>Let's define some terminology. In the follow- ing passage, the strings 'Scott and de <ref type="bibr">Souza, 1990' and</ref><ref type="bibr">'Kibble and</ref><ref type="bibr">Power, 2004</ref>' are both citation to- kens:</p><p>A variety of coherence theories have been developed over the years ... and their principles have found application in many symbolic text generation sys- tems (e.g. Scott and de <ref type="bibr">Souza, 1990;</ref><ref type="bibr">Kibble and Power, 2004)</ref> Note that a citation token can use any standard for- mat. Furthermore</p><p>• a citation context is the context in which a ci- tation token occurs, with no limit as to repre- sentation of this context, length or processing involved; • a collection-internal reference is a reference in the bibliography of the source document that matches a document in a given corpus; • a resolvable citation is an in-text citation to- ken which resolves to a collection-internal reference.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Related work</head><p>While the existing work in this specific area is far from extensive, previous experiments in evalu- ating context-based citation recommendation sys- tems have used one of three approaches. First, evaluation can be carried out through user studies, which is costly because it cannot be reused (e.g. <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Chandrasekaran et al. (2008)</ref>). Second, a set of relevance judgements can be created for repeated testing. <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Ritchie (2009)</ref> details the building of a large set of relevance judgements in order to evaluate an experimental document re- trieval system. The judgements were mainly pro- vided by the authors of papers submitted to a lo- cally organised conference, for over 140 queries, each of them being the main research question of one paper. This is a standard approach in IR, known as building a test collection <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Sanderson, 2010)</ref>, which the author herself notes was an ar- duous and time-consuming task.</p><p>Third, as we outlined above, existing citations between papers can be exploited as a source of human judgements. The most relevant previous work on this is <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">He et al. (2010)</ref>, who built an ex- perimental CBCR system using the whole index of CiteSeerX as a test collection (over 450,000 docu- ments). They avoided direct human evaluation and instead used three relevance metrics:</p><p>• Recall, the presence of the original reference in the list of suggestions generated by the sys- tem; • Co-cited probability, a ratio between, on the one hand, the number of papers citing both the original reference and a recommended one, and on the other hand, the number of pa- pers citing either of them; and • Normalized Discounted Cumulative Gain, a measure based on the rank of the original ref- erence in the list of suggested references, its score decreasing logarithmically.</p><p>However, these metrics fail to adequately recog- nise that the particular reference used by an author e.g. in support of an argument or as exemplifica- tion of an approach, may not be the most appro- priate that could be found in the whole collection. This does not just amount to a difference of opin- ion between different authors; it is possible that within a large enough collection there exists a pa- per which the original author herself would con- sider to be more appropriate by any criteria (per- suasive power, discoverability or the publication, etc.) than the one actually cited in the paper. Also, given that recommending the original citation used by the author in first position is our key criterion, a metric with smooth discounting like NDCG is too lenient for our purposes.</p><p>We have then chosen top-1 accuracy as our met- ric, where every time the original citation is first on the list of suggestions, it receives a score of 1, and 0 otherwise, and these scores are averaged over all resolved citations in the document collection. This metric is intuitive in measuring the efficiency of the system at this task, as it is immediately in- terpretable as a percentage of success.</p><p>While previous experiments in CBCR, like the ones we have just presented, have treated the task as an Information Retrieval problem, our ultimate purpose is different and travels beyond IR into Question Answering. We want to ultimately be able to assess the reason a document was cited in the context of the argumentation structure of the document, following previous work on the auto- matic classification of citation function by , <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Liakata et al. (2012)</ref> and <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Schäfer and Kasterka (2010)</ref>. We expect this will allow us to identify claims made in a draft paper and match them with related claims made in other papers for support or contrast, and so offer answers in the form of relevant passages extracted from the sug-gested documents.</p><p>It is frequently observed that the reasons for cit- ing a paper go beyond its contribution to the field and its relevance to the research being reported <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Hyland, 2009)</ref>. There is a large body of research on the motivations behind citing documents <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(MacRoberts and MacRoberts, 1996)</ref>, and it is likely that this will come to play a part in our research in the future.</p><p>In this paper, however, we present our initial results which compare three different sets of IR- based approaches to generating the document rep- resentation for a CBCR system. One is based on the contents of the document itself, one is based on the existing contexts of citations of this paper in other documents, and the third is a mixture of the two.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">The task: Citation Resolution</head><p>In this section we present the evaluation method in more abstract terms; for the implementation used in this paper, please see Sections 4 and 5. The core criterion of this task is to use only the human judgements that we have clearest evidence for. Let d be a document and R the collection of all doc- uments that are referenced in d. We believe it is reasonable to assume that the author of document d knows enough about the contents of each doc- ument R i to choose the most appropriate citation from the collection R for every citation context in the document.</p><p>This captures a very strong relevance judge- ment about the relation between a particular cita- tion context in the document and a particular cited reference document. We use these judgements for evaluation: our task is to match every citation con- text in the document (i.e. the surrounding context of a citation token) with the right reference from the list of references cited by that paper.</p><p>This task differs somewhat from standard Infor- mation Retrieval, in that we are not trying to re- trieve a document from a larger collection outside the source document, but trying to resolve the cor- rect reference for a given citation context from an existing list of documents, that is, from the bibli- ography that has been manually curated by the au- thors. Our document collection used for retrieval is further composed of only the references of that document that we can access.</p><p>The algorithm for the task is presented in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure  1</ref>. For any given test document (2), we first extract all the citation tokens found in the text that cor- respond to a collection-internal reference (a). We then create a document representation of the refer- enced document (currently a Vector Space Model, but liable to change). This representation can be based on any information found in the document collection, excluding the document d itself: e.g. the text of the referenced document and the text of documents that cite it.</p><p>For each citation token we then extract its con- text (b.i), which becomes the query in IR terms. One way of doing this that we present here is to select a list of word tokens around the citation. We then attempt to resolve the citation by computing a score for the match between each reference rep- resentation and the citation context (b.ii). We rank all collection-internal references by this score in decreasing order, aiming for the original reference to be in the first position (b.iii).</p><p>In the case where multiple citations share the same context, that is, they are made in di- rect succession (e.g. "...compared with previous approaches ( <ref type="bibr">Author (2005)</ref>, <ref type="bibr">Author and Author (2007)</ref>)"), the first n elements of the list of sug- gested documents all count as the first element. That is, if any of the references in a multiple ci- tation of n elements appears in the first n posi- tions of the list of suggestions, it counts as a suc- cessful resolution and receives a score of 1. The final score is averaged over all citation contexts processed.</p><p>The set of experiments we present here apply this evaluation to test a number of IR techniques which we detail in the next section. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Experiments</head><p>Our test corpus consists of approx. 9000 papers from the ACL Anthology 2 converted from PDF to XML format. This corpus, the rationale behind its selection and the process used to convert the files is described in depth in <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Ritchie et al. (2006)</ref>. This is an ideal corpus for these tests for a large number of reasons, but these are key for us: all the papers are freely available, the ratio of collection-internal references for each paper is high (the authors mea- sure it at 0.33) and it is a familiar domain for us.</p><p>For our tests, we selected the documents of this corpus with at least 8 collection-internal refer- ences. This yielded a total of 278 test documents and a total of 5446 resolvable citations.</p><p>We substitute all citations in the text with ci- tation token placeholders and extract the citation context for each using a simple window of up to w words left and w words right around the place- holder. This produces a list of word tokens that is equivalent to a query in IR. This is a frequently employed technique <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(He et al., 2010)</ref>, although it is often observed that this may be too simplistic a method <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(Ritchie, 2009)</ref>. Other methods have been tried, e.g. full sentence extraction ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">He et al., 2012)</ref> and comparing these methods is something we plan to incorporate in future work.</p><p>We then make the document's collection- internal references our test collection D and use a number of methods for generating the document representation. We use the well-known Vector Space Model and a standard implementation of tf- idf and cosine similarity as implemented by the scikit-learn Python framework 3 . At present, we are applying no cut-off and just rank all of the doc- ument's collection-internal references for each ci- tation context, aiming to rank the correct one in the first positions in the list.</p><p>We tested three different approaches to gener- ating a document's VSM representation: internal representations, which are based on the contents of the document, external representations, which are built using a document's incoming link cita- tion contexts (following <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Ritchie (2009)</ref> and <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">He et al. (2010)</ref>) and mixed representations, which are an attempt to combine the two.</p><p>• The internal representations of the documents were generated using three different methods: title plus abstract, full text and passage. Pas- sage consists in splitting the document into half-overlapping passages of a fixed length of k words and choosing for each document the 3 http://scikit-learn.org passage with the maximum cosine similarity score with the query. We present the results of using 250, 300 and 350 as values for k.</p><p>• The external representations (inlink context) are based on extracting the context around ci- tation tokens to the document from other doc- uments in the collection, excluding the set of test papers. This is the same as using the an- chor text of a hyperlink to improve results in web-based IR (see <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Davison (2000)</ref> for exten- sive analyis). This context is extracted in the same way as the query: as a window, or list of w tokens surrounding the citation left and right. We present our best results, using sym- metrical and asymmetrical windows of w = [(5, 5), (10, 10), (10, 5), <ref type="bibr">(20,</ref><ref type="bibr">20)</ref>, <ref type="formula">(30, 30)</ref>].</p><p>• We build the mixed representations by simply concatenating the internal and external bags- of-words that represent the documents, from which we then build the VSM representa- tion. For this, we combine different window sizes for the inlink context with: full text, ti- tle abstract and passage350. <ref type="table">Table 1</ref> presents a selection of the most relevant results, where the best result and document rep- resentation method of each type is highlighted. We present results for the most relevant parameter values, producing the highest scores of all those tested. From a close look at internal methods, we can see that the passage method with k = 400 beats both full text and title abstract, suggesting that a more elaborate way of building a document repre- sentation should improve results. This is consis- tent with previous findings: <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Gay et al. (2005)</ref> had already reported that using selected sections plus captions of figures and title and abstract to build the internal document representation improves the results of their indexing task by 7.4% over just using title and abstract. Similarly, <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Jimeno-Yepes et al. (2013)</ref> showed that automatically generated summaries lead to similar recall and better index- ing precision than full-text articles for a keyword- based indexing task.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Results and discussion</head><p>However, it is immediately clear that purely ex- ternal methods obtain higher scores than internal ones. The best score of 0.413 is obtained by the inlink context method with a window of 10 tokens left, 5 right, combined with the similarly-sized ex-Method window5 5 window10 10 window10 5 window20 20 window30 30  <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>: Accuracy for each document representation method (rows) and context window size (columns).</p><p>traction method for the query (window10 10). We find it remarkable that inlink context is superior to internal methods, beating the best (passage400) by 0.02 absolute accuracy points. Whether this is be- cause the descriptions of these papers in the con- texts of incoming link citations capture the essence or key relevance of the paper, or whether this ef- fect is due to authors reusing their work or to these descriptions originating in a seed paper and be- ing then propagated through the literature, remain interesting research questions that we intend to tackle in future work.</p><p>The key finding from our experiments is how- ever that a mixture of internal and external methods beats both individually. The highest score is 0.469, achieved by a combination of in- link context 20 and the passage method, for a win- dow of w = 20, with a tie between using 250 and 350 as values for k (passage size). The small dif- ference in score between parameter values is per- haps not as relevant as the finding that, taken to- gether, mixed methods consistently beat both ex- ternal and internal methods.</p><p>These results also show that the task is far from solved, with the highest accuracy achieved being just under 47%. There is clear room for improve- ment, which we believe could firstly come from a more targeted extraction of text, both for generat- ing the document representations and for extract- ing the citation contexts.</p><p>Our ultimate goal is matching claims and com- paring methods, which would likely benefit from an analysis of the full contents of the document and not just previous citations of it, so in future work we also intend to use the context from the successful external results as training data for a summarisation stage.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Conclusion and future work</head><p>In this paper we have presented Citation Reso- lution: an evaluation method for context-based citation recommendation (CBCR) systems. Our method exploits the implicit human relevance judgements found in existing scientific articles and so does not require purpose-specific human anno- tation.</p><p>We have employed Citation Resolution to test three approaches to building a document repre- sentation for a CBCR system: internal (based on the contents of the document), external (based on the surrounding contexts to citations to that doc- ument) and mixed (a mixture of the two). Our evaluation shows that: 1) using chunks of a doc- ument (passages) as its representation yields bet- ter results that using its full text, 2) external meth- ods obtain higher scores than internal ones, and 3) mixed methods yield better results than either in isolation.</p><p>We intend to investigate more sophisticated ways of document representation and of extract- ing a citation's context. Our ultimate goal is not just to suggest to the author documents that are "relevant" to a specific chunk of the paper (sen- tence, paragraph, etc.), but to do so with attention to rhetorical structure and thus to citation function. We also aim to apply our evaluation to other docu- ment collections in different scientific domains in order to test to what degree these results can be generalized.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: Algorithm for citation resolution.</figDesc></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="2"> http://http://aclweb.org/anthology/</note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Modeling local coherence: An entity-based approach</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Regina</forename><surname>Barzilay</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mirella</forename><surname>Lapata</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Computational Linguistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">34</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="34" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Conceptbased document recommendations for citeseer authors</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kannan</forename><surname>Chandrasekaran</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Susan</forename><surname>Gauch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Praveen</forename><surname>Lakkaraju</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hiep Phuc</forename><surname>Luong</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Adaptive Hypermedia and Adaptive WebBased Systems</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="83" to="92" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Topical locality in the web</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Brian D Davison</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 23rd annual international ACM SIGIR conference on Research and development in information retrieval</title>
		<meeting>the 23rd annual international ACM SIGIR conference on Research and development in information retrieval</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="272" to="279" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Semi-automatic indexing of full text biomedical articles</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Clifford</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mehmet</forename><surname>Gay</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alan</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Kayaalp</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Aronson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">AMIA Annual Symposium Proceedings</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
			<biblScope unit="page">271</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Context-aware citation recommendation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Qi</forename><surname>He</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jian</forename><surname>Pei</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Daniel</forename><surname>Kifer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Prasenjit</forename><surname>Mitra</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lee</forename><surname>Giles</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 19th international conference on World wide web</title>
		<meeting>the 19th international conference on World wide web</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="421" to="430" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Position-aligned translation model for citation recommendation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jing</forename><surname>He</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jian-Yun</forename><surname>Nie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yang</forename><surname>Lu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wayne Xin</forename><surname>Zhao</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">String Processing and Information Retrieval</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="251" to="263" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Academic discourse: English in a global context</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ken</forename><surname>Hyland</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<publisher>Bloomsbury Publishing</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Mesh indexing based on automatically generated summaries</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Laura</forename><surname>Antonio J Jimeno-Yepes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">James</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Plaza</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alan</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Mork</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alberto</forename><surname>Aronson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Díaz</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">BMC bioinformatics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">208</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Automatic recognition of conceptualization zones in scientific articles and two life science applications</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Maria</forename><surname>Liakata</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Shyamasree</forename><surname>Saha</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Simon</forename><surname>Dobnik</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Colin</forename><surname>Batchelor</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dietrich</forename><surname>Rebholz-Schuhmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Bioinformatics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">28</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="991" to="1000" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Problems of citation analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Michael</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Barbara</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Macroberts</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Macroberts</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Scientometrics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">36</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="435" to="444" />
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Creating a test collection for citation-based ir experiments</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Anna</forename><surname>Ritchie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Simone</forename><surname>Teufel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Stephen</forename><surname>Robertson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the main conference on Human Language Technology Conference of the North American Chapter of the Association of Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the main conference on Human Language Technology Conference of the North American Chapter of the Association of Computational Linguistics</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="391" to="398" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Citation context analysis for information retrieval</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Anna</forename><forename type="middle">Ritchie</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>University of Cambridge Computer Laboratory</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
<note type="report_type">Technical report</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Test collection based evaluation of information retrieval systems</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mark</forename><surname>Sanderson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<publisher>Now Publishers Inc</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Scientific authoring support: A tool to navigate in typed citation graphs</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ulrich</forename><surname>Schäfer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Uwe</forename><surname>Kasterka</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the NAACL HLT 2010 workshop on computational linguistics and writing: Writing processes and authoring aids</title>
		<meeting>the NAACL HLT 2010 workshop on computational linguistics and writing: Writing processes and authoring aids</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="7" to="14" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Automatic classification of citation function</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Simone</forename><surname>Teufel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Advaith</forename><surname>Siddharthan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dan</forename><surname>Tidhar</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2006 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</title>
		<meeting>the 2006 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="103" to="110" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Association for Computational Linguistics</note>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
