<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T10:23+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Bilingual Event Extraction: a Case Study on Trigger Type Determina-tion</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date>June 23-25</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Zhu</forename><surname>Zhu</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">Natural Language Processing Lab Soochow University</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Nanjing University of Science and Technology</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Shoushan</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">Natural Language Processing Lab Soochow University</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Nanjing University of Science and Technology</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">†</forename></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">Natural Language Processing Lab Soochow University</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Nanjing University of Science and Technology</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Guodong</forename><surname>Zhou</surname></persName>
							<email>gdzhou@suda.edu.cn</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">Natural Language Processing Lab Soochow University</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Nanjing University of Science and Technology</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rui</forename><surname>Xia</surname></persName>
							<email>rxia@njust.edu.cn</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">Natural Language Processing Lab Soochow University</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Nanjing University of Science and Technology</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Bilingual Event Extraction: a Case Study on Trigger Type Determina-tion</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 52nd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (Short Papers)</title>
						<meeting>the 52nd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (Short Papers) <address><addrLine>Baltimore, Maryland, USA</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="842" to="847"/>
							<date type="published">June 23-25</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Event extraction generally suffers from the data sparseness problem. In this paper, we address this problem by utilizing the labeled data from two different languages. As a preliminary study, we mainly focus on the sub-task of trigger type determination in event extraction. To make the training data in different languages help each other, we propose a uniform text representation with bilingual features to represent the samples and handle the difficulty of locating the triggers in the translated text from both monolingual and bilingual perspectives. Empirical studies demonstrate the effectiveness of the proposed approach to bilingual classification on trigger type determination. </p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Event extraction is an increasingly hot and chal- lenging research topic in the natural language processing (NLP) community <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Ahn, 2006;</ref><ref type="bibr">Saun et al. 2006;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b19">Zhao et al. 2008)</ref>. It aims to automat- ically extract certain types of events with the ar- guments to present the texts under a structured form. In event extraction, there are four primary subtasks, named trigger identification, trigger type determination, argument identification, and argument role determination <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Chen and NG, 2012)</ref>. As an important technology in infor- mation extraction, event extraction could be ap- plied to many fields such as information retrieval, summarization, text mining, and question an- swering.</p><p>Recently, the dominative approach to event extraction is based on supervised learning where a set of labeled samples are exploited to train a model to extract the events. However, the availa-  * Corresponding author ble labeled data are rather sparse due to various kinds of event categories. For example, the event taxonomy in ACE 2005 1 (Automatic Content Extraction) includes 8 types of events, with 33 subtypes, such as "Marry/Life" (subtype/type), and "Transport/Movement". Moreover, some subtypes such as "Nominate/Personnel" and "Convict/Justice" contain less than 10 labeled samples in the English and Chinese corpus re- spectively. Apparently, such a small scale of training data is difficult to yield a satisfying per- formance.</p><p>One possible way to alleviate the data sparse- ness problem in event extraction is to conduct bilingual event extraction with training data from two different languages. This is motivated by the fact that labeled data from a language is highly possible to convey similar information in another language. For example, E1 is an event sample from the English corpus and E2 is another one in the Chinese corpus. Apparently, E1 and the Eng- lish translation text of E2, share some important clues such as meet and Iraq which highly indi- cates the event type of "Meet/Contact". In this paper, we address the data sparseness problem in event extraction with a bilingual pro-cessing approach which aims to exploit bilingual training data to enhance the extraction perfor- mance in each language. As a preliminary work, we mainly focus on the subtask of trigger type determination. Accordingly, our goal is to design a classifier which is trained with labeled data from two different languages and is capable of classifying the test data from both languages. Generally, this task possesses two main chal- lenges.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>E1: Bush arrived in Saint</head><p>The first challenge is text representation, namely, how to eliminate the language gap be- tween the two languages. To tackle this, we first employ Google Translate 2 , a state-of-the-art ma- chine translation system, to gain the translation of an event instance, similar to what has been widely done by previous studies in bilingual classification tasks e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">Wan (2008)</ref>; Then, we uniformly represent each text with bilingual word features. That is, we augment each original feature vector into a novel one which contains the translated features.</p><p>The second challenge is the translation for some specific features. It is well-known that some specific features, such as the triggers and their context features, are extremely important for determining the event types. For example, in E3, both trigger "left" and named entity "Sad- dam" are important features to tell the event type, i.e., "Transport/Movement". When it is translated to Chinese, it is also required to know trigger "离 开"(left) and named entity "萨达姆" <ref type="bibr">(Saddam)</ref> in E4, the Chinese translation of E3. E3: Saddam's clan is said to have left for a small village in the desert.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>E4: Chinese translation: 据说 萨达姆 (Saddam) 家族 已经 离开(left) 沙漠 中 的 一个 小 村庄。</head><p>However, it is normally difficult to know which words are the triggers and surrounding entities in the translated sentence. To tackle this issue, we propose to locate the trigger from both monolingual and bilingual perspectives in the translation text. Empirical studies demonstrate that adding the translation of these specific fea- tures substantially improves the classification performance.</p><p>The remainder of this paper is organized as follows. Section 2 overviews the related work on event extraction. Section 3 proposes our ap-proach to bilingual event extraction. Section 4 gives the experimental studies. In Section 5, we conclude our work and give some future work.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Related Work</head><p>In the NLP community, event extraction has been mainly studied in both English and Chinese.</p><p>In English, various supervised learning ap- proaches have been explored recently. <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Bethard and Martin (2006)</ref> formulate the event identifica- tion as a classification problem in a word- chunking paradigm, introducing a variety of lin- guistically motivated features. Ahn (2006) pro- poses a trigger-based method. It first identifies the trigger in an event, and then uses a multi- classifier to implement trigger type determina- tion. <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Ji and Grishman (2008)</ref> employ an ap- proach to propagate consistent event arguments across sentences and documents. <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Liao and Grishman (2010)</ref>  In Chinese, relevant studies in event extraction are in a relatively primary stage with focus on more special characteristics and challenges. <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Tan et al. (2008)</ref> employ local feature selection and explicit discrimination of positive and negative features to ensure the performance of trigger type determination. <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Chen and Ji (2009)</ref> apply lexical, syntactic and semantic features in trigger label- ing and argument labeling to improve the per- formance. More recently, <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Li et al. (2012)</ref> and  introduce two inference mechanisms to infer unknown triggers and recover trigger mentions respectively with morphological struc- tures.</p><p>In comparison with above studies, we focus on bilingual event extraction. Although bilingual classification has been paid lots of attention in other fields <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">(Wan 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Haghighi et al., 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Ismail et al., 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr">Lu et al., 2011；Li et al., 2013</ref>, there is few related work in event extrac- tion. The only one related work we find is Ji (2009) which proposes an inductive learning ap- proach to exploit cross-lingual predicate clusters to improve the event extraction task with the main goal to get the event taggers from extra re- sources, i.e., an English and Chinese parallel corpus. Differently, our goal is to make the la-beled data from two languages help each other without any other extra resources, which is origi- nal in the study of event extraction.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">The Proposed Approach</head><p>Trigger type determination aims to determine the event type of a trigger given the trigger and its context (e.g., a sentence). Existing approaches to trigger type determination mainly focus on mon- olingual classification. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 1</ref> illustrates the framework for Chinese and English.</p><p>In comparison, our approach exploits the cor- pora from two different languages. <ref type="figure">Figure 2</ref> illus- trates the framework. As shown in the figure, we first get the translated corpora of Chinese and English origin corpora through machine transla- tion. Then, we represent each text with bilingual features, which enables us to merge the training data from both languages so as to make them help each other. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Text Representation</head><p>In a supervised learning approach, labeled data is trained to obtain a classifier. In this approach, the extracted features are the key components to make a successful classifier. <ref type="table">Table 1</ref> shows some typical kinds of features in a monolingual classi- fication task for trigger type determination. To better understand these features, the real feature examples in E3 are given in the table.</p><p>Given the feature definition, a monolingual sample x is represented as the combination of all the features, i.e., <ref type="bibr">12</ref>  In bilingual classification, we represent a sam- ple with bilingual features, which makes it possi- ble to train with the data from two languages. To achieve this goal, we employ a single feature augmentation strategy to augment the monolin- gual features into bilingual features, i.e.,</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">, Chinese English x x x <label>(2)</label></formula><p>Specifically, a sample x is represented as fol- lows: <ref type="bibr">1</ref>  </p><formula xml:id="formula_1">                          <label>(3)</label></formula><p>Where the tokens with the 'c'/'e' subscript mean the features generated from the Chinese/English text. From the features, we can see that some</p><p>Classifier Results</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Chinese event corpus</head><p>Machine trans- lation features, such as Tri_con and Ent, depend on the location of the trigger word. Therefore, locating the trigger in the translated text becomes crucial. In this paper, the above function could be solved in two perspectives: monolingual and bi- lingual ones. The former uses the English train- ing data alone to locate the trigger while the lat- ter exploit the bilingual information to get the translated counterpart of the Chinese trigger.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Locating Translated Trigger</head><p>The monolingual perspective: The objective is to locate the trigger with the monolingual in- formation. That is, </p><p>Where e R denotes the training resource in Eng- lish. In fact, this task is exactly the first subtask in event extraction named trigger identification, as mentioned in Introduction. For a simplified implementation, we first estimate the probabili- ties of   </p><p>Where c Tri is the trigger word in Chinese and e s is the translated text towards c s . More generally, this can be solved from a standard word align- ment model in machine translation ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Och et al, 1999;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Koehn et al, 2003</ref>). However, training a word alignment requires a huge parallel corpus which is not available here.</p><p>For a simplified implementation, we first get the </p><p>Where 0.9 is an empirical value which makes the translation probability become a dominative fac- tor when the translation of the trigger is found in the translated sentence.  is a small value which makes the sum of all probabilities equals 1. The final decision is made according to both the monolingual and bilingual perspectives, i.e.,</p><formula xml:id="formula_5">    _ 1, _ arg max | , | , , k l e e e k l m k l e e c c P e Tri s R P e Tri s s Tri   <label>(8)</label></formula><p>Note that we reduce the computational cost by make the word length of the trigger less than 3, i.e., 3 lk .</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Experimentation</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">Experimental Setting</head><p>Data sets: The Chinese and English corpus for even extraction are from ACE2005, which in- volves 8 types and 33 subtypes. All our experi- ments are conducted on the subtype case. Due to the space limit, we only report the statistics for each type, as shown in  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Classification algorithm:</head><p>The maximum en- tropy (ME) classifier is implemented with the public tool, Mallet Toolkits 3 .</p><p>Evaluation metric: The performance of event type recognition is evaluated with F-score.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">Experimental Results</head><p>In this section, we evaluate the performance of our approach to bilingual classification on trigger type determination. For comparison, following approaches are implemented:  Monolingual: perform monolingual classi- fication on the Chinese and English corpus individually, as shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 1</ref>.  Bilingual: perform bilingual classification with partial bilingual features, ignoring the context features (e.g., context words, con- text entities) under the assumption that the trigger location task is not done.  Bilingual_location: perform bilingual clas- sification by translating each sample into another language and using a uniform repre- sentation with all bilingual features as shown in Section 3.2. This is exactly our approach. The number of the context words and entities before or after the trigger words is set as 3.  <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Figure 3</ref> shows the classification results of the three approaches on the Chinese and English test data. From this figure, we can see that Bilin- gual_location apparently outperform Monolin- gual, which verifies the effectiveness of using bilingual corpus. Specifically, the improvement by our approach in Chinese is impressive, reach- ing 7.6%. The results also demonstrate the im- portance of the operation of the trigger location, without which, bilingual classification can only slightly improve the performance, as shown in the English test data.</p><p>The results demonstrate that our bilingual classification approaches are more effective for the Chinese data. This is understandable because the size of English data is much larger than that of Chinese data, 5285 vs. 2710, as shown in Ta- ble 2. Specifically, after checking the results in each subtype, we find that some subtypes in Chi- nese have very few samples while corresponding subtypes in English have a certain number sam- ples.</p><p>For example, the subtype of "Elect/Personnel" only contains 30 samples in the Chinese data while 161 samples can be found in the English data, which leads a very high im- provement (15.4%) for the Chinese test data. In summary, our bilingual classification approach provides an effective way to handle the data sparseness problem in even extraction.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Conclusion and Future Work</head><p>This paper addresses the data sparseness problem in event extraction by proposing a bilingual clas- sification approach. In this approach, we use a uniform text representation with bilingual fea- tures and merge the training samples from both languages to enlarge the size of the labeled data. Furthermore, we handle the difficulty of locating the trigger from both the monolingual and bilin- gual perspectives. Empirical studies show that our approach is effective in using bilingual cor- pus to improve monolingual classification in trigger type determination.</p><p>Bilingual event extraction is still in its early stage and many related research issues need to be investigated in the future work. For example, it is required to propose novel approaches to the bi- lingual processing tasks in other subtasks of event extraction. Moreover, it is rather challeng- ing to consider a whole bilingual processing framework when all these subtasks are involved together.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>apply document level infor- mation to improve the performance of event ex- traction. Hong et al. (2011) leverage cross-entity information to improve traditional event extrac- tion, regarding entity type consistency as a key feature. More recently, Li et al. (2013) propose a joint framework based on structured prediction which extracts triggers and arguments together.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: The framework of monolingual classification for trigger type determination</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head>Figure 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Figure 3: Performance comparison of the three approaches on the Chinese and English test data</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4" validated="false"><head>the objective is to get the English trigger e Tri in e s , given the Chinese trigger word c Tri in c s .</head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Without loss of generality, we consider the case 
of translating a Chinese event sample into an 
English one. Formally, the word sequence of a 
Chinese event sample is denoted as 

12 

( , , , ) 

cn 

s 
c c 
c 
 
, while the sequence of the 
translated one is denoted as 

12 

( , 
, ) 

em 

s 
e e 
e 
 
. 
Then, The objective function is given as fol-
lows: 

 
 

_ 
1, 

arg max 

k l 
e 
k l m 

P e 
Tri 

 

 
(4) 

Where _ 

kl 

e denotes the substring 

1 

( , 
, ) 

k 
k 
l 

e e 
e 

 

in e 
s and 1, k l m 
 . 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_6" validated="false"><head>Table 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>For each subtype, 
</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_7" validated="false"><head>Table 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Statistics in each event type in both Chinese 
and English data sets 

Features: The features have been illustrated in 
Table 1 in Section 3.2. </table></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> http://www.nist.gov/speech/tests/ace/2005</note>

			<note place="foot" n="2"> www.google.com</note>

			<note place="foot" n="3"> http://mallet.cs.umass.edu/</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Stages of Event Extraction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Ahn</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Workshop on Annotating and Reasoning about Time and Events</title>
		<meeting>the Workshop on Annotating and Reasoning about Time and Events</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="8" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Identification of Event Mentions and Their Semantic Class</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Bethard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Martin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of EMNLP-2006</title>
		<meeting>EMNLP-2006</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="146" to="154" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Joint Modeling for Chinese Event Extraction with Rich Linguistic Features</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Ng</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of COLING-2012</title>
		<meeting>COLING-2012</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="529" to="544" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Language Specific Issue and Feature Exploration in Chinese Event Extraction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Ji</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of NAACL-2009</title>
		<meeting>NAACL-2009</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="209" to="212" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Learning Bilingual Lexicons from Monolingual Corpora</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Haghighi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Liang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Berg-Kirkpatrick</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Klein</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of ACL2008</title>
		<meeting>ACL2008</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="771" to="779" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Using Cross-Entity Inference to Improve Event Extraction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Hong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Ma</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Yao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Zhou</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of ACL-2011</title>
		<meeting>ACL-2011</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1127" to="1136" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Bilingual Lexicon Extraction from Comparable Corpora Using Indomain Terms</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Ismail</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Manandhar</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of COLING-2010</title>
		<meeting>COLING-2010</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="481" to="489" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Cross-lingual Predicate Cluster Acquisition to Improve Bilingual Event Extraction by Inductive Learning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Ji</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Workshop on Unsupervised and Minimally Supervised Learning of Lexical Semantics</title>
		<meeting>the Workshop on Unsupervised and Minimally Supervised Learning of Lexical Semantics</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="27" to="35" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Refining Event Extraction through Cross-Document Inference</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Ji</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Grishman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of ACL-2008</title>
		<meeting>ACL-2008</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="254" to="262" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Statistical Phrase-based Translation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Koehn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Och</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Marcu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of HTLNAACL-2003</title>
		<meeting>HTLNAACL-2003</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="127" to="133" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Employing Morphological Structures and Sememes for Chinese Event Extraction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Zhou</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of COLING-2012</title>
		<meeting>COLING-2012</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1619" to="1634" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Using Compositional Semantics and Discourse Consistency to Improve Chinese Trigger Identification</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Q</forename><surname>Zhu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Zhou</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of COLING-2013</title>
		<meeting>COLING-2013</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="399" to="415" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Joint Event Extraction via Structured Prediction with Global Features</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Q</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Ji</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Liang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of ACL-2013</title>
		<meeting>ACL-2013</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="73" to="82" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Active Learning for Cross-Lingual Sentiment Classification</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of Natural Language Processing and Chinese Computing</title>
		<meeting>Natural Language Processing and Chinese Computing</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="236" to="246" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Using Document Level Cross-event Inference to Improve Event Extraction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Liao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Grishman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of ACL-2010</title>
		<meeting>ACL-2010</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="789" to="797" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Joint Bilingual Sentiment Classification with Unlabeled Parallel Corpora</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Lu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Tan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Cardie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Tsou</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of ACL-2011</title>
		<meeting>ACL-2011</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="320" to="330" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Improved Alignment Models for Statistical Machine Translation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Och</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Tillmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Ney</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of EMNLP-1999</title>
		<meeting>EMNLP-1999</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="20" to="28" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Identification of Chinese Event and Their Argument Roles</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Tan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Zhao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Zheng</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of CITWORKSHOPS-2008</title>
		<meeting>CITWORKSHOPS-2008</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="14" to="19" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Using Bilingual Knowledge and Ensemble Techniques for Unsupervised Chinese Sentiment Analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Wan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of EMNLP-2008</title>
		<meeting>EMNLP-2008</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="553" to="561" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Research on Chinese Event Extraction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Zhao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Qin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of Journal of Chinese Information</title>
		<meeting>Journal of Chinese Information</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3" to="8" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
