<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T10:27+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Recognizing Implied Predicate-Argument Relationships in Textual Inference</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
				<availability status="unknown"><p>Copyright Association for Computational Linguistics</p>
				</availability>
				<date>June 23-25 2014. 2014</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Asher</forename><surname>Stern</surname></persName>
							<email>astern7@cs.biu.ac.il</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Computer Science Department Bar-Ilan University</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Computer Science Department Bar-Ilan University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ido</forename><surname>Dagan</surname></persName>
							<email>dagan@cs.biu.ac.il</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Computer Science Department Bar-Ilan University</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Computer Science Department Bar-Ilan University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Recognizing Implied Predicate-Argument Relationships in Textual Inference</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 52nd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
						<meeting>the 52nd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics <address><addrLine>Baltimore, Maryland, USA</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="739" to="744"/>
							<date type="published">June 23-25 2014. 2014</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>We investigate recognizing implied predicate-argument relationships which are not explicitly expressed in syntactic structure. While prior works addressed such relationships as an extension to semantic role labeling, our work investigates them in the context of textual inference scenarios. Such scenarios provide prior information, which substantially eases the task. We provide a large and freely available evaluation dataset for our task setting, and propose methods to cope with it, while obtaining promising results in empirical evaluations.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Motivation and Task</head><p>This paper addresses a typical sub-task in tex- tual inference scenarios, of recognizing implied predicate-argument relationships which are not expressed explicitly through syntactic structure. Consider the following example: While a human reader understands that the withdrawal refers to Vioxx, and hence an im- plied predicate-argument relationship holds be- tween them, this relationship is not expressed in the syntactic structure, and will be missed by syn- tactic parsers or standard semantic role labelers.</p><p>This paper targets such types of implied rela- tionships in textual inference scenarios. Partic- ularly, we investigate the setting of Recognizing Textual Entailment (RTE) as a typical scenario of textual inference. We suggest, however, that the same challenge, as well as the solutions proposed in our work, are applicable, with proper adap- tations, to other textual-inference scenarios, like Question Answering, and Information Extraction (see <ref type="table">Section 6</ref>).</p><p>An RTE problem instance is composed of two text fragments, termed Text and Hypothesis, as in- put. The task is to recognize whether a human reading the Text would infer that the Hypothesis is most likely true ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Dagan et al., 2006</ref>). For our problem, consider a positive Text Hypothesis pair, where the Text is example (i) above and the Hy- pothesis is:</p><p>(ii) <ref type="bibr">Merck withdrew Vioxx.</ref> A common approach for recognizing textual en- tailment is to verify that all the textual elements of the Hypothesis are covered, or aligned, by el- ements of the Text. These elements typically in- clude lexical terms as well as relationships be- tween them. In our example, the Hypothesis lexi- cal terms ("Merck", "withdrew" and "Vioxx") are indeed covered by the Text. Yet, the predicate- argument relationships (e.g., "withdrawal-Vioxx") are not expressed in the text explicitly. In such a case, an RTE system has to verify that the predicate-argument relationships which are ex- plicitly expressed in the Hypothesis, are implied from the Text discourse. Such cases are quite fre- quent (∼17%) in the settings of our dataset, de- scribed in Section 3.</p><p>Consequently, we define the task of recognizing implied predicate-argument relationships, with il- lustrating examples in <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>, as follows. The input includes a Text and a Hypothesis. Two terms in the Hypothesis, predicate and argument, are marked, where a predicate-argument relationship between them is explicit in the Hypothesis syntac- tic structure. Two terms in the Text, candidate- predicate and candidate-argument, aligned to the Hypothesis predicate and argument, are marked as well. However, no predicate-argument rela- tionship between them is expressed syntactically. The task is to recognize whether the predicate-</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head># Hypothesis</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Text</head><p>Y/N 1 Merck <ref type="bibr">[withdrew]</ref> pred <ref type="bibr">[Vioxx]</ref> arg from the market. The crucial role <ref type="bibr">[Vioxx]</ref> cand-arg plays in <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">Merck's  portfolio was apparent last week when Merck's  shares plunged 27 percent to 33 dollars after the  [withdrawal]</ref>  argument relationship, as expressed in the Hypoth- esis, holds implicitly also in the Text.</p><p>To address this task, we provide a large and freely available annotated dataset, and propose methods for coping with it. A related task, de- scribed in the next section, deals with such implied predicate-argument relationships as an extension to Semantic Role Labeling. While the results re- ported so far on that annotation task were rela- tively low, we suggest that the task itself may be more complicated than what is actually required in textual inference scenarios. On the other hand, the results obtained for our task, which does fit textual inference scenarios, are promising, and en- courage utilizing algorithms for this task in actual inference systems.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Prior Work</head><p>The most notable work targeting implied predicate-argument relationships is the 2010 SemEval task of Linking Events and Their Par- ticipants in <ref type="bibr">Discourse (Ruppenhofer et al., 2009</ref>).</p><p>This task extends Semantic Role Labeling to cases in which a core argument of a predicate is missing in the syntactic structure but a filler for the corresponding semantic role appears elsewhere and can be inferred from discourse. For example, in the following sentence the semantic role goal is unfilled:</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">(iii) He arrived (0 Goal ) at 8pm.</formula><p>Yet, we can expect to find an implied filler for goal elsewhere in the document.</p><p>The SemEval task, termed henceforth as Im- plied SRL, involves three major sub-tasks. First, for each predicate, the unfilled roles, termed Null Instantiations (NI), should be detected. Second, each NI should be classified as Definite NI (DNI), meaning that the role filler must exist in the dis- course, or Indefinite NI otherwise. Third, the DNI fillers should be found (DNI linking).</p><p>Later works that followed the SemEval chal- lenge include <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(Silberer and Frank, 2012)</ref> and <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(Roth and Frank, 2013)</ref>, which proposed auto-matic dataset generation methods and features which capture discourse phenomena. Their high- est result was 12% F1-score. Another work is the probabilistic model of <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Laparra and Rigau (2012)</ref>, which is trained by properties captured not only from implicit arguments but also from explicit ones, resulting in 19% F1-score. Another notable work is ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Gerber and Chai, 2012)</ref>, which was lim- ited to ten carefully selected nominal predicates.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">Annotations vs. Recognition</head><p>Comparing to the implied SRL task, our task may better fit the needs of textual inference. First, some relatively complex steps of the implied SRL task are avoided in our setting, while on the other hand it covers more relevant cases.</p><p>More concretely, in textual inference the can- didate predicate and argument are typically iden- tified, as they are aligned by the RTE system to a predicate and an argument of the Hypothesis. Thus, the only remaining challenge is to verify that the sought relationship is implied in the text. Therefore, the sub-tasks of identifying and classi- fying DNIs can be avoided.</p><p>On the other hand, in some cases the candi- date argument is not a DNI, but is still required in textual inference. One type of such cases are non-core arguments, which cannot be Definite NIs. However, textual inference deals with non-core ar- guments as well (see example 3 in <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>).</p><p>Another case is when an implied predicate- argument relationship holds even though the cor- responding role is already filled by another argu- ment, hence not an NI. Consider example 4 of Ta- ble 1. While the object of "threatened" is filled (in the Text) by "southeastern United States", a hu- man reader also infers the "threatened-New Or- leans" relationship. Such cases might follow a meronymy relation between the filler ("southeast- ern United States") and the candidate argument ("New Orleans"), or certain types of discourse (co- )references (e.g., example 5 in <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>), or some other linguistic phenomena. Either way, they are crucial for textual inference, while not being NIs.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Dataset</head><p>This section describes a semi-automatic method for extracting candidate instances of implied predicate-argument relationship from an RTE dataset. This extraction process directly follows our task formalization. Given a Text Hypothe- sis pair, we locate a predicate-argument relation- ship in the Hypothesis, where both the predicate and the argument appear also in the Text, while the relationship between them is not expressed in its syntactic structure. This process is performed automatically, based on syntactic parsing (see be- low). Then, a human reader annotates each in- stance as "Yes" -meaning that the implied rela- tionship indeed holds in the Text, or "No" other- wise. Example instances, constructed by this pro- cess, are shown in <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>.</p><p>In this work we used lemma-level lexical matching, as well as nominalization matching, to align the Text predicates and arguments to the Hy- pothesis. We note that more advanced match- ing, e.g., by utilizing knowledge resources (like WordNet), can be performed as well. To identify explicit predicate-argument relationships we uti- lized dependency parsing by the Easy-First parser <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Goldberg and Elhadad, 2010)</ref>. Nominalization matching (e.g., example 1 of <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>) was per- formed with <ref type="bibr">Nomlex (Macleod et al., 1998)</ref>.</p><p>By applying this method on the RTE-6 dataset ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Bentivogli et al., 2010)</ref>, we constructed a dataset of 4022 instances, where 2271 (56%) are annotated as positive instances, and 1751 as negative ones. This dataset is significantly larger than prior datasets for the implied SRL task. To calculate inter-annotator agreement, the first author also annotated 185 randomly-selected instances. We have reached high agreement score of 0.80 Kappa. The dataset is freely available at www.cs.biu.ac.il/ ˜ nlp/resources/ downloads/implied-relationships.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Recognition Algorithm</head><p>We defined 15 features, summarized in <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">Table 2</ref>, which capture local and discourse phenomena. These features do not depend on manually built resources, and hence are portable to resource-poor languages. Some features were proposed in prior works, and are marked by G&amp;C (Gerber and Chai, 2012) or S&amp;F ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Silberer and Frank, 2012)</ref>. Our best results were obtained with the Random Forests learning algorithm <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Breiman, 2001</ref>). The first two features are described in the next subsection, while the others are explained in the table itself.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">Statistical discourse features</head><p>Statistical features in prior works mostly cap- ture general properties of the predicate and the #</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Category</head><p>Feature Prev. work 1 co-occurring predicate (explained in subsection 4.1) New 2 statistical discourse co-occurring argument (explained in subsection 4.1) New 3 co-reference: whether an explicit argument of p co-refers with a. New 4 last known location: If the NE of a is "location", and it is the last location mentioned before p in the document.  argument, like selectional preferences, lexical similarities, etc. On the contrary, our statis- tical features follow the intuition that explicit predicate-argument relationships in the discourse provide plausible indication that an implied relationship holds as well. In our experiments we collected the statistics from Reuters corpus RCV1 (trec.nist.gov/data/reuters/ reuters.html), which contains more than 806,000 documents.</p><p>We defined two features: Co-occurring predi- cate and Co-occurring argument. Let p and a be the candidate predicate and the argument in the text. While they are not connected syntactically, each of them often has an explicit relationships with other terms in the text, that might support the sought (implied) relationship between a and p.</p><p>More concretely, a is often an explicit argument of another predicate p . For example, example 6 in <ref type="table">Table 1</ref> includes the explicit relationship "derail- ment of train", which might indicate the implied relationship "crash of train". Hence p="crash", a="train" and p ="derailment". The Co-occurring predicate feature estimates the probability that a document would contain a as an argument of p, given that a appears elsewhere in that document as an argument of p , based on explicit predicate- argument relationships in a large corpus.</p><p>Similarly, the Co-occurring argument feature captures cases where p has another explicit argu- ment, a . This is exemplified in example 5 of <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>, where p="renew", a="Patriot Act" and a ="law". Accordingly, the feature quantifies the probability that a document including the relation- ship p-a would also include the relationship p-a.</p><p>More details about these features can be found in the first author's Ph.D. thesis at www.cs.biu. ac.il/ ˜ nlp/publications/theses/</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Results</head><p>We tested our method in a cross-validation setting, and obtained high result as shown in the first row of <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">Table 3</ref>. Since our task and dataset are novel, there is no direct baseline with which we can com- pare this result. As a reference point we mention the majority class proportion, and also report a configuration in which only features adopted from prior works (G&amp;C and S&amp;F) are utilized. This Configuration Accuracy % ∆ % Full algorithm 81.0 - Union of prior work 78.0 3.0 Major category (all true) 56.5 24.5 Ablation tests no statistical discourse 79.9 1.1 no local discourse 79.3 1.7 no local candidate properties 79.2 1.8 no predicate-argument relatedness 79.7 1.3  <ref type="table">Table 4</ref>: RTE-6 Experiment comparison shows that the contribution of our new features (3%) is meaningful, which is also statis- tically significant with p &lt; 0.01 using Bootstrap Resampling test <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Koehn, 2004</ref>). The high results show that this task is feasible, and its solutions can be adopted as a component in textual infer- ence systems. The positive contribution of each feature category is shown in ablation tests. An additional experiment tests the contribution of recognizing implied predicate-argument rela- tionships for overall RTE, specifically on the RTE- 6 dataset. For the scope of this experiment we de- veloped a simple RTE system, which uses the F1 optimized logistic regression classifier of Jansche (2005) with two features: lexical coverage and predicate-argument relationships coverage. We ran three configurations for the second feature, where in the first only syntactically expressed re- lationships are used, in the second all the implied relationships, as detected by a human annotator, are added, and in the third only the implied rela- tionships detected by our algorithm are added.</p><p>The results, presented in <ref type="table">Table 4</ref>, first demon- strate the full potential of the implied relation- ship recognition task to improve textual entail- ment recognition (Human annotation vs. Explicit only). One third of this potential improvement is achieved by our algorithm 1 . Note that all these re- sults are higher than the median result in the RTE- 6 challenge (36.14%). While the delta in the F1 score is small in absolute terms, such magnitudes are typical in RTE for most resources and tools (see <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Bentivogli et al., 2010)</ref>).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Discussion and Conclusions</head><p>We formulated the task of recognizing implied predicate-argument relationships within textual in- ference scenarios. We compared this task to the labeling task of SemEval 2010, where no prior in- formation about candidate arguments in the text is available. We point out that in textual inference scenarios the candidate predicate and argument are given by the Hypothesis, while the challenge is only to verify that a predicate-argument rela- tionship between these candidates is implied from the given Text. Accordingly, some complex steps necessitated in the SemEval task can be avoided, while additional relevant cases are covered.</p><p>Moreover, we have shown that this simpler task is more feasibly solvable, where our 15 features achieved more than 80% accuracy.</p><p>While our dataset and algorithm were presented in the context of RTE, the same challenge and methods are applicable to other textual inference tasks as well. Consider, for example, the Ques- tion Answering (QA) task. Typically QA sys- tems detect a candidate predicate that matches the question's predicate. Similarly, candidate argu- ments, which match either the expected answer type or other arguments in the question are de- tected too. Consequently, our methods which ex- ploit the availability of the candidate predicate and argument can be adapted to this scenario as well.</p><p>Similarly, a typical approach for Event Extrac- tion (a sub task of Information Extraction) is to start by applying an entity extractor, which identi- fies argument candidates. Accordingly, candidate predicate and arguments are detected in this sce- nario too, while the remaining challenge is to as- sess the likelihood that a predicate-argument rela- tionship holds between them.</p><p>Following this observation, we propose future work of applying our methods to other tasks. An additional direction for future work is to further develop new methods for our task, possibly by incorporating SRL resources and/or linguistically oriented rules, in order to improve the results we achieved so far.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>The crucial role Vioxx plays in Merck's port- folio was apparent last week when Merck's shares plunged 27 percent to 33 dollars after the withdrawal announcement.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" validated="false"><head>Table 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Algorithmic features. p and a denote the candidate predicate and argument respectively.</figDesc><table></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3" validated="false"><head>Table 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Accuracy of our method, followed by 
baselines and ablation tests. 

Configuration (input) 
Recall Precision 
F1 % 
Explicit only 
44.6 
44.3 
44.4 
Human annotations 
50.9 
43.4 
46.8 
Algorithm recognition 
48.5 
42.3 
45.2 

</table></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> Following the relatively modest size of the RTE dataset, the Algorithm vs. Explicit result is not statistically significant (p 0.1). However, the Human annotation vs. Explicit result is statistically significant with p &lt; 0.01.</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>This work was partially supported by the EC-funded project EXCITEMENT (FP7ICT-287923).</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The sixth pascal recognizing textual entailment challenge</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Luisa</forename><surname>Bentivogli</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Peter</forename><surname>Clark</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ido</forename><surname>Dagan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hoa</forename><forename type="middle">Trang</forename><surname>Dang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Danilo</forename><surname>Giampiccolo</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proccidings of TAC</title>
		<meeting>cidings of TAC</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Random forests. Machine Learning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Leo</forename><surname>Breiman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">45</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The pascal recognising textual entailment challenge</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Oren</forename><surname>Ido Dagan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bernardo</forename><surname>Glickman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Magnini</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Machine Learning Challenges. Evaluating Predictive Uncertainty, Visual Object Classification, and Recognising Tectual Entailment</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="177" to="190" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The stanford typed dependencies representation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marie-Catherine</forename><surname>De Marneffe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christopher</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Manning</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">proceedings of COLING 2008 Workshop on Cross-framework and Cross-domain Parser Evaluation</title>
		<meeting>COLING 2008 Workshop on Cross-framework and Cross-domain Parser Evaluation</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Incorporating non-local information into information extraction systems by gibbs sampling</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jenny</forename><forename type="middle">Rose</forename><surname>Finkel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Trond</forename><surname>Grenager</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christopher</forename><surname>Manning</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of ACL</title>
		<meeting>ACL</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Semantic role labeling of implicit arguments for nominal predicates</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Matthew</forename><surname>Gerber</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Joyce</forename><forename type="middle">Y</forename><surname>Chai</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Computational Linguistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">An efficient algorithm for easy-first non-directional dependency parsing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yoav</forename><surname>Goldberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Elhadad</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of NAACL</title>
		<meeting>NAACL</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Simple coreference resolution with rich syntactic and semantic features</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Aria</forename><surname>Haghighi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dan</forename><surname>Klein</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of EMNLP</title>
		<meeting>EMNLP</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mark</forename><surname>Hall</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Eibe</forename><surname>Frank</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Geoffrey</forename><surname>Holmes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bernhard</forename><surname>Pfahringer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Peter</forename><surname>Reutemann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ian</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Witten</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">The weka data mining software: An update. SIGKDD Explorations</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<biblScope unit="page">11</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Maximum expected f-measure training of logistic regression models</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Martin</forename><surname>Jansche</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of EMNLP</title>
		<meeting>EMNLP</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Statistical significance tests for machine translation evaluation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Philipp</forename><surname>Koehn</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of EMNLP</title>
		<meeting>EMNLP</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Exploiting explicit annotations and semantic types for implicit argument resolution</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Egoitz</forename><surname>Laparra</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">German</forename><surname>Rigau</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of IEEE-ICSC</title>
		<meeting>IEEE-ICSC</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Nomlex: A lexicon of nominalizations</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Catherine</forename><surname>Macleod</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ralph</forename><surname>Grishman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Adam</forename><surname>Meyers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Leslie</forename><surname>Barrett</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ruth</forename><surname>Reeves</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of EURALEX</title>
		<meeting>EURALEX</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Automatically identifying implicit arguments to improve argument linking and coherence modeling</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Roth</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Anette</forename><surname>Frank</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of *SEM</title>
		<meeting>*SEM</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Semeval-2010 task 10: Linking events and their participants in discourse</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Josef</forename><surname>Ruppenhofer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Caroline</forename><surname>Sporleder</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Roser</forename><surname>Morante</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Collin</forename><surname>Baker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Martha</forename><surname>Palmer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">The NAACL-HLT 2009 Workshop on Semantic Evaluations: Recent Achievements and Future Directions</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>SEW-09</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Semeval-2010 task 10: Linking events and their participants in discourse</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Josef</forename><surname>Ruppenhofer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Caroline</forename><surname>Sporleder</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Roser</forename><surname>Morante</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Collin</forename><surname>Baker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Martha</forename><surname>Palmer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 5th International Workshop on Semantic Evaluation</title>
		<meeting>the 5th International Workshop on Semantic Evaluation</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Casting implicit role linking as an anaphora resolution task</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Carina</forename><surname>Silberer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Anette</forename><surname>Frank</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of *SEM</title>
		<meeting>*SEM</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Feature-rich part-ofspeech tagging with a cyclic dependency network</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kristina</forename><surname>Toutanova</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dan</forename><surname>Klein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christopher</forename><surname>Manning</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yoram</forename><surname>Singer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of NAACL</title>
		<meeting>NAACL</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
