<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T12:11+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">WoSIT: A Word Sense Induction Toolkit for Search Result Clustering and Diversification</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date>June 23-24, 2014</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Daniele</forename><surname>Vannella</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Dipartimento di Informatica Sapienza</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Università di Roma</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tiziano</forename><surname>Flati</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Dipartimento di Informatica Sapienza</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Università di Roma</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Roberto</forename><surname>Navigli</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Dipartimento di Informatica Sapienza</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Università di Roma</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">WoSIT: A Word Sense Induction Toolkit for Search Result Clustering and Diversification</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of 52nd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics: System Demonstrations</title>
						<meeting>52nd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics: System Demonstrations <address><addrLine>Baltimore, Maryland USA</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="67" to="72"/>
							<date type="published">June 23-24, 2014</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>In this demonstration we present WoSIT, an API for Word Sense Induction (WSI) algorithms. The toolkit provides implementations of existing graph-based WSI algorithms, but can also be extended with new algorithms. The main mission of WoSIT is to provide a framework for the extrinsic evaluation of WSI algorithms, also within end-user applications such as Web search result clustering and diversification .</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>The Web is by far the world's largest information archive, whose content -made up of billions of Web pages -is growing exponentially. Unfortu- nately the retrieval of any given piece of infor- mation is an arduous task which challenges even prominent search engines such as those developed by Google, Yahoo! and Microsoft. Even today, such systems still find themselves up against the lexical ambiguity issue, that is, the linguistic prop- erty due to which a single word may convey dif- ferent meanings.</p><p>It has been estimated that around 4% of Web queries and 16% of the most frequent queries are ambiguous <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">(Sanderson, 2008)</ref>. A major issue as- sociated with the lexical ambiguity phenomenon on the Web is the low number of query words sub- mitted by Web users to search engines. A pos- sible solution to this issue is the diversification of search results obtained by maximizing the dissimi- larity of the top-ranking Web pages returned to the user ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Agrawal et al., 2009;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Ashwin Swaminathan and Kirovski, 2009)</ref>. Another solution consists of clustering Web search results by way of clustering engines such as Carrot <ref type="bibr">1</ref> and Yippy <ref type="bibr">2</ref> and presenting them to the user grouped by topic.</p><p>Diversification and Web clustering algorithms, however, do not perform any semantic analysis of search results, clustering them solely on the basis of their lexical similarity. Recently, it has been shown that the automatic acquisition of the mean- ings of a word of interest, a task referred to as Word Sense Induction, can be successfully inte- grated into search result clustering and diversifica- tion ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Navigli and Crisafulli, 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Di Marco and Navigli, 2013</ref>) so as to outperform non-semantic state-of-the-art Web clustering systems.</p><p>In this demonstration we describe a new toolkit for Word Sense Induction, called WoSIT, which i) provides ready implementations of existing WSI algorithms; ii) can be extended with addi- tional WSI algorithms; iii) enables the integration of WSI algorithms into search result clustering and diversification, thereby providing an extrinsic evaluation tool. As a result the toolkit enables the objective comparison of WSI algorithms within an end-user application in terms of the degree of di- versification of the search results of a given am- biguous query.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">WoSIT</head><p>In <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref> we show the workflow of the WoSIT toolkit, composed of three main phases: WSI; semantically-enhanced search result clustering and diversification; evaluation. Given a target query q whose meanings we want to automati- cally acquire, the toolkit first builds a graph for q, obtained either from a co-occurrence database, or constructed programmatically by using any user- provided input. The co-occurrence graph is then input to a WSI algorithm, chosen from among those available in the toolkit or implemented by the user. As a result, a set of word clusters is produced. This concludes the first phase of the WoSIT workflow. Then, the word clusters produced are used for assigning meanings to the search results returned by a search engine for the query q, i.e. search result disambiguation. The</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>+ MANUAL ANNOTATIONS</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>DB DB</head><p>Search result disambiguation <ref type="bibr">w</ref>   outcome is that we obtain a clustering of search results. Finally, during the third phase, we apply the evaluation module which performs an evalua- tion of the search result clustering quality and the diversification performance.</p><p>We now describe in detail the three main phases of WoSIT.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">Word Sense Induction</head><p>The first phase of WoSIT consists of the automatic identification of the senses of a query of inter- est, i.e. the task of Word Sense Induction. Al- though WoSIT enables the integration of custom implementations which can potentially work with any WSI paradigm, the toolkit provides ready-to- use implementations of several graph-based algo- rithms that work with word co-occurrences. All these algorithms carry out WSI in two steps: co- occurrence graph construction (Section 2.1.1) and discovery of word senses (Section 2.1.2).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1.1">Co-occurrence graph construction</head><p>Given a target query q, we build a co-occurrence graph G q = (V, E) such that V is the set of words co-occurring with q and E is the set of undi- rected edges, each denoting a co-occurrence be- tween pairs of words in V . In <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 2</ref> we show an example of a co-occurrence graph for the target word excalibur.</p><p>WoSIT enables the creation of the co- occurrence graph either programmatically, by adding edges and vertices according to any user- specific algorithm, or starting from the statis- tics for co-occurring words obtained from a co- occurrence database (created, e.g., from a text cor- pus, as was done by <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Di Marco and Navigli (2013)</ref>).</p><p>In either case, weights for edges have to be pro- vided in terms of the correlation strength between pairs of words (e.g. using Dice, Jaccard or other co-occurrence measures).</p><p>The information about the co-occurrence database, e.g. a MySQL database, is provided programmatically or via parameters in the prop- erties configuration file (db.properties). The co-occurrence database has to follow a given schema provided in the toolkit docu- mentation.</p><p>An additional configuration file (wosit.properties) also allows the user to specify additional constraints, e.g. the minimum weight value of co-occurrence (the wordGraph.minWeight parameter) to be added as edges to the graph.</p><p>The graphs produced can also be saved to binary (i.e. serialized) or text file:</p><p>g.saveToSer(fileName); g = WordGraph.loadFromSer(fileName); g.saveToTxt(fileName); g = WordGraph.loadFromTxt(fileName);</p><p>We are now ready to provide our co-occurrence graph, created with just a few lines of code, as in- put to a WSI algorithm, as will be explained in the next section.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1.2">Discovery of Word Senses</head><p>Once the co-occurrence graph for the query q is built, it can be input to any WSI algorithm which extends the GraphClusteringAlgorithm class in the toolkit. WoSIT comes with a number of ready-to-use such algorithms, among which:  <ref type="bibr">• HyperLex (Véronis, 2004)</ref>, an algorithm which identifies hubs in co-occurrence graphs, thereby identifying basic meanings for the input query.</p><p>• Chinese Whispers ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Biemann, 2006</ref>), a ran- domized algorithm which partitions nodes by means of the iterative transfer of word sense information across the co-occurrence graph <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Biemann, 2006</ref>).</p><p>• Squares, Triangles and Diamonds (SquaT++) <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(Di Marco and Navigli, 2013)</ref>, an extension of the SquaT algorithm ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Navigli and Crisafulli, 2010</ref>) which exploits three cyclic graph patterns to determine and discard those vertices (or edges) with weak degree of connectivity in the graph.</p><p>We also provide an implementation of a word clustering algorithm, i.e. Lin98 (Lin, 1998), which does not rely on co-occurrence graphs, but just on the word co-occurrence information to it- eratively refine word clusters on the basis of their "semantic" relationships.</p><p>A programmatic example of use of the B-MST WSI algorithm is as follows: where g is a co-occurrence graph created as ex- plained in Section 2.1.1, provided as input to the constructor of the algorithm's class. The makeClustering method implements the in- duction algorithm and creates the word clus- ters, which can then be retrieved calling the getClustering method. As a result an in- stance of the Clustering class is provided. As mentioned above, WoSIT also enables the creation of custom WSI implementa- tions.</p><p>This can be done by extending the GraphClusteringAlgorihm abstract class. The new algorithm just has to implement two methods:</p><p>public void makeClustering(); public Clustering getClustering();</p><p>As a result, the new algorithm is readily inte- grated into the WoSIT toolkit.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">Semantically-enhanced Search Result Clustering and Diversification</head><p>We now move to the use of the induced senses of our target query q within an application, i.e. search result clustering and diversification.</p><p>Search result clustering. The next step (cf. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Fig- ure 1)</ref> is the association of the search results re- turned by a search engine for query q with the most suitable word cluster (i.e. meaning of q). This can be done in two lines:</p><p>SnippetAssociator associator = SnippetAssociator.getInstance(); SnippetClustering clustering = associator.associateSnippet( targetWord, searchResults, wordClusters, AssociationMetric.DEGREE_OVERLAP);</p><p>The first line obtains an instance of the class which performs the association between search re- sult snippets and the word clusters obtained from the WSI algorithm. The second line calls the asso- ciation method associateSnippet which in- puts the target word, the search results obtained from the search engine, the word clusters and, fi- nally, the kind of metric to use for the associa- tion. Three different association metrics are im- plemented in the toolkit:</p><p>• WORD OVERLAP performs the association by maximizing the size of the intersection be- tween the word sets in each snippet and the word clusters; • DEGREE OVERLAP performs the association by calculating for each word cluster the sum of the vertex degrees in the co-occurrence graph of the words occurring in each snippet; • TOKEN OVERLAP is similar in spirit to WORD OVERLAP, but takes into account each token occurrence in the snippet bag of words.</p><p>Search result diversification. The above two lines of code return a set of snippet clusters and, as a result, semantically-enhanced search result clus- tering is performed. At the end, the resulting clus- tering can be used to provide a diversified rerank- ing of the results:</p><p>List&lt;Snippet&gt; snippets = clustering.diversify(sorter);</p><p>The diversify method returns a flat list of snippet results obtained according to the Sorter object provided in input. The Sorter abstract class is designed to rerank the snippet clusters ac- cording to some predefined rule. For instance, the CardinalitySorter class, included in the toolkit, sorts the clusters according to the size of each cluster. Once a sorting order has been es- tablished, an element from each snippet cluster is added to an initially-empty list; next, a second el- ement from each cluster is added, and so on, until all snippets are added to the list.</p><p>The sorting rules implemented in the toolkit are:</p><p>• CardinalitySorter: sorts the clusters according to their size, i.e. the number of ver- tices in the cluster; • MeanSimilaritySorter: sorts the clus- ters according to the average association score between the snippets in the cluster and the backing word cluster (defined by the se- lected association metrics).</p><p>Notably, the end user can then implement his or her own custom sorting procedure by simply ex- tending the Sorter class.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2.1">Search Result Datasets</head><p>The framework comes with two search result datasets of ambiguous queries: the AMBI- ENT+MORESQUE dataset made available by <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Bernardini et al. (2009)</ref> and <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Navigli and Crisafulli (2010)</ref>, respectively, and the SemEval-2013- Task11 dataset. <ref type="bibr">3</ref> New result datasets can be pro- vided by users complying with the dataset format described below.</p><p>A search result dataset in WoSIT is made up of at least two files:</p><p>• topics.txt, which contains the queries (topics) of interest together with their nu- meric ids. For instance:</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">id description 1 polaroid 2 kangaroo 3 shakira ... ...</formula><p>• results.txt, which lists the search re- sults for each given query, in terms of URL, page title and page snippet: Therefore, the two files provide the queries and the corresponding search results returned by a search engine. In order to enable an automatic evaluation of the search result clustering and diversification output, two additional files have to be provided:</p><p>• subTopics.txt, which for each query provides the list of meanings for that query, e.g.: • STRel.txt, which provides the manual as- sociations between each search result and the most suitable meaning as provided in the subTopics.txt file. For instance:</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">subTopicID resultID 1.1 1.1 1.1 1.2 1.1 1.3 ...</formula><p>...</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3">WSI Evaluator</head><p>As shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref> the final component of our workflow is the evaluation of WSI when integrated into search result clustering and diversification (al- ready used by <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Navigli and Vannella (2013)</ref>). This component, called the WSI Evaluator, takes as input the snippet clusters obtained for a given query together with the fully annotated search re- sult dataset, as described in the previous section. Two kinds of evaluations are carried out, described in what follows.</p><p>1 Dataset searchResults = Dataset.getInstance(); 2 DBConfiguration db = DBConfiguration.getInstance(); 3 for(String targetWord : dataset.getQueries()) 4 { 5 WordGraph g = WordGraph.createWordGraph(targetWord, searchResults, db); 6</p><p>BMST mst = new BMST(g); 7</p><p>mst.makeClustering(); 8</p><p>SnippetAssociator snippetAssociator = SnippetAssociator.getInstance(); 9</p><p>SnippetClustering snippetClustering = snippetAssociator.associateSnippet( 10 targetWord, searchResults, mst.getClustering(), AssociationMetric.WORD_OVERLAP); 11 snippetClustering.export("output/outputMST.txt", true); 12 } 13 WSIEvaluator.evaluate(searchResults, "output/outputMST.txt"); <ref type="figure">Figure 3</ref>: An example of evaluation code for the B-MST clustering algorithm.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3.1">Evaluation of the clustering quality</head><p>The quality of the output produced by semantically-enhanced search result cluster- ing is evaluated in terms of Rand Index <ref type="bibr">(Rand, 1971, RI)</ref>, Adjusted Rand Index <ref type="bibr">(Hubert and Arabie, 1985, ARI)</ref>, Jaccard Index (JI) and, finally, precision and recall as done by <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Crabtree et al. (2005)</ref>, together with their F1 harmonic mean.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3.2">Evaluation of the clustering diversity</head><p>To evaluate the snippet clustering diversity the measures of S-recall@K and S-precision@r ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Zhai et al., 2003</ref>) are calculated. These measures de- termine how many different meanings of a query are covered in the top-ranking results shown to the user. We calculate these measures on the output of the three different association metrics illustrated in Section 2.2.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">A Full Example</head><p>We now show a full example of usage of the WoSIT API. The code shown in <ref type="figure">Figure 3</ref> initially obtains a search result dataset (line 1), selects a database (line 2) and iterates over its queries (line 3). Next, a co-occurrence graph for the current query is created from a co-occurrence database (line 5) and an instance of the B-MST WSI algo- rithm is created with the graph as input (line 6). After executing the algorithm (line 7), the snippets for the given query are clustered (lines 8-10). The resulting snippet clustering is appended to an out- put file (line 11). Finally, the WSI evaluator is run on the resulting snippet clustering using the given dataset (line 13).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Experiments</head><p>We applied the WoSIT API to the AMBI- ENT+MORESQUE dataset using 4 induction al-</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Algorithm</head><p>Assoc  <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>: Results of WSI algorithms with a Web1T co-occurrence database and the three association metrics (Word Overlap, Degree Overlap and To- ken Overlap). The reported measures are Ad- justed Rand Index (ARI), Jaccard Index (JI) and F1. We also show the average number of clusters per query produced by each algorithm.</p><p>gorithms among those available in the toolkit, where co-occurrences were obtained from the Google Web1T corpus <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Brants and Franz, 2006</ref>).</p><p>In <ref type="table">Table 1</ref> we show the clustering quality results output by the WoSIT evaluator, whereas in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">Fig- ure 4</ref> we show the diversification performance in terms of S-recall@K.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Conclusions</head><p>In this demonstration we presented WoSIT, a full- fledged toolkit for Word Sense Induction algo- rithms and their integration into search result clus- tering and diversification. The main contributions are as follows: first, we release a Java API for performing Word Sense Induction which includes several ready-to-use implementations of existing algorithms; second, the API enables the use of the acquired senses for a given query for enhancing search result clustering and diversification; third, we provide an evaluation component which, given an annotated dataset of search results, carries out different kinds of evaluation of the snippet cluster- ing quality and diversity.</p><p>WoSIT is the first available toolkit which pro- vides an end-to-end approach to the integration of WSI into a real-world application. The toolkit en- ables an objective comparison of WSI algorithms as well as an evaluation of the impact of apply- ing WSI to clustering and diversifying search re- sults. As shown by <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Di Marco and Navigli (2013)</ref>, this integration is beneficial and allows outperfor- mance of non-semantic state-of-the-art Web clus- tering systems.</p><p>The toolkit, licensed under a Creative Com- mons Attribution-Non Commercial-Share Alike 3.0 License, is available at http://lcl. uniroma1.it/wosit/.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: The WoSIT workflow.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2: Example of a co-occurrence graph for the word excalibur.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><head>Figure 4 :</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Figure 4: S-recall@K performance.</figDesc></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> http://search.carrot2.org 2 http://yippy.com</note>

			<note place="foot" n="3"> For details visit http://lcl.uniroma1.it/ wosit/.</note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Alan Halverson, and Samuel Ieong</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rakesh</forename><surname>Agrawal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sreenivas</forename><surname>Gollapudi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of the Second International Conference on Web Search and Web Data Mining (WSDM 2009)</title>
		<meeting>of the Second International Conference on Web Search and Web Data Mining (WSDM 2009)<address><addrLine>Barcelona, Spain</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="5" to="14" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Diversifying search results</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Essential Pages</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Cherian</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Darko</forename><surname>Mathew Ashwin Swaminathan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Kirovski</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of the</title>
		<meeting>of the</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="173" to="182" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>IEEE</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Full-Subtopic Retrieval with Keyphrase-Based Search Results Clustering</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Andrea</forename><surname>Bernardini</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Claudio</forename><surname>Carpineto</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Massimiliano D&amp;apos;</forename><surname>Amico</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of Web Intelligence</title>
		<meeting>of Web Intelligence<address><addrLine>Los Alamitos, CA, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="206" to="213" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Chinese Whispers-an Efficient Graph Clustering Algorithm and its Application to Natural Language Processing Problems</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chris</forename><surname>Biemann</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of TextGraphs: the First Workshop on Graph Based Methods for Natural Language Processing</title>
		<meeting>of TextGraphs: the First Workshop on Graph Based Methods for Natural Language essing<address><addrLine>New York City</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="73" to="80" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Web 1T 5gram, ver. 1, LDC2006T13. In Linguistic Data Consortium</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Thorsten</forename><surname>Brants</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alex</forename><surname>Franz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
			<pubPlace>Philadelphia, USA</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Improving web clustering by cluster selection</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Daniel</forename><surname>Crabtree</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xiaoying</forename><surname>Gao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Peter</forename><surname>Andreae</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of the 2005 IEEE/WIC/ACM International Conference on Web Intelligence</title>
		<meeting>of the 2005 IEEE/WIC/ACM International Conference on Web Intelligence<address><addrLine>Washington, DC, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="172" to="178" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Clustering Web Search Results with Maximum Spanning Trees</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Antonio</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Di</forename><surname>Marco</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Roberto</forename><surname>Navigli</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of the XIIth International Conference of the Italian Association for Artificial Intelligence</title>
		<meeting>of the XIIth International Conference of the Italian Association for Artificial Intelligence<address><addrLine>AI*IA; Palermo, Italy</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="201" to="212" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Clustering and Diversifying Web Search Results with Graph-Based Word Sense Induction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Antonio</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Di</forename><surname>Marco</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Roberto</forename><surname>Navigli</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Computational Linguistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">39</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="709" to="754" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Comparing Partitions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lawrence</forename><surname>Hubert</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Phipps</forename><surname>Arabie</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Classification</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="193" to="218" />
			<date type="published" when="1985" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Automatic Retrieval and Clustering of Similar Words</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dekang</forename><surname>Lin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of the 17 th International Conference on Computational linguistics (COLING)</title>
		<meeting>of the 17 th International Conference on Computational linguistics (COLING)<address><addrLine>Montreal, Canada</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="768" to="774" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Inducing Word Senses to Improve Web Search Result Clustering</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Roberto</forename><surname>Navigli</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Giuseppe</forename><surname>Crisafulli</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of the 2010 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</title>
		<meeting>of the 2010 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language essing<address><addrLine>Boston, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="116" to="126" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Roberto</forename><surname>Navigli</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Daniele</forename><surname>Vannella</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Evaluating Word Sense Induction &amp; Disambiguation within An End-User Application</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Semeval</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of the 7 th International Workshop on Semantic Evaluation (SemEval 2013), in conjunction with the Second Joint Conference on Lexical and Computational Semantics (*SEM 2013)</title>
		<meeting>of the 7 th International Workshop on Semantic Evaluation (SemEval 2013), in conjunction with the Second Joint Conference on Lexical and Computational Semantics (*SEM 2013)<address><addrLine>Atlanta, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="193" to="201" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Objective criteria for the evaluation of clustering methods</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">William</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Rand</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of the American Statistical association</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">66</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">336</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="846" to="850" />
			<date type="published" when="1971" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Ambiguous queries: test collections need more sense</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mark</forename><surname>Sanderson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of the 31st annual international ACM SIGIR conference on Research and development in information retrieval</title>
		<meeting>of the 31st annual international ACM SIGIR conference on Research and development in information retrieval<address><addrLine>Singapore</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="499" to="506" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">HyperLex: lexical cartography for information retrieval</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jean</forename><surname>Véronis</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Computer, Speech and Language</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">18</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="223" to="252" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Beyond independent relevance: Methods and evaluation metrics for subtopic retrieval</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chengxiang</forename><surname>Zhai</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">William</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Cohen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">John</forename><surname>Lafferty</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of the 26th annual international ACM SIGIR conference on Research and development in information retrieval</title>
		<meeting>of the 26th annual international ACM SIGIR conference on Research and development in information retrieval<address><addrLine>Toronto, Canada</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="10" to="17" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
