<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T12:10+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Exploiting Timelines to Enhance Multi-document Summarization</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
				<availability status="unknown"><p>Copyright Association for Computational Linguistics</p>
				</availability>
				<date>June 23-25 2014. 2014</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jun-Ping</forename><surname>Ng</surname></persName>
							<email>njunping@dso.org.sg</email>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">School of Computing</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">National University of Singapore</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="SG">Singapore</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yan</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="laboratory">State Key Laboratory of Software Development Environment</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Beihang University</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Min-Yen</forename><surname>Kan</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">School of Computing</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">National University of Singapore</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="SG">Singapore</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff3">
								<orgName type="department">Interactive and Digital Media Institute</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">National University of Singapore</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="SG">Singapore</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Zhoujun</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="laboratory">State Key Laboratory of Software Development Environment</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Beihang University</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">DSO National Laboratories</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="SG">Singapore</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Exploiting Timelines to Enhance Multi-document Summarization</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 52nd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
						<meeting>the 52nd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics <address><addrLine>Baltimore, Maryland, USA</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="923" to="933"/>
							<date type="published">June 23-25 2014. 2014</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>We study the use of temporal information in the form of timelines to enhance multi-document summarization. We employ a fully automated temporal processing system to generate a timeline for each input document. We derive three features from these timelines, and show that their use in supervised summarization lead to a significant 4.1% improvement in ROUGE performance over a state-of-the-art base-line. In addition, we propose TIMEMMR, a modification to Maximal Marginal Relevance that promotes temporal diversity by way of computing time span similarity , and show its utility in summarizing certain document sets. We also propose a filtering metric to discard noisy timelines generated by our automatic processes, to purify the timeline input for summariza-tion. By selectively using timelines guided by filtering, overall summarization performance is increased by a significant 5.9%.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>There has been a good amount of research in- vested into improving the temporal interpretation of text. Besides the increasing availability of an- notation standards (e.g., TIMEML (Pustejovsky et al., 2003a)) and corpora (e.g., TIDES ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Ferro et al., 2000</ref>), TimeBank ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Pustejovsky et al., 2003b)</ref>), the community has also organized three success- ful evaluation workshops -TempEval-1 ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">Verhagen et al., 2009</ref>), -2 ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Verhagen et al., 2010)</ref>, and -3 ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Uzzaman et al., 2013)</ref>. As the state-of-the- art improves, these workshops have moved away from the piecemeal evaluation of individual tem- poral processing tasks and towards the evaluation of complete end-to-end systems in TempEval-3.</p><p>We believe our understanding of the temporal in- formation found in text is sufficiently robust, and that there is an opportunity to now leverage this in- formation in downstream applications. In this pa- per, we present our work in incorporating the use of such temporal information into multi-document summarization.</p><p>The goal of multi-document summarization is to generate a summary which includes the main points from an input collection of documents with minimal repetition of similar points. We hope to improve the quality of the summaries that are gen- erated by considering temporal information found in the input text. To motivate how temporal in- formation can be useful in summarization, let us refer to <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref>. The three sentences describe a recent cyclone and a previous one which happened in 1991. Recognizing that sentence (3) is about a storm that had happened in the past is important when writing a summary about the recent storm, as it is not relevant and can likely be excluded.</p><p>It is reasonable to expect that a collection of documents about the recent storm will contain more references to it, compared with the earlier one that happened in 1991. Visualized on a time- line, this will translate to more events (bolded in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref>) around the time when the recent storm occurred. There should be fewer events mentioned in the collection for the earlier 1991 time period. <ref type="figure">Figure 2</ref> illustrates a possible timeline laid out with the events found in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref>. The events from the more recent storm are found together at the same time. There are fewer events which talk about the previous storm. Thus, temporal informa- tion does assist in identifying which sentences are more relevant to the final summary.</p><p>Our work is significant as it addresses an im- portant gap in the exploitation of temporal infor- mation. While there has been prior work making use of temporal information for multi-document (1) A fierce cyclone packing extreme winds and torrential rain smashed into Bangladesh's southwestern coast Thursday, wiping out homes and trees in what officials described as the worst storm in years. (2) More than 100,000 coastal villagers have been evacuated before the cyclone made landfall. (3) The storm matched one in 1991 that sparked a tidal wave that killed an estimated 138,000 people, Karmakar told AFP. Figure 2: Possible timeline for events in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref>. summarization, they 1) have been largely con- fined to helping to chronologically order content within summaries ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Barzilay et al., 1999</ref>), or 2) focus only on the use of recency as an indicator of saliency ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Goldstein et al., 2000;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b25">Wan, 2007)</ref>. In this work we construct timelines (as a repre- sentation of temporal information) automatically and incorporate them into a state-of-the-art multi- document summarization system. This is achieved with 1) three novel features derived from time- lines to help measure the saliency of sentences, as well as 2) TIMEMMR, a modification to the traditional Maximal Marginal Relevance (MMR) <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Carbonell and Goldstein, 1998)</ref>. TimeMMR pro- motes diversity by additionally considering tem- poral information instead of just lexical similari- ties. Through these, we demonstrate that temporal information is useful for multi-document summa- rization. Compared to a competitive baseline, sig- nificant improvements of up to 4.1% are obtained. Automatic temporal processing systems are not perfect yet, and this may have an impact on their use for downstream applications. This work ad- ditionally proposes the use of the lengths of time- lines as a metric to gauge the usefulness of time- lines. Together with the earlier described contribu- tions, this metric further improves summarization, yielding an overall 5.9% performance increase. <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Barzilay et al. (1999)</ref> were one of the first to use time for multi-document summarization. They recognized the importance of generating a sum- mary which presents the time perspective of the summarized documents correctly. They estimated the chronological ordering of events with a small set of heuristics, and also made use of lexical pat- terns to perform basic time normalization on terms like "today" relative to the document creation time. The induced ordering is used to present the selected summary content, following the chrono- logical order in the original documents.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Related Work</head><p>In another line of work, <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Goldstein et al. (2000)</ref> made use of the temporal ordering of documents to be summarized. In computing the relevance of a passage for inclusion into the final summary, they considered the recency of the passage's source document. Passages from more recent documents are deemed to be more important. <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">Wan (2007)</ref> and <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Demartini et al. (2010)</ref> made similar assump- tions in their work on TIMEDTEXTRANK and en- tity summarization, respectively.</p><p>Instead of just considering the notion of re- cency, <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Liu et al. (2009)</ref> proposed an interesting approach using a temporal graph. Events within a document set correspond to vertices in their pro- posed graph, while edges are determined by the temporal ordering of events. From the resulting weakly-connected graph, the largest forests are as- sumed to contain key topics within the document set and used to influence a scoring mechanism which prefers sentences touching on these topics. <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">Wu (2008)</ref> also made use of the relative or- dering of events. He assigned complete times- tamps to events extracted from text. After lay- ing out these events onto a timeline by making use of these timestamps, the number of events that happen within the same day is used to influence sentence scoring. The motivation behind this ap- proach is that days which have a large number of events should be more important and more worthy of reporting than others.</p><p>These prior works target either 1) sentence re- ordering, or 2) the use of recency as an indicator of saliency. In sentence re-ordering, final summaries are re-arranged so that the extracted sentences that form the summary are in a chronological order. We argue that this may not be appropriate for all summaries. Depending on the style of writing or journalistic guidelines, a summary can arguably be written in a number of ways. The use of recency as an indicator of saliency is useful, yet disregards other accessible temporal information. If a sum- mary of a whole sequence of events is desired, re- cency becomes less useful.</p><p>The work of <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">Wu (2008)</ref> is closely related to one of the features proposed in this paper. He had also made use of temporal information to weight sen- tences to generate summaries. However his ap- proach is guided by the number of events hap- pening within the same time span, and relies on event co-referencing. In this work, we have sim- plified this idea by dropping the need for event co- referencing (removing a source of propagated er- ror), and augmented it with two additional features derived from timelines. By doing so, we are able to make better use of the available temporal infor- mation, taking into account all known events and the time in which they occur.</p><p>A useful note here is that this work is ar- guably different from the Temporal Summariza- tion (TmpSum) track at the Text Retrieval Confer- ence ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Aslam et al., 2013)</ref>. Given a large stream of data in real-time, the purpose of the TmpSum track is to look out for a query event, and retrieve specific details about the event over a period of time. Systems are also expected to identify the source sentences from which these details are re- trieved. This is not the same as our approach here, which makes use of temporal information encoded in timelines to generate prose summaries.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Methodology</head><p>To incorporate temporal information into multi- document summarization, we adopt the workflow in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 3</ref>, which has two key processes: 1) tem- poral processing, and 2) summarization. Temporal Processing generates timelines from text, one for each input document. Timelines are well-understood constructs which have often been used to represent temporal information <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Denis and Muller, 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Do et al., 2012)</ref>. They indicate the temporal relationships between two basic tempo- ral units: 1) events, and 2) time expressions (or timexes for short). In this work, we adopt the definitions proposed in the standardized TIMEML annotation ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">Pustejovsky et al., 2003a</ref>). An event refers to an eventuality, a situation that occurs or an action; while a timex is a reference to a partic- ular date or time (e.g. "2013 December 31").</p><p>Following the "divide-and-conquer" approach described in <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Verhagen et al. (2010)</ref>, results from the three temporal processing steps: 1) timex nor- malization, 2) event-timex temporal relationship classification, and 3) event-event temporal rela- tionship classification, are merged to obtain time- lines (top half of <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 3</ref>). We tap on existing systems for each of these steps <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">Strötgen and Gertz, 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Ng et al., 2013)</ref>.</p><p>Summarization. We make use of a state-of- the-art summarization system, SWING (Ng et al., 2012) (bottom half of <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 3</ref>). SWING is a su- pervised, extractive summarization system which ranks sentences based on scores computed using a set of features in the Sentence Scoring phase. The Maximal Marginal Relevance (MMR) algo- rithm is then used in the Sentence Re-ordering phase to re-order and select sentences to form the final summary. The timelines built in the ear- lier temporal processing can be incorporated into this pipeline by deriving a set of features used to score sentences in Sentence Scoring, and as input to the MMR algorithm when computing similarity in Sentence Re-ordering.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Timelines from Temporal Processing</head><p>A typical timeline used in this work has been shown earlier in <ref type="figure">Figure 2</ref>. The arrowed, horizon- tal axis is the timeline itself. The timeline can be viewed as a continuum of time, with points on the timeline referring to specific moments of time. Small solid blocks on the timeline itself are ref- erences to absolute timestamps along the timeline (e.g., "2013-Feb-13 11:32 +0000" in the <ref type="figure">figure)</ref>.</p><p>The black square boxes above the timeline de- note events. Events can either occur at a specific instance of time (e.g., an explosion), or over a pe- riod of time (e.g. a football match). Generalizing, we refer to the time period an event takes place in as its time span (vertical dotted lines). As a simpli- Note that in our work, time spans may not cor- respond to specific instances of time, but instead help in inferring an ordering of events. Events which appear to the left of others take place ear- lier, while events within the same time span hap- pen together over the same time period.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Sentence Scoring with Timelines</head><p>We derive three features from the constructed timelines, which are then used for downstream Sentence Scoring. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 4</ref> shows a simplified timeline, along with annotations that are refer- enced in this section to help explain how these timeline features are derived.</p><p>1. Time Span Importance (TSI). We hypothe- size that when more events happen within a partic- ular time span, that time span is potentially more relevant for summarization. Sentences that men- tion events found in such a time span should be as- signed higher scores. Referring to <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref>, whose timeline is shown in <ref type="figure">Figure 2</ref>, we see that the time span with the most number of events is when the latest cyclone made landfall. Assigning higher scores for sentences which contain events in this time span will help us to select more relevant sen- tences if we want a summary about the cyclone.</p><p>Let T S L be the time span with the largest num- ber of events in a timeline. The importance of a time span T S i is computed by normalizing the number of events in T S i against the number of events in T S L . The T SI of a sentence s is then the sum of the time span importance associated to all the words in s:</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">T SI(s) = w∈s |T Sw| |T S L | |s| (1)</formula><p>where T S w denotes the time span which a word w is associated with, and |T S w | is the number of events within the time span.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>2.</head><p>Contextual Time Span Importance (CTSI). The importance of a time span may not depend solely on the number of events that hap- pen within it. If it is near time spans which are "important" (i.e., one that has a large number of events), it should also be of relative importance. A more concrete illustration of this can also be seen in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref>. <ref type="bibr">Sentence (2)</ref> explains that a lot of peo- ple have been evacuated prior to the cyclone mak- ing landfall. It is imaginable that this can be use- ful information to be included in a summary, even though from looking at the corresponding timeline in <ref type="figure">Figure 2</ref>, the "evacuated" event falls in a time span with a low importance score (i.e., the time span only has one event). CTSI seeks to promote sentences such as this.</p><p>We derive the CTSI of a sentence by first com- puting the contextual importance of words in the sentence. We define the contextual importance of a word found in time span T S i as a weighted sum of the time span importance of the two nearest peaks T S lp and T S rp found to the left and right of T S i , respectively. In <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 4</ref>, taking reference from event e (shaded in black), the left peak to the time span which e is in happens to be time span A, while the right peak is time span A + 4. The contribution of each peak to the weighted sum is decayed by its distance from T S i . Formally, the contextual time span importance of a word w can be expressed as:</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">ζ(w) = α I lp |T Sw − T S lp | × (1 − α) Irp |T Srp − T Sw|<label>(2)</label></formula><p>where T S w is the time span associated with w. I lp and I rp are the time span importance of the peaks to the left and right of T S w respectively, while |T S w − T S lp | and |T S rp − T S w | are the num- ber of time spans between the left and right peaks of T S w respectively. α balances the importance of the left and right peaks, intuitively set to 0.5. The CTSI of a sentence is computed as:</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">CT SI(s) = e∈Es ζ(e) |E s |<label>(3)</label></formula><p>where E s denotes the set of events words in s.</p><p>3. Sentence Temporal Coverage Density (TCD). We first define the temporal coverage of a sentence. This corresponds to the number of time spans that the events in a sentence talk about. Sup- pose a sentence contains events which are associ- ated with time spans T S a , T S b , T S c . The time spans are ordered in the sequence they appear on the timeline. Then the temporal coverage of a sen- tence is defined as the number of time spans be- tween the earliest time span T S a and the latest time span T S c . Referring to <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 4</ref>, suppose a sentence contains the three events which have been shaded black. The temporal coverage in this case includes all the time spans from time span A to time span A + 4, inclusive.</p><p>The constraint on the number of sentences that can be included in a summary requires us to select compact sentences which contain as many rele- vant facts as possible. Traditional lexical measures may attempt to achieve this by computing the ra- tio of keyphrases to the number of words in a sen- tence ( <ref type="bibr">Gong and Liu, 2001</ref>). Stated equivalently, when two sentences are of the same length, if one contains more keyphrases, it should contain more useful facts. TCD parallels this idea with the use of temporal information, i.e. if two sentences are of the same temporal coverage, then the one with more events should carry more useful facts.</p><p>Formally, if a sentence s contains events E s = {e 1 , . . . , e n }, where each event is associated with a time span T S i , then T CD is computed using:</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">T CD(s) = |E s | |T S n − T S 1 |<label>(4)</label></formula><p>where |E s | is the number of events found in s, and |T S n − T S 1 | is the temporal coverage of s.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3">Enhancing MMR with TimeMMR</head><p>In the sentence re-ordering stage of the SWING pipeline, the iterative MMR algorithm is used to adjust the score of a candidate sentence, s. In each iteration, s is penalized if it is lexically similar to other sentences that have already been selected to form the eventual summary S = {s 1 , s 2 , . . .}. The motivating idea is to reduce repeated information by preferring sentences which bring in new facts. Incorporating temporal information can poten- tially improve this. In <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Figure 5</ref>, the sentences de- scribe many events which took place within the same time span. They describe the destruction caused by a hurricane with trees uprooted and buildings blown away. A summary about the hur- ricane need not contain all of these sentences as they are all describing the same thing. However it is not trivial for the lexically-motivated MMR algorithm to detect that events like "passed", "up- rooted" or "damaged" are in fact repetitive.</p><p>Thus, we propose further penalizing the score of s if it contains events that happen in similar time spans as those contained in sentences within S. We refer to this as TIMEMMR. Modifying the MMR equation from :</p><formula xml:id="formula_4">T imeM M R(s) = Score(s) − γR2(s, S) − (1 − γ)T (s, S) (5)</formula><p>where Score(s) is the score of s, S is the set of sentences already selected to be in the summary from previous iterations, and R2 is the predicted ROUGE-2 score of s with respect to the already selected sentences (S). γ is a weighting parameter which is empirically set to 0.9 after tuning over a development dataset. T is the proportion of events in s which happen in the same time span as another event in any other sentence in S. Two events are said to be in the same time span if one happens within the time period the other happens in. For example, an event that takes place in "2014 June" is said to take place within the year "2014".</p><p>While TIMEMMR is proposed here as an im- provement over MMR, the premise is that incor- porating temporal information can be helpful to minimize redundancy in summaries. In future work, one could apply it to other state-of-the-art lexical-based approaches including that of <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Hendrickx et al. (2009)</ref> and <ref type="bibr">Celikyilmaz and HakkaniTur (2010)</ref>. We also believe the same idea can be transplanted even to non-lexical motivated tech- niques such as the corpus-based similarity mea- sure proposed by <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">Xie and Liu (2008)</ref>. We chose to use MMR here as a proof-of-concept to demon- strate the viability of such a technique, and to eas- ily integrate our work into SWING.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.4">Gauging Usefulness of Timelines</head><p>Temporal processing is imperfect. Together with the simplifying assumptions that were made in timeline construction, our generated timelines have errors which propagate into the summariza- tion process. With this in mind, we selectively em- ploy timelines to generate summaries only when we are confident of their accuracy. This can be done by computing a metric which can be used to decide whether or not timelines should be used for a particular input document collection. We refer to this as reliability filtering.</p><p>We postulate that the length of a timeline can serve as a simple reliability filtering metric. The intuition for this is that for longer timelines (which contain more events), possible errors are spread over the entire timeline, and do not overpower any useful signal that can be obtained from the time- line features outlined earlier. Errors are however (1) An official in Barisal, 120 kilometres south of Dhaka, spoke of severe destruction as the 500 kilometre-wide mass of cloud passed overhead. (2) "Many trees have been uprooted and houses and schools blown away," Mostofa Kamal, a district relief and rehabilitation officer, told AFP by telephone. (3) "Mud huts have been damaged and the roofs of several houses blown off," said the state's relief minister, Mortaza Hossain. very easily propagated into summary generation for shorter timelines, leading to less useful results.</p><p>We incorporate this into our process as follows: given an input document collection (which con- sists of 10 documents), the average size of all the timelines for each of these 10 documents is com- puted. Only when this value is larger than a thresh- old value are the timelines used.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Experiments and Results</head><p>The proposed timeline features and TIMEMMR were implemented on top of SWING, and eval- uated on the test documents from <ref type="bibr">TAC-2011 (Owczarzak and</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Dang, 2011)</ref>. SWING makes use of three generic features and two features targeted specifically at guided summarization. Since the focus of this paper is on multi-document summa- rization, we employ only the three generic fea- tures, i.e., 1) sentence position, 2) sentence length, and 3) interpolated n-gram document frequency in our experiments below. Summarization evalua- tion is done using ROUGE-2 (R-2) ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Lin and Hovy, 2003)</ref>, as it has previously been shown to correlate well with human assessment <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Lin, 2004</ref>) and is of- ten used to evaluate automatic text summarization.</p><p>The results obtained are shown in <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>. In the table, each row refers to a specific summariza- tion system configuration. We also show the re- sults of two reference systems, CLASSY (Conroy et al., 2011) and POLYCOM <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">(Zhang et al., 2011</ref>), as benchmarks. CLASSY and POLYCOM are top performing systems at TAC-2011 (ranked 2nd and 3rd by R-2 in TAC 2011, respectively; the full ver- sion of SWING was ranked 1st with a R-2 score of 0.1380). From these results, we can see that SWING is a very competitive baseline.</p><p>Rows 9 to 16 additionally incorporate our time- line reliability filtering. We assume that the var- ious input document sets to be summarized are available at the time of processing. Hence in these experiments, the threshold for filtering is set to be the average of all the timeline sizes over the whole input dataset. In a production environment where this assumption may not hold, this threshold could  <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>: R-2 scores after incorporating temporal information into SWING. '**' and '*' denotes sig- nificant differences with respect to Row R (paired one-tailed Student's t-test; p &lt; 0.05 and p &lt; 0.1 respectively), and TMMR denotes TIMEMMR.</p><p>be set by empirical tuning over a development set. Row 1 shows the usefulness of the proposed timeline-based features. A statistically significant improvement of 4.1% is obtained with the use of all three features over SWING. When we use re- liability filtering (Row 9), this improvement in- creases to 5.9%.</p><p>The ablation test results in Rows 2 to 4 show a drop in R-2 each time a feature is left out. With the exception of Row 4, removing a feature lessens the improvement in R-2 to be insignificant from SWING's. The same drop occurs even when reli- ability filtering is used <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">(Rows 9 to 12)</ref>. These in- dicate that all the proposed features are important and need to be used together to be effective.</p><p>Rows 5 to 8 and Rows 13 to 16 show the ef- fect of TIMEMMR. While the results do not uni- formly show that TIMEMMR is effective, it can be helpful, such as when comparing Rows 2 and 6, or Rows 10 and 14, where R-2 improves marginally.</p><p>Looking at Rows 1 to 8, and Rows 9 to 16, we see the importance of reliability filtering. It is able to guide the use of timelines such that significant improvements in R-2 over SWING are obtained.</p><p>To help visualize what the differences in these ROUGE scores mean, <ref type="figure">Figure 7</ref> shows two sum- maries 1 generated for document set D1117C of the TAC-2011 dataset. The left one is produced by the configuration in Row 9, and the right one is pro- duced by SWING without the use of any temporal information. The higher R-2 score obtained by the summary on the left (0.0873) compared to the one on the right (0.0723) suggests that temporal information can help to identify salient sentences more accu- rately. A closer look at sentences (L2) and (R2) and their R-2 scores (0.0424 and 0.0249, respec- tively) is instructive. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Figure 6</ref> shows the raw fea- ture scores of both sentences. Both sentences score similarly for the SWING features of sen- tence position (SP), sentence length (Length), and interpolated n-gram document frequency (INDF); however, the scores for all three timeline features higher for (L2) than (R2). This helps our time sen- sitive system prefer (L2).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Discussion</head><p>We now examine the proposed 1) timeline fea- tures, 2) TIMEMMR algorithm, and 3) reliabil- ity filtering metric in greater detail to gain insight into their efficacy. For the analysis on timeline features, we only present an analysis for TSI and CTSI due to space constraints.</p><p>Time Span Importance. <ref type="figure">Figure 8</ref> shows the last sentences from a pair of summaries generated with and without the use of TSI (all other sen- tences were the same). The original articles de- scribe an accident where casualties were suffered when a crane toppled onto a building. It is easy to see why (L1) scores higher for R-2 -it describes the cause of the accident just as it occurred. (R1) however talks about events which happened before the accident itself (e.g., how much of the tower had already been erected). In this case time span im- portance is able to correctly guide summary gen- eration by favoring time spans containing events related to the actual toppling.</p><p>Contextual Time Span Importance. CTSI recognizes that events which happen around the time of a big cluster of other events can be im- portant too. The benefits of this feature can be clearly seen in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_8">Figure 9</ref>. The summary on the left achieved a R-2 score of 0.1215 while the one on the right achieved 0.0861. (L2) and (L3) were both boosted by the use of the contextual impor- tance feature. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 10</ref> shows an extract of the timeline gen- erated for the source document from which (L3) is extracted. The two events inside (L3) fall in time spans A and B marked in the figure. Their proximity to the peak P between them gives the sentence a higher score for CTSI. This boost re- sults in the sentence being selected for inclusion in the final summary. It turns out that this sentence was lifted exactly in one of the model summaries for this document set, resulting in a very good R-2 score when contextual importance is used. Is TIMEMMR Useful? The experimental re- sults do not conclusively affirm the usefulness of TIMEMMR. However we believe it is because the ROUGE measures that are used for evalua- tion are not suited for this purpose. Recall that TIMEMMR seeks to eliminate redundancy based on time span similarities and not lexical likeness. ROUGE, however, measures the latter.</p><p>An interesting case in point is given in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Fig- ure 11</ref>. The summary on the left is generated using TIMEMMR and achieved a lower ROUGE score. The one on the right is generated with- out TIMEMMR and scores higher, suggesting that TIMEMMR is not helpful. The key difference in R-2: 0.0873 R-2: 0.0723 (L1,R1) The Army's surgeon general criticized stories in The Washington Post disclosing problems at Walter Reed Army Medical Center, saying the series unfairly characterized the living conditions and care for soldiers recuperating from wounds at the hospital's facilities. (L2) Defense Secretary Robert Gates says people found to have been responsible for allowing sub- standard living conditions for soldier outpatients at Walter Reed Army Medical Center in Washington will be "held accountable," although so far no one in the Army chain of command has offered to re- sign.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>= =</head><p>(R2) A top Army general vowed to personally oversee the upgrading of Walter Reed Army Medi- cal Center's Building 18, a dilapidated former hotel that houses wounded soldiers as outpatients.</p><p>(L3) Top Army officials visited Building 18, the decrepit former hotel housing more than 80 recov- ering soldiers, outside Reliability Filtering. <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">Table 2</ref> shows the ef- fect of varying the filtering threshold on R-2 for the best performing configuration from <ref type="table">Table 1</ref> (i.e., SWING+TSI+CTSI+TCD). The result ob- tained in Row 9 using a threshold of 42.68 is also re-produced for reference. T=0 means that time- lines are used for all input document sets, whereas T=100 means that no timelines are used, as the length of the longest timeline is less than 100.</p><formula xml:id="formula_5">= =<label>(</label></formula><p>As the threshold increases from 0 to 40-50, summarization performance improves while the  number of document sets where temporal informa- tion is used is reduced. This suggests that filtering is successful in identifying timelines that are not sufficiently accurate to be useful for summariza- tion. R-2 performance peaks around a threshold of 40. This affirms our use of the average length of timelines as the threshold value in our earlier experiments. Beyond 60, the R-2 scores are still higher than that obtained by SWING, but no longer significantly different. At these higher thresholds, temporal information is still able to help get an im- provement in R-2. However as this affects only very few out of the 44 document sets, statistical variances mean that these R-2 scores are no longer R-2: 0.1215 R-2: 0.0861 ((L1,R1) Caribbean coral species essential to the region's reef ecosystems are at risk of extinction as a result of climate change. (L2) But destructive fishing methods and over- harvesting have reduced worldwide catches by 90 percent in the past two decades.  significant from that produced by SWING.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Conclusion</head><p>We have shown in this work how temporal in- formation in the form of timelines can be incor- porated into multi-document summarization. We achieve this through two means, using: 1) three novel features derived from timelines to mea- sure the saliency of sentences, and 2) TIMEMMR which considers time span similarity to enhance the traditional MMR's lexical diversity measure. To overcome errors propagated from the under- lying temporal processing systems, we proposed a reliability filtering metric which can be used to help decide when temporal information should be used for summarization. The use of this metric leads to an overall 5.9% gain in R-2 over the com- petitive SWING baseline.</p><p>In future work, we are keen to study our pro- posed timeline-related features more intrinsically in the context of human-generated summaries. This can help us better understand their value in improving content selection. As noted earlier, it will be also be useful to repeat our experi- ments with less lexicon-influenced measures like the Pyramid method ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">Passonneau et al., 2005</ref>). Manual assessment of the generated summaries can also be done to give a better picture of the quality of the summaries generated with the use of timelines. Finally, given the importance of re- liability filtering, a natural question is if there are other metrics that can be used to get better results.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: Modified extract from a news article which describes a cyclone landfall. Several events which appear in Figure 2 are bolded.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Figure 3: Incorporating temporal information into the SWING summarization pipeline.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 4 :</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Figure 4: A simplified timeline illustrating how the various timeline features can be derived. fying assumption, events are laid out on the timeline based on the starting time of their time span. Note that in our work, time spans may not correspond to specific instances of time, but instead help in inferring an ordering of events. Events which appear to the left of others take place earlier, while events within the same time span happen together over the same time period.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>Figure 5 :</head><label>5</label><figDesc>Figure 5: Extract from a news article which describes several events (bolded) happening at the same time.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head>Figure 6 :</head><label>6</label><figDesc>Figure 6: Breakdown of raw feature scores for sentences (L2) and (R2) from Figure 7.</figDesc><graphic url="image-3.png" coords="7,111.85,195.67,151.16,60.60" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><head>Figure 10 :</head><label>10</label><figDesc>Figure 10: Extract of timeline generated for document APW ENG 20070615.0356 from the TAC2011 dataset.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_6"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 7: Generated summaries for document set D1117C from the TAC-2011 dataset. Left summary is generated by SWING+TSI+CTSI+TCD with filtering; right summary is by SWING. R-2: 0.1683 R-2: 0.1533 .. .. .. .. .. .. (L1) A piece of steel fell and sheared off one of the ties holding it to the building, causing it to detach and topple, said Stephen Kaplan</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_7"><head>)</head><label></label><figDesc>The Coral Reef Task Force, created in the Clinton administration, regularly assesses coral health. (L3) Scientists warn that up to half of the world's coral reefs could disappear by 2045. = = (R3) With a finished necklace retailing for up to 20,000 dollars (15,000 euros), red corals are among the world's most expensive wildlife com- modities. . . . . . . . . . . . .</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_8"><head>Figure 9 :</head><label>9</label><figDesc>Figure 9: Extract from summaries for document set D1131F from the TAC-2011 dataset. Left extract is generated by SWING+TSI+CTSI+TCD; right extract is by SWING+TSI+TCD. R-2: 0.2643 R-2: 0.2772 (L1,R1)-An Iraqi reporter threw his shoes at visiting U.S. President George W. Bush and called him a "dog" in Arabic during a news conference with Iraqi Prime Minister Nuri al-Maliki in Baghdad (L2,R2) "All I can report is it is a size 10,. (L3) Muntadhar al-Zaidi, reporter of Baghdadiya television jumped and threw his two shoes one by one at the president, who ducked and thus narrowly missed being struck, raising chaos in the hall in Baghdad's heavily fortified green Zone. = = (R3) The incident occurred as Bush was appearing with Iraqi Prime Minister Nouri al-Maliki.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" validated="false"><head>Table 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Effect of different reliability filtering 
thresholds for SWING+TSI+CTSI+TCD. 'T' is 
the threshold used; '#' is the number of input col-
lections (out of 44) where timelines are used; '**' 
and '*' is statistical significance over SWING of 
p &lt; 0.05 and p &lt; 0.1, respectively. 

</table></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> The produced summaries are truncated to fit within a 100-word limit imposed by the TAC-2011 guidelines.</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>This research is supported by the Singapore Na-tional Research Foundation under its International Research Centre @ Singapore Funding Initiative and administered by the IDM Programme Office.</p><p>This work is also partially supported by the National Natural Science Foundation of China (Grant Nos. 61170189, 61370126, 61202239), the Fund of the State Key Laboratory of Software Development Environment <ref type="bibr">(Grant No. SKLSDE2013ZX-19)</ref>, and the Innovation Foundation of Beihang University for Ph.D. Graduates (YWF-13-T-YJSY-024).</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">TREC 2013 Temporal Summarization</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Javed</forename><surname>Aslam</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Matthew</forename><surname>Ekstrand-Abueg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Virgil</forename><surname>Pavlu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Fernado</forename><surname>Diaz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tetsuya</forename><surname>Sakai</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 22nd Text Retrieval Conference (TREC), November</title>
		<meeting>the 22nd Text Retrieval Conference (TREC), November</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Information Fusion in the Context of Multi-document Summarization</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Regina</forename><surname>Barzilay</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kathleen</forename><surname>Mckeown</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Elhadad</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 37th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics on Computational Linguistics (ACL)</title>
		<meeting>the 37th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics on Computational Linguistics (ACL)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1999-06" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="550" to="557" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Use of MMR, Diversity-based Reranking for Reordering Documents and Producing Summaries</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jaime</forename><surname>Carbonell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jade</forename><surname>Goldstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 21st Annual International ACM Conference on Research and Development in Information Retrieval (SIGIR)</title>
		<meeting>the 21st Annual International ACM Conference on Research and Development in Information Retrieval (SIGIR)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1998-08" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="335" to="336" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A Hybrid Hierarchical Model for Multi-document Summarization</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Asli</forename><surname>Celikyilmaz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dilek</forename><surname>Hakkani-Tur</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 48th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL)</title>
		<meeting>the 48th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010-07" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="815" to="824" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">CLASSY 2011 at TAC: Guided and Multi-lingual Summaries and Evaluation Metrics</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">John</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Conroy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Judith</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Schlesinger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jeff</forename><surname>Kubina</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Peter</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Rankel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dianne</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>O&amp;apos;leary</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Text Analysis Conference (TAC)</title>
		<meeting>the Text Analysis Conference (TAC)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011-11" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Entity Summarization of News Articles</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gianluca</forename><surname>Demartini</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Malik</forename><forename type="middle">Muhammad</forename><surname>Saad Missen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Roi</forename><surname>Blanco</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hugo</forename><surname>Zaragoza</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 33rd Annual International ACM Conference on Research and Development in Information Retrieval (SIGIR)</title>
		<meeting>the 33rd Annual International ACM Conference on Research and Development in Information Retrieval (SIGIR)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010-07" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="798" to="796" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Predicting Globally-Coherent Temporal Structures from Texts via Endpoint Inference and Graph Decomposition</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Pascal</forename><surname>Denis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Philippe</forename><surname>Muller</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 22nd International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence (IJCAI)</title>
		<meeting>the 22nd International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence (IJCAI)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011-07" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Joint Inference for Event Timeline Construction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wei</forename><surname>Quang Xuan Do</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dan</forename><surname>Lu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Roth</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2012 Joint Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing and Computational Natural Language Learning (EMNLP)</title>
		<meeting>the 2012 Joint Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing and Computational Natural Language Learning (EMNLP)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012-07" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="677" to="689" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Instruction Manual for the Annotation of Temporal Expressions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lisa</forename><surname>Ferro</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Laurie</forename><surname>Gerber</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Inderjeet</forename><surname>Mani</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Beth</forename><surname>Sundheim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">George</forename><surname>Wilson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
			<publisher>The MITRE Corporation</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
<note type="report_type">Technical report</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Generic Text Summarization Using Relevance Measure and Latent Semantic Analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jade</forename><surname>Goldstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Vibhu</forename><surname>Mittal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jaime</forename><surname>Carbonell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mark</forename><surname>Kantrowitz</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 24th Annual International ACM Conference on Research and Development in Information Retrieval (SIGIR)</title>
		<meeting>the 24th Annual International ACM Conference on Research and Development in Information Retrieval (SIGIR)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2000-04" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="19" to="25" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Proceedings of the 2000 NAACL-ANLP Workshop on Automatic Summarization</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Reducing Redundancy in Multi-document Summarization using Lexical Semantic Similarity</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Iris</forename><surname>Hendrickx</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Walter</forename><surname>Daelemans</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Erwin</forename><surname>Marsi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Emiel</forename><surname>Krahmer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Workshop on Language Generation and Summarisation (UCNLG+Sum)</title>
		<meeting>the Workshop on Language Generation and Summarisation (UCNLG+Sum)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009-08" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="63" to="66" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Automatic Evaluation of Summaries Using N-gram Cooccurrence Statistics</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chin-Yew</forename><surname>Lin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Eduard</forename><surname>Hovy</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Conference of the North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics on Human Language Technology (NAACL)</title>
		<meeting>the Conference of the North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics on Human Language Technology (NAACL)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003-05" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="71" to="78" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Looking for a Few Good Metrics: ROUGE and its Evaluation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chin-Yew</forename><surname>Lin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Working Notes of the 4th NTCIR Workshop Meeting</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004-06" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Extractive Summarization Based on Event Term Temporal Relation Graph and Critical Chain</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Maofu</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wenjie</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Huijun</forename><surname>Hu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Information Retrieval Technology</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Berlin Heidelberg</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">5839</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="87" to="99" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Improved Temporal Relation Classification using Dependency Parses and Selective Crowdsourced Annotations</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jun-Ping</forename><surname>Ng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Min-Yen</forename><surname>Kan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the International Conference on Computational Linguistics (COLING)</title>
		<meeting>the International Conference on Computational Linguistics (COLING)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012-12" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2109" to="2124" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Exploiting Category-Specific Information for Multi-Document Summarization</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jun-Ping</forename><surname>Ng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Praveen</forename><surname>Bysani</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ziheng</forename><surname>Lin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Min-Yen</forename><surname>Kan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chew-Lim</forename><surname>Tan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the International Conference on Computational Linguistics (COLING)</title>
		<meeting>the International Conference on Computational Linguistics (COLING)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012-12" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2093" to="2108" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Exploiting Discourse Analysis for Article-Wide Temporal Classification</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jun-Ping</forename><surname>Ng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Min-Yen</forename><surname>Kan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ziheng</forename><surname>Lin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wei</forename><surname>Feng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bin</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jian</forename><surname>Su</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chew-Lim</forename><surname>Tan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP)</title>
		<meeting>the Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013-10" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="12" to="23" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Overview of the TAC 2011 Summarization Track: Guided Task and AESOP Task</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Karolina</forename><surname>Owczarzak</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hoa</forename><surname>Dang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Text Analysis Conference (TAC)</title>
		<meeting>the Text Analysis Conference (TAC)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011-11" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Applying the Pyramid Method in DUC</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rebecca</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Passonneau</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ani</forename><surname>Nenkova</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kathleen</forename><surname>Mckeown</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sergey</forename><surname>Sigelman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Document Understanding Conference Workshop on Text Summarization</title>
		<meeting>the Document Understanding Conference Workshop on Text Summarization</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005-10" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">TimeML: Robust Specification of Event and Temporal Expressions in Text</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">James</forename><surname>Pustejovsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">José</forename><surname>Castano</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Robert</forename><surname>Ingria</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Roser</forename><surname>Saurí</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Robert</forename><surname>Gaizauskas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Andrea</forename><surname>Setzer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Graham</forename><surname>Katz</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 5th International Workshop on Computational Semantics (IWCS)</title>
		<meeting>the 5th International Workshop on Computational Semantics (IWCS)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003-01" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The TIMEBANK corpus</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">James</forename><surname>Pustejovsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Patrick</forename><surname>Hanks</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Roser</forename><surname>Sauri</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Andrew</forename><surname>See</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Robert</forename><surname>Gaizauskas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Andrea</forename><surname>Setzer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dragomir</forename><surname>Radev</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Beth</forename><surname>Sundheim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Day</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lisa</forename><surname>Ferro</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marcia</forename><surname>Lazo</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of Corpus Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>Corpus Linguistics</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003-03" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="647" to="656" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Multilingual and Cross-domain Temporal Tagging. Language Resources and Evaluation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jannik</forename><surname>Strötgen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Gertz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">47</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="269" to="298" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">SemEval-2013 Task 1: TEMPEVAL3: Evaluating Time Expressions, Events, and Temporal Relations</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Naushad</forename><surname>Uzzaman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hector</forename><surname>Llorens</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Leon</forename><surname>Derczynski</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marc</forename><surname>Verhagen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">James</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Allen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">James</forename><surname>Pustejovsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 7th International Workshop on Semantic Evaluation (SemEval)</title>
		<meeting>the 7th International Workshop on Semantic Evaluation (SemEval)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013-06" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The TempEval Challenge: Identifying Temporal Relations in Text. Language Resources and Evaluation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marc</forename><surname>Verhagen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Robert</forename><surname>Gaizauskas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Frank</forename><surname>Schilder</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mark</forename><surname>Hepple</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jessica</forename><surname>Moszkowicz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">James</forename><surname>Pustejovsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">43</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="161" to="179" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">SemEval-2010 Task 13: TempEval-2</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marc</forename><surname>Verhagen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Roser</forename><surname>Saurí</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tommaso</forename><surname>Caselli</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">James</forename><surname>Pustejovsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 5th International Workshop on Semantic Evaluation (SemEval)</title>
		<meeting>the 5th International Workshop on Semantic Evaluation (SemEval)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010-07" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="57" to="62" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">TimedTextRank: Adding the Temporal Dimension to Multi-Document Summarization</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xiaojun</forename><surname>Wan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 30th Annual International ACM Conference on Research and Development in Information Retrieval (SIGIR)</title>
		<meeting>the 30th Annual International ACM Conference on Research and Development in Information Retrieval (SIGIR)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007-07" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="867" to="868" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Investigations on TemporalOriented Event-Based Extractive Summarization</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mingli</forename><surname>Wu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>Hong Kong Polytechnic University</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
<note type="report_type">Ph.D. thesis</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Using Corpus and Knowledge-based Similarity Measure in Maximum Marginal Relevance for Meeting Summarization</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Shasha</forename><surname>Xie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yang</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the International Conference on Acoustics, Speech, and Signal Processing (ICASSP)</title>
		<meeting>the International Conference on Acoustics, Speech, and Signal Processing (ICASSP)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008-03" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="4985" to="4988" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Guided Summarization with Aspect Recognition</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Renxian</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">You</forename><surname>Ouyang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wenjie</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Text Analysis Conference (TAC)</title>
		<meeting>the Text Analysis Conference (TAC)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011-11" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
