<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T11:07+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Automatic Annotation Suggestions and Custom Annotation Layers in WebAnno</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date>June 23-24, 2014</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Seid</forename><surname>Muhie</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Dept. of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Dept. of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">FG Language Technology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">Technische Universität Darmstadt</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit3">Technische Universität Darmstadt</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yimam</forename></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Dept. of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Dept. of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">FG Language Technology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">Technische Universität Darmstadt</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit3">Technische Universität Darmstadt</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Richard</forename><surname>Eckart De Castilho</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Dept. of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Dept. of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">FG Language Technology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">Technische Universität Darmstadt</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit3">Technische Universität Darmstadt</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Iryna</forename><surname>Gurevych</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Dept. of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Dept. of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">FG Language Technology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">Technische Universität Darmstadt</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit3">Technische Universität Darmstadt</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chris</forename><surname>Biemann</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Dept. of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Dept. of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">FG Language Technology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">Technische Universität Darmstadt</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit3">Technische Universität Darmstadt</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Automatic Annotation Suggestions and Custom Annotation Layers in WebAnno</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of 52nd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics: System Demonstrations</title>
						<meeting>52nd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics: System Demonstrations <address><addrLine>Baltimore, Maryland USA</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="91" to="96"/>
							<date type="published">June 23-24, 2014</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<note>(2) Ubiquitous Knowledge Processing Lab (UKP-TUDA) (3) Ubiquitous Knowledge Processing Lab (UKP-DIPF) German Institute for Educational Research and Educational Information http://www.{lt,ukp}.tu-darmstadt.de</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>In this paper, we present a flexible approach to the efficient and exhaustive manual annotation of text documents. For this purpose, we extend WebAnno (Yimam et al., 2013) an open-source web-based annotation tool. 1 While it was previously limited to specific annotation layers, our extension allows adding and configuring an arbitrary number of layers through a web-based UI. These layers can be annotated separately or simultaneously, and support most types of linguistic annotations such as spans, semantic classes, dependency relations, lexical chains, and morphology. Further, we tightly integrate a generic machine learning component for automatic annotation suggestions of span annotations. In two case studies, we show that automatic annotation suggestions , combined with our split-pane UI concept, significantly reduces annotation time.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>The annotation of full text documents is a costly and time-consuming task. Thus, it is important to design annotation tools in such a way that the an- notation process can happen as swiftly as possible.</p><p>To this end, we extend WebAnno with the capabil- ity of suggesting annotations to the annotator.</p><p>A general-purpose web-based annotation tool can greatly lower the entrance barrier for linguistic annotation projects, as tool development costs and preparatory work are greatly reduced. WebAnno 1.0 only partially fulfilled desires regarding gen- erality: Although it covered already more kinds of annotations than most other tools, it supported only a fixed set of customizable annotation lay- ers (named entities, part-of-speech, lemmata, co- reference, dependencies). Thus, we also remove a limitation of the tool, which was previously bound to specific, hardcoded annotation layers.</p><p>We have generalized the architecture to support three configurable generic structures: spans, rela- tions, and chains. These support all of the original layers and allow the user to define arbitrary custom annotation layers based on either of these struc- tures. Additionally, our approach allows maintain- ing multiple properties on annotations, e.g. to sup- port morphological annotations, while previously only one property per annotation was supported.</p><p>Automatic suggestion of annotations is based on machine learning, which is common practice in annotation tools. However, most of existing web-based annotation tools, such as GATE <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Cunningham et al., 2011</ref>) or brat ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Stenetorp et al., 2012)</ref>, depend on external preprocessing and post- processing plugins or on web services. These tools have limitations regarding adaptability (difficulty to adapt to other annotation tasks), reconfigurabil- ity (generating a classifier when new features and training documents are available is complicated), and reusability (requires manual intervention to add newly annotated documents into the iteration).</p><p>For our approach, we assume that an annota- tor actually does manually verify all annotations to produce a completely labeled dataset. This task can be sped up by automatically suggesting anno- tations that the annotator may then either accept or correct. Note that this setup and its goal differs from an active learning scenario, where a system actively determines the most informative yet unan- notated example to be labeled, in order to quickly arrive at a high-quality classifier that is then to be applied to large amounts of unseen data.</p><p>Our contribution is the integration of machine learning into the tool to support exhaustive an-notation of documents providing a shorter loop than comparable tools <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Cunningham et al., 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Stenetorp et al., 2012)</ref>, because new documents are added to the training set as soon as they are completed by the annotators. The machine learn- ing support currently applies to sequence classifi- cation tasks only. It is complemented by our ex- tension allowing to define custom annotation lay- ers, making it applicable to a wide range of anno- tation tasks with only little configuration effort.</p><p>Section 2 reviews related work about the uti- lization of automatic supports and customiza- tion of annotation schemes in existing annotation tools. The integration of automatic suggestions into WebAnno, the design principles followed, and two case studies are explained in Section 3. Sec- tion 4 presents the implementation of customiz- able annotation layers into the tool. Finally, Sec- tion 5 summarizes the main contributions and fu- ture directions of our work.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Related Work</head><p>Automatic annotation support The impact of using lexical and statistical resources to produce pre-annotation automatically to increase the anno- tation speed has been studied widely for various annotation tasks. For the task of medical named entity labeling, <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Lingren et al. (2013)</ref> investigate the impact of automatic suggestions on annotation speed and potential biases using dictionary-based annotations. This technique results in 13.83% to 21.5% time saving and in an inter-annotator agree- ment (IAA) increase by several percentage points.</p><p>WordFreak <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Morton and LaCivita, 2003</ref>) in- cludes an automation component, where instances with a low machine learning confidence are pre- sented for annotation in an active learning setup. <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Beck et al. (2013)</ref> demonstrate that the use of ac- tive learning for machine translation reduces the annotation effort and show a reduced annotation load on three out of four datasets.</p><p>The GoldenGATE editor <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(Sautter et al., 2007</ref>) integrates NLP tools and assistance features for manual XML editing. The tool is used in correct- ing/editing an automatically annotated document with an editor where both text and XML markups are modified. GoldenGATE is merely used to fa- cilitate the correction of an annotation while pre- annotation is conducted outside of the tool.</p><p>Automatic annotation support in brat ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Stenetorp et al., 2012</ref>) was carried out for a semantic class disambiguation task to investigate how such au- tomation facilitates the annotators' progress. They report a 15.4% reduction in total annotation time. However, the automation process in brat 1) de- pends on bulk annotation imports and web service configurations, which is labor intensive, 2) is task specific so that it requires a lot of effort to adapt it to different annotation tasks, 3) there is no way of using the corrected result for the next iteration of training the automatic tool.</p><p>The GATE Teamware ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Bontcheva et al., 2013</ref>) automation component is most similar to our work. It is based either on plugins and externally trained classification models, or uses web services. Thus, it is highly task specific and requires exten- sive configuration. The automatic annotation sug- gestion component in our tool, in contrast, is easily configurable and adaptable to different annotation tasks and allows the use of annotations from the current annotation project.</p><p>Custom annotation layers Generic annotation data models are typically directed graph models (e.g. GATE, UIMA CAS ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Götz and Suhre, 2004</ref>), <ref type="bibr">GrAF (Ide and Suderman, 2007)</ref>). In addition, an annotation schema defines possible kinds of anno- tations, their properties and relations. While these models offer great expressiveness and flexibility, it is difficult to adequately transfer their power into a convenient annotation editor. For example, one schema may prescribe that the part-of-speech tag is a property on a Token annotation, another one may prescribe that the tag is a separate annotation, which is linked to the token. An annotator should not be exposed to these details in the UI and should be able to just edit a part-of-speech tag, ignorant of the internal representation.</p><p>This problem is typically addressed in two ways. Either, the full complexity of the annota- tion model is exposed to the annotator, or the an- notation editor uses a simplified model. The first approach can easily lead to an unintuitive UI and make the annotation an inconvenient task. The second approach (e.g. as advocated by brat) re- quires the implementation of specific import and export filters to transform between the editor data model and the generic annotation data models.</p><p>We propose a third approach integrating a con- figurable mapping between a generic annotation model (UIMA CAS) and a simplified editing model (brat) directly into the annotation tool. Thus, we avoid exposing the full complexity of the generic model to the user and also avoid the necessity for implementing import/export filters. Similar approaches have already been used to map annotation models to visualization modules (cf. ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Zeldes et al., 2009)</ref>), but have, to our knowledge, not been used in an annotation editor. Our ap- proach is different from schema-based annotation editors (e.g. GATE), which employ a schema as a template of properties and controlled vocabular- ies that can be used to annotate documents, but which do not allow to map structures inherent in annotations, like relations or chains, to respective concepts in the UI.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Automatic Annotation Suggestions</head><p>It is the purpose of the automatic annotation sug- gestion component to increase the annotation ef- ficiency, while maintaining the quality of annota- tions. The key design principle of our approach is a split-pane ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref>) that displays automatic an- notation suggestions in the suggestion pane (lower part) and only verified or manual ones in the anno- tation pane (upper part). In this way, we force the annotators to review each automatic suggestion as to avoid overlooking wrong suggestions. Lower: the suggestion pane, displaying predic- tions or automatic suggestions, and coding their status in color. This examples shows automatic suggestions for parts-of-speech. Unattended anno- tations are rendered in blue, accepted annotations in grey and rejected annotations in red. Here, the last five POS annotations have been attended, four have been accepted by clicking on the suggestion, and one was rejected by annotating it in the anno- tation pane.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Suggestion modes</head><p>We distinguish three modes of automatic annota- tion suggestion:</p><p>Correction mode In this mode, we import doc- uments annotated by arbitrary external tools and present them to the user in the suggestion pane of the annotation page. This mode is specifi- cally appropriate for annotation tasks where a pre- annotated document contains several possibilities for annotations in parallel, and the user's task is to select the correct annotation. This allows to leverage specialized external automatic annotation components, thus the tool is not limited to the in- tegrated automation mechanism.</p><p>Repetition mode In this mode, further occur- rences of a word annotated by the user are high- lighted in the suggestion pane. To accept sugges- tions, the user can simply click on them in the sug- gestion pane. This basic -yet effective -sugges- tion is realized using simple string matching.</p><p>Learning mode For this mode, we have inte- grated MIRA <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Crammer and Singer, 2003)</ref>, an ex- tension of the perceptron algorithm for online ma- chine learning which allows for the automatic sug- gestions of span annotations. MIRA was selected because of its relatively lenient licensing, its good performance even on small amounts of data, and its capability of allowing incremental classifier up- dates. Results of automatic tagging are displayed in the suggestion pane. Our architecture is flexible to integrate further machine learning tools.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Suggestion Process</head><p>The workflow to set up an automatically supported annotation project consists of the following steps.</p><p>Importing annotation documents We can im- port documents with existing annotations (manual or automatic). The annotation pane of the automa- tion page allows users to annotate documents and the suggestion pane is used for the automatic sug- gestion as shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref>. The suggestion pane facilitates accepting correct pre-annotations with minimal effort.</p><p>Configuring features For the machine learning tool, it is required to define classification features to train a classifier. We have designed a UI where a range of standard classification features for se- quence tagging can be configured. The features include morphological features (prefixes, suffixes, and capitalization), n-grams, and other layers as a feature (for example POS annotation as a feature for named entity recognition). While these stan- dard features do not lead to state-of-the-art per- formance on arbitrary tasks, we have found them to perform very well for POS tagging, named en- tity recognition, and chunking. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 2</ref> shows the feature configuration in the project settings.</p><p>Importing training documents We offer two ways of providing training documents: importing an annotated document in one of the supported file formats, such as CoNLL, TCF, or UIMA XMI; or using existing annotation documents in the same project that already have been annotated.</p><p>Starting the annotation suggestion Once fea- tures for a training layer are configured and train- ing documents are available, automatic annotation is possible. The process can be started manually by the administrator from the automation settings page, and it will be automatically re-initiated when additional documents for training become avail- able in the project. While the automatic annotation is running in the background, users still can work on the annotation front end without being affected. Training and creating a classifier will be repeated only when the feature configuration is changed or when a new training document is available.</p><p>Display results on the monitoring page Af- ter the training and automatic annotation are com- pleted, detailed information about the training data such as the number of documents (sentence, to- kens), features used for each layer, F-score on held-out data, and classification errors are dis- played on the monitoring page, allowing an esti- mation whether the automatic suggestion is use- ful. The UI also shows the status of the training process (not started, running, or finished).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3">Case Studies</head><p>We describe two case studies that demonstrate lan- guage independence and flexibility with respect to sequence label types of our automatic annotation suggestions. In the first case study, we address the task of POS tagging for Amharic as an example of an under-resourced language. Second, we explore German named entity recognition.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3.1">Amharic POS tagging</head><p>Amharic is an under-resourced language in the Semitic family, mainly spoken in Ethiopia. POS tagging research for Amharic is mostly conducted as an academic exercise. The latest result re- ported by Gebre (2009) was about 90% accuracy using the Walta Information Center (WIC) corpus of about 210,000 tokens (1065 news documents). We intentionally do not use the corpus as training data because of the reported inconsistencies in the tagging process <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Gebre, 2009)</ref>. Instead, we man- ually annotate Amharic documents for POS tag- ging both to test the performance of the automa- tion module and to produce POS-tagged corpora for Amharic. Based upon the work by <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Petrov et al. (2012)</ref> and Ethiopian Languages Research Cen- ter (ELRC) tagset, we have designed 11 POS tags equivalent to the Universal POS tags. The tag DET is not included as Amharic denotes definiteness as noun suffixes.</p><p>We collected some Amharic documents from an online news portal. <ref type="bibr">2</ref> Preprocessing of Amharic documents includes the normalization of charac- ters and tokenization (sentence and word bound- ary detection). Initially, we manually annotated 21 sentences. Using these, an iterative automatic an- notation suggestion process was started until 300 sentences were fully annotated. We obtained an F-score of 0.89 with the final model. Hence the automatic annotation suggestion helps in decreas- ing the total annotation time, since the user has to manually annotate only one out of ten words, while being able to accept most automatic sugges- tions. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 3</ref> shows such an Amharic document in WebAnno.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3.2">German Named Entity Recognition</head><p>A pilot Named Entity Recognition (NER) project for German was conducted by <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Benikova et al. (2014)</ref>. We have used the dataset -about 31,000 sentences, over 41,000 NE annotations -for train- ing NER. Using this dataset, an F-score of about 0.8 by means of automatic suggestions was ob- tained, which leads to an increase in annotation speed of about 21% with automatic suggestion.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Customs Annotation Layers</head><p>The tasks in which an annotation editor can be em- ployed depends on the expressiveness of the un- derlying annotation model. However, fully expos- ing the expressive power in the UI can make the editor inconvenient to use.</p><p>We propose an approach that allows the user to configure a mapping of an annotation model to concepts well-supported in a web-based UI. In this way, we can avoid to expose all details of the an- notation model in the UI, and remove the need to implement custom import/export filters. WebAnno 1.0 employs a variant of the annota- tion UI provided by brat, which offers the concepts of spans and arcs. Based on these, WebAnno 1.2 implements five annotation layers: named entity, part-of-speech, lemmata, co-reference, and depen- dencies. In the new WebAnno version, we gener- alized the support for these five layers into three structural categories: span, relation (arc), and chain. Each of these categories is handled by a generic adapter which can be configured to sim- ulate any of the original five layers. Based on this generalization, the user can now define cus- tom layers <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">(Figure 4)</ref>.</p><p>Additionally, we introduced a new concept of constraints. For example, NER spans should not cross sentence boundaries and attach to whole to- kens (not substrings of tokens). Such constraints not only help preventing the user from making in- valid annotations, but can also offer extra conve- nience. We currently support four hard-coded con- straints:</p><p>Lock to token offsets Defines if annotation boundaries must coincide with token boundaries, e.g. named entities, lemmata, part-of-speech, etc. For the user's convenience, the annotation is auto- matically expanded to include the full token, even if only a part of a token is selected during annota- tion (span/chain layers only).</p><p>Allow multiple tokens Some kinds of annota- tions may only cover a single token, e.g. part-of- speech, while others may cover multiple tokens, e.g. named entities (span/chain layers only).</p><p>Allow stacking Controls if multiple annotations of the same kind can be at the same location, e.g. if multiple lemma annotations are allowed per to- ken. For the user's convenience, an existing an- notation is replaced if a new annotation is created when stacking is not allowed.</p><p>Allow crossing sentence boundaries Certain annotations, e.g. named entities or dependency de- lations, may not cross sentence boundaries, while others need to, e.g. coreference chains.</p><p>Finally, we added the ability to define multiple properties for annotations to WebAnno. For exam- ple, this can be use to define a custom span-based morphology layer with multiple annotation prop- erties such as gender, number, case, etc.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Conclusion and Outlook</head><p>We discussed two extensions of WebAnno: the tight and generic integration of automatic annota- tion suggestions for reducing the annotation time, and the web-based addition and configuration of custom annotation layers.</p><p>While we also support the common practice of using of external tools to automatically pre- annotate documents, we go one step further by tightly integrating a generic sequence classifier into the tool that can make use of completed an- notation documents from the same project. In two case studies, we have shown quick convergence for Amharic POS tagging and a substantial reduc- tion in annotation time for German NER. The key concept here is the split-pane UI that allows to dis- play automatic suggestions, while forcing the an- notator to review all of them.</p><p>Allowing the definition of custom annotation layers in a web-based UI is greatly increasing the number of annotation projects that potentially could use our tool. While it is mainly an engineer- ing challenge to allow this amount of flexibility and to hide its complexity from the user, it is a ma- jor contribution in the transition from specialized tools towards general-purpose tools.</p><p>The combination of both -custom layers and automatic suggestions -gives rise to the rapid setup of efficient annotation projects. Adding to existing capabilities in WebAnno, such as cura- tion, agreement computation, monitoring and fine- grained annotation project definition, our contri- butions significantly extend the scope of annota- tion tasks in which the tool can be employed.</p><p>In future work, we plan to support annota- tion suggestions for non-span structures (arcs and chains), and to include further machine learning algorithms.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: Split-pane UI. Upper: the annotation pane, which should be completed by the annotator. Lower: the suggestion pane, displaying predictions or automatic suggestions, and coding their status in color. This examples shows automatic suggestions for parts-of-speech. Unattended annotations are rendered in blue, accepted annotations in grey and rejected annotations in red. Here, the last five POS annotations have been attended, four have been accepted by clicking on the suggestion, and one was rejected by annotating it in the annotation pane.</figDesc><graphic url="image-1.png" coords="3,73.09,456.01,216.09,132.04" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2: Configuring an annotation suggestion: 1) layers for automation, 2) different features, 3) training documents, 4) start training classifier.</figDesc><graphic url="image-2.png" coords="4,106.02,62.81,385.51,169.03" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Figure 3: Example Amharic document. The red tags in the suggestion pane have not been confirmed by the annotator.</figDesc><graphic url="image-3.png" coords="5,82.92,62.81,196.44,73.67" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>Figure 4 :</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Figure 4: UI for custom annotation layers.</figDesc><graphic url="image-4.png" coords="5,307.28,62.81,218.26,107.13" type="bitmap" /></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> WebAnno is open-source software under the terms of the Apache Software License 2.0. This paper describes v1.2: http://webanno.googlecode.com</note>

			<note place="foot" n="2"> http://www.ethiopianreporter.com/</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>The work presented in this paper was funded by a German BMBF grant to the CLARIN-D project, the Hessian LOEWE research excellence program as part of the research center "Digital Humanities" and by the Volkswagen Foundation as part of the Lichtenberg-Professorship Program under grant No. I/82806.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Reducing annotation effort for quality estimation via active learning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Daniel</forename><surname>Beck</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lucia</forename><surname>Specia</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Trevor</forename><surname>Cohn</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. ACL 2013 System Demonstrations</title>
		<meeting>ACL 2013 System Demonstrations<address><addrLine>Sofia, Bulgaria</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">NoSta-D Named Entity Annotation for German: Guidelines and Dataset</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Darina</forename><surname>Benikova</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chris</forename><surname>Biemann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marc</forename><surname>Reznicek</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. LREC</title>
		<meeting>LREC<address><addrLine>Reykjavik, Iceland</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">GATE Teamware: a web-based, collaborative text annotation framework</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kalina</forename><surname>Bontcheva</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Cunningham</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Roberts</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Roberts</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Tablan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Aswani</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Gorrell</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Language Resources and Evaluation</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">47</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1007" to="1029" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Ultraconservative online algorithms for multiclass problems</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Koby</forename><surname>Crammer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yoram</forename><surname>Singer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">In Journal of Machine Learning Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="951" to="991" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Text Processing with GATE (Version 6)</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hamish</forename><surname>Cunningham</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Maynard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Bontcheva</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Tablan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Aswani</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Roberts</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Gorrell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Funk</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Roberts</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Damljanovic</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Heitz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Greenwood</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Saggion</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Petrak</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Peters</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="978" to="0956599315" />
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>University of Sheffield Department of Computer Science</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Part-of-speech tagging for Amharic</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Binyam Gebrekidan Gebre</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ISMTCL Proceedings, International Review Bulag</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>PUFC</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Design and implementation of the UIMA Common Analysis System</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Götz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Suhre</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IBM Systems Journal</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">43</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="476" to="489" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">GrAF: A graph-based format for linguistic annotations</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nancy</forename><surname>Ide</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Keith</forename><surname>Suderman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. Linguistic Annotation Workshop</title>
		<meeting>Linguistic Annotation Workshop<address><addrLine>Prague, Czech Republic</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="8" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Evaluating the impact of pre-annotation on annotation speed and potential bias: natural language processing gold standard development for clinical named entity recognition in clinical trial announcements</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Todd Lingren</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Deleger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Molnar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Zhai</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Meinzenderr</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Kaiser</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Q</forename><surname>Stoutenborough</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Solti</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">In Journal of the American Medical Informatics Association</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="951" to="991" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">WordFreak: an open tool for linguistic annotation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Thomas</forename><surname>Morton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jeremy</forename><surname>Lacivita</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. NAACL 2003, demonstrations</title>
		<meeting>NAACL 2003, demonstrations<address><addrLine>Edmonton, Canada</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="17" to="18" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A universal part-of-speech tagset</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Slav</forename><surname>Petrov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dipanjan</forename><surname>Das</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ryan</forename><surname>Mcdonald</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc LREC 2012</title>
		<meeting>LREC 2012<address><addrLine>Turkey</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Istanbul</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Empirical Evaluation of Semi-automated XML Annotation of Text Documents with the GoldenGATE Editor</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Guido</forename><surname>Sautter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Klemens</forename><surname>Böhm</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Frank</forename><surname>Padberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Walter</forename><surname>Tichy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
			<pubPlace>Budapest, Hungary</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">brat: a Web-based Tool for NLP-Assisted Text Annotation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Pontus</forename><surname>Stenetorp</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sampo</forename><surname>Pyysalo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Goran</forename><surname>Topi´ctopi´c</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tomoko</forename><surname>Ohta</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sophia</forename><surname>Ananiadou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jun&amp;apos;ichi</forename><surname>Tsujii</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. EACL 2012 Demo Session</title>
		<meeting>EACL 2012 Demo Session<address><addrLine>Avignon, France</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">WebAnno: A flexible,web-based and visually supported system for distributed annotations</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Iryna</forename><surname>Seid Muhie Yimam</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Richard</forename><surname>Gurevych</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chris</forename><surname>Eckart De Castilho</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Biemann</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. ACL 2013 System Demonstrations</title>
		<meeting>ACL 2013 System Demonstrations<address><addrLine>Sofia, Bulgaria</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="6" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">ANNIS: A search tool for multi-layer annotated corpora</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Amir</forename><surname>Zeldes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Julia</forename><surname>Ritz</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. Corpus Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>Corpus Linguistics<address><addrLine>UK</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Anke Lüdeling, and Christian Chiarcos</note>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
