<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T11:40+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Web Information Mining and Decision Support Platform for the Modern Service Industry</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date>June 23-24, 2014</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Binyang</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Dept. of Information Science &amp; Technology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of International Relations</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Dept. of Systems Engineering &amp; Engineering Management</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">The Chinese University of Hong Kong</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Shatin, Hong Kong</settlement>
									<region>N.T</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lanjun</forename><surname>Zhou</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Dept. of Systems Engineering &amp; Engineering Management</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">The Chinese University of Hong Kong</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Shatin, Hong Kong</settlement>
									<region>N.T</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="institution">MoE Key Laboratory of High Confidence Software Technologies</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Zhongyu</forename><surname>Wei</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Dept. of Systems Engineering &amp; Engineering Management</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">The Chinese University of Hong Kong</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Shatin, Hong Kong</settlement>
									<region>N.T</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="institution">MoE Key Laboratory of High Confidence Software Technologies</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kam-Fai</forename><surname>Wong</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Dept. of Systems Engineering &amp; Engineering Management</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">The Chinese University of Hong Kong</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Shatin, Hong Kong</settlement>
									<region>N.T</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="institution">MoE Key Laboratory of High Confidence Software Technologies</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff3">
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Shenzhen Research Institute</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">The Chinese University of Hong Kong</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ruifeng</forename><surname>Xu</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff4">
								<orgName type="institution">Harbin Institute of Technology Shenzhen Graduate School</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Shenzhen</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yunqing</forename><surname>Xia</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff5">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science &amp; Technology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Tsinghua University</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>TNList</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Web Information Mining and Decision Support Platform for the Modern Service Industry</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of 52nd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics: System Demonstrations</title>
						<meeting>52nd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics: System Demonstrations <address><addrLine>Baltimore, Maryland USA</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="97" to="102"/>
							<date type="published">June 23-24, 2014</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>This demonstration presents an intelligent information platform MODEST. MODEST will provide enterprises with the services of retrieving news from websites, extracting commercial information , exploring customers&apos; opinions, and analyzing collaborative/competitive social networks. In this way, enterprises can improve the competitive abilities and facilitate potential collaboration activities. At the meanwhile, MODEST can also help governments to acquire information about one single company or the entire board timely, and make prompt strategies for better support. Currently, MODEST is applied to the pillar industries of Hong Kong, including innovative finance, modem logistics, information technology, etc.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>With the rapid development of Web 2.0, the amount of information is exploding. There are millions of events towards companies and bil- lions of opinions on products generated every day (Liu, 2012). Such enormous information cannot only facilitate companies to improve their competitive abilities, but also help government to make prompt decisions for better support or timely monitor, e.g. effective risk management. For this reason, there is a growing demand of Web information mining and intelligent decision support services for the industries. Such services are collectively referred as modern service, which includes the following requirements:</p><p>(1) To efficiently retrieve relevant information from the websites; (2) To accurately determine the latest business news and trends of the company; (3) To identify and analyze customers' opinions towards the company; (4) To explore the collaborative and competitive relationship with other companies; (5) To leverage the knowledge mined from the business news and company social network for decision support. In this demonstration, we will present a Web information mining and decision support plat- form, MODEST <ref type="bibr">1</ref> . The objective of MODEST is to provide modern services for both enterprises and government, including collecting Web in- formation, making deep analysis, and providing supporting decision. The innovation of MOD- EST is focusing on deep analysis which incor- porates the following functions:  Topic detection and tracking function is to cluster the hot events and capture the rela- tionship between the relevant events based on the collected data from websites (event also referred as topic in this paper). In order to re- alize this function, Web mining techniques are adopted, e.g. topic clustering, heuristics algorithms, etc.  The second function is to identify and analyze customers' opinions about the company. Opinion mining technology ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Zhou et al., 2010</ref>) is adopted to determine the polarity of those news, which can help the company timely and appropriately adjust the policy to strengthen the dominant position or avoid risks.  <ref type="table">third function is to explore and analyze  social network based on the company centric.</ref> We utilize social network analysis (SNA) technology (  to discover the relationships, and we further analyze the con- tent in fine-grained granularity to identify its potential partners or competitors.</p><p>With the help of MODEST, the companies can acquire modern service-related information, and timely adjust corporate policies and marketing plan ahead. Hence, the ability of information ac- quisition and the competitiveness of the enter- prises can be improved accordingly.</p><p>In this paper, we will use a practical example to illustrate our platform and evaluate the per- formance of main functions.</p><p>The rest of this paper is organized as follows. Section 2 will introduce the system description as well as the main functions implementation. The practical case study will be illustrated in Section 3. The performance of MODEST will be evaluated in Section 4.Finally, this paper will be concluded in Section 5.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">System Description</head><p>In this section, we first outline the system archi- tecture of MODEST, and then describe the im- plementation of the main functionality in detail.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">Architecture and Workflow</head><p>The MODEST system consists of three modules: data acquisition, data analysis, and result display. The system architecture is shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 1</ref>. (1) The core technique in the data acquisition module is the crawler, which is developed to collect raw data from websites, e.g. news portals, blogosphere. Then the system parse the raw web pages and extract information to store in the local database for further processing. (2) The data analysis module can be divided into two parts:  NLP pre-processor: utilizes NLP (natural language processing) techniques and some toolkits to perform the pre-processing on the raw data in (1), including word segmenta- tion, part-of-speech (POS) tagging 1 , stop- word removal, and named entity recognition (NER) 2 . We then create knowledgebase for individual industry, such as domain-specific sentiment word lexicon, name entity collec- tion, and so on. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">Function Implementation</head><p>Since the innovation of MODEST is focusing on the module of data analysis, we will describe its main functions in detail, including topic detec- tion and tracking, opinion mining, and social networks analysis.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2.1">Topic Detection and Tracking</head><p>The TDT function targets on detecting and tracking the hot topics for each individual com- pany. Given a period of data collected from web- sites, there are various discussions about the company. In order to extract these topics, clus- tering methods ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Viermetz et al., 2007 and</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Yoon et al., 2009</ref>) are implemented to explore the top- ics. Note that during the period of data collection, different topics with respect to the same compa- ny may have relations. We, therefore, utilize hi- erarchical clustering methods 4 to capture the po- tential relations.</p><p>Due to the large amount of data, it is impossi- ble to view all the topics at a snapshot. MODEST utilizes topic tracking technique ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Wang et al., 2008</ref> media. It is convenient for the users to see the latest information about the company. In summary, TDT function provides the ser- vices of detecting and tracking the latest and emergent topics, analyzing the relationships of topics on the dynamics of the company. It meets the aforementioned demand, "to accurately grasp the latest business news and trends of the com- pany".</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2.2">Opinion Mining</head><p>The objective of OM function is to discover opinions towards a company and classify the opinions into positive, negative, or neutral.</p><p>The opinion mining function is redesigned based on our own opinion mining engine ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Zhou et al., 2010)</ref>. It separates opinion identification and polarity classification into two stages.</p><p>Given a set of documents that are relevant to the company, we first split the documents into sentences, and then identify whether the sentence is opinionated or not. We extract the features shown in <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Punctuation level features</head><p>The presence of direct quote punctuation """ and """ The presence of other punctuations: "?" and "!" These features are then combined using a ra- dial basis function (RBF) kernel and a support vector machine (SVM) classifier ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Drucker et al., 1997</ref>) is trained based on the NTCIR 8training data for opinion identification <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Kando, 2010)</ref>.</p><p>For those opinionated sentences, we then clas- sify them into positive, negative, or neutral. In addition to the features shown in <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>, we incorporate features of s-VSM (Sentiment Vector Space Model) ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Xia et al., 2008</ref>) to enhance the performance. The principles of the s-VSM are listed as follows: (1) Only sentiment-related words are used to produce sentiment features for the s-VSM. <ref type="formula">(2)</ref> The sentiment words are appro- priately disambiguated with the neighboring ne- gations and modifiers. (3) Negations and modifi- ers are included in the s-VSM to reflect the func- tions of inversing, strengthening and weakening. Sentiment unit is the appropriate element com- plying with the above principles. ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Zhou et al., 2010)</ref> In addition to polarity classification, opinion holder and target are also recognized in OM function for further identifying the relationship that two companies have, e.g. collaborative or competitive. Both of the dependency parser and the semantic role labeling 1 (SRL) tool are in- corporated to identify the semantic roles of each chunk based on verbs in the sentence.</p><p>The OM function provides the company with services of analyzing the social sentimental feedback on the dynamics of the company. It meets the aforementioned demand, "to identify and analyze customers' opinions towards the company".</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2.3">Social Network Analysis</head><p>SNA function aims at producing the commercial network of companies that are hidden within the articles.</p><p>To achieve this goal, we maintain two lexicons, the commercial named entity lexicon and com- mercial relation lexicon. Commercial named en- tity are firstly located within the text and then recorded in the commercial entity lexicon in the pre-processor NER. Commercial relation lexicon record the articles/documents that involve the commercial relations. Note that the commercial relation lexicon <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">(Table 2)</ref> is manually compiled. In this work, we consider only two general commercial relations, namely cooperation and competition. SNA function produces the social network of a centric company, which can provide the compa-ny with the impact analysis and decision-making chain tracking. It meets the aforementioned de- mand, "to explore the collaborative and competi- tive relationship between companies".</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Practical Example</head><p>In this section, we use a case study to illustrate our system and further evaluate the performance of the main functions with respect to those com- panies. Due to the limited space, we just illus- trate the main functions of topic detection, opin- ion mining and social network analysis. Multi-document summary of the latest news is provided for the company and more news with the similar topics can be found by pressing the button "更多" (more). Since there are a lot of duplicates of a piece of news on the websites, the summary is a direct way to acquire the recent news, which can improve the effectiveness of the company.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Topic Detection and Opinion Mining</head><p>The results of opinion mining function are shown at the bottom of <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Figure 2(a)</ref>, where the green line indicates negative while the red line indicates positive. In order to give a dynamic insight of public opinions, we provide the amount changes of positive and negative articles with time variant. This is very helpful for the company to capture the feedback of their mar- keting policies. As shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Figure 2</ref>(a), there were 14 negative articles (負面信息) on Oct. 29, 2012, which achieved negative peak within the 6 months. The users would probably read those 14 articles and adjust the company strategy accord- ingly. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Figure 2(b)</ref> shows the social network based on the centric company in yellow, Sun Hung Kai Properties (新鴻基地產). We only list the half of the connected companies with collaborative relationship from Sun Hung Kai Properties, and remove the competitive ones due to limited space. The thickness of the line indicates the strength of the collaboration between the two companies. The social network can explore the potential partners/competitors of a company. Furthermore, users are allowed to adjust the depth and set the nodes count of the network. The above analysis can provide a richer insight in to a company.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Social Network Analysis</head><p>In the following section, we will make exper- iments to investigate the performance of the above functions. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Experiment and Result</head><p>In our evaluation, the experiments were made based on 17692 articles collected from 52 Hong Kong websites during 6 months (1/7/2012~ 31/12/2012). We investigate the performance of MODEST based on the standard metrics pro- posed by NIST 1 , including precision, recall, and F-score. Precision (P) is the fraction of detected articles (U) that are relevantto the topic (N).</p><p>Recall (R) is the fraction of the articles (T) that are relevant to the topic that are successfully de- tected (N).</p><p>Usually, there is an inverse relationship be- tween precision and recall, where it is possible to increase one at the cost of reducing the other. Therefore, precision and recall scores are not discussed in isolation. Instead, F-Score (F) is proposed to combine precision and recall, which is the harmonic meanof precision and recall.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">Topic Detection and Tracking</head><p>We first assess the performance of the topic de- tection function. The data is divided into 6 parts according to the time. For different companies, the amount of articles vary a lot. Therefore, we calculate the metrics for each individual dataset, and then compute the weighted mean value. The experimental results are shown in <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">Table 3</ref>. From the experimental results, we can find that the average F-Score is about 85.69%.The dataset in the second row achieves the best per- formance while the dataset in the third only get 76.56% in F-Score. It is because that the amount of articles is smaller than the others and the re- call value is very low. As far as we know, the best run of topic detection in ( <ref type="bibr">Allan et al., 2007</ref>) achieved 84%. The performance of topic detec- tion in MODEST is comparable.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">Opinion Mining</head><p>We then evaluate the performance of opinion mining function. We manually annotated 1568 articles, which is further divided into 8 datasets randomly. Precision, recall, and F-score are also used as the metrics for the evaluation. The ex- perimental results are shown in <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">Table 4</ref>.</p><p>From <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">Table 4</ref>, we can find that the average F-Score can reach 74.09%. Note that the opinion mining engine of MODEST is the implementa- tion of ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Zhou et al., 2010)</ref>, which achieved the best run in NTCIR. However, the engine is trained on NTCIR corpus, which consists of arti- cles of general domain, while the test set focuses on the financial domain. We further train our engine on the data from the financial domain and the average F-Score improves to over 80%.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Conclusions</head><p>This demonstration presents an intelligent infor- mation platform designed to mine Web infor- mation and provide decisions for modern service, MODEST. MODEST can provide the services of retrieving news from websites, extracting com- mercial information, exploring customers' opin- ions about a given company, and analyzing its collaborative/competitive social networks. Both enterprises and government are the target cus- tomers. For enterprise, MODEST can improve the competitive abilities and facilitate potential collaboration. For government, MODEST can collect information about the entire industry, and make prompt strategies for better support.</p><p>In this paper, we first introduce the system ar- chitecture design and the main functions imple- mentation, including topic detection and tracking, opinion mining, and social network analysis. Then a case study is given to illustrate the func- tions of MODEST. In order to evaluate the per- formance of MODEST, we also conduct the ex- periments based on the data from 52 Hong Kong websites, and the results show the effectiveness of the above functions.</p><p>In the future, MODEST will be improved in two directions:  Extend to other languages, e.g. English, Simplified Chinese, etc.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head></head><p>Enhance the compatibility to implement on mobile device.</p><p>The demo of MODEST and the related toolkits can be found on the homepage: http://sepc111.se.cuhk.edu.hk:8080/adcom_hk/ </p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>The</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: System architecture. (The module in blue is data acquisition, the module in orange is data analysis, and the module in light green is result display)</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Miner：makes use of data mining techniques to realize four functions, topic detection and tracking (TDT), multi-document summari- zation 3 (MDS), social network analysis (SNA), and opinion mining (OM). The re- sults of data analysis are also stored in the database. (3) The result display module read out the analy- sis results from the database and display them to users in the form of plain text, charts, figures, as well as video.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>Word-Level and entity-level features</head><label></label><figDesc>The presence of known opinion operators The percentage of known opinion word in sentence Presence of a named entity Presence of pronoun Presence of known opinion indicators Presence of known degree adverbs Presence of known conjunctions Bi-gram features Named entities + opinion operators Pronouns + opinion operators Nouns or named entities + opinion words Pronouns + opinion words Opinion words (adjective) + opinion words(noun) Degree adverbs + opinion words Degree adverbs + opinion operators</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head>Figure 2 (</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2(a) showed the results of topic detection and opinion mining functions for a Hong Kong local financial company Sun Hung Kai Properties (新鴻基地產). On top of the figure are the results of topic detection and tracking function. Multi-document summary of the latest news is provided for the company and more news with the similar topics can be found by pressing the button "更多" (more). Since there are a lot of duplicates of a piece of news on the websites, the summary is a direct way to acquire the recent news, which can improve the effectiveness of the company. The results of opinion mining function are shown at the bottom of Figure 2(a), where the green line indicates negative while the red line</figDesc><graphic url="image-4.png" coords="4,83.75,467.46,429.30,239.39" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><head>(Figure 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2: Screenshot of the MODEST system.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" validated="true"><head>Table 2 : Statistics on relation lexicon.</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Type 
Amount 
Examples 
Competition 
20 
挑战(challenge), 竞争 
(compete), 
对手 
(opponent) 
Collaboration 
18 
协作(collaborate),协同 
(coordinate), 合作 
(cooperate) 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3" validated="true"><head>Table 3 : Experimental results on topic detection.</head><label>3</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Dataset 
Recall Precision F-Score 
1/7/12-31/7/12 
85.71% 
89.52% 
85.38% 
1/8/12-31/8/12 
93.10% 
93.68% 
92.49% 
1/9/12-30/9/12 
76.50% 
83.13% 
76.56% 
1/10/12-31/10/12 83.32% 
88.53% 
85.84% 
1/11/12-30/11/12 86.11% 
89.94% 
87.98% 
1/12/12-31/12/12 84.26% 
87.65% 
85.92% 
Average 
85.13% 
88.78% 
85.69% 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4" validated="true"><head>Table 4 : Experimental results on opinion mining.</head><label>4</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Dataset 
Size Precision Recall F-Score 
dataset-1 
200 
76.57% 
78.26% 76.57% 
dataset-2 
200 
83.55% 
89.64% 86.07% 
dataset-3 
200 
69.12% 
69.80% 69.44% 
dataset-4 
200 
77.13% 
75.40% 75.67% 
dataset-5 
200 
76.21% 
77.65% 76.74% 
dataset-6 
200 
63.76% 
66.22% 64.49% 
dataset-7 
200 
78.56% 
78.41% 78.43% 
dataset-8 
168 
65.72% 
65.15% 65.32% 
Average 
196 
73.83% 
75.07% 74.09% </table></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> This work is supported by the Innovation and Technology Fund of Hong Kong SAR.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> http://ir.hit.edu.cn/demo/ltp</note>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> http://trec.nist.gov/</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgements</head><p>This research is partially supported by General Re-search Fund of Hong Kong (417112), Shenzhen Fun-damental Research Program (JCYJ201304011720464 50, JCYJ20120613152557576), KTO(TBF1ENG007), National Natural Science Foundation of China (61203378, 61370165), and Shenzhen International Cooperation Funding (GJHZ20120613110641217).</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Topic Detection and Tracking Pilot Study: Final Report</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">James</forename><surname>Allan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jaime</forename><surname>Carbonell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">George</forename><surname>Doddington</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jonathan</forename><surname>Yamron</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yiming</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the DARPA Broadcast News Transcription and Understanding Workshop</title>
		<meeting>the DARPA Broadcast News Transcription and Understanding Workshop</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Support Vector Regression Machines</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Harris</forename><surname>Drucker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chris</forename><forename type="middle">J C</forename><surname>Burges</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Linda</forename><surname>Kaufman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alex</forename><surname>Smola</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Vladimir</forename><surname>Vpnik</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of Advances in Neural Information Processing Systems</title>
		<meeting>Advances in Neural Information Processing Systems</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="155" to="161" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Noriko</forename><surname>Kando</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Overview of the Eighth NTCIR Workshop. Proceedings of NTCIR-8 Workshop</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Sentiment Analysis and Opinion Mining</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bing</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of Synthesis Lectures on Human Language Technologies</title>
		<meeting>Synthesis Lectures on Human Language Technologies</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="167" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Using Topic Discovery to Segment Large Communication Graphs for Social Network Analysis. Proceedings of the IEEE</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Maximilian</forename><surname>Viermetz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michal</forename><surname>Skubacz</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ACM International Conference on Web Intelligence</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="95" to="99" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Automatic Online News Topic Ranking Using Media Focus and User Attention based on Aging Theory</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Canhui</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Min</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Liyun</forename><surname>Ru</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Shaoping</forename><surname>Ma</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Conference on Information and Knowledge Management</title>
		<meeting>the Conference on Information and Knowledge Management</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Mining Commercial Networks from Online Financial News</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yunqing</forename><surname>Xia</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nianxing</forename><surname>Ji</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Weifeng</forename><surname>Su</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yi</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the IEEE International Conference on E-Business Engineering</title>
		<meeting>the IEEE International Conference on E-Business Engineering</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="17" to="23" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Coarse-Fine Opinion Mining-WIA in NTCIR-7 MOAT Task</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ruifeng</forename><surname>Xu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kam-Fai</forename><surname>Wong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yunqing</forename><surname>Xia</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">NTCIR-7 Workshop</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="307" to="313" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jung-Hwan</forename><surname>Seok-Ho Yoon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sang-Wook</forename><surname>Shin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sunju</forename><surname>Kim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Park</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Extraction of a Latent Blog Community based on Subject. Proceeding of the 18 th ACM Conference on Information and Knowledge Management</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1529" to="1532" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">WIA-Opinmine System in NTCIR-8 MOAT Evaluation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lanjun</forename><surname>Zhou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yunqing</forename><surname>Xia</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Binyang</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kam-Fai</forename><surname>Wong</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of NTCIR-8 Workshop Meeting</title>
		<meeting>NTCIR-8 Workshop Meeting</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="286" to="292" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
