<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T13:02+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Determiner-Established Deixis to Communicative Artifacts in Pedagogical Text</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date>June 23-25</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Shomir</forename><surname>Wilson</surname></persName>
							<email>shomir@cs.cmu.edu, jon@inf.ed.ac.uk</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">School of Informatics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Edinburgh</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="GB">United Kingdom</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">School of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Carnegie Mellon University</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jon</forename><surname>Oberlander</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">School of Informatics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Edinburgh</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="GB">United Kingdom</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Determiner-Established Deixis to Communicative Artifacts in Pedagogical Text</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 52nd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (Short Papers)</title>
						<meeting>the 52nd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (Short Papers) <address><addrLine>Baltimore, Maryland, USA</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="409" to="414"/>
							<date type="published">June 23-25</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Pedagogical materials frequently contain deixis to communicative artifacts such as textual structures (e.g., sections and lists), discourse entities, and illustrations. By relating such artifacts to the prose, deixis plays an essential role in structuring the flow of information in informative writing. However, existing language technologies have largely overlooked this mechanism. We examine properties of deixis to communicative artifacts using a corpus rich in determiner-established instances of the phenomenon (e.g., &quot;this section&quot;, &quot;these equations&quot;, &quot;those reasons&quot;) from Wikibooks, a collection of learning texts. We use this corpus in combination with WordNet to determine a set of word senses that are characteristic of the phenomenon, showing its diversity and validating intuitions about its qualities. The results motivate further research to extract the connections encoded by such deixis, with the goals of enhancing tools to present pedagogical e-texts to readers and, more broadly, improving language technologies that rely on deictic phenomena.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Deixis often appears in written language as an anaphoric mechanism to refer to communicative entities in a document. Such deixis can have a variety of referent types. For example, consider that idea in Sentence (1), those names in <ref type="bibr">(2)</ref>, this section in (3), and these figures in (4):</p><p>(1) That idea has been challenged by many. The kinds of deixis represented in (1) and (2) are similar to discourse deixis <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">(Webber, 1991)</ref> and textual deixis <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(Lyons, 1977)</ref>, respectively. Sentence (3) contains deixis to a structural element of a document <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Paraboni and Deemter, 2006</ref>), and (4) contains an example of deixis to illustrative items such as figures or examples. We collectively term such deictic acts as communicative deixis (CD for brevity), recognizing their shared characteristics, and we name their referents communicative artifacts (CAs). Prior studies have focused on narrow varieties of CD (such as those identified above), leaving unknown their properties when viewed together as a whole. Moreover, efforts to automatically identify or resolve CD have been piecemeal at best. Given the complexity of the referents, conventional tools for coreference or anaphora resolution are poorly applicable.</p><p>This paper describes analysis of the first collection of instances of deixis in English targeted to refer to a broad variety of CAs. Texts from the website Wikibooks are used, for the intuitive density of CD in pedagogical material and the potential value of augmenting them with interpretive metadata. The diversity of referents in this corpus enables new inferences on the composition and relative frequencies of CD varieties in text. We focus on determiner- established instances, i.e., anaphoric noun phrases that begin with determiners this, that, these, or those (e.g., (1)- <ref type="formula">(4)</ref>). This focus has the advantage of collecting instances that explicitly identify the relevant capacities of their referents (e.g., (1) reifies its referent as an "idea").</p><p>The remainder of this paper is structured as follows. Section 2 surveys related work on deixis to specific types of CAs. Section 3 describes the text source for this study and the procedure used to collect and label instances. Section 4 describes our use of WordNet to characterize CAs, resulting in an ontology of such referents and inter-annotator agreement results for labeling of artifact types. Finally, Section 5 provides some conclusions and directions for future work.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Related Work</head><p>The value of CD in pedagogical contexts has been established by studies such as those by <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Mayer (2009)</ref> and <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Buisine and Martin (2007)</ref>. Those motivate our work to fill the present lack of corpus-based linguistic knowledge of the phenomenon. Also, although spatial deixis falls beyond the scope of this paper, we acknowledge the efforts of others such as <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Gergle et al. (2013)</ref> to study its value in collaborative communication.</p><p>Prior works have examined discourse deixis in text, though little attention has been given to CD as a phenomenon or deixis to other CAs. Seminal papers by <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Webber (1988</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b18">Webber ( , 1991</ref> established the importance of discourse deixis, although they focused upon demonstrative pronouns such as "this" or "that". Many efforts have addressed discourse deixis in the context of anaphora; these include <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Poesio and Artstein's (2008)</ref>, who created a corpus of anaphoric relations inclusive of (but not limited to) discourse. Their collection included 455 instances of discourse deixis, although they noted ambiguity in the set of markables. <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Dipper and Zinsmeister (2012)</ref> also addressed discourse deixis through anaphora resolution and produced a collection of 225 abstract anaphors out of 643 candidate instances.</p><p>Prior studies of shell nouns revealed capacities of referents similar to a subset of those found in our work. Such nouns are used anaphorically to refer to complex, proposition-like pieces of information such as points, assumptions, or acts <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(Schmid, 2000</ref>). <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Kolhatkar et al. (2013)</ref> noted the pervasiveness of shell nouns in text and their tendency to "characterize and label" their antecedents. However, such antecedents only partly intersect with CAs. The set of shell nouns studied by Schmid did not include typical document entities such as section, <ref type="figure">figure,</ref> or list. Simultaneously, the set included many nouns with little or no relevance as CAs, such as fury, miracle, and pride.</p><p>The task of identifying CD in text and referent CAs bears some similarity to coreference resolution. However, coreference resolvers tried by the authors (namely CoreNLP ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Recasens et al., 2013)</ref>, ArkRef (O' <ref type="bibr">Connor and Heilman, 2013)</ref> and the work of <ref type="bibr">Roth and Bengston (2008)</ref>) were ineffective at this task. We posit that many CAs are not noun phrases, which makes them difficult or inappropriate to characterize as referring expressions. This limits the effectiveness of traditional approaches to coreference resolution toward the present problem.</p><p>Our results are further distinct from prior work by focusing on the communicative capacities of a variety of referents represented in documents. However, the present focus upon determiner- established phrases is more exclusive, and our results do not include demarcation of referents. We posit that the tradeoff is worthwhile, given limited prior work on identifying CD and the lack of prior efforts to study CAs other than discourse entities.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Corpus Creation</head><p>Textbooks from Wikibooks were chosen to supply pedagogical text. Among the alternatives, this source provided the largest volume of material with a license amenable to corpus redistribution. Moreover, the collection of English language textbooks on the site covers a diverse set of topics and contains samples from a variety of writers. Below we describe our text pre-processing and then explain how candidate instances of CD were identified.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Source Material</head><p>To simplify collection and processing, 122 Wikibooks textbooks with printable versions were selected for use. Contained in this set are textbooks in eleven different subject areas, such as computing, humanities, and the sciences. In preparation for analysis, the documents were POS tagged and parsed by the Stanford CoreNLP suite <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">(Socher et al., 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Toutanova et al., 2003)</ref>. <ref type="table">Table 1</ref> presents some statistics on the texts in aggregate. They illustrate the substantial size of most texts, though a few were freshly started or incomplete. Overall, the corpus is comparable in size with corpora from efforts cited in Section 2, though text genera and sought markables vary.</p><p>Next, potential instances of CD were identified. Such instances were noun phrases beginning with determiners this, that, these, or those. We include these and those to collect CD to sets of entities, a nuance absent from any previous work. 9252 sentences, or 8% of the corpus, contained at least one potential instance.  This collection contained substantial boilerplate text, and sentences that appeared verbatim in at least ten different books were discarded. This filtering produced a set of 7613 candidate instances. <ref type="table">Table 2</ref> shows the most frequent head nouns in candidate instances. Some resemble the shell nouns of prior work, but the presence of others illustrates the diversity of CD. Diversity was expected from pedagogical texts and validates Wikibooks as a rich source of CD. We conducted a preliminary survey of the corpus contents by reading a random selection of 10% of candidates and judging their statuses as instances of CA. <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Table 3</ref> shows examples of candidate instances, categorized by the foci of prior studies (cited in the Introduction) of CD phenomena. The researchers estimated that 48% of candidates were instances of CD, although directly labeling large numbers of candidates was deemed impractical. Instead, we noted that the word sense of the noun in a candidate instance is an important (albeit not definitive) indication of its CD status. Accordingly, we shift our focus from individual candidate instances to words that appear in them (i.e., lemmas) and word senses.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Word Senses</head><p>The noun in an instance of CD has a doubly salient role in CA, by providing a cue to the intended referent and also by reifying the referent. For example, an illustrating referent might be referred to as "this example" or "this ideal", with divergent consequences. The noun choice semantically identifies the relevant capacity of the referent, affecting its message.</p><p>To identify the varieties and characteristics of CD in pedagogical text, we examine in aggregate the senses of those words that appear in candidate phrases in the corpus. WordNet 3.0 <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Fellbaum, 1998</ref>) was chosen to provide an ontological structure for relevant word senses and thus for CAs. First, synsets for the 27 most frequent nouns in candidate phrases were collected, irrespective of viability for CD. This covered 34% of candidate instances and resulted in a set of 200 synsets. Their glosses were labeled as viable or non-viable for CD by two expert annotators, who first worked separately and then collaborated to resolve differences in their annotations.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Lemma</head><p>Freq <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">.  Lemma  Freq.  page  314  function  83  book  287  chapter  73  case  249  information  70  example  126  problem  69  point  121  value  62  section  116  type  59  way  112  process  56  option  102  feature  56  time  101  number  54  message  93  text  54   Table 2</ref>. The 20 most frequent head nouns in candidate instances.</p><p>For each synset gloss, perform the following:</p><p>Imagine instantiating the type represented by the gloss. Judge its suitability for the following statements.</p><p>(1) [an instantiation of the type] is about a topic.</p><p>(2) [an instantiation of the type] is intended to communicate an idea.</p><p>(3) [an instantiation of the type] can be produced in a document or as a document to convey information.</p><p>If at least two of the three statements above are coherent, mark 'y' for the gloss. Otherwise, mark 'n'. <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref>. Instructions given to annotators.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Category Examples</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Structural</head><p>Many of the resources listed elsewhere in this section have… In this chapter, we will show you how to draw… Illustrative Consider these sentences: [followed by example sentences]</p><p>[following a source code fragment] …the first time the computer sees this statement, 'a' is zero, so it is less than 10.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Discourse</head><p>Utilizing this idea, subunit analogies were invented… In this case, you've narrowed the topic down to "Badges."</p><p>Non-CD Devices similar to resistors turn this energy into light, motion… What type of things does a person in that career field know?  <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref> shows the annotation instructions, which were designed to address the combined range of CAs from prior work. To illustrate its application, consider the noun chapter. One gloss of chapter is "a subdivision of a written work; usually numbered and titled". This sense clearly satisfies the third numbered statement in <ref type="figure">Figure  1</ref>. Coherency arguments for the first and second statements are less definitional, but both annotators decided at least one was satisfactory, leading to a y mark. Another gloss of chapter is "any distinct period in history or in a person's life". This sense fails to satisfy the second or third statement, leading to an n mark.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Results and Discussion</head><p>Resolving differences between the annotators' labels produced a set of 62 synsets whose glosses characterized CAs. We refer to the sets of 200 synsets and 62 synsets as the CCS (candidates for communicative senses) and VCS (verified communicative senses) sets, respectively. We offer the complete results of our annotations online 1 to encourage further research on this topic. In this section we present inter-annotator agreement statistics and describe the composition of the VCS set using the structure of WordNet.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">Inter-Annotator Agreement</head><p>The kappa statistic for category agreement between the two annotators was 0.70, with matching annotations on 174 of 200 senses. Although this metric is an imperfect indicator, this value is generally regarded as substantial <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(Viera and Garrett, 2005</ref>) albeit with some tentativeness <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Carletta, 1996)</ref>. The annotators respectively placed 33% and 30% of instances in the VCS set, suggesting general agreement on the distribution of labels irrespective of specific instances. The annotators agreed that some cases were difficult to label without context, and a combination of sense labeling and in-text instance labeling may be fruitful for future work.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">Representation in WordNet</head><p>We use the structure of WordNet to illustrate the properties of CAs that VCS senses represent. To do this, the hypernym closure (i.e., the sequence(s) of hypernyms from a given synset to the root synset) was computed for each VCS sense. These "traces" were aggregated into a 1 http://www.cs.cmu.edu/~shomir/wb_cd_study/ reproduction of a subset of WordNet's synsets and relations, resulting in a de facto ontology of CAs. The same procedure was performed for the CCS set to create an illustrative baseline. <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">Table 4</ref> shows the structure of the most general synsets in the ontologies constructed from VCS and CCS traces. Fractions illustrate the relative constituent weight of each synset, by virtue of the traces that include it. For example, 65 of the 72 traces for VCS synsets pass through abstraction.n.06, and 37 of those 65 traces pass through communication.n.02. The total quantities of traces for CCS and VCS are greater than their respective set sizes because of a small number of synsets in those sets with multiple hyponym paths to the root. The rightmost column of <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">Table  4</ref> shows the decimal result of subtracting the CCS constituent weight fraction from the VCS fraction. Positive numbers indicate that the manual labeling of senses magnified the weight of a synset over the CCS baseline.</p><p>The constituent weights confirm some intuitions but also hold a few surprises. The vast majority of CAs are abstractions rather than physical entities, and most of the abstractions are "something that is communicated by or to or between people or groups" (the gloss of communication.n.02). Psychological features are also a substantial constituency, with traces to VCS synsets that represent words such as method, plan, and question. Most of the few VCS physical entities are communicative artifacts in their complete form (e.g., a book or a periodical issue). Matter as a physical entity may seem out of place in  has the gloss "one side of one leaf (of a book or magazine or newspaper or letter etc.) or the written or pictorial matter it contains." Both annotators believed it merited inclusion in VCS.</p><p>Finally, we observed that many VCS senses (58%) were not the first sense for their words, indicating different senses appear more often 2 . This likely hinders word sense disambiguation of nouns in CD instances: the common baseline of first sense tagging is futile in these cases, and their extra-topical nature means that appropriate CA senses are not implied by the surrounding words <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">(Wilson, 2011)</ref>. This suggests that identification of CD instances may require a dedicated approach to word sense tagging.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Conclusion</head><p>The results of this study illustrate the significance of CD, both for the processing of pedagogical texts and for the broader project of understanding anaphora. Its pervasiveness and its diversity show its potential as a conduit for language technologies to enrich documents with pragmatic metadata. Our next effort will be to identify the referents of CD instances using knowledge from the present study of the character and distribution of those referents. CAs are represented by spans of content in a document (e.g., text or figures), and accordingly the identification of a CD referent will involve the selection of the correct span of content. We expect that the word sense of the noun in a CD phrase will limit the set of potentially relevant CAs, and that both localized features (such as paragraph position of a CD instance and the expected CA count) and document-level features (e.g., proximity of potential referents) will be valuable.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>( 2 )</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Those names are Welsh in origin. (3) In this section, we cover some early work. (4) Quantities in these figures are approximate.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Statistic</head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" validated="false"><head>Table 3 .</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Examples of candidate instances. Bold text denotes the determiner and head noun in each instance. Sentences are truncated in the table for brevity.</figDesc><table></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" validated="false"><head>Table 4 .</head><label>4</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>The VCS synset 
</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3" validated="false"><head>Table 4 .</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Distributions of traces through the first two hyponym relations emanating from the root synset entity.n.01, for CCS and VCS. Fractions indicate the constituent weight of each synset.</figDesc><table></table></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="2"> The WordNet manual advises that senses are &quot;generally&quot; ordered by frequency.</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgment</head><p>This research was supported by grant #1159236 from the US National Science Foundation's International Research Fellowship Program.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Synset</head><p>CCS VCS Chg. 0 entity.n.01 1 abstraction.n.06 2 psych._feature.n.01 2 communication.n.02 2 attribute.n.02 2 group.n.01 2 measure.n.02 2 relation.n.01 1 physical_entity.n.01 2 object.n.01 2 causal_agent.n.01 2 thing.n.12 2 process.n.06 2 matter.n.03</p></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Understanding the value of features for coreference resolution</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Bengtson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Roth</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. EMNLP</title>
		<meeting>EMNLP</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The effects of speech-gesture cooperation in animated agents&apos; behavior in multimedia presentations</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Buisine</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J.-C</forename><surname>Martin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="doi">doi:10.1016/j.intcom.2007.04.002</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Interacting with Computers</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="484" to="493" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Assessing agreement on classification tasks: The kappa statistic</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Carletta</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Computational Linguistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="249" to="254" />
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Annotating abstract anaphora</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Dipper</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Zinsmeister</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="doi">doi:10.1007/s10579-011-9160-1</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. LREC</title>
		<meeting>LREC</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">46</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="37" to="52" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">WordNet: An Electronic Lexical Database</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Fellbaum</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
			<publisher>MIT Press</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Cambridge</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Using visual information for grounding and awareness in collaborative tasks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Gergle</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Kraut</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Fussell</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Human-Computer Interaction</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">28</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="39" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Interpreting anaphoric shell nouns using antecedents of cataphoric shell nouns as training data</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Kolhatkar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Zinsmeister</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Hirst</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. EMNLP</title>
		<meeting>EMNLP</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="300" to="310" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Semantics</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Lyons</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1977" />
			<publisher>Cambridge University Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Mayer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Multimedia Learning</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Cambridge University Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">ARKref: A rule-based coreference resolution system</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>O&amp;apos;connor</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Heilman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:1310.1975</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Referring via document parts</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Paraboni</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Deemter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="doi">10.1007/11671299_31</idno>
		<ptr target="http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/11671299_31" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Computational Linguistics and Intelligent Text Processing</title>
		<editor>A. Gelbukh</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Berlin Heidelberg</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">3878</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="299" to="310" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Anaphoric annotation in the ARRAU Corpus</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Poesio</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Artstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. LREC. Marrakech, Morocco: European Language Resources Association (ELRA)</title>
		<meeting>LREC. Marrakech, Morocco: European Language Resources Association (ELRA)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The life and death of discourse entities: Identifying singleton mentions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Recasens</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Catherine De Marneffe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Potts</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. NAACL</title>
		<meeting>NAACL</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">English Abstract Nouns as Conceptual Shells: From Corpus to Cognition</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H.-J</forename><surname>Schmid</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
			<publisher>Walter de Gruyter</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Parsing with compositional vector grammars</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Socher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Bauer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Manning</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">Y</forename><surname>Ng</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. ACL</title>
		<meeting>ACL</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="455" to="465" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Feature-rich part-of-speech tagging with a cyclic dependency network</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Toutanova</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Klein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Manning</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Singer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="doi">doi:10.3115/1073445.1073478</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. NAACL</title>
		<meeting>NAACL</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Understanding interobserver agreement: The kappa statistic</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Viera</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Garrett</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Family Medicine</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">37</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="360" to="363" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Discourse deixis: Reference to discourse segments</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Webber</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="doi">doi:10.3115/982023.982037</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. ACL</title>
		<meeting>ACL</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1988" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="113" to="122" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Structure and ostension in the interpretation of discourse deixis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Webber</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Natural Language and Cognitive Processes</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1991" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">A Computational Theory of the Use-Mention Distinction in Natural Language. University of Maryland at College Park</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Wilson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<pubPlace>College Park, MD, USA</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
<note type="report_type">PhD Thesis</note>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
