<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T11:08+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Enhanced Search with Wildcards and Morphological Inflections in the Google Books Ngram Viewer</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
				<availability status="unknown"><p>Copyright Association for Computational Linguistics</p>
				</availability>
				<date>June 23-24. 2014. 2014</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jason</forename><surname>Mann</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Columbia University ♦ USC ♥ Cornell University ♠ Google Inc. Contact</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">♣</forename></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Columbia University ♦ USC ♥ Cornell University ♠ Google Inc. Contact</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Columbia University ♦ USC ♥ Cornell University ♠ Google Inc. Contact</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lu</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Columbia University ♦ USC ♥ Cornell University ♠ Google Inc. Contact</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dipanjan</forename><surname>Das</surname></persName>
							<email>dipanjand@google.com, slav@google.com</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Columbia University ♦ USC ♥ Cornell University ♠ Google Inc. Contact</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Slav</forename><surname>Petrov</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Columbia University ♦ USC ♥ Cornell University ♠ Google Inc. Contact</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Enhanced Search with Wildcards and Morphological Inflections in the Google Books Ngram Viewer</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of 52nd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics: System Demonstrations</title>
						<meeting>52nd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics: System Demonstrations <address><addrLine>Baltimore, Maryland USA</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="115" to="120"/>
							<date type="published">June 23-24. 2014. 2014</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>We present a new version of the Google Books Ngram Viewer, which plots the frequency of words and phrases over the last five centuries; its data encompasses 6% of the world&apos;s published books. The new Viewer adds three features for more powerful search: wildcards, morphological inflections , and capitalization. These additions allow the discovery of patterns that were previously difficult to find and further facilitate the study of linguistic trends in printed text.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>The Google Books Ngram project facilitates the analysis of cultural, social and linguistic trends through five centuries of written text in eight languages. The Ngram Corpus <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Michel et al., 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Lin et al., 2012)</ref> consists of words and phrases (i.e., ngrams) and their usage frequency over time. <ref type="bibr">1</ref> The interactive Ngram Viewer 2 allows users to retrieve and plot the frequency of mul- tiple ngrams on a simple webpage. The Viewer is widely popular and can be used to efficiently explore and visualize patterns in the underlying ngram data. For example, the ngram data has been used to detect emotion trends in 20th cen- tury books ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Acerbi et al., 2013)</ref>, to analyze text focusing on market capitalism throughout the past century ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Schulz and Robinson, 2013)</ref>, detect so- cial and cultural impact of historical personalities <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(Skiena and Ward, 2013)</ref>, or to analyze the corre- lation of economic crises with a literary 'misery * The majority of this work was carried out during an internship at Google. <ref type="bibr">1</ref> The Ngram Corpus is freely available for download at http://books.google.com/ngrams/datasets. <ref type="bibr">2</ref> See http://books.google.com/ngrams.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1930">1965 2000 Relative Frequency</head><p>Query: "President Kennedy, President Reagan, President Nixon" "President Kennedy" "President Reagan" "President Nixon" index' reflected in printed text during crises peri- ods ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Bentley et al., 2014)</ref>.</p><p>A limitation of the Viewer, however, is that all the reasoning has to be done by the user, and only individual, user-specified ngrams can be re- trieved and plotted. For example, to compare the popularity of different presidents, one needs to come up with a list of presidents and then search for them one-by-one. The result of the query 'President Kennedy, President Nixon, President Reagan' is shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref>. To determine the most popular president, one would need to search for all presidents, which is cumbersome and should ideally be automated.</p><p>In this paper, we therefore present an updated version of the Viewer that enhances its search functionality. We introduce three new features that automatically expand a given query and re- trieve a collection of ngrams, to facilitate the dis- covery of patterns in the underlying data. First, users can replace one query term with a place- holder symbol ' * ' (wildcard, henceforth), which will return the ten most frequent expansions of the wildcard in the corpus for the specified year range. Second, by adding a specific marker to any word in a query <ref type="bibr">(' INF')</ref>, ngrams with all morphological inflections of that word will be re- trieved. Finally, the new Viewer supports capi- talization searches, which return all capitalization variants of the query ngram. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 2</ref> provides ex- amples for these three new types of queries.</p><p>While it is fairly obvious how the above search features can be implemented via brute-force com- putation, supporting an interactive application with low latency necessitates some precomputa- tion. In particular, the wildcard search feature poses some challenges because the most frequent expansions depend on the selected year range (consider the frequency with which presidents are mentioned during different decades, for example). To this end, we provide details of our system ar- chitecture in §2 and discuss how the new search features are implemented in §3. In addition, we present an overhaul of the Ngram Viewer's user interface with interactive features that allow for easier management of the increase in data points returned.</p><p>Detailed analysis and interpretation of trends uncovered with the new search interface is beyond the scope of this paper. We highlight some in- teresting use cases in §4; many of the presented queries were difficult (or impossible) to execute in the previous versions of the system. We emphasize that this demonstration updates only the Viewer, providing tools for easier analysis of the underly- ing corpora. The ngram corpora themselves are not updated.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">System Overview</head><p>We first briefly review the two editions of the Ngram Corpus ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Michel et al., 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Lin et al., 2012)</ref> and then describe the extensions to the ar- chitecture of the Viewer that are needed to support the new search features.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">The Ngram Corpus</head><p>The Google Books Ngram Corpus provides ngram counts for eight different languages over more than 500 years; additionally, the English corpus is split further into British vs. American English and Fiction to aid domain-specific analysis. This corpus is a subset of all books digitized at Google and represents more than 6% of all publicized texts ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Lin et al., 2012</ref>  Michel et al. (2011) extract ngrams for each page in isolation. More specifically, they use whitespace tokenization and extract all ngrams up to length five. These ngrams include ones that po- tentially span sentence boundaries, but do not in- clude ngrams that span across page breaks (even when they are part of the same sentence). <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Lin et al. (2012)</ref> on the other hand perform tokeniza- tion, text normalization and segmentation into sen- tences. They then add synthetic START and END tokens to the beginning and end of the sen-tences to enable the distinction of sentence me- dial ngrams from those near sentence boundaries. They also ensure that sentences that span across page boundaries are included. Due to these dif- ferences, as well as the availability of additional book data, improvements to the optical character recognition algorithms and metadata extraction for dating the books, the ngrams counts from the two editions are not the same.</p><p>The edition from Lin et al. <ref type="formula">(2012)</ref> additionally includes syntactic ngrams. The corpus is tagged using the universal part-of-speech (POS) tag set of : NOUN (nouns), VERB (verbs), ADJ (adjectives), ADV (adverbs), PRON (pronouns), DET (determiners and articles), ADP (prepositions and postpositions), CONJ (conjunc- tions). Words can be disambiguated by their POS tag by simply appending the tag to the word with an underscore (e.g. book NOUN) and can also be replaced by POS tags in the ngrams, see <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Lin et al. (2012)</ref> for details. The corpus is parsed with a dependency parser and head-modifier syntactic relations between words in the same sentence are extracted. Dependency relations are represented as '=&gt;' in the corpus. Our new enhanced search features for automatic expansions can also be ap- plied to these syntactic ngrams. In fact, some of the most interesting queries use expansions to au- tomatically uncover related ngrams, while using syntax to focus on particular patterns.</p><p>The Viewer supports the composition of ngram frequencies via arithmetic operators. Addition (+), subtraction (-) and division (/) of ngrams are car- ried out on a per year basis, while multiplication ( * ) is performed by a scalar that is applied to all counts in the time series. Where ambiguous, the wildcard operator takes precedence over the mul- tiplication operator. Parentheses can be used to disambiguate and to force the interpretation of a mathematical operation.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">Architecture</head><p>The Ngram Viewer provides a lightweight inter- face to the underlying ngram corpora. In its basic form, user requests are directed through the server to a simple lookup table containing the raw ngrams and their frequencies. This data flow is displayed in the top part of <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 3</ref> and is maintained for queries that do not involve the new expansion fea- tures introduced in this work.</p><p>The expansion queries could in principle be</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Raw Ngrams</head><p>'King James' : {(1900, 234), <ref type="bibr">(1901,</ref><ref type="bibr">122)</ref>  implemented by scanning the raw ngrams on the fly and returning the matching subset: to answer the query 'President * ', one would need to obtain all bigrams starting with the word President (there are 23,693) and extract the most frequent ten. Given the large number of ngrams (especially for larger n), such an approach turns out to be too slow for an interactive appli- cation. We therefore pre-compute intermediate re- sults that can be used to more efficiently retrieve the results for expansion queries. The intermedi- ate results are stored in additional lookup tables (shown at the bottom in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 3</ref>). When the user executes an expansion search, the query is first routed to the appropriate lookup table which stores all possible expansions (including expansions that might not appear in the corpus). These expanded ngrams are then retrieved from the raw ngram ta- ble, sorted by frequency and returned to he user. We describe the intermediate results tables and how they are generated in the next section. Note that we only support one expansion oper- ation per query ngram. This is needed in order to avoid the combinatorial explosion that would re- sult from mixing multiple expansion operators in the same query.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">New Features</head><p>The three new search features are implemented via the same two-step approach. As shown in <ref type="figure">Fig- ure</ref>  </p><note type="other">Query: "President *" President of President 's President and President to President Roosevelt 1800 1900 2000 Relative Frequency Query: "President *_NOUN, 1800-2000" President Roosevelt_NOUN President Wilson_NOUN President Lincoln_NOUN President Johnson_NOUN President Truman_NOUN 1950 1975 2000 Relative Frequency Query: "President *_NOUN, 1950-2000"</note></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>President Roosevelt_NOUN President Truman_NOUN President Kennedy_NOUN President Johnson_NOUN President Eisenhower_NOUN</head><p>Figure 4: Different wildcard queries for bigrams starting with President. Specification of a POS tag along with the wildcard operator results in more specific results, and the results vary depending on the selected yaer range.</p><p>ing the new search types. In all cases the lookup tables provide a set of possible expansions that are then retrieved in the original raw ngram table. Be- low we describe how these intermediate results are generated and how they are used to retrieve the fi- nal results.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Wildcards</head><p>Wildcards provide a convenient way to automat- ically retrieve and explore related ngrams. Be- cause of the large number of possibilities that can fill a wildcard slot, returning anything but the top few expansions is likely to be overwhelming. We therefore return only the ten most frequent expan- sions. Determining the most frequent expansions is unfortunately computationally very expensive because of the large number of ngrams; the query 'the * ' for example has 2,353,960 expansions.</p><p>To avoid expensive on-the-fly computations, we precompute the most frequent expansions for all possible queries. The problem that arises is that the ten most frequent expansions depend on the selected year range. Consider the query 'President * '; we would like to be able get the correct result for any year range. Since our data spans more than 500 years, precomputing the results for all year ranges is not a possibility. In- stead, we compute the possible wildcard expan- sions for each year. The top expansions for the entire range are then taken from the union of top expansions for each year. This set is at most of size 10n (where n is the year range) and in practice typically a lot smaller. Theoretically it is possible for this approximation to miss an expansion that is never among the top ten for a particular year, but is cumulatively in the top ten for the entire range. This would happen if there were many spikes in the data, which is not the case.</p><p>To make the wildcard expansions more rele- vant, we filter expansions that consist entirely of punctuation symbols. To further narrow down the expansions and focus on particular patterns, we allow wildcards to be qualified via POS tags. <ref type="figure">Figure 4</ref> shows some example wildcard queries involving bigrams that start with the word 'President.' See also <ref type="table">Table 1</ref> for some addi- tional examples. Note that it is possible to replace POS tags with wildcards (e.g., cook * ) which will find all POS tags that the query word can take.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Morphological Inflections</head><p>When comparing ngram frequencies (especially across languages, but also for the same language), it can be useful to examine and potentially aggre- gate the frequencies of all inflected forms. This can be accomplished by manually deriving all in- flected forms and then using arithmetic operations to aggregate their counts. Our new inflected form search accomplishes this automatically. By ap- pending the keyword INF to a word, a set of ngrams with all inflected forms of the word will be retrieved. To generate the inflected forms we make use of Wiktionary 3 and supplement it with automatically generated inflection tables based on the approach of <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Durrett and DeNero (2013)</ref>.</p><p>Because there are at most a few dozen inflected forms for any given word, we can afford to sub- stitute and retrieve all inflections of the marked word, even the ones that are not grammatical in a given ngram context. This has the advantage that we only need to store inflected forms for individ- ual words rather than entire ngrams. If a generated ngram has no support in the corpus, we simply omit it from the final set of results. We do not per- form any additional filtering; as a result, an inflec- tion search can produce many results, especially for morphologically rich languages like Russian. We have therefore updated the user interface to better deal with many data lines ( §4).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Query</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Possible Replacements</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>* 's Theorem Lagrange 's Theorem, Gauss 's Theorem, Euler 's Theorem, Pascal 's Theorem</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>War=&gt; * NOUN War=&gt;World NOUN, War=&gt;Civil NOUN, War=&gt;Second NOUN, War=&gt;Cold NOUN lubovv INF</head><p>lubil, lublu, lubit, lubitt, lubila, lubimy˘ i, lubixx book INF book, books, booked, booking book INF NOUN book, books cook * cook NOUN, cook VERB the cook (case insensitive) THE COOK, the cook, The Cook, the Cook, The cook <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>: Examples expansions for wildcard, inflection, and capitalization queries.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3">Capitalization</head><p>By aggregating different capitalizations of the same word, one can normalize between sentence- initial and sentence-medial occurrences of a given word. A simple way to accomplish this is by searching for a lowercased, capitalized and all caps spelling of the query. This however can miss CamelCase spelling and other capitalization vari- ants (consider FitzGerald for example). It is of course not feasible to try all case variants of ev- ery letter in the query. Instead, we perform an of- fline precomputation step in which we collect all ngrams that map to the same lowercased string. Due to scanning errors and spelling mistakes there can be many extremely rare capitalization variants for a given query. We therefore filter out all vari- ants that have a cumulative count of less than 1% of the most frequent variant for a given year range. Capitalization searches are enabled by selecting a case-insensitive check box on the new interface.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Use Cases</head><p>The three features introduced in this paper repre- sent a major extension of the capabilities of the Ngram Viewer. While the second edition of the Ngram Corpus ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Lin et al., 2012</ref>) introduced syn- tactic ngrams, the functionality of the Viewer had remained largely unchanged since its first launch five years ago. Together, the updated Corpus and Viewer enable a much more detailed analysis of the underlying data. Below we provide some uses cases highlighting the ways in which sophisticated queries can be crafted. While the results produce some intriguing patterns, we leave their analysis to the experts.</p><p>Since we have made no modifications to the un- derlying raw ngrams, all of the plots in this pa- per could have also been generated with the pre- vious version of the Viewer. They would, how- ever, have required the user to manually generate and issue all query terms. For example, <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref> shows manually created queries searching for spe- cific presidents; contrarily, <ref type="figure">Figure 4</ref> shows single wildcard queries that automatically retrieve the ten most frequently mentioned presidents and uncover additional trends that would have required extra work on behalf of the user.</p><p>The wildcard feature used on its own can be a powerful tool for the analysis of top expansions for a certain context. Although already useful on its own, it becomes really powerful when com- bined with POS tags. The user can attach an un- derscore and POS tag to either a wildcard-based or inflection-based query to specify that the ex- pansions returned should be of a specific part of speech. Compare the utility of the generic wild- card and a search with a noun part-of-speech spec- ification in a query examining president names, 'President * ' vs. 'President * NOUN' shown in <ref type="figure">Figure 4</ref>. The former gives a mixture of prepositions, particles, and verbs along with names of presidents, and because the latter spec- ifies the noun tag, the top expansions turn out to be names and more in line with the intention of the search. Also, note in <ref type="figure">Figure 4</ref> the difference in expansions that searching over two different time ranges provides. In Query: "light_INF" "light" "lights" "lighted" "lighter" "lit" "lighting" "lightest" 1700 1850 2000 Relative Frequency Query: "light_VERB_INF" "light_VERB" "lighted_VERB" "lit_VERB" "lighting_VERB" "lights_VERB"   Comparison of the top modifiers of the verb drinks, or its equivalent in translation, in all corpora, retrieved via the query drinks VERB=&gt; * NOUN and equivalents in the other languages. The modifiers can appear both in subject and in object position because we have access only to unlabeled dependencies.</p><p>interface that creates static URLs maintaining all the raw ngrams retrieved from any query. This pre- vents statically linked charts from changing over time, and allowing for backwards compatibility.</p><p>One of the primary benefits of the capitalization feature is the combination of multiple searches in one, which allows the user to compare case- insensitive usages of two different phrases. An alternative use is in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 2(c)</ref>, where capitaliza- tion search allows the immediate identification of changing orthographic usage of a word or phrase; in this case the figure shows the arrival of F. Scott Fitzgerald in the early to mid 20th century, as well as the rise in popularity of the CamelCase variety of his surname at the turn of the 19th century.</p><p>Searches using inflections can be useful for the same reasons as the capitalization feature, and also be used to compare changes in spelling; it is par- ticularly useful for the analysis of irregular verbs, where the query can return both the regular and irregular forms of a verb.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Conclusions</head><p>We have presented an update to the Ngram Viewer that introduces new search features. Users can now perform more powerful searches that auto- matically uncover trends which were previously difficult or impossible to extract. We look forward to seeing what users of the Viewer will discover.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: Mention frequencies for three different American presidents queried one-by-one.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2: In the new enhanced search features of the Ngram Viewer, a single query is automatically expanded to retrieve multiple related ngrams. From top to bottom, we show examples of the wildcard operator (' * '), the ' INF' marker that results in morphological inflections, and the case insensitive search functionality. Due to space considerations we show only a subset of the results returned by the Ngram Viewer. (2012). The new search features presented here are available for both editions. Michel et al. (2011) extract ngrams for each page in isolation. More specifically, they use whitespace tokenization and extract all ngrams up to length five. These ngrams include ones that potentially span sentence boundaries, but do not include ngrams that span across page breaks (even when they are part of the same sentence). Lin et al. (2012) on the other hand perform tokenization, text normalization and segmentation into sentences. They then add synthetic START and END tokens to the beginning and end of the sen</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Figure 3: Overview of the Ngram Viewer architecture.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>Figure 5 :</head><label>5</label><figDesc>Figure 5: Comparison of specification of POS tag in wildcard search.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" validated="false"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>). Two editions of the corpus are available: the first edition dates from 2009 and is described in Michel et al. (2011); the second edi- tion is from 2012 and is described in Lin et al.</figDesc><table>1900 
1950 
2000 
Relative Frequency 

Query: "University of *" 

University of California 
University of Chicago 
University of Wisconsin 
University of Michigan 
University of Pennsylvania 

1950 
1975 
2000 
Relative Frequency 

Query: "book_INF a hotel" 

book a hotel 
booked a hotel 
booking a hotel 
books a hotel 

1800 
1900 
2000 
Relative Frequency 

Query: "fitzgerald [case-insensitive]" 

Fitzgerald 
FitzGerald 
FITZGERALD 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" validated="false"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>3, we add three new lookup tables that store intermediate results needed for efficiently support-</figDesc><table>117 

1800 

1900 
2000 
Relative Frequency 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3" validated="false"><head>Table 2 ,</head><label>2</label><figDesc>we compare the com- bination of the wildcard feature with the existing dependency link feature to highlight a comparison of context across several languages. It is worth noting that the newly introduced fea- tures could result in many lines in the resulting chart. Hence, we have updated the Viewer's user interface to better handle charts involving many ngrams. The new interactive functionality allows the user to highlight a line by hovering over it, keep that focus by left clicking, and clear all fo- cused lines by double clicking. A right click on any of the expansions returned by an issued query combines them into the year-wise sum total of all the expansions. We added another feature to the</figDesc><table>119 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_5" validated="false"><head>Table 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table></table></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="3"> See http://www.wiktionary.org/. Because Wiktionary is an evolving resource, results for a particular query may change over time.</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Acknowledgements</head><p>We would like to thank John DeNero, Jon Orwant, Karl Moritz Hermann for many useful discussions.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Robustness of emotion extraction from 20th century english books</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Acerbi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Lampos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Bentley</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the IEEE International Conference on Big Data</title>
		<meeting>the IEEE International Conference on Big Data</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Books average previous decade of economic misery</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Bentley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Acerbi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Ormerod</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Lampos</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">PLOS One</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">9</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Supervised learning of complete morphological paradigms</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Durrett</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Denero</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of NAACL-HLT</title>
		<meeting>NAACL-HLT</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Syntactic annotations for the Google Books Ngram Corpus</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Lin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J.-B</forename><surname>Michel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Aiden</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Orwant</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Brockman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Petrov</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the ACL</title>
		<meeting>the ACL</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Quantitative analysis of culture using millions of digitized books</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J.-B</forename><surname>Michel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Shen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Aiden</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Veres</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Gray</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<editor>J. P. Pickett, D. Hoiberg, D. Clancy, P. Norvig, J. Orwant, S. Pinker, M. A. Nowak, and E. Lieberman Aiden</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>The Google Books Team</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A universal part-of-speech tagset</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Petrov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Das</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Mcdonald</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of LREC</title>
		<meeting>of LREC</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Shifting grounds and evolving battlegrounds</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Schulz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Robinson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">American Journal of Cultural Sociology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="373" to="402" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Who&apos;s Bigger?: Where Historical Figures Really Rank</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Skiena</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Ward</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<publisher>Cambridge University Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
