<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T12:24+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Constructing a Turkish-English Parallel TreeBank</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
				<availability status="unknown"><p>Copyright Association for Computational Linguistics</p>
				</availability>
				<date>June 23-25 2014. 2014</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Olcay</forename><surname>Taner Yıldız</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">Alcatel Lucent Teletas¸TelekomünikasyonTeletas¸Teletas¸Telekomünikasyon A.S ¸</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Istanbul</settlement>
									<country key="TR">Turkey</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ercan</forename><surname>Solak</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">Alcatel Lucent Teletas¸TelekomünikasyonTeletas¸Teletas¸Telekomünikasyon A.S ¸</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Istanbul</settlement>
									<country key="TR">Turkey</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Onur</forename><surname>Görg</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">Alcatel Lucent Teletas¸TelekomünikasyonTeletas¸Teletas¸Telekomünikasyon A.S ¸</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Istanbul</settlement>
									<country key="TR">Turkey</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Görg¨</forename><surname>Görgün</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">Alcatel Lucent Teletas¸TelekomünikasyonTeletas¸Teletas¸Telekomünikasyon A.S ¸</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Istanbul</settlement>
									<country key="TR">Turkey</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Razieh</forename><surname>Ehsani</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">Alcatel Lucent Teletas¸TelekomünikasyonTeletas¸Teletas¸Telekomünikasyon A.S ¸</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Istanbul</settlement>
									<country key="TR">Turkey</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Is¸ıkIs¸ık University</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Istanbul</settlement>
									<country>Turkey †</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Constructing a Turkish-English Parallel TreeBank</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 52nd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
						<meeting>the 52nd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics <address><addrLine>Baltimore, Maryland, USA</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="112" to="117"/>
							<date type="published">June 23-25 2014. 2014</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>In this paper, we report our preliminary efforts in building an English-Turkish parallel treebank corpus for statistical machine translation. In the corpus, we manually generated parallel trees for about 5,000 sentences from Penn Treebank. English sentences in our set have a maximum of 15 tokens, including punctuation. We constrained the translated trees to the reordering of the children and the replacement of the leaf nodes with appropriate glosses. We also report the tools that we built and used in our tree translation task.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Turkish is an agglutinative and morphologically rich language with a free constituent order. Al- though statistical NLP research on Turkish has taken significant steps in recent years, much re- mains to be done. Especially for the annotated cor- pora, Turkish is still behind similar languages such as Czech, Finnish, or Hungarian. For example, EuroParl corpus <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(Koehn, 2002</ref>), one of the biggest parallel corpora in statistical machine translation, contains 22 languages (but not Turkish). Although there exist some recent works to produce paral- lel corpora for Turkish-English pair, the produced corpus is only applicable for phrase-based training <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">(Yeniterzi and Oflazer, 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">El-Kahlout, 2009)</ref>.</p><p>In recent years, many efforts have been made to annotate parallel corpora with syntactic structure to build parallel treebanks. A parallel treebank is a parallel corpus where the sentences in each language are syntactically (if necessary morpho- logically) annotated, and the sentences and words are aligned. In the parallel treebanks, the syntactic annotation usually follows constituent and/or de- pendency structure. Well-known parallel treebank efforts are</p><p>• Prague Czech-English dependency treebank annotated with dependency structure <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Cmejrek et al., 2004)</ref> • English-German parallel treebank, annotated with POS, constituent structures, functional relations, and predicate-argument structures ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Cyrus et al., 2003)</ref> • Linköping English-Swedish parallel treebank that contains 1,200 sentences annotated with POS and dependency structures <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Ahrenberg, 2007)</ref> • Stockholm multilingual treebank that con- tains 1,000 sentences in English, German and Swedish annotated with constituent structure <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Gustafson-Capkova et al., 2007)</ref> In this study, we report our preliminary efforts in constructing an English-Turkish parallel tree- bank corpus for statistical machine translation. Our approach converts English parse trees into equivalent Turkish parse trees by applying several transformation heuristics. The main components of our strategy are (i) tree permutation, where we permute the children of a node; and (ii) leaf re- placement, where we replace English word token at a leaf node. This paper is organized as follows: In Section 2, we give the literature review for parallel treebank construction efforts in Turkish. In Section 3, we give a very brief overview on Turkish syntax. We give the details of our corpus construction strategy in Section 4 and explain our transformation heuris- tics in Section 5. Finally, we conclude in Section 6.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Literature Review</head><p>Turkish Treebank creation efforts started with the METU-Sabancı dependency Treebank. METU- Sabancı Treebank explicitly represents the head- dependent relations and functional categories. In order to adapt the corpus written in 1990's Turk- ish to further studies, a subset of 7.262 sentences of the corpus was manually annotated morpho- logically and syntactically ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Atalay et al., 2003)</ref>. METU-Sabancı Treebank is then used in many Turkish NLP studies <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Yuret, 2006;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Riedel et al., 2006;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b21">Ruket and Baldridge, 2006;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Eryigit et al., 2008)</ref>.</p><p>METU-Sabancı Treebank is also subject to transformation efforts from dependency-structure to constituency-structure. Combinatory Categori- cal Grammar (CCG) is extracted from the METU- Sabancı Treebank with annotation of lexical cat- egories <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Cakici, 2005</ref>). Sub-lexical units reveal- ing the internal structure of the words are used to generate a Lexical Grammar Formalism (LGF) for Turkish with the help of finite state ma- chines ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Cetinoglu and Oflazer, 2006;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Cetinoglu and Oflazer, 2009</ref>).</p><p>Swedish-Turkish parallel treebank is the first parallel Treebank effort for Turkish ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Megyesi et al., 2008)</ref>. The treebank is a balanced syntactically annotated corpus containing both fiction and tech- nical documents. In total, it consists of approxi- mately 160,000 tokens in Swedish and 145,000 in Turkish. Parallel texts are linguistically annotated using different layers from part of speech tags and morphological features to dependency annotation.</p><p>English-Swedish-Turkish parallel treebank ( <ref type="bibr">Megyesi et al., 2010)</ref>, mainly the successor of the Swedish-Turkish parallel treebank, consists of approximately 300,000 tokens in Swedish, 160,000 in Turkish and 150,000 in English. The majority of the original text is written in Swedish and translated to Turkish and/or English. For the syntactic description, dependency structure is chosen instead of the constituent structure. All data is automatically annotated with syntactic tags using MaltParser ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">Nivre et al., 2006a</ref>). MaltParser is trained on the Penn Treebank for English, on the Swedish treebank Talbanken05 ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">Nivre et al., 2006b</ref>), and on the METU-Sabancı Turkish Treebank ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Atalay et al., 2003)</ref>, respectively.</p><p>ParGram parallel treebank ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Sulger et al., 2013</ref>) is a joint effort for the construction of a par- allel treebank involving ten languages (English, Georgian, German, Hungarian, Indonesian, Nor- wegian, Polish, Turkish, Urdu, Wolof) from six language families. The treebank is based on deep Lexical-Functional Grammars that were devel- oped within the framework of the Parallel Gram- mar effort. ParGram treebank allows for the align- ment of sentences at several levels: dependency structures, constituency structures and POS infor- mation.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Turkish syntax</head><p>Turkish is an agglutinative language with rich derivational and inflectional morphology through suffixes. Word forms usually have a complex yet fairly regular morphotactics.</p><p>Turkish sentences have an unmarked SOV or- der. However, depending on the discourse, con- stituents can be scrambled to emphasize, topical- ize and focus certain elements. Case markings identify the syntactic functions of the constituents, (Kornfilt, 1997).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Corpus construction strategy</head><p>In order to constrain the syntactic complexity of the sentences in the corpus, we selected from the Penn Treebank II 9560 trees which contain a maxi- mum of 15 tokens. These include 8660 trees from the training set of the Penn Treebank, 360 trees from its development set and 540 trees from its test set. In the first phase of our work, we trans- lated 4247 trees of the training set and all of those in the development and the test sets.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">Tools</head><p>Manual annotation is an error prone task. From simple typos to disagreements among annotators, the range of errors is fairly large. An annotation tool needs to help reduce these errors and help the annotator locate them when they occur. Moreover, the tool needs to present the annotator with a vi- sual tree that is both easy to understand and ma- nipulate for the translation task.</p><p>We built a range of custom tools to display, ma- nipulate and save annotated trees in the treebank. The underlying data structure is still textual and uses the standard Treebank II style of syntactic bracketing.</p><p>We also implemented a simple statistical helper function within the tool. When translating an En- glish word to a gloss in Turkish, the translator may choose from a list of glosses sorted according their likelihood calculated over their previous uses in similar cases. Thus, as the corpus grows in size, the translators use the leverage of their previous choices. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">Tree permutation</head><p>In translating an English syntactic tree, we confine ourselves to two operations. We can permute the children of a node and we can replace the English word token at a leaf node. No other modification of the tree is allowed. In particular, we use the same set of tags and predicate labels in the non- leaf nodes and do not use new tags for the Turkish trees. Adding or deleting nodes are not allowed either.</p><p>This might seem like a rather restrictive view of translation. Indeed, it is very easy to construct pairs of translated sentences which involve opera- tions outside our restricted set when transformed into each other.</p><p>However, we use the following method to alle- viate the restrictions of the small set of operations.</p><p>We use the *NONE* tag when we can not use any direct gloss for an English token. In itself, this operation corresponds to effectively mapping an English token to a null token. However, when we use the *NONE* tag, permute the nodes and choose the full inflected forms of the glosses in the Turkish tree, we have a powerful method to convert subtrees to an inflected word. The tree in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 2</ref>. illustrates this. Note that the POS tag se- quence VP-RB-MD-PRP in the Turkish sentence corresponds to the morphological analysis "geç- NEG-FUT-2SG" of the verb "geçmeyeceksin". In general, we try to permute the nodes so as to cor- respond to the order of inflectional morphemes in the chosen gloss. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Transformation heuristics</head><p>When we have a sufficiently rich corpus of paral- lel trees, our next step is to train a SMT learner to imitate the human translator who operates un- der our restricted set of operations. Naturally, hu- man translators often base their transformation de- cisions on the whole tree. Still, having a common set of rules and heuristics helps the translators in both consistency and speed. In the following, we illustrate these heuristics.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.1">Constituent and morpheme order</head><p>Majority of unmarked Turkish sentences have the SOV order. When translating English trees, we permute its shallow subtrees to reflect the change of constituent order in Turkish. Also, the agglutinative suffixes of Turkish words dictate the order when permuting the con- stituents which correspond to prepositions and particles.</p><p>The semantic aspects expressed by preposi- tions, modals, particles and verb tenses in En- glish in general correspond to specific morphemes attached to the corresponding word stem. For example, "Ali/NNP will/MD sit/VB on/IN a/DT chair/NN" is literally translated as Ali bir sandalye-ye otur-acak. Ali a chair-DAT sit-FUT.</p><p>If we embed a constituent in the morphemes of a Turkish stem, we replace the English constituent leaf with *NONE*.</p><p>In some cases, the personal pronouns acting as subjects are naturally embedded in the verb inflec- tion. In those cases, pronoun in the original tree is replaced with *NONE* and its subtree is moved to after the verb phrase. See <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 3</ref>. There is no definite article in Turkish correspond- ing to "the". Depending on the context, "the" is translated either as *NONE* or one of the demon- strative adjectives in Turkish, corresponding to "this" and "that" in English. See <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 3</ref> .</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.3">Case markers</head><p>Turkish, being a fairly scrambling language, uses case markers to denote the syntactic functions of nouns and noun groups. For example, accusative case may be used to mark the direct object of a transitive verb and locative case may be used to mark the head of a prepositional phrase. In trans- lation from English to Turkish, the prepositions are usually replaced with *NONE* and their cor- responding case is attached to the nominal head of the phrase. See <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Figure 4</ref>. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.4">Plural in nouns and verb inflection</head><p>Number agreement between the verb in the pred- icate and the subject is somewhat loose in Turk- ish. We preserved this freedom in translation and chose the number inflection that sounds more nat- ural. Also, plural nouns under NNS tag in the En- glish tree are sometimes translated as singular. In those cases, we kept the original POS tag NNS in- tact but used the singular gloss. See <ref type="figure">Figure 5</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.5">Tense ambiguity</head><p>It is in general not possible to find an exact map- ping among the tense classes in a pair of lan- guages. When translating the trees, we mapped the English verb tenses to their closest semantic classes in Turkish while trying to keep the over- all flow of the Turkish sentence natural. In many cases, we mapped the perfective tense in English to the past tense in Turkish. Similarly, we some- times mapped the present tense to present contin- uous. See <ref type="figure">Figure 5</ref>. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.7">Miscellany</head><p>In the translation of nominal clauses, the copula marker "-dIr" corresponding to verb "be" is often dropped. The proper nouns are translated with their com- mon Turkish gloss if there is one. So, "London" becomes "Londra".</p><p>Subordinating conjunctions, marked as "IN" in English sentences, are transformed to *NONE* and the appropriate participle morpheme is ap- pended to the stem in the Turkish translation.</p><p>A multiword expression may correspond to a single English word. Conversely, more than one words in English may correspond to a single word in Turkish. In the first case, we use the multiword expression as the gloss. In the latter case, we re- place some English words with *NONE*.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Conclusion</head><p>Parallel treebank construction efforts increased significantly in the recent years. Many parallel treebanks are produced to build statistically strong language models for different languages. In this study, we report our preliminary efforts to build such a parallel corpus for Turkish-English pair. We translated and transformed a subset of parse trees of Penn Treebank to Turkish. We cover more than 50% of all sentences with a maximum length of 15-words including punctuation.</p><p>This work constitutes the preliminary step of parallel treebank generation. As a next step, we will focus on morphological analysis and disam- biguation of Turkish words. After determining the correct morphological analysis of Turkish words, we will use the parts of these analyses to re- place the leaf nodes that we intentionally left as "*NONE*". As a future work, we plan to expand the dataset to include all Penn Treebank sentences.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: A screenshot of the tree translation tool</figDesc><graphic url="image-1.png" coords="3,72.14,62.87,453.50,246.33" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2: The permutation of the nodes and the replacement of the leaves by the glosses or *NONE*.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Figure 3: Original and translated trees, sandalye-ye otur-ma-yacaˇgyacaˇg-ım chair-DAT sit-NEG-FUT-1SG</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>Figure 4 :</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Figure 4: Original and translated trees, Ali top-u ban-a at-tı Ali ball-ACC me-DAT throw-PAST-3SG</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head>Figure 5 :Figure 6 :</head><label>56</label><figDesc>Figure 5: Original and translated trees, C ¸ ocuk-larüçlar¨larüç elma ye-di Child-PL three apple eat-PAST-3SG</figDesc></figure>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Lines: An english-swedish parallel treebank</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lars</forename><surname>Ahrenberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The annotation process in the Turkish treebank</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Nart</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kemal</forename><surname>Atalay</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bilge</forename><surname>Oflazer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Say</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">4th International Workshop on Linguistically Interpreted Corpora</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Automatic induction of a ccg grammar for Turkish</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ruken</forename><surname>Cakici</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ACL Student Research Workshop</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ozlem</forename><surname>Cetinoglu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kemal</forename><surname>Oflazer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Morphology-syntax interface for Turkish lfg</title>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Computational Linguistics and Annual Meeting of the Association</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Integrating derivational morphology into syntax</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ozlem</forename><surname>Cetinoglu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kemal</forename><surname>Oflazer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Recent Advances in Natural Language Processing V</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Prague czech-english dependency treebank: Syntactically annotated resources for machine translation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Martin</forename><surname>Cmejrek</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jan</forename><surname>Haji</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Vladislav</forename><surname>Kubo</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of EAMT 10th Annual Conference</title>
		<meeting>EAMT 10th Annual Conference</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
			<biblScope unit="page">4</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">FuSe-a multi-layered parallel treebank</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lea</forename><surname>Cyrus</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hendrik</forename><surname>Feddes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Frank</forename><surname>Schumacher</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Second Workshop on Treebanks and Linguistic Theories</title>
		<meeting>the Second Workshop on Treebanks and Linguistic Theories<address><addrLine>Växjö, Sweden; Växjö</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Växjö University Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2003-11" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="213" to="216" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Joakim Nivre and Erhard Hinrichs</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Statistical machine translation from english to turkish</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Ilknur</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>El-Kahlout</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>ph.d. thesis</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Statistical dependency parsing for Turkish</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gulsen</forename><surname>Eryigit</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kemal</forename><surname>Oflazer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">11th Conference of the European Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Türkçe cümlelerin kural tabanlı ba˘ glılık analizi</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gulsen</forename><surname>Eryigit</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Esref</forename><surname>Adali</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kemal</forename><surname>Oflazer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">15th Turkish Symposium on Artificial Intelligence and Neural Networks</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gulsen</forename><surname>Eryigit</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Joakim</forename><surname>Nivre</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kemal</forename><surname>Oflazer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Dependency parsing of Turkish. Computational Linguistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Smultron (version 1.0)the stockholm multilingual parallel treebank. an english-german-swedish parallel treebank with subsentential alignments</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sofia</forename><surname>Gustafson-Capkova</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yvonne</forename><surname>Samuelsson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Martin</forename><surname>Volk</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Europarl: A multilingual corpus for evaluation of machine translation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Philipp</forename><surname>Koehn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Kornfilt</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Turkish. Routledge</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Swedish-turkish parallel treebank</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Beáta</forename><surname>Megyesi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bengt</forename><surname>Dahlqvist</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Eva</forename><surname>Pettersson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Joakim</forename><surname>Nivre</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">LREC</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Beáta</forename><surname>Megyesi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bengt</forename><surname>Dahlqvist</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Evá</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Csató</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The english-swedish-turkish parallel treebank</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Joakim</forename><surname>Nivre</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">LREC</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Maltparser: A data-driven parser-generator for dependency parsing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Joakim</forename><surname>Nivre</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Johan</forename><surname>Hall</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jens</forename><surname>Nilsson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of LREC-2006</title>
		<meeting>of LREC-2006</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2216" to="2219" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Talbanken05: A swedish treebank with phrase structure and dependency annotation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Joakim</forename><surname>Nivre</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jens</forename><surname>Nilsson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Johan</forename><surname>Hall</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the fifth international conference on Language Resources and Evaluation (LREC2006</title>
		<meeting>the fifth international conference on Language Resources and Evaluation (LREC2006</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="24" to="26" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Multi-lingual dependency parsing with incremental integer linear programming</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Riedel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ruket</forename><surname>Cakici</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Meza-Ruiz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Projective and nonprojective Turkish parsing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jason</forename><surname>Ruket</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Baldridge</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Fifth International Workshop on Treebanks and Linguistic Theories</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Pargrambank: The pargram parallel treebank</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sebastian</forename><surname>Sulger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Miriam</forename><surname>Butt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tracy</forename><forename type="middle">Holloway</forename><surname>King</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Paul</forename><surname>Meurer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tibor</forename><surname>Laczkó</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">György</forename><surname>Rákosi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Cheikh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Helge</forename><surname>Bamba Dione</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Victoria</forename><surname>Dyvik</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Koenraad</forename><forename type="middle">De</forename><surname>Rosén</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Agnieszka</forename><surname>Smedt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Patejuk</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Meladel</forename><surname>Ozlem C ¸ Etinoglu, I Wayan Arka</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Mistica</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ACL (1)</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="550" to="560" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Syntax-tomorphology mapping in factored phrase-based statistical machine translation from english to turkish</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Reyyan</forename><surname>Yeniterzi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kemal</forename><surname>Oflazer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 48th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics, ACL &apos;10</title>
		<meeting>the 48th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics, ACL &apos;10<address><addrLine>Stroudsburg, PA, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="454" to="464" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dependency parsing as a classification problem</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Deniz</forename><surname>Yuret</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Tenth Conference on Computational Natural Language Learning</title>
		<meeting>the Tenth Conference on Computational Natural Language Learning</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
