<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T11:42+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Word Segmentation of Informal Arabic with Domain Adaptation</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Will</forename><surname>Monroe</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Computer Science Department</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Stanford University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Spence</forename><surname>Green</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Computer Science Department</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Stanford University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christopher</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Manning</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Computer Science Department</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Stanford University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Word Segmentation of Informal Arabic with Domain Adaptation</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Segmentation of clitics has been shown to improve accuracy on a variety of Arabic NLP tasks. However, state-of-the-art Ara-bic word segmenters are either limited to formal Modern Standard Arabic, performing poorly on Arabic text featuring dialectal vocabulary and grammar, or rely on linguistic knowledge that is hand-tuned for each dialect. We extend an existing MSA segmenter with a simple domain adaptation technique and new features in order to segment informal and dialectal Arabic text. Experiments show that our system outper-forms existing systems on broadcast news and Egyptian dialect, improving segmenta-tion F 1 score on a recently released Egyp-tian Arabic corpus to 92.09%, compared to 91.60% for another segmenter designed specifically for Egyptian Arabic.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Segmentation of words, clitics, and affixes is essen- tial for a number of natural language processing (NLP) applications, including machine translation, parsing, and speech recognition ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Chang et al., 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Tsarfaty, 2006;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Kurimo et al., 2006</ref>). Segmentation is a common practice in Arabic NLP due to the lan- guage's morphological richness. Specifically, clitic separation has been shown to improve performance on Arabic parsing <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Green and Manning, 2010)</ref> and Arabic-English machine translation <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Habash and Sadat, 2006</ref>). However, the variety of Arabic di- alects presents challenges in Arabic NLP. Dialectal Arabic contains non-standard orthography, vocab- ulary, morphology, and syntax. Tools that depend on corpora or grammatical properties that only con- sider formal Modern Standard Arabic (MSA) do not perform well when confronted with these differ- ences. The creation of annotated corpora in dialec- tal Arabic ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Maamouri et al., 2006</ref>) has promoted the development of new systems that support dialec- tal Arabic, but these systems tend to be tailored to specific dialects and require separate, costly efforts for Egyptian Arabic, Levantine Arabic, Maghrebi Arabic, etc.</p><p>We present a single clitic segmentation model that is accurate on both MSA and informal Arabic. The model is an extension of the character-level conditional random field (CRF) model of <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Green and DeNero (2012)</ref>. Our work goes beyond theirs in three aspects. First, we handle two Arabic ortho- graphic normalization rules that commonly require rewriting of tokens after segmentation. Second, we add new features that improve segmentation ac- curacy. Third, we show that dialectal data can be handled in the framework of domain adaptation. Specifically, we show that even simple feature space augmentation <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Daumé, 2007</ref>) yields significant im- provements in task accuracy.</p><p>We compare our work to the original Green and DeNero model and two other Arabic segmenta- tion systems: the MADA+TOKAN toolkit v. 3.1 ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Habash et al., 2009</ref>) and its Egyptian dialect vari- ant, MADA-ARZ v. 0. <ref type="bibr">4 (Habash et al., 2013)</ref>. We demonstrate that our system outperforms all three other systems on broadcast news and Egyptian di- alect in F 1 segmentation score, achieving a 92.09% F 1 score evaluated against a gold standard on Egyp- tian dialect data, compared to 91.60% for MADA- ARZ and 88.64% for Green and DeNero. In ad- dition, our model decodes input an order of mag- nitude faster than either version of MADA. Like the Green and DeNero system, but unlike MADA and MADA-ARZ, our system does not rely on a morphological analyzer, and can be applied di- rectly to any dialect for which segmented training data is available. The source code is available in the latest public release of the Stanford Word Seg- menter (http://nlp.stanford.edu/software/ segmenter.shtml).</p><p>A CRF model <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(Lafferty et al., 2001</ref>) defines a distri- bution p(Y|X; θ), where X = {x 1 , . . . , x N } is the observed input sequence and Y = {y 1 , . . . , y N } is the sequence of labels we seek to predict. Green and DeNero use a linear-chain model with X as the sequence of input characters, and Y * chosen according to the decision rule</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">Y * = arg max Y N i=1 θ φ(X, y i , . . . , y i−3 , i) .</formula><p>where φ is the feature map defined in Section 2.1. Their model classifies each y i as one of I (contin- uation of a segment), O (whitespace outside any segment), B (beginning of a segment), or F (pre- grouped foreign characters).</p><p>Our segmenter expands this label space in order to handle four Arabic-specific orthographic rules. In our model, each y i can take on one of the five values {I, O, B, F, RRR}, where the label RRR in- dicates one of the following orthographic rewrites:</p><p>• if the current character is the Arabic letter l, it should start a new segment and be trans- formed into the definite article al-when segmented. This type of transformation occurs after the prefix li-"to".</p><p>• if the current character is the letter t, it is a continuation but should become the letter h when segmented. Arabic orthography rules restrict the occurrence of h to the word-final position, writing it instead as t whenever it is followed by a clitic.</p><p>• if the current character is the letter y or ¯ a, it is a continuation but should become the opposite letter. In MSA, certain prepositions are spelled with a ¯ a that becomes y when a clitic follows; in Egyptian dialect, these two letters are often interchangeable.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">Features</head><p>The model of Green and DeNero is a third-order (i.e., 4-gram) Markov CRF, employing the follow- ing indicator features:</p><p>• a five-character window around the current character: for each −2 ≤ δ ≤ 2 and 1 ≤ i ≤ N , the triple (x i+δ , δ, y i )</p><p>• n-grams consisting of the current character and up to three preceding characters: for each 2 ≤ n ≤ 4 and n ≤ i ≤ N , the character-sequence/label-sequence pair</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">(x i−n+1 . . . x i , y i−n+1 . . . y i )</formula><p>• whether the current character is punctuation</p><p>• whether the current character is a digit</p><p>• the Unicode block of the current character</p><p>• the Unicode character class of the current char- acter</p><p>In addition to these, we include two other types of features motivated by specific errors the original system made on Egyptian dialect development data:</p><p>• Word length and position within a word: for each 1 ≤ i ≤ N , the pairs (, y i ), (a, y i ), and (b, y i ), where , a, and b are the total length of the word containing x i , the number of char- acters after x i in the word, and the number of characters before x i in the word, respectively. Some incorrect segmentations produced by the original system could be ruled out with the knowledge of these statistics.</p><p>• First and last two characters of the current word, separately influencing the first two labels and the last two labels: for each word consisting of characters x s . . . x t , the tu- ples (x s x s+1 , x t−1 x t , y s y s+1 , "begin") and (x s x s+1 , x t−1 x t , y t−1 y t , "end"). This set of features addresses a particular dialectal Arabic construction, the negation m¯ a-+ [verb] + -sh, which requires a matching prefix and suffix to be segmented simultaneously. This feature set also allows the model to take into ac- count other interactions between the beginning and end of a word, particularly those involving the definite article al-.</p><p>A notable property of this feature set is that it re- mains highly dialect-agnostic, even though our ad- ditional features were chosen in response to errors made on text in Egyptian dialect. In particular, it does not depend on the existence of a dialect- specific lexicon or morphological analyzer. As a result, we expect this model to perform similarly well when applied to other Arabic dialects.  <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Green and DeNero (2012)</ref>. Rew is support for orthographic rewrites with the RRRAA and RRRT labels. The fifth row shows the strongest baseline, which is the GD+Rew model trained on the concatenated training sets from all three treebanks. DA is domain adaptation via feature space augmentation. Feat adds the additional feature templates described in section 2.1. ATB is the newswire ATB; BN is the Broadcast News treebank; ARZ is the Egyptian treebank. Best results (bold) are statistically significant (p &lt; 0.001) relative to the strongest baseline.</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">F 1 (%) TEDEval (%) Model</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">Domain adaptation</head><p>In this work, we train our model to segment Arabic text drawn from three domains: newswire, which consists of formal text in MSA; broadcast news, which contains scripted, formal MSA as well as extemporaneous dialogue in a mix of MSA and di- alect; and discussion forum posts written primarily in Egyptian dialect.</p><p>The approach to domain adaptation we use is that of feature space augmentation <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Daumé, 2007)</ref>. Each indicator feature from the model described in Section 2.1 is replaced by N + 1 features in the augmented model, where N is the number of domains from which the data is drawn (here, N = 3). These N + 1 features consist of the original feature and N "domain-specific" features, one for each of the N domains, each of which is active only when both the original feature is present and the current text comes from its assigned domain.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Experiments</head><p>We train and evaluate on three corpora: parts 1-3 of the newswire Arabic Treebank (ATB), <ref type="bibr">1</ref>  ATB, we use the same split as <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Chiang et al. (2006)</ref>. For the other two corpora, we use the procedure defined by <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Diab et al. (2013)</ref>. <ref type="bibr">4</ref> We train the Green and DeNero model and our improvements using L-BFGS with L 2 regularization.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Evaluation metrics</head><p>We use two evaluation metrics in our experiments. The first is an F 1 precision-recall measure, ignoring orthographic rewrites. F 1 scores provide a more informative assessment of performance than word- level or character-level accuracy scores, as over 80% of tokens in the development sets consist of only one segment, with an average of one segmentation every 4.7 tokens (or one every 20.4 characters).</p><p>The second metric we use is the TEDEval met- ric ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Tsarfaty et al., 2012)</ref>. TEDEval was devel- oped to evaluate joint segmentation and parsing 5 in Hebrew, which requires a greater variety of or- thographic rewrites than those possible in Arabic. Its edit distance-based scoring algorithm is robust enough to handle the rewrites produced by both MADA and our segmenter.</p><p>We measure the statistical significance of differ- ences in these metrics with an approximate ran- domization test <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(Yeh, 2000;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Padó, 2006</ref>), with R = 10,000 samples.   <ref type="table">Table 2</ref>: Test set results. Our final model (last row) is trained on all available data (ATB+BN+ARZ). Font style indicates significance relative to the next highest model (bold: p &lt; 0.001, bold italic: p &lt; 0.05).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>ATB</head><p>BN ARZ MADA 705.6 ± 5.1 472.0 ± 0.8 767.8 ± 1.9 MADA-ARZ 784.7 ± 1.6 492.1 ± 4.2 779.0 ± 2.7 GD+Rew+DA+Feat 90.0 ± 1.0 59.5 ± 0.3 72.7 ± 0.2 <ref type="table">Table 3</ref>: Wallclock time (in seconds) for MADA, MADA-ARZ, and our model for decoding each of the three development datasets. Means and standard deviations were computed for 10 independent runs. <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">Table 1</ref> contains results on the development set for the model of Green and DeNero and our im- provements. Using domain adaptation alone helps performance on two of the three datasets (with a sta- tistically insignificant decrease on broadcast news), and our additional features further improve segmen- tation on all datasets. <ref type="table">Table 2</ref> shows the segmenta- tion scores our model achieves when evaluated on the three test sets, as well as the results for MADA and MADA-ARZ. Our segmenter matches or out- performs both MADA and MADA-ARZ on all met- rics and datasets except for the TEDEval metric on the Egyptian dataset, which reflects the greater variety of orthographic normalizations <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Habash et al., 2012</ref>) implemented in MADA-ARZ. In addi- tion, our segmenter is faster than MADA. <ref type="table">Table 3</ref> compares the running times of the three systems. Our segmenter achieves a 7x or more speedup over MADA and MADA-ARZ on all datasets.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Results</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Error Analysis</head><p>We randomly sampled 100 of the errors made by our final model on the ARZ development set; see <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">Table  4</ref>. These errors fall into three general categories:</p><p>• typographical errors and annotation inconsis- tencies in the gold data;</p><p>• errors that can be fixed with a fuller analysis of just the problematic token, and therefore represent a deficiency in the feature set; and</p><p>• errors that would require additional context or sophisticated semantic awareness to fix.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">Typographical errors and annotation inconsistencies</head><p>Of the 100 errors we sampled, 33 are due to typo- graphical errors or inconsistencies in the gold data. We classify 7 as typos and 26 as annotation incon- sistencies, although the distinction between the two is murky: typos are intentionally preserved in the treebank data, but segmentation of typos varies de- pending on how well they can be reconciled with standard Arabic orthography. Four of the seven typos are the result of a missing space, such as:</p><p>• yashar-bi-'l-lay¯ al¯ ı "staysawakeat- night" ( yashar + bi-+ al-lay¯ al¯ ı)</p><p>• amilatn¯ a-an "madeus" ( amilat + -n¯ a + an)</p><p>The first example is segmented in the Egyptian tree- bank but is left unsegmented by our system; the second is left as a single token in the treebank but is split into the above three segments by our system. Of the annotation inconsistencies that do not in- volve typographical errors, a handful are segmenta- tion mistakes; in most cases, however, the segmen- tation is justifiable but arbitrary. In particular, a few colloquial "filler" expressions are sometimes not segmented, despite containing Arabic clitics that are segmented elsewhere in the data. These include rabbin¯ a "[our] Lord" (oath); indam¯ a "when"/"while"; and khall¯ ık "keep"/"stay".</p><p>Also, tokens containing foreign words are some- times not segmented, despite carrying clitics. An  example is wamistur "and Mister <ref type="bibr">[English]</ref>", which could be segmented as wa-+ mistur.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">Features too local</head><p>In 36 of the 100 sampled errors, we conjecture that the presence of the error indicates a shortcoming of the feature set, resulting in segmentations that make sense locally but are not plausible given the full token. Two examples of these are:</p><p>• wafit . ar¯ ıqah "and in the way" seg- mented as wa-+ fit . ar¯ ıqah (correct analysis is wa-+ fi-+ t . ar¯ ıqah). ft . r "break"/"breakfast" is a common Ara- bic root, but the presence of q should indi- cate that ft . r is not the root in this case.</p><p>• wal¯ ayuhimmhum "and it's not im- portant to them" segmented as wa-+ li-+ -ayuhimm + -hum (correct analysis is wa-+ l¯ a + yuhimm + -hum). The 4-character window l¯ ayh occurs commonly with a segment boundary after the l, but the segment -ayuhimm</p><p>is not a well-formed Arabic word.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3">Context-sensitive segmentations and multiple word senses</head><p>In the remaining 31 of 100 errors, external context is needed. In many of these, it is not clear how to address the error without sophisticated semantic reasoning about the surrounding sentence.</p><p>One token accounts for five of these errors:</p><p>wl¯ a, which in Egyptian dialect can be analyzed as wa-+ l¯ a "and [do/does] not" or as wall¯ a "or". In a few cases, either is syntactically correct, and the meaning must be inferred from context. Two other ambiguities are a frequent cause of error and seem to require sophisticated disambigua- tion. The first is -n¯ a, which is both a first person plural object pronoun and a first person plural past tense ending. The former is segmented, while the latter is not. An example of this is the pair ilmun¯ a "our knowledge" ( ilmu + -n¯ a) versus alimn¯ a "we knew" (one segment). The other is -y, which is both a first person singular possessive pronoun and the nisba suffix ("of or related to"); only the former is segmented. One example of this distinction that appeared in the development set is the pair mawd . ¯ u¯ ı "my topic" ( mawd . ¯ u + -y) versus mawd . ¯ u¯ ıy "topical", "objective".</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Conclusion</head><p>In this paper we demonstrate substantial gains on Arabic clitic segmentation for both formal and dialectal text using a single model with dialect- independent features and a simple domain adap- tation strategy. We present a new Arabic segmenter which performs better than tools employing sophis- ticated linguistic analysis, while also giving im- pressive speed improvements. We evaluated our segmenter on broadcast news and Egyptian Arabic due to the current availability of annotated data in these domains. However, as data for other Arabic di- alects and genres becomes available, we expect that the model's simplicity and the domain adaptation method we use will allow the system to be applied to these dialects with minimal effort and without a loss of performance in the original domains.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>F</head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" validated="false"><head>1 (%)98.74 98.29 92.32</head><label>1</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>TEDEval (%) 
ATB 
BN 
ARZ ATB 
BN 
ARZ 

MADA 
98.01 97.06 76.85 98.64 97.98 84.45 
MADA-ARZ 
93.65 94.82 91.60 95.32 96.38 93.33 
GD+Rew+DA+Feat 98.24 97.39 92.09 </table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4" validated="false"><head>Table 4 :</head><label>4</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Counts of error categories (out of 100 
randomly sampled ARZ development set errors). 

</table></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="4"> Listings for these splits are available at http://nlp.stanford.edu/software/parserarabic-data-splits.shtml. 5 In order to evaluate segmentation in isolation, we convert each segmented sentence from both the model output and the gold standard to a flat tree with all segments descending directly from the root.</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>We thank the three reviewers, Nizar Habash for helping discover and correct problems in process-ing the LDC data, and Reut Tsarfaty for valuable correspondence regarding TEDEval. The second author is supported by a National Science Foun-dation Graduate Research Fellowship. This work was supported by the Defense Advanced Research Projects Agency (DARPA) Broad Operational Lan-guage Translation (BOLT) program through IBM. Any opinions, findings, and conclusions or recom-mendations expressed in this material are those of the author(s) and do not necessarily reflect the view of DARPA or the US government.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Optimizing Chinese word segmentation for machine translation performance</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Pi-Chuan</forename><surname>Chang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michel</forename><surname>Galley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christopher</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Manning</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">WMT</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Parsing Arabic dialects</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Chiang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mona</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Diab</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nizar</forename><surname>Habash</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Owen</forename><surname>Rambow</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Safiullah</forename><surname>Shareef</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">EACL</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Frustratingly easy domain adaptation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hal</forename><surname>Daumé</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Iii</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ACL</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">LDC Arabic treebanks and associated corpora: Data divisions manual</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mona</forename><surname>Diab</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nizar</forename><surname>Habash</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Owen</forename><surname>Rambow</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ryan</forename><surname>Roth</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>CCLS-13-02</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>Center for Computational Learning Systems, Columbia University</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
<note type="report_type">CCLS Technical Report</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A class-based agreement model for generating accurately inflected translations</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Spence</forename><surname>Green</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">John</forename><surname>Denero</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ACL</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Better Arabic parsing: Baselines, evaluations, and analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Spence</forename><surname>Green</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Christopher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Manning</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">COLING</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Arabic preprocessing schemes for statistical machine translation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nizar</forename><surname>Habash</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Fatiha</forename><surname>Sadat</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">NAACL</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Short Papers</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">MADA+TOKAN: A toolkit for Arabic tokenization, diacritization, morphological disambiguation, POS tagging, stemming and lemmatization</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nizar</forename><surname>Habash</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Owen</forename><surname>Rambow</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ryan</forename><surname>Roth</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">MEDAR</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Conventional orthography for dialectal Arabic</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nizar</forename><surname>Habash</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mona</forename><surname>Diab</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Owen</forename><surname>Rambow</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">LREC</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Morphological analysis and disambiguation for dialectal Arabic</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nizar</forename><surname>Habash</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ryan</forename><surname>Roth</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Owen</forename><surname>Rambow</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">HLTNAACL</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Ramy Eskander, and Nadi Tomeh</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Unlimited vocabulary speech recognition for agglutinative languages</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mikko</forename><surname>Kurimo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Antti</forename><surname>Puurula</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ebru</forename><surname>Arisoy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Vesa</forename><surname>Siivola</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Teemu</forename><surname>Hirsimäki</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Janne</forename><surname>Pylkkönen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tanel</forename><surname>Alumäe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Murat</forename><surname>Saraclar</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">HLT-NAACL</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Conditional random fields: Probabilistic models for segmenting and labeling sequence data</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">John</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Lafferty</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Andrew</forename><surname>Mccallum</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Fernando</forename><forename type="middle">C N</forename><surname>Pereira</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ICML</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Developing and using a pilot dialectal Arabic treebank</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mohamed</forename><surname>Maamouri</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ann</forename><surname>Bies</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tim</forename><surname>Buckwalter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mona</forename><surname>Diab</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nizar</forename><surname>Habash</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Owen</forename><surname>Rambow</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dalila</forename><surname>Tabessi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">LREC</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">User&apos;s guide to sigf: Significance testing by approximate randomisation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sebastian</forename><surname>Padó</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Joint evaluation of morphological segmentation and syntactic parsing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Reut</forename><surname>Tsarfaty</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Joakim</forename><surname>Nivre</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Evelina</forename><surname>Andersson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ACL</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Short Papers</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Integrated morphological and syntactic disambiguation for Modern Hebrew</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Reut</forename><surname>Tsarfaty</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">COLING-ACL</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">More accurate tests for the statistical significance of result differences</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alexander</forename><surname>Yeh</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">COLING</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
