<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T10:35+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Negation and Speculation Identification in Chinese Language</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date>July 26-31, 2015</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bowei</forename><surname>Zou</surname></persName>
							<email>zoubowei@gmail.com, {qmzhu, gdzhou}@suda.edu.cn</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">School of Computer Science and Technology</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">Natural Language Processing Lab</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Soochow University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>215006</postCode>
									<settlement>Suzhou</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Qiaoming</forename><surname>Zhu</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">School of Computer Science and Technology</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">Natural Language Processing Lab</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Soochow University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>215006</postCode>
									<settlement>Suzhou</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Guodong</forename><surname>Zhou</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">School of Computer Science and Technology</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">Natural Language Processing Lab</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Soochow University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>215006</postCode>
									<settlement>Suzhou</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Negation and Speculation Identification in Chinese Language</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 53rd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics and the 7th International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing</title>
						<meeting>the 53rd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics and the 7th International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing <address><addrLine>Beijing, China</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="656" to="665"/>
							<date type="published">July 26-31, 2015</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Identifying negative or speculative narrative fragments from fact is crucial for natural language processing (NLP) applications. Previous studies on negation and speculation identification in Chinese language suffers much from two problems: corpus scarcity and the bottleneck in fundamental Chinese information processing. To resolve these problems, this paper constructs a Chinese corpus which consists of three sub-corpora from different resources. In order to detect the negative and speculative cues, a sequence labeling model is proposed. Moreover, a bilingual cue expansion method is proposed to increase the coverage in cue detection. In addition, this paper presents a new syntactic structure-based framework to identify the linguistic scope of a cue, instead of the traditional chunking-based framework. Experimental results justify the usefulness of our Chinese corpus and the appropriateness of our syntactic structure based framework which obtained significant improvement over the state-of-the-art on negation and speculation identification in Chinese language. *</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Negation and speculation are ubiquitous phe- nomena in natural language. While negation is a grammatical category which comprises various kinds of devices to reverse the truth value of a proposition, speculation is a grammatical catego- ry which expresses the attitude of a speaker to- wards a statement in terms of degree of certainty, * Corresponding author reliability, subjectivity, sources of information, and perspective <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(Morante and Sporleder, 2012)</ref>.</p><p>Current studies on negation and speculation identification mainly focus on two tasks: 1) cue detection, which aims to detect the signal of a negative or speculative expression, and 2) scope resolution, which aims to determine the linguistic coverage of a cue in sentence, in distinguishing unreliable or uncertain information from facts. For example, (E1) and (E2) include a negative cue and a speculative cue respectively, both de- noted in boldface with their linguistic scopes denoted in square brackets (adopted hereinafter). In sentence (E1), the negative cue "不(not)" trig- gers the scope of "不会追究酒店的这次管理失 职(would not investigate the dereliction of ho- tel)", within which the fragment "investigate the dereliction of hotel" is the part that is repudiated; While the speculative cue "有望(expected)" in sentence (E2) triggers the scope "后期仍有望反 弹(is still expected to rebound in the late)", with- in which the fragment "the benchmark Shanghai Composite Index will rebound in the late" is the speculative part. (Although dragged down by GEM last Fri- day, the benchmark Shanghai Composite In- dex [is still expected to rebound in the late].) Negation and speculation identification is very relevant for almost all NLP applications involv- ing text understanding which need to discrimi- nate between factual and non-factual information. The treatment of negation and speculation in computational linguistics has been shown to be useful for biomedical text processing <ref type="bibr">(Morante et al., 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Chowdhury and Lavelli, 2013</ref>), infor- mation retrieval <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Averbuch, 2004</ref>), sentiment analysis ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Councill et al., 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b18">Zhu et al., 2014</ref>), recognizing textual entailment ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Snow et al., 2006</ref>), machine translation ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Baker et al., 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Wetzel and Bond, 2012)</ref>, and so forth.</p><p>The research on negation and speculation identification in English has received a noticea- ble boost. However, in contrast to the significant achievements concerning English, the research progress in Chinese language is quite limited. The main reason includes the following two as- pects: First, the scarcity of linguistic resource seriously limits the advance of related research. To the best of our knowledge, there are no pub- licly available standard Chinese corpus of rea- sonable size annotated with negation and specu- lation. Second, this may be attributed to the limi- tations of Chinese information processing.</p><p>The contributions of this paper are as follows: • To address the aforementioned first issue, this paper seeks to fill this gap by presenting the Chinese negation and speculation corpus which consists of three kind of sub-corpora annotated for negative and speculative cues, and their linguistic scopes. The corpus has been made publicly available for research purposes and it is freely downloadable from http://nlp.suda.edu.cn/corpus.</p><p>• For cue detection, we propose a feature-based sequence labeling model to identify cues. It is worth noting that the morpheme feature is employed to better represent the composition- al semantics inside Chinese words. Moreover, for improving the low recall rate which suf- fers from the unknown cues, we propose a cross-lingual cue expansion strategy based on parallel corpora.</p><p>• For scope resolution, we present a new syn- tactic structure-based framework on depend- ency tree. Evaluation justifies the appropri- ateness and validity of this framework on Chinese scope resolution, which outperforms the chunking-based framework that widely used in mainstream scope resolution systems. The layout of the rest paper is organized as follows. Section 2 describes related work. Sec- tion 3 provides details about annotation guide- lines and also presents statistics about corpus characteristics. Section 4 describes our approach in detail. Section 5 reports and discusses our ex- perimental results. Finally, we conclude our work and indicate some future work in Section 6.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Related Work</head><p>Currently, both cue detection task and scope res- olution task are always modeled as a classifica- tion problem with the purpose of predicting whether a token is inside or outside the cue and its scope. Among them, feature-based and ker- nel-based approaches are most popular.</p><p>In the feature-based framework, Agarwal and Yu (2010) employed a conditional random fields (CRFs) model to detect speculative cues and their scopes on the BioScope corpus. The CRFs- based model achieved an F1-meature of 88% in detecting speculative cues. We train this model on our corpus as the baseline system for cue de- tection. Our work is different from theirs in that we employ a new feature (morpheme feature) which is particularly appropriate for Chinese.</p><p>Besides, kernel-based approaches exploit the structure of the tree that connects cue and its cor- responding scope. <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">Zou et al. (2013)</ref> developed a tree kernel-based system to resolve the scope of negation and speculation, which captures the structured information in syntactic parsing trees. To the best of our knowledge, this system is the best English scope resolution system. For this reason, we train this system on our corpus as the baseline system for scope resolution.</p><p>Compared with a fair amount of works on English negation and speculation identification, unfortunately, few works has been published on Chinese. <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Ji et al. (2010)</ref> developed a system to detect speculation in Chinese news texts. How- ever, only the speculative sentences have been found out, with no more fine-grained information such as scope. The insufficient study on Chinese negation and speculation identification drives us to construct a high-quality corpus and investigate how to find an approach that is particularly ap- propriate for Chinese language.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Corpus Construction</head><p>In this section, we elaborate on the overall char- acteristics of the Chinese Negation and Specula- tion (abbr., CNeSp) corpus we constructed, in- cluding a brief description of the sources that constitute our corpus, general guidelines which illustrated with lots of examples and some spe- cial cases, and statistics on the overall results of our corpus.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Sources</head><p>To capture the heterogeneity of language use in texts, the corpus consists of three different sources and types, including scientific literature, product reviews, and financial articles. <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Vincze et al. (2008)</ref> described that it is neces- sary to separate negative and speculative infor- mation from factual especially in science articles, because conclusions of science experiment are always described by using diversity of expres- sions and include hypothetical asserts or view- points. For this reason, we adopt the 19 articles from Chinese Journal of <ref type="bibr">Computers (Vol.35(11)</ref>), an authoritative academic journal in Chinese, to construct the Scientific Literature sub-corpus.</p><p>Another part of the corpus consists of 311 ar- ticles from "股市及时雨(timely rain for stock market)" column from Sina.com in April, 2013. There are 22.3% and 40.2% sentences in the Fi- nancial Article sub-corpus containing negation and speculation respectively.</p><p>Many researches have investigated the role of negation in sentiment analysis task, as an im- portant linguistic qualifier which leads to a change in polarity. For example, <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Councill et al. (2010)</ref> investigated the problem of determining the polarity of sentiment in movie reviews when negation words occur in the sentences. On the other hand, speculation is a linguistic expression that tends to correlate with subjectivity which is also crucial for sentiment analysis. <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Pang and Lee (2004)</ref> showed that subjectivity detection in the review domain helps to improve polarity classifi- cation. Therefore, the Product Review sub- corpus consists of 821 comments of hotel service from the website Ctrip.com.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Annotation Guidelines</head><p>The guidelines of our CNeSp corpus have partly referred to the existing Bioscope corpus guide- lines <ref type="bibr">(BioScope, 2008</ref>) in order to fit the needs of the Chinese language. In annotation process, negative or speculative cues and their linguistic scopes in sentence are annotated. There are sev- eral general principles below: (G1) Cue is contained in its scope. (G2) The minimal unit that expresses negation or speculation is annotated as a cue.</p><p>(E3) 该股极有可能再度出现涨停.</p><p>(The stock is very likely to hit limit up.) To G2, the modifiers such as prepositions, de- terminers, or adverbs are not annotated as parts of the cue. For example, in Sentence (E3), "极 (very)" is only a modifier of the speculative cue "可能(likely)", but not a constituent of the cue.</p><p>For the drawbacks of the Bioscope corpus guidelines either on itself or for Chinese lan- guage, we introduced some modifications. These main changes are summarized below: (G3) A cue is annotated only relying on its actual semantic in context.</p><p>(E4) 大盘不可能再次出现高开低走.</p><p>(It is not possible that the broader market opens high but slips later again.) To G3, "不可能(not possible)" means that the author denies the possibility of the situation that "the broader market opens high but slips later again", which contains negative meanings than speculative. Thus, the phrase "不可能(not possi- ble)" should be labeled as a negative cue. (G4) A scope should contain the subject which contributes to the meaning of the content being negated or speculated if possible.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>(E5) *Once again, the Disorder module does</head><p>[not contribute positively to the prediction]. The BioScope corpus suggests that the scope of negative adverbs usually starts with the cue and ends at the end of the phrase, clause or sen- tence (E5). However, in our view, the scope should contain the subject for the integrity of meaning. Following is an exceptional case. (G5) Scope should be a continuous fragment in sentence.</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">(E6) 酒店有高档的配套设施,然而却[不能多给 我们提供一个枕头].</formula><p>(The hotel are furnished with upscale facili- ties, but [cannot offer us one more pillow].) Some rhetoric in Chinese language, such as parallelism or ellipsis, often gives rise to separa- tion of some sentence constituents from others. For example, in Sentence (E6), the subject of the second clause should be " 酒 店 (the hotel)", which is omitted. In this situation, we only need to identify the negative or speculative part in sen- tence than all semantic constituents which can be completed through other NLP technologies, such as zero subject anaphora resolution or semantic role labeling. (G6) A negative or speculative character or word may not be a cue.</p><p>(E7) 早茶的种类之多不得不赞.</p><p>(We are difficult not to give credit to the variety of morning snack.) We have come across several cases where the presence of a negative or speculative character or word does not denote negative or speculative meaning. For example, there are lots of double negatives in Chinese language only for empha- sizing than negative meanings. In Sentence (E7), obviously, the author wants to emphasis the praise of the variety of breakfast buffet by using the phrase "不得不(be difficult not to)" which does not imply a negative meaning.</p><p>The CNeSp corpus is annotated by two inde- pendent annotators who are not allowed to com- municate with each other. A linguist expert re- solves the differences between the two annota- tors and modified the guidelines when they are confronted with problematic issues, yielding the gold standard labeling of the corpus. <ref type="table">Table 1</ref> summarizes the chief characteristics of the three sub-corpora, including Scientific Litera- ture (Sci., for short), Financial Article (Fin.), and Product Review (Prod.). As shown in <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>, out of the total amount of 16,841 sentences more than 20% contained negation or speculation, con- firming the availability for corpus.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3">Statistics and Agreement Analysis</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Item</head><p>Sci  <ref type="table">Table 2</ref>. Inter-annotator agreement. We measured the inter-annotator agreement of annotating cues and their linguistic scope for all of three sub-corpora between the two independ- ent annotators in terms of Kappa <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Cohen, 1960)</ref>. The results are shown in <ref type="table">Table 2</ref>. The 2nd and 4th rows of the table show the kappa value of only cue annotation for negation and speculation, respectively. The 3rd and 5th rows show the agreement rate for both cue and its full scope. The most obvious conclusions here are that the identification of speculation is more complicated than negation even for humans because of the higher ambiguity of cues and the longer average length of scopes in speculation.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Chinese Negation and Speculation Identification</head><p>As a pipeline task, negation and speculation identification generally consists of two basic stages, cue detection and scope resolution. The former detects whether a word or phrase implies negative or speculative meanings, while the latter determines the sequences of terms which are dominated by the corresponding cue in sentence.</p><p>In this section, we improve our cue detection system by using the morpheme features of Chi- nese characters and expanding the cue clusters based on bilingual parallel corpora. Then, we present a new syntactic structure-based frame- work for Chinese language, which regards the sub-structures of dependency tree selected by a heuristic rule as scope candidates.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">Cue Detection</head><p>Most of the existing cue detection approaches are proposed from feature engineering perspective. They formulate cue detection as a classification issue, which is to classify each token in sentence as being the element of cue or not.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Feature-based sequence labeling model</head><p>At the beginning, we explore the performance of an English cue detection system, as described in <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Agarwal and Yu (2010)</ref>, which employs a condi- tional random fields (abbr., CRFs) model with lexical and syntactic features. Unfortunately, the performance is very low on Chinese texts (Sec- tion 5.1). This may be attributed to the different characteristic of Chinese language, for example, no word boundaries and lack of morphologic variations. Such low performance drives us to investigate new effective features which are par- ticularly appropriate for Chinese. We employed three kinds of features for cue detection: 1) N-gram features For each character c i , assuming its 5-windows characters are c i-2 c i-1 c i c i+1 c i+2 , we adopt follow- ing features:</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">c i-2 , c i-1 , c i , c i+1 , c i+2 , c i-1 c i , c i c i+1 , c i- 2 c i-1 c i , c i-1 c i c i+1 , c i c i+1 c i+2 .</formula><p>2) Lexical features To achieve high performance as much as pos- sible, we also use some useful basic features which are widely used in other NLP tasks on Chinese. The basic feature set consists of POS tag, the left/right character and its PoS tag. It is worth noting that the cue candidates in our model are characters. Thus, in order to get these fea- tures, we substitute them with corresponding fea- tures of the words which contain the characters.</p><p>3</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>) Morpheme features</head><p>The word-formation of Chinese implies that almost all of the meanings of a word are made up by the morphemes, a minimal meaningful unit in Chinese language contained in words. This more fine-grained semantics are the compositional se- mantics inside Chinese words namely. We as- sume that the morphemes in a given cue are also likely to be contained in other cues. For example, "猜测(guess)" is a given speculative cue which consists of " 猜 (guess)" and " 测 (speculate)", while the morpheme "猜(guess)" could be ap- peared in "猜想(suppose)". In consideration of the Chinese characteristics, we use every poten- tial character in cues to get the morpheme feature.</p><p>A Boolean feature is taken to represent the morpheme information. Specifically, the charac- ters which appear more than once within differ- ent cues in training corpus were selected as the features. The morpheme feature is set to 1, if the character is a negative or speculative morpheme.</p><p>For the ability of capturing the local infor- mation around a cue, we choose CRFs, a condi- tional sequence model which represents the probability of a hidden state sequence given some observations, as classifier to label each character with a tag indicating whether it is out of a cue (O), the beginning of the cue (B) or a part of the cue except the beginning one (I). In this way, our CRFs-based cue identifier performs sequential labeling by assigning each character one of the three tags and a character assigned with tag B is concatenated with following char- acters with tag I to form a cue.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Cross-lingual Cue Expansion Strategy</head><p>The feature-based cue detection approach men- tioned above shows that a bottleneck lies in low recall (see <ref type="table" target="#tab_5">Table 4</ref>). This is probably due to the absence of about 12% negation cues and 17% speculation cues from the training data. It is a challenging task to identify unknown cues with the limited amount of training data. Hence, we propose a cross-lingual cue expansion strategy.</p><p>In the approach, we take use of the top 5 Chi- nese cues in training corpus as our "anchor set". For each cue, we search its automatically aligned English words from a Chinese-English parallel corpus to construct an English word cluster. The parallel corpus consisting of 100,000 sentence pairs is built by using Liu's approach ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Liu et al., 2014)</ref>, which combines translation model with language model to select high-quality translation pairs from 16 million sentence pairs. The word alignment was obtained by running Giza++ <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Och and Ney, 2003)</ref>. In each cluster, we record the frequency of each unique English word. Consid- ering the word alignment errors in cross-lingual clusters, we filter the clusters by word alignment probability which is formulated as below: m n align w w is the number of alignments of word w m and word w n in parallel corpus. ∑i <ref type="bibr">( , )</ref> mi n align w w is the sum of the num- ber of alignments which contain word w n . The parameter α∈ <ref type="bibr">[0,</ref><ref type="bibr">1]</ref> is the coefficient controlling the relative contributions from the two directions of translation probability.</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">( | ) (1 ) ( | )      A E C C E P P w w P w w ( , ) ( , ) (1 ) ( ) ( )      E C E C C E P w w P w w P w P w ( , ) ( , ) (1 ) ( , )<label>( ,</label></formula><p>Then we conduct the same procedure in the other direction to construct Chinese word clus- ters anchored by English cues, until no new word comes about. For example, applying the above approach from the cue "可能(may)", we obtain 59 Chinese speculative cues. All of words in the final expansion cluster are identified as cues.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">Scope Resolution</head><p>Currently, mainstream approaches formulated the scope resolution as a chunking problem, which classifies every word of a sentence as be- ing inside or outside the scope of a cue. However, unlike in English, we found that plenty of errors occurred in Chinese scope resolution by using words as the basic identifying candidate.</p><p>In this paper we propose a new framework us- ing the sub-structures of dependency tree as scope candidates. Specifically, given a cue, we adopt the following heuristic rule to get the scope candidates in the dependency tree.</p><p>Setting constituent X and its siblings as the root nodes of candidate structure of scope, X should be the ancestor node of cue or cue itself.</p><p>For example, in the sentence "所有住客均表 示不会追究酒店的这次管理失职(All of guests said that they would not investigate the derelic- tion of hotel)", the negative cue "不(not)" has four constituent Xs and seven scope candidates, as shown in <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref>. According to the above rule, three ancestor nodes {Xa: "表示(said)", Xb: "追究(investigate)", and Xc: "会(would)"} cor- respond to three scope candidates (a, b1, and c), <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref>. Examples of a negative cue and its seven scope candidates in dependency tree.  and the cue itself is certainly a scope candidate (d). In addition, the Xb node has two siblings in dependency tree {"住客(guests)" and "均(all of)"}. Therefore, the two scope candidates cor- responding to them are b2 and b3, respectively. Similarly, the sibling of the Xc node is labeled as candidate c2. A binary classifier is applied to determine each candidate as either part of scope or not. In this paper, we employ some lexical and syntactic features about cue and candidate. <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">Table 3</ref> lists all of the features for scope resolution classification (with candidate b1 as the focus constituent (i.e., the scope candidate) and "不(not)" as the giv- en cue, regarding candidate b1 in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 1(2)</ref>).</p><p>For clarity, we categorize the features into three groups according to their relevance with the giv- en cue (C, in short), scope candidate (S, in short), and the relationship between cue andcandidate (R, in short). <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 2</ref> shows four kinds of posi- tional features between cue and scope candidate we defined (R4). Some features proposed above may not be ef- fective in classification. Therefore, we adopt a greedy feature se-lection algorithm as described in <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(Jiang and Ng, 2006</ref>) to pick up positive fea- tures incrementally according to their contribu-tions on the development data. Additionally, a cue should have one continuous block as its scope, but the scope identifier may result in dis- continuous scope due to independent candidate in classification. For this reason, we employ a post-processing algorithm as described in <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Zhu et al. (2010)</ref> to identify the boundaries.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Experimentation</head><p>In this section, we evaluate our feature-based sequence labeling model and cross-lingual cue expansion strategy on cue detection, and report the experimental results to justify the appropri- ateness of our syntactic structure-based frame- work on scope resolution in Chinese language.</p><p>The performance is measured by Precision (P), Recall (R), and F1-score (F). In addition, for scope resolution, we also report the accuracy in PCS (Percentage of Correct Scopes), within which a scope is fully correct if the output of scope resolution system and the correct scope have been matched exactly.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.1">Cue Detection</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results of the Sequence Labeling Model</head><p>Every sub-corpus is randomly divided into ten equal folds so as to perform ten-fold cross vali- dation. Lexical features are gained by using an open-source Chinese language processing plat- form, LTP 1 ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Che et al., 2010</ref>) to perform word segmentation, POS tagging, and syntactic pars- ing. CRF++0.58 2 toolkit is employed as our se- quence labeling model for cue detection. <ref type="table" target="#tab_5">Table 4</ref> lists the performances of cue detection systems using a variety of features. It shows that the morpheme features derived from the word- formation of Chinese improve the performance for both negation and speculation cue detection systems on all kinds of sub-corpora. However, the one exception occurs in negation cue detec- tion on the Product Review sub-corpus, in which the performance is decreased about 4.55% in precision. By error analysis, we find out the main reason is due to the pseudo cues. For example, "非常(very)" is identified by the negative mor- pheme "非(-un)", which is a pseudo cue. <ref type="table" target="#tab_5">Table 4</ref> also shows a bottleneck of our se- quence labeling model, which lies in low recall. Due to the diversity of Chinese language, many cues only appear a few times in corpus. For ex-ample, 83% (233/280) of speculative cues appear less than ten times in Financial Article sub- corpus. This data sparse problem directly leads to the low recall of cue detection.  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Negation</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results of the Cross-lingual Cue Expansion Strategy</head><p>Before cue expansion, we select the parameter α as defined in formula (1) by optimizing the F1- measure score of on Financial Article sub-corpus. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 3</ref> shows the effect on F1-measure of vary- ing the coefficient from 0 to 1. We can see that the best performance can be obtained by select- ing parameter 0.6 for negation and 0.7 for specu- lation. Then we apply these parameter values directly for cue expansion.  <ref type="table">Table 5</ref> lists the performances of feature-based system, expansion-based system, and the com- bined system. A word is identified as a cue by combined system if it is identified by one of the above systems (Feat-based or Exp-based) at least.</p><p>For both negation and speculation, the cross- lingual cue expansion approach provides signifi- cant improvement over the feature-based se- quence labeling model, achieving about 15-20% better recall with little loss in precision. More importantly, the combined system obtains the best performance.  <ref type="table">Table 5</ref>. Performance of cue detection.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Negation</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.2">Syntactic Structure-based Scope Reso- lution</head><p>Considering the effectiveness of different fea- tures, we divide the Financial Article sub-corpus into 5 equal parts, within which 2 parts are used for feature selection. Then, the feature selection data are divided into 5 equal parts, within which 4 parts for training and the rest for developing. On this data set, a greedy feature selection algo- rithm ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Jiang and Ng, 2006</ref>) is adopted to pick up positive features proposed in <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">Table 3</ref>. In addition, SVM Light3 with the default parameter is selected as our classifier. <ref type="table">Table 6</ref> lists the performance of selected fea- tures. 7 features {C1, C2, S4, S5, S6, R1, R4} are selected consecutively for negation scope resolution, while 9 features {C2, S1, S3, S4, S5, R1, R2, R3, R4} are selected for speculation scope resolution. We will include those selected features in all the remaining experiments.  <ref type="table">Table 6</ref>. Feature selection for scope resolution on golden cues (PCS %).</p><p>The feature selection experiments suggest that the feature C2 (POS of cue) plays a critical role for both negation and speculation scope resolu- tion. It may be due to the fact that cues of differ- ent POS usually undertake different syntactic roles. Thus, there are different characteristics in triggering linguistic scopes. For example, an ad- jective cue may treat a modificatory structure as 3 http://svmlight.joachims.org its scope, while a conjunction cue may take the two connected components as its scope.</p><p>As a pipeline task, the negation and specula- tion identification could be regarded as a combi- nation of two sequential tasks: first, cue detection, and then scope resolution. Hence, we turn to a more realistic scenario in which cues are auto- matically recognized.  <ref type="table">Table 7</ref>. Performance of scope resolution with automatic cue detection. <ref type="table">Table 7</ref> lists the performance of scope resolu- tion by using automatic cues. It shows that auto- matic cue detection lowers the performance by 3.08, 6.83, and 8.76 in PCS for the three sub- corpora, respectively; while it lowers the perfor- mance by 5.80, 8.31 and 13.11 in PCS for specu- lation scope resolution on the three sub-corpora, respectively (refer to <ref type="table">Table 6</ref>). The main reason of performance lost is the error propagation from the automatic cue detection.</p><p>We employ a start-of-the-art chunking-based scope resolution system (described in <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">Zou et al., (2013)</ref>) as a baseline, in which every word in sentence has been labelled as being the element of the scope or not. <ref type="table">Table 8</ref> compares our syntac- tic structure-based framework with the chunking- based framework on scope resolution. Note that all the performances are achieved on Financial Article sub-corpus by using golden cues. The results in <ref type="table">Table 8</ref> shows that our scope resolution system outperforms the chunking ones both on negation and speculation, improving 8.75 and 7.44 in PCS, respectively.  <ref type="table">Table 8</ref>. Comparison with the chunking-based system on Financial Article sub-corpus.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Conclusion</head><p>In this paper we construct a Chinese corpus for negation and speculation identification, which annotates cues and their linguistic scopes. For cue detection, we present a feature-based se- quence labeling model, in which the morpheme feature is employed to better catch the com- position semantics inside the Chinese words. Complementally, a cross-lingual cue expansion strategy is pro-posed to increase the coverage in cue detection. For scope resolution, we present a new syntactic structure-based framework to iden- tify the linguistic scope of a cue. Evaluation jus- tifies the usefulness of our Chinese corpus and the appropriateness of the syntactic structure- based framework. It also shows that our ap- proach outperforms the state-of-the-art chunking ones on negation and speculation identification in Chinese language. In the future we will explore more effective features to improve the negation and speculation identification in Chinese language, and focus on joint learning of the two subtasks.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>(</head><label></label><figDesc>E1) 所有住客均表示[不会追究酒店的这次管 理失职]. (All of guests said that they [would not in- vestigate the dereliction of hotel].) (E2) 尽管上周五沪指盘中还受创业板的下跌 所拖累,但[后期仍有望反弹].</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2. Positional features.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 3 .</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Figure 3. The effect of varying the value of parameter α on Financial Article sub-corpus.</figDesc><graphic url="image-3.png" coords="7,326.43,473.94,177.60,140.40" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" validated="false"><head>is the translation probability of English word w E conditioned on Chinese word w C , reversely, while ( | ) C E P w w is the translation probability of Chinese word w C conditioned on English word w E .</head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><table>) 

 
 

 
 

 
 

E 
C 
E 
C 

Ei 
C 
Ci 
E 
i 
i 

align w w 
align w w 

align w w 
align w w 

(1) 

where ( | ) 

E 
C 

P w w ( , ) 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3" validated="false"><head>Table 3 .</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Features and their instantiations for scope resolution.</figDesc><table></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_5" validated="false"><head>Table 4 .</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Contribution of features to cue detection.</figDesc><table></table></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> http://www.ltp-cloud.com 2 https://crfpp.googlecode.com/svn/trunk/doc/index.html</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Detecting hedge cues and their scope in biomedical text with conditional random fields</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Shashank</forename><surname>Agarwal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hong</forename><surname>Yu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Biomedical Informatics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">43</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="953" to="961" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Context-sensitive medical information retrieval</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mordechai</forename><surname>Averbuch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tom</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Karson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Benjamin</forename><surname>Ben-Ami</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Oded</forename><surname>Maimon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lior</forename><surname>Rokach</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 11th World Congress on Medical Informatics (MEDINFO&apos;04</title>
		<meeting>the 11th World Congress on Medical Informatics (MEDINFO&apos;04</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="8" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A modality lexicon and its use in automatic tagging</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kathrin</forename><surname>Baker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Bloodgood</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bonnie</forename><surname>Dorr</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nathaniel</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Filardo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lori</forename><surname>Levin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christine</forename><surname>Piatko</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Seventh Conference on International Language Resources and Evaluation (LREC&apos;10</title>
		<meeting>the Seventh Conference on International Language Resources and Evaluation (LREC&apos;10</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1402" to="1407" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">LTP: A Chinese language technology platform</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wanxiang</forename><surname>Che</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Zhenghua</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ting</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 23rd International Conference on Computational Linguistics (COLING&apos;10): Demonstrations</title>
		<meeting>the 23rd International Conference on Computational Linguistics (COLING&apos;10): Demonstrations</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="13" to="16" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Exploiting the scope of negations and heterogeneous features for relation extraction: A case study for drug-drug interaction extraction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Md</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alberto</forename><surname>Faisal Mahbub Chowdhury</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Lavelli</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2013 Conference of the North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics: Human Language Technologies (NAACL-HLT&apos;13)</title>
		<meeting>the 2013 Conference of the North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics: Human Language Technologies (NAACL-HLT&apos;13)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="765" to="771" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A coefficient of agreement for nominal scales</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jacob</forename><surname>Cohen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Educational and Psychological Measurement</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="37" to="46" />
			<date type="published" when="1960" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">What&apos;s great and what&apos;s not: Learning to classify the scope of negation for improved sentiment analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Isaac</forename><surname>Councill</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ryan</forename><surname>Mcdonald</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Leonid</forename><surname>Velikovich</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Workshop on Negation and Speculation in Natural Language Processing</title>
		<meeting>the Workshop on Negation and Speculation in Natural Language Processing</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="51" to="59" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Semantic role labeling of NomBank: A maximum entropy approach</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Zhengping</forename><surname>Jiang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Hwee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Ng</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Human Language Technology Conference and Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP&apos;06)</title>
		<meeting>the Human Language Technology Conference and Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP&apos;06)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="138" to="145" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Effective selection of translation model training data</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Le</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yu</forename><surname>Hong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hao</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xing</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jianmin</forename><surname>Yao</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 52nd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL&apos;14)</title>
		<meeting>the 52nd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL&apos;14)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Short Papers</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="569" to="573" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Exploring uncertainty sentences in Chinese</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Feng</forename><surname>Ji</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xipeng</forename><surname>Qiu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xuanjing</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 16th China Conference on Information Retreval</title>
		<meeting>the 16th China Conference on Information Retreval</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="594" to="601" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Learning the scope of negation in biomedical texts</title>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Human Language Technology Conference and Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP&apos;08)</title>
		<editor>Roser Morante, Anthony Liekens, and Walter Daelemans</editor>
		<meeting>the Human Language Technology Conference and Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP&apos;08)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="715" to="724" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Modality and negation: an introduction to the special issue</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Roser</forename><surname>Morante</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Caroline</forename><surname>Sporleder</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Comput. Linguist</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">38</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="223" to="260" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A systematic comparison of various statistical alignment models</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Josef</forename><surname>Franz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hermann</forename><surname>Och</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Ney</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Comput. Linguist</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">29</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="19" to="51" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A sentimental education: sentiment analysis using subjectivity</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bo</forename><surname>Pang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lillian</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 42nd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL&apos;04)</title>
		<meeting>the 42nd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL&apos;04)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="271" to="278" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Effectively using syntax for recognizing false entailment</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rion</forename><surname>Snow</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lucy</forename><surname>Vanderwende</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Arul</forename><surname>Menezes</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Main Conference on Human Language Technology Conference of the North American Chapter of the Association of Computational Linguistics (HLTNAACL&apos;06)</title>
		<meeting>the Main Conference on Human Language Technology Conference of the North American Chapter of the Association of Computational Linguistics (HLTNAACL&apos;06)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="33" to="40" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The BioScope corpus: biomedical texts annotated for uncertainty, negation and their scopes</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Veronika</forename><surname>Vincze</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">György</forename><surname>Szarvas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Richárd</forename><surname>Farkas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">György</forename><surname>Móra</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">János</forename><surname>Csirik</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">BMC Bioinformatics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">9</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Suppl</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Enriching parallel corpora for statistical machine translation with semantic negation rephrasing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dominikus</forename><surname>Wetzel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Francis</forename><surname>Bond</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 6th Workshop on Syntax, Semantics and Structure in Statistical Translation</title>
		<meeting>the 6th Workshop on Syntax, Semantics and Structure in Statistical Translation</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="20" to="29" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A Unified Framework for Scope Learning via Simplified Shallow Semantic Parsing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Qiaoming</forename><surname>Zhu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Junhui</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hongling</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Guodong</forename><surname>Zhou</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2010 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP&apos;10)</title>
		<meeting>the 2010 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP&apos;10)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="714" to="724" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">An empirical study on the effect of negation words on sentiment</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xiaodan</forename><surname>Zhu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hongyu</forename><surname>Guo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Saif</forename><surname>Mohammad</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Svetlana</forename><surname>Kiritchenko</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 52nd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL&apos;14</title>
		<meeting>the 52nd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL&apos;14</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="304" to="313" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Tree kernel-based negation and speculation scope detection with structured syntactic parse features</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bowei</forename><surname>Zou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Guodong</forename><surname>Zhou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Qiaoming</forename><surname>Zhu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2013 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP&apos;13)</title>
		<meeting>the 2013 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP&apos;13)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="968" to="976" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
