<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T12:57+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main"></title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kuan-Yu</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Emily</forename><surname>Bender</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><roleName>Microsoft</roleName><forename type="first">Chin-Yew</forename><surname>Lin</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Stephan</forename><surname>Oepen</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Timothy</forename><surname>Baldwin</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">John</forename><surname>Carroll</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Stephen</forename><surname>Clark</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lars</forename><surname>Hellan</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Aravind</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Joshi</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Min-Yen</forename><surname>Kan</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wei</forename><surname>Lu</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alessandro</forename><surname>Moschitti</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Faculty Advisors</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Walter Daelemans</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">University of Melbourne Srinivas Bangalore, AT&amp;T Labs-Research António Branco, University of Lisbon Chris Brew, Thomson-Reuters Claire Cardie Kevin Knight, University of Southern California Philipp Koehn</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">National Taiwan University Angelina Ivanova</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">University of Oslo Ellie Pavlick</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit3">University of Pennsylvania</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit4">University of Washington</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit5">University of Oslo</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit6">Cornell University</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit7">University of Sussex</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit8">University of Cambridge</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit9">University of Antwerp</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit10">Norwegian University of Science and Technology Kristiina Jokinen</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit11">University of Helsinki</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit12">University of Pennsylvania</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit13">National University of Singapore</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit14">University of Edinburgh</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit15">Kyoto University</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Zheng-Hua Li</addrLine>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="laboratory" key="lab1">Singapore University of Technology and Design Daniel Marcu, University of Southern California Mitchell Marcus, University of Pennsylvania Diana McCarthy, University of Cambridge Kathy McKeown, Columbia University Rada Mihalcea</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory" key="lab2">The University of Texas at Dallas Joakim Nivre, Uppsala University Kemal Oflazer, Carnegie Mellon University in Qatar Miles Osborne, Bloomberg v</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Soochow University</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">University of Michigan</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit3">University of Trento Vincent Ng</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<note>Production and Manufacturing by Taberg Media Group AB Box 94, 562 02 Taberg Sweden Order print-on-demand copies from: Curran Associates 57 Morehouse Lane Red Hook, New York 12571 USA ii iii Organizers: Program Committee: Michael Elhadad, Ben-Gurion University of the Negev Katrin Erk, University of Texas at Austin George Foster, Google Ralph Grishman, New York University Jan Haji˘ c, Charles University in Prague Dilek Hakkani-Tur, Microsoft Research</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract/>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Introduction</head><p>Welcome to the ACJ-IJCNLP 2015 Student Research Workshop! Following the tradition of the previous years' workshops, we have two tracks: research papers and thesis proposals. The research papers track is as a venue for Ph.D. students, masters students, and advanced undergraduates to describe completed work or work-in-progress along with preliminary results. The thesis proposal track is offered for advanced Ph.D. students who have decided on a thesis topic and are interested in feedback about their proposal and ideas about future directions for their work.</p><p>We received in total 18 submissions: 5 thesis proposals and 13 research papers. Of these, we accepted 3 thesis proposals and 4 research papers, giving an acceptance rate of 39% overall: 60% for thesis proposals and 31% for research papers.</p><p>This year, all of the accepted papers will be presented as posters alongside the main conference short paper posters on the second day of the conference. In addition, authors will each have a chance to give a short oral presentation to advertise their work. The oral session will be held on immediately prior to the poster session.</p><p>Mentoring programs are a central part of the SRW. This year, students had the opportunity to participate in a pre-submission mentoring program prior to the submission deadline. The mentoring offers students a chance to receive comments from an experienced researcher in the field, in order to improve the quality of the writing and presentation before making their final submission. Fourteen authors participated in the pre-submission mentoring, more than twice as many as participated last year.</p><p>In addition, authors of accepted papers are matched with mentors who will meet with the students in person during the workshop. This year, each research paper is assigned two mentors and each thesis proposal is assigned one mentor. Each mentor will prepare in-depth comments and questions prior to the student's presentation, and will provide discussion and feedback during the workshop.</p><p>We are very grateful for the generous financial support from BAOBAG Language Solutions, Google, the Don and Betty Walker Scholarship Fund, and the National Science Foundation. The support of our sponsors allows the SRW to cover the travel and lodging expenses of the authors, keeping the workshop accessible to all students.</p><p>We would also like to thank our program committee members for their constructive reviews for each paper and all of our mentors for donating their time to work one-on-one with our student authors. Thank you to our faculty advisers for their advice and guidance, and to the ACL-IJCNLP 2015 organizing committee for their constant support. Finally, a huge thank you to all students for their submissions and their participation in this year's SRW. Looking forward to a wonderful workshop!  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Massimo Poesio, University of Essex Jonathon Read, Teesside University Satoshi Sekine, New York University Mark Steedman, University of Edinburgh Keh-Yih Su, National Tsing Hua University</head><note type="other">Mihai Surdeanu, Univesity of Arizona Pre-submission Mentors: Marine Carpuat, National Research Council Canada Silvie Cinková, Charles University in Prague Hal Daumé III, University of Maryland Michael Gamon, Microsoft Research Ralph Grishman, New York University Sophia Katrenko, Elsevier Haizhou Li, Institute for Infocomm</note></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" validated="false"><head>Table of Contents</head><label>of</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Unsupervised Learning and Modeling of Knowledge and Intent for Spoken Dialogue Systems 
Yun-Nung Chen . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . 1 

Leveraging Compounds to Improve Noun Phrase Translation from Chinese and German 
Xiao Pu, Laura Mascarell, Andrei Popescu-Belis, Mark Fishel, Ngoc-Quang Luong and Martin 
Volk . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . 8 

Learning Representations for Text-level Discourse Parsing 
Gregor Weiss . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . 16 

Transition-based Dependency DAG Parsing Using Dynamic Oracles 
Alper Tokgöz and Gül¸senGül¸sen Eryi˘ git . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . 22 

Disease Event Detection based on Deep Modality Analysis 
Yoshiaki Kitagawa, Mamoru Komachi, Eiji Aramaki, Naoaki Okazaki and Hiroshi Ishikawa . . . 28 

Evaluation Dataset and System for Japanese Lexical Simplification 
Tomoyuki Kajiwara and Kazuhide Yamamoto . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . 35 

Learning to Map Dependency Parses to Abstract Meaning Representations 
Wei-Te Chen . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . 41 

vii 

Workshop Program 

Monday, July 27, 2015 

11:50-13:20 Student Lunch 

Tuesday, July 28, 2015 

16:30-17:55 Student Oral Presentations 

16:30-16:45 Unsupervised Learning and Modeling of Knowledge and Intent for Spoken Dialogue 
Systems 
Yun-Nung Chen 

16:45-16:55 Leveraging Compounds to Improve Noun Phrase Translation from Chinese and 
German 
Xiao Pu, Laura Mascarell, Andrei Popescu-Belis, Mark Fishel, Ngoc-Quang Luong 
and Martin Volk 

16:55-17:10 Learning Representations for Text-level Discourse Parsing 
Gregor Weiss 

17:10-17:20 Transition-based Dependency DAG Parsing Using Dynamic Oracles 
Alper Tokgöz and Gül¸senGül¸sen Eryi˘ git 

17:20-17:30 Disease Event Detection based on Deep Modality Analysis 
Yoshiaki Kitagawa, Mamoru Komachi, Eiji Aramaki, Naoaki Okazaki and Hiroshi 
Ishikawa 

17:30-17:40 Evaluation Dataset and System for Japanese Lexical Simplification 
Tomoyuki Kajiwara and Kazuhide Yamamoto 

17:40-17:55 Learning to Map Dependency Parses to Abstract Meaning Representations 
Wei-Te Chen 

18:00-19:30 Poster and Dinner Session 

ix </table></figure>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl/>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
