<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T12:51+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Joint Graphical Models for Date Selection in Timeline Summarization</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
				<availability status="unknown"><p>Copyright Association for Computational Linguistics</p>
				</availability>
				<date>July 26-31, 2015. 2015</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Giang</forename><surname>Tran</surname></persName>
							<email>gtran@l3s.de</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory" key="lab1">L3S Research Center Leibniz-University Hannover</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory" key="lab2">L3S Research Center Leibniz-University Hannover Katja Markert L3S Research Center Leibniz-University Hannover and School of Computing University of Leeds</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Eelco</forename><surname>Herder</surname></persName>
							<email>herder@l3s.de</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory" key="lab1">L3S Research Center Leibniz-University Hannover</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory" key="lab2">L3S Research Center Leibniz-University Hannover Katja Markert L3S Research Center Leibniz-University Hannover and School of Computing University of Leeds</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Joint Graphical Models for Date Selection in Timeline Summarization</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 53rd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics and the 7th International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing</title>
						<meeting>the 53rd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics and the 7th International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing <address><addrLine>Beijing, China</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="1598" to="1607"/>
							<date type="published">July 26-31, 2015. 2015</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Automatic timeline summarization (TLS) generates precise, dated overviews over (often prolonged) events, such as wars or economic crises. One subtask of TLS selects the most important dates for an event within a certain time frame. Date selection has up to now been handled via supervised machine learning approaches that estimate the importance of each date separately , using features such as the frequency of date mentions in news corpora. This approach neglects interactions between different dates that occur due to connections between subevents. We therefore suggest a joint graphical model for date selection. Even unsupervised versions of this model perform as well as supervised state-of-the-art approaches. With parameter tuning on training data, it outperforms prior supervised models by a considerable margin.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Major events (such as the Egypt revolution starting in 2011) often last over a long period of time and have impact for a considerable time afterwards. In order to find out what happened when during such an event, time-related queries to search engines are often insufficient as traditional IR does not handle time-related queries well <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Foley and Allan, 2015)</ref>. To provide readers with comprehensive overviews of long events, many news outlets employ time- line summaries: a timeline summary is a list of selected dates with a few sentences describing the most important events on each date. An example can be seen in <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table 1</ref>. Timelines allow the reader to gain a quick overview over a complex event and to answer questions such as: How and when did the event start? What were the main consequences of the initial events? What happened to the main protagonists in the event? In addition, timelines are frequent means in education (such as history teaching) so that their generation is relevant for education as well as journalism.  Though convenient for the reader, the manual creation of a timeline can take a long time even for experts. For example, the creator of the start- up Timeline says that it initially took a multi- person team a full work day to create a single timeline. <ref type="bibr">1</ref> Therefore, automatic timeline summa- rization (TLS) has emerged as an NLP task in the past few years ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">Tran et al., 2013a;</ref><ref type="bibr">Kessler et al., 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Nguyen et al., 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b25">Yan et al., 2011b;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Yan et al., 2011a</ref>; <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Wang et al., 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Tran et al., 2013b;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b21">Tran et al., 2015)</ref>. TLS has been divided into two subtasks: (i) ranking the dates between beginning and end of the timeline in order of importance, to achieve date selection and (ii) generating a good daily summary for each of the selected dates. In this paper, we tackle the first task. Date selection is challenging, as normally only a small set of the available dates is chosen for inclusion in the time- line (see <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table 1</ref>). Date selection may be partially subjective: different journalists might include dif- ferent dates. <ref type="bibr">2</ref> Existing approaches to date selection ( <ref type="bibr">Kessler et al., 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b19">Tran et al., 2013a</ref>) use supervised ma- chine learning, where each date receives a score for ranking the dates. Features used (such as fre- quency of date mention) are extracted from a cor- pus of event-related newspaper articles. Though the features are well-explored, the models score each date independently of other dates.</p><p>In contrast, we argue that interaction between dates should be taken into account. Timeline summaries tend to include "substories" in which the majority of selected dates are part of a chain of events that share major actors or demonstrate cause-effect. <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table 1</ref> shows at least two such chains: the (a1-4-5) chain of protests leading to Mubarak's resignation and the necessity of new elections, as well as the similar (a8-10-26) chain on Mursi. These chains can also be observed in the corresponding news articles. For example, some background articles on Mubarak's step-down will likely explain the reasons behind it. However, ex- tracting such causal information can be difficult, as demonstrated by the still low results for dis- course relation extraction ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Lin et al., 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Braud and Denis, 2014</ref>). Instead, we use date reference graphs, which model which date refers to which other date. In our example, articles published on Mubarak's resignation date might refer to the date when the protest started. Although weaker than direct causal links, these links are easy to extract and we will show that they are very useful. In ad- dition, references from important dates (such as Mubarak's resignation date) should be weighted higher than other references. This is akin to IR models such as PageRank, which weigh links from popular pages higher than links from less popular pages.</p><p>The main contributions of this work are: (i) we leverage interaction between dates via date ref- erence graphs as a basis for date selection in TLS (ii) we provide a novel random walk model on this graph that incorporates both topical importance of referring sentences as well as frequency and tem- poral distance of references. We propose both un- supervised as well as supervised versions of this model.</p><p>We show that the proposed date selection approach outperforms previous approaches with evaluations on four real-life, long-term news events. We also discuss variations in timeline con- struction over different events, as well as by dif- ferent journalists.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Related Work</head><p>Timeline summarization is a special case of multi- document summarization (MDS). As TLS orga- nizes events by date, timelines can be generated by MDS systems (such as ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Radev et al., 2004b;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Radev et al., 2004a;</ref><ref type="bibr">McKeown et al., 2003;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Erkan and Radev, 2004;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Metzler and Kanungo, 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Hong and Nenkova, 2014</ref>) by applying their sum- marization techniques on news articles for every individual date to create corresponding daily sum- maries. However, manually written timelines nor- mally only include a small number of dates; in addition, the temporal component imposes con- straints on sentence selection for timeline sum- marization, such as the preference for little over- lap between sentences selected for different dates <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">(Yan et al., 2011b</ref>).</p><p>Many studies specific to timeline summariza- tion, such as <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">(Swan and Allan, 2000;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Allan et al., 2001;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Chieu and Lee, 2004;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b25">Yan et al., 2011b;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b21">Tran et al., 2015)</ref>, focus on the extraction of salient sentences or headlines for generating the textual content of timelines. They assume either that the dates are given in advance or they use simple mea- sures such as burstiness ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Chieu and Lee, 2004;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b25">Yan et al., 2011b</ref>) for date selection, where bursti- ness relies on the number of date mentions.</p><p>Prior approaches dedicated specifically to date selection are <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">Tran et al. (2013a)</ref> and <ref type="bibr">Kessler et al. (2012)</ref>. <ref type="bibr">3</ref> They use supervised machine learn- ing methods that score dates independently of each other. Features are extracted from a cor- pus of event-related newspaper articles, including frequency-based features (such as how often the date is referred to in the corpus), temporal distance features (such as how long into the future a date keeps being referred to) and topical features (such as whether the date mention is associated with the most significant keywords of the event). We, how- ever, score dates jointly, making use of interac- tions between dates in a graphical model. This improves substantially over prior approaches. We also propose unsupervised variations that perform competitively to prior supervised models.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Problem Definition and Approach</head><p>Similar to <ref type="bibr">Kessler et al. (2012)</ref> and <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">Tran et al. (2013a)</ref>, we use the day as the timeline time unit (so, for example, we exclude hourly timelines).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Problem Definition</head><p>Given a main event and a time window [t 1 , t 2 ] within the event duration, our task is to select the top k dates</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">(d 1 , d 2 , ..., d k ) ∈ [t 1 , t 2 ]</formula><p>, when the most important (sub)events occurred. Therefore, timelines of variable length can be constructed. Like ( <ref type="bibr">Kessler et al., 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b19">Tran et al., 2013a</ref>), we also assume that we have a corpus C, consisting of news articles about the main event. This corpus gives evidence about the dates in [t 1 , t 2 ].</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Proposed Approach</head><p>We build a date reference graph, which is a fully directed graph G = (V, E), where V is the set of dates mentioned in any text in corpus C, including publication dates. The edges E = {e(d i , d j )} in- dicate that at least one text published on d i refers to the date d j .</p><p>We represent each such link as a multi-value tuple</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">e(d i , d j ) = (M ij , f req(d i , d j ), I temporal (d i , d j ), I topical (d i , d j ))</formula><p>to integrate different measures of date importance. The first value, M ij = 1 N expresses the prior stochastic transitional probability between 2 dates where N = |V|. The others express the strength of the connection between d i and d j modelled by the following aspects: frequency (f req), temporal influence (I temporal ) and topical influence (I topical ). We also suggest different combinations of these parameters.</p><p>Then we introduce a random walk model that uses these perspectives to rank the collection of dates. Frequency of References. When a date d j is re- ferred to from either a past or future news article (published on d i ), it is likely involved in the events that are reported in that article. An example pub- lished on Mubarak's resignation date and referring back to the protest start can be seen below:</p><p>(1) On January 25, an uprising of Egyptians erupted calling for Mubaraks resignation as president. Protests contin- ued to grow . . . <ref type="bibr">(CBS Detroit, 2011-02-11)</ref> We hypothesize that the more frequent such references are, the stronger this involvement is. Hence, we compute f req(d i , d j ) as the number of references to d j from news articles published on d i . While prior work ( <ref type="bibr">Kessler et al., 2012)</ref> uses aggregate frequency of references to d j over the whole corpus as a feature, they do not handle the interaction between dates and can therefore not score dates jointly. Topical Influence. In Example 1 above, the ref- erence sentence mentions only major actors in the Egypt crisis (Mubarak, Egyptians) as well as only major subevents (uprising, protests). This makes for a link between 2011-02-11 (publication date) and 2011-01-25 (referred date) that is relevant to the main event and emphasises the importance of the referred date. In contrast, Example 2 also talks about less salient entities in context of the Egypt revolution and makes for a less topical link be- tween 2011-02-02 (publication date) and 2011-01- 25 (referred date).</p><p>(2) Mr Ghonim is Google's head of marketing for Mid- dle East and North Africa and was in Egypt when the protests started on Jan 25 (DailyMail, 2011-02-02).</p><p>We quantify the topical influence between dates as follows: Let S i→j = {s ij } be the set of sen- tences that are published in d i and refer to d j . We are interested in how relevant this connection is to the overall news event, looking at the content in S i→j . To do so, we represent the overall content of the news collection by a set of keywords Q = {q 1 , q 2 , ..., q n }, which are computed via TextRank ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Mihalcea and Tarau, 2004</ref>). <ref type="bibr">4</ref> We compute a rel- evance score for each sentence s ij in S i→j by the famous Okapi BM25 function ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Robertson et al., 1994)</ref>, which ranks a sentence more topical if it contains more as well as more of the most salient collection keywords Q. <ref type="bibr">5</ref> We compute topical in- fluence (I topical ) as either the maximum value or the sum value of the relevance scores of all s ij .</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">I max topical (di, dj) = max s ij ∈S i→j BM 25(sij, Q) (3) I f req * topical (di, dj) = s ij ∈S i→j BM 25(sij, Q) (4) Intuitively, I f req * topical (d i , d j ) is proportional</formula><p>to the size of S i→j as well as to the relevance scores of its sentences whereas I max topical (d i , d j ) does not consider reference frequency at all.</p><p>When d j is not mentioned by any articles pub- lished on d i , the value of the topical influence is equal to zero. Temporal Influence. The longer ago an event happened the more likely it is to have been for- gotten. Only very important events are referred to over long time frames. We therefore hypothesise that a date d j is more influential (for another date d i ) if d i mentions d j and the temporal distance between the two dates is high. Overall, d j gath- ers importance with several long-term references. Ex. 5 showcases an example: We define the temporal influence of an existing edge I temporal (d i , d j ) as either the absolute value of temporal distance between the two dates or by the product of the temporal distance with the num- ber of references f req(d i , d j ). In the second com- putation, the temporal influence between two dates increases when d i references d j more than once.</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">I |temporal| (di, dj) = ∆t = |di − dj| (6) I f req * temporal (di, dj) = f req(di, dj) · |di − dj|<label>(7)</label></formula><p>When d j is not mentioned by any articles pub- lished on d i , the temporal influence is set as zero.</p><p>Random Walk Model for Date Ranking. A random walk on a given graph is a Markov pro- cess, where each node represents a state and a walk transiting from one state to another state is based on a transition probability matrix. One well- known random walk algorithm is PageRank ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Page et al., 1999</ref>), which models web surfer behavior to determine the importance of web pages with the following formula:</p><formula xml:id="formula_4">xt(j) = α i∈L − j Mijxt−1(i) + (1 − α)vj,<label>(8)</label></formula><p>where M ij is the stochastic transition probability from page p i to p j , x t (j) is the importance score of page p j at step t, α is a damping factor that controls how often the walker jumps to an arbi- trary node, v j is the initial probabilistic impor- tance score (generally set to 1/N , where N is the number of nodes in the graph), and L − i is the set of incoming links of page p i . When t is iterated enough, the importance score vector reaches a sta- tionary distribution that can be used for ranking pages.</p><p>The traditional PageRank process in Eq. 8 cap- tures only the observed linking characteristics of nodes but ignores other sources of information which can be indicators for their importance. We extend the model by introducing an influence-based random walk model (IRW) that allows the random walker to take into account multiple sources of information and perform vot- ing more effectively. The random walk process we propose can be defined by the following formula:</p><formula xml:id="formula_5">xt(j) = α i∈L − j I(i, j) · Mij · xt−1(i) + (1 − α)vj (9)</formula><p>where I(i, j) is the normalized influence factor that indicates how influential the edge d i → d j is in the global context of the event. The normaliza- tion is done by scaling the range of value from <ref type="bibr">[0,</ref><ref type="bibr">1]</ref>. M is the stochastic transitional matrix. In our case, I(i, j) can be just the value of f req(</p><formula xml:id="formula_6">d i , d j ), I topical (d i , d j ) , I temporal (d i , d j )</formula><p>alone or a lin- ear combination of them. Note that, (I · M ) in most case is not stochastic and must not be trans- formed into a stochastic transitional matrix, as the transformation will collapse the global context of I. IRW is different to PageRank on weighted graph, weighted or personalized PageRank and their variations e.g, ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">Xing and Ghorbani, 2004;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Haveliwala, 2002</ref>), among others. In particu- lar, weighted PageRank integrates influence scores into the stochastic transitional matrix. Thus, the random walker contributes the voting impact of a node X to its neighbor with an influence score nor- malized by the sum of scores on all outgoing con- nections. That process leverages how good this connection is in the sub-graph (G*) which consists of X and its outgoing neighbors. In contrast, our proposed model uses the non-normalized value of the influence score to leverage how good this con- nection is on the entire graph instead of G*. To give an example, if date X1 mentions only X2 with a raw temporal distance score of 20 and X3 men- tions only X4 with a score of 100, then in weighted Page Rank both would be normalized to a weight one, losing the information that X4 is mentioned after a much longer time period than X2. The pro- cess for combination in our model is defined as the following:</p><formula xml:id="formula_7">xt(j) = αω i∈L − j W1(i, j) · Mij · xt−1(i) + α(1 − ω) i∈L − j W2(i, j) · Mij · xt−1(i) + (1 − α)vj (10)</formula><p>where</p><formula xml:id="formula_8">W 1 (i, j) = I topical (d i ,d j )</formula><p>maxuv I topical (du,dv) is the normalized value for topical influence, and</p><formula xml:id="formula_9">W 2 (i, j) = I temporal (d i ,d j )</formula><p>maxuv I temporal (du,dv) is the normalized value for temporal influence. <ref type="bibr">6</ref> Here, the hyper-parameter 0 ≤ ω ≤ 1 controls the proportion of the topical influence from d i to d j . When ω = 0, no topical influence is taken into account. No temporal influence is considered when ω = 1. Intuitively, at every step, the random walker can follow the outgoing nodes and either carry topical influence (the first part) or temporal influence (the second part) to contribute to the rank of the outgoing nodes. Otherwise, it teleports to an arbitrary node with probability (1 − α).</p><p>Convergence Property. Starting from Eq. 10, we now show that the IRW model converges to a stationary distribution.</p><p>Let Λ and Λ be the matrix with elements W 1 (i, j) and W 2 (ij) respectively, with any edge (d i , d j ), I be the n × n identity matrix, and v be the transpose of 1 × n uniform stochastic vector. M denotes the transitional matrix for G.</p><formula xml:id="formula_10">Proposition 1. (I − α(wM T Λ + (1 − ω)M T Λ ))</formula><p>is invertible for all M, Λ, Λ , α, ω.</p><p>Proof. Let P = wM T Λ + (1 − ω)M T Λ , we need to prove that I − αP is invertible. Equivalently, we prove its transpose I − αP T is invertible, which can be proved by showing that (I − αP T )y = 0 only has the trivial solution y = 0.</p><formula xml:id="formula_11">(I − αP T )y = 0 y = αP T y yi = α j Pjiyj = α j ((ωW1(i, j) + (1 − ω)W2(i, j))Mij yj ).<label>(11)</label></formula><p>Let u = arg maxj yj. When i == u, Eq. 11 infers,</p><formula xml:id="formula_12">yu ≤ α j ((ωW1(u, j) + (1 − ω)W2(u, j))Muj yu). yu ≤ αyu j ((ωW1(u, j) + (1 − ω)W2(u, j))Muj yu(1 − αFu) ≤ 0.<label>(12)</label></formula><p>where Fu = j ((ωW1(u, j) + (1 − ω)W2(u, j))Muj. Clearly, Fu ≤ 1 because W1(u, j) ≤ 1 and W2(u, j) ≤ 1 and j Muj = 1. Since α &lt; 1 and Fu ≤ 1, (1 − αFu) &gt; 0. Therefore yu ≤ 0. Similarly, let v = arg minj yj we have that yv ≥ 0. As yv ≤ yu, this implies yu = yv = 0 to satisfy all inequalities. Consequently, yi = 0 for all i, or y = 0.</p><formula xml:id="formula_13">Thus, I − αP T invertible. Equivalently,(I − α(ωM T Λ + (1 − ω)M T Λ )) is invertible.</formula><p>Proposition 2. The iteration in Eq. 9 converges to</p><formula xml:id="formula_14">(1 − α)(I − α(ωM T Λ + (1 − ω)M T Λ )) −1 v.</formula><p>Proof. We can re-write Eq. 9 in matrix form:</p><formula xml:id="formula_15">xt = αPxt−1 + (1 − α)v = (αP) t x0 + (1 − α)( t i=1 (αP) i−1 )v<label>(13)</label></formula><p>We will show that lim</p><formula xml:id="formula_16">t→∞ xt = (1 − α)(I − αP) −1 v. i (αP ) t ij = i k (αP ) ik (αP ) t−1 kj = k (αP ) t−1 kj i (αP ) ik = k (αP ) t−1 kj α(F k ) ≤ k (αP ) t−1 kj α ≤ (α) t<label>(14)</label></formula><p>Here,</p><formula xml:id="formula_17">F k = i ((ωW1(k, i)+(1−ω)W2(k, i))M ki ≤ 1 (proof similarly to Proposition 1</formula><p>Because α &lt; 1, this column sum converges to zero when t → ∞. We then derive lim</p><formula xml:id="formula_18">t→∞ (αP) t x0 = 0. When t → ∞,</formula><p>given Proposition 1 and Neumann series, Eq. 13 becomes: </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Experiments</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">Ground Truth and Data Preprocessing</head><p>Kessler et al. (2012) use 91 timelines from AFP as ground truth along with the AFP news corpus for feature extraction. However, their dataset is not publically available. In addition, although they consider a wide spread of events, each event is only represented by a single timeline from a sin- gle source, making that method somewhat vul- nerable to journalism bias (as discussed by them- selves in their paper). The data collected by us previously ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">Tran et al., 2013a</ref>) is publically avail- able at http://l3s.de/ ˜ gtran/timeline/ and has since been extended by us ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">Tran et al., 2015</ref>). Similar to <ref type="bibr">Kessler et al. (2012)</ref>, it contains ground truth timelines as well as a corpus of news articles covering each event. The dataset is suitable for our purpose because of the following reasons: (1) it is a heterogeneous dataset which contains news arti- cles and expert timeline summaries from different news agencies. Thus, it is more likely to avoid the issue of bias. Also, each event is represented by more than one timeline; (2) it covers long-term stories that have been happening since 2011, mak- ing the date selection problem non trivial for any system.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Timelines. The groundtruth contains 21 time- lines for 4 main events (Egypt Revolution, Libya</head><p>War, Syria War, Yemen Crisis), created by profes- sional journalists. <ref type="table">Table 2</ref> shows statistics about the timelines. Only a small number of all pos- sible dates in a time range is included in at least one timeline (for example, only 122 dates among a possible 918 dates for the Egypt Revolution).</p><p>News Corpus. The news articles have been col- lected from 24 well-known news outlets by query- ing Google with the event name together with the outlets' sitename and time range specification. The crawl time range starts from the first of the month of the earliest event in any timeline (for ex- ample, 2011-01-01 for the Egypt revolution) and ends at crawl date. The top-ranked 300 news ar- ticles from each news site were collected, if still available. The article creation date is parsed from the answers returned by Google. The corpus con- tains 15,534 news articles. Its statistics are sum- marised in <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">Table 3</ref>. The overlap between time- line date ranges and news corpus date ranges is only partial: on the one hand, the corpora have many articles published after the timelines end; on the other hand, sometimes the corpus has no ar- ticles published near the beginning of the time- line (Syria War). The distribution of document frequency leans towards the end date of the news collection. The reason could be that most search engines rank recent documents higher than those published longer ago.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Story</head><p>Time   <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Strötgen and Gertz, 2010)</ref> for this task.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">Experimental settings</head><p>As can be seen from <ref type="table">Table 2</ref>, different timelines for the same event can contain varying dates, due to different ranges timelines might cover but also due to selection preferences by individual writers. Therefore, we consider the union of all timelines for an event. The set of input dates for ranking are all dates from the start t 1 and end t 2 of the union of timelines. <ref type="bibr">7</ref> We call that input time range T R e , depending on main event e. We consider two evaluation settings: relaxed setting: A date from T R e selected by an algorithm is counted as correct if it is included in the union of timelines, therefore in at least one individual timeline.</p><p>strict setting: A date from T R e selected by an algorithm is counted as correct if it is included in at least two individual timelines. The first setting is the one used in previous work such as ( <ref type="bibr">Kessler et al., 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b19">Tran et al., 2013a)</ref>. It is also the only one that can be used if only one timeline per event is considered as in <ref type="bibr">Kessler et al. (2012)</ref>. We therefore include it for compari- son purposes. However, we think it is better to consider several timelines as it allows us to con- sider agreement between timeline writers. If more than one writer agrees on a date being important we have more evidence that a system should find that date. Finding dates that only a single writer includes is less important and could even be due to bias or system overfitting. Therefore, our sec- ond setting is preferable as it emphasizes highly important dates selected by multiple journalists.</p><p>Each system selects the top k dates during the input time range. We evaluate the systems by Mean Average Precision at k (MAP@k) for k = 5, 10, 15, 20 over all four events.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3">Systems.</head><p>Baseline. We use three unsupervised baselines. The baseline Document Frequency ranks dates ac- cording to the number of news articles published on that date. Our assumption is that on a date where one or more important events happened, there would be a spread of information over dif- ferent news agencies in the world. Therefore, this date has more news articles published. This base- line is related to the burstiness date selection used by <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">Yan et al. (2011b)</ref>.</p><p>The baseline MaxLength ranks dates by the maximum article length of all articles published on that date. Our hypothesis is that important events <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">5  81  26  24  42  10  2011/01/22 -2012/02/27  401  Number of timelines (#TL)</ref>, number of dates occurring in at least one timeline (#atLeastOnce), number of dates that appear in at least 2 timelines, average (avgL), max (maxL) and min (minL) length of timelines; the Time Range of the union of timelines and all potential dates (#dates) within the time range. <ref type="table">Table 2</ref>: Overview of groundtruth timelines often receive more attention from writers, leading to longer articles.</p><note type="other">Story #TL #atLeastOnce #atLeastTwice avgL maxL minL Time Range #dates Egypt 4 122 18 36 57 24 2011/01/01 -2013/07/07 918 Libya 7 118 56 34 62 22 2011/02/14 -2011/11/22 281 Syria 5 106 17 60 26 13 2011/03/15 -2013/07/06 844 Yemen</note><p>Date Frequency ranks a date d by the total num- ber of sentences referring to d that are not pub- lished on d. This is a simple measure of d's influ- ence without joint scoring of dates or integration of temporal distance or topic.</p><p>Competitors. We reimplement <ref type="bibr">Kessler et al. (2012)</ref>'s model. It first detects all sentences with date references and filters out certain types of sen- tences according to linguistic features (such as presence of modality as this can put the factual- ity of the event into question). Then, the impor- tance score of a date is determined by the prod- uct of the Lucene score of referring sentences and an ML-predicted score that takes into account date reference frequencies, temporal distance of date references and topical importance of referring sen- tences. To use the same setting as for our systems, we use the list of keywords extracted by TextRank ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Mihalcea and Tarau, 2004</ref>) to formulate a topic query for the Lucene index.</p><p>We reimplement <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">Tran et al. (2013a)</ref> who use a supervised ML approach based on a more detailed consideration of date reference frequencies.</p><p>Both <ref type="bibr">Kessler et al. (2012)</ref> and <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">Tran et al. (2013a)</ref> are retrained and tested via 4-fold cross- validation on events. In addition, we noted that the two supervised systems could profit from the fact that for certain dates in T R e no published news articles exist in the news collection and that they are therefore a priori unlikely to be relevant. We therefore also run those systems with a stricter input time range, which intersects T R e with the dates that are the publication date of at least one article in the news collection. We indicate these systems as <ref type="bibr">Kessler</ref>  Our Approach. Our system builds graphs with all dates referenced in the news corpus for an event as nodes. We select the top k highest ranked nodes that also fall within T R e . We measure the perfor- mance with different strategies for the Influence factor I. We use the following five unsupervised strategies, where we just set the damping factor α to 0.85 as suggested by <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Page et al. (1999)</ref>. <ref type="bibr">8</ref> IRW f req only uses the frequency aspect. This corresponds to a joint modelling version of the Date Frequency baseline.</p><p>IRW max topical uses topical influence, disre- garding frequency aspect in its computation.</p><p>IRW f req * topical uses topical influence, incor- porating the frequency aspect in its computation.</p><p>IRW |temporal| uses temporal influence, disre- garding the frequency aspect.</p><p>IRW f req * temporal uses temporal influence in- corporating the frequency aspect.</p><p>Furthermore, we are interested in combining topical and temporal influence (with or without frequency aspects). Here, our model is parame- terized by ω which controls the impact of topi- cal influence vs. temporal influence. This param- eter is tuned on the training set via 4-fold cross- validation and, therefore, the next two models have a small element of supervision.</p><p>IRW max topical+f req * temporal combines topical and temporal influence, integrating the frequency aspect into temporal influence.</p><p>IRW f req * topical+|temporal| combines topical and temporal influence, integrating the frequency aspect into topical influence. <ref type="table">Table 4</ref> shows an analysis of the four date refer- ence graphs. In this Table, #sent provides the total number of sentences from all news articles while #hasRef shows the number of sentences that re- fer to a date (around 15%), suggesting a sustain- able part of data can be helpful for the interaction- based approach. The number of nodes shows the unique dates that are involved in a date reference link.  <ref type="table">Table 4</ref>: Interaction-based analysis on experimental news collections proportion of the edges that link to groundtruth dates in the strict setting and relaxed setting.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.4">Analysis of date reference graphs</head><p>Those edges cover almost all the groundtruth dates (i.e, reachStrict and reachRelaxed), i.e almost all groundtruth dates are indeed referenced at least once in our corpus. <ref type="table" target="#tab_5">Table 5</ref> shows the average performance of differ- ent systems over our four events. Several general observations stand out. First, we notice that the scores wrt. relaxed setting of all systems are higher than those wrt. strict setting. That is expected, as in relaxed setting, a selected date has a higher like- lihood to be one of the milestones in the timeline of at least one expert. Second, simple baselines such as Document Frequency and MaxLength per- form reasonably well in the relaxed-setting. That confirms our assumptions that important dates of- ten possess more published news articles and are likely to have at least one article of substantial length. However, these baselines are not enough to distinguish highly important dates (which are selected by more than one journalist) as shown by their performance in the strict setting (around 0.3 MAP@k only). Using Date Frequency leads to a substan- tial performance improvement in the strict set- ting comapred to the publication-based baselines. Therefore, highly important dates are more likely to be kept mentioning in the future and that sup- ports our research direction to better leverage date interaction for ranking date importance. This is further confirmed by the performance of the IRW f req system which is the joint modelling ver- sion of the DateFrequency baseline and outper- foms the baseline without inclusion of any further information such as topical salience. It can even compete with prior supervised competitors when their input time range is not modified.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.5">Results</head><p>Our supervised competitors ( <ref type="bibr">Kessler et al., 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b19">Tran et al., 2013a</ref>) perform overall well and both profit from modifying their input time range as suggested in the Pub versions. However, the un- supervised versions of our system IRW max topical and IRW f req * topical perform very comparably to the supervised competitors in the strict and relaxed setting, respectively.</p><p>The last two lines of <ref type="table" target="#tab_5">Table 5</ref> show the re- sults of our proposed method when using a lin- ear combination of the different influence fac- tors, and the hyperparameter ω having been tuned on the training set. IRW max topical+f req * temporal shows the result of our system with ω = 0.2 and IRW f req * topical+|temporal| with ω = 0.1 These systems outperform the state-of-the-art systems clearly in the strict setting and for most measures in the relaxed setting.</p><p>Stability. We also investigated the stability of the performance of different systems by look- ing into their results on each event. <ref type="table">Table 6</ref> presents the performance of our best system IRW max topical+f req * temporal and its best super- vised competitors <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">Tran et al. (2013a)</ref> (Pub) and <ref type="bibr">Kessler et al. (2012) (Pub)</ref>. All systems perform worse on the Syria story although our dropoff is less than the one of prior systems.</p><p>We speculate that the competitor systems are more sensitive to the amount of available pub- lished content on a target date than ours. In partic- ular, <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">Tran et al. (2013a)</ref> use the frequency of pub- lished dates and sentences as one of their features, and <ref type="bibr">Kessler et al. (2012)</ref> rely on the returned re- sults from Lucene index which tends towards sub- stories from the publication periods. Different to others, the time range for the Syria news collection does not include the time range for the Syria time- lines fully or almost fully (see <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">Tables 2 and 3)</ref>. We therefore are not as dependent on an exact match between timeline dates and news collection dates and can use news articles from later dates more effectively.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Conclusion and Future Work</head><p>This paper addresses the problem of date selec- tion for timeline summarization. Our approach leverages the interactions between dates via a joint model based on a date reference graph, improving on individual scoring of dates.</p><p>We capture the interactions between dates from the number of cross-references between dates, and System strict setting <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">relaxed-setting  MAP@5  MAP@10  MAP@15  MAP@20  MAP@5  MAP@10  MAP@15</ref>    <ref type="table">Table 6</ref>: Stability of our systems vs. competitors their temporal and topical influences. We present a novel random walk model that incorporates these perspectives into connectivity-based computation.</p><p>Experimental results on four news events that span a long time period show that the proposed models outperform state-of-the art approaches. Even un- supervised versions of the model perform on a par with previous supervised methods. We also draw attention to the necessity to take personal bias into account, which leads to differences between man- ually created timelines for the same event -we encourage future work to always consider several timelines per event in the way that other NLP work uses several annotators to create ground truth.</p><p>In future work, we will consider a wider range of events and event types. This will also lead to considering timelines where the day as unit of granularity might not be appropriate or where the unit of granularity might be varying across the timeline. We will also explore in depth the effect of size and type of news corpus on resulting time- lines, research further into the issue of human dis- agreement in timeline creation and explore human evaluation of timeline summarization.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>(</head><label></label><figDesc>a1) 2011-01-25 Egyptians hold nationwide demonstrations against the au- thoritarian rule of Hosni Mubarak, who has led the country for nearly three decades. (a2) 2011-01-26 A large security force moves into Cairo's Tahrir Square (a3) 2011-01-28 Protesters burn down the ruling party's headquarters, and the military is deployed. (a4) 2011-02-11 Mubarak steps down and turns power over to the military. (a5) 2011-03-19 In the first post Mubarak vote, Egyptians cast ballots on constitutional amendments . . . , including scheduling the first parliamentary and presidential elections (a8) 2012-04-20 The presidential campaign officially begins. (a10) 2012-06-24 Election officials declare Morsi the winner (a26) 2013-07-03 Egypt's military chief says Morsi has been replaced by Adly Mansour, the chief justice of constitutional court.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>( 5 )</head><label>5</label><figDesc>Military generals took over power from Mubarak when he stepped down on February 11 last year. (Daily Mail, 2012-01-25).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>xt</head><label></label><figDesc>= (αP) t x0 + (1 − α)(I − αP) −1 v hence, lim t→∞ xt = (1−α)(I−αP) −1 v. Convergence proved.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>et al. (2012) (Pub) and Tran et al. (2013a) (Pub).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" validated="false"><head>Table 1 : A timeline about the Egypt revolution published by</head><label>1</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>the Associated Press (AP). We leave out intermediate dates 
due to space constraints. The whole timeline includes 30 
dates between 2011-01-25 and 2013-07-07. 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" validated="false"><head>Table 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Overview of the news corpus 

Preprocessing. Accurate date extraction includ-
ing both implicit (like last Friday) and explicit 
(like 11 Feb ) temporal expressions is vital to 
our approach as well as for competitor systems. 
We use the Heideltime state-of-the art toolkit 
(</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_5" validated="false"><head>Table 5 :</head><label>5</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Average MAP@k scores of different systems on 4 news collections 

Egypt 
Libya 
Syria 
Yemen 
IRW max topical+f req * temporal 
MAP@5 
0.960 
1.000 
0.713 
0.843 
MAP@10 
0.738 
0.969 
0.598 
0.735 
MAP@15 
0.600 
0.854 
0.503 
0.676 
MAP@20 
0.520 
0.776 
0.433 
0.619 
Kessler et al. (2012) (Pub) 
MAP@5 
0.703 
0.843 
0.257 
1.000 
MAP@10 
0.566 
0.759 
0.203 
0.952 
MAP@15 
0.507 
0.697 
0.187 
0.894 
MAP@20 
0.450 
0.659 
0.171 
0.816 
Tran et al. (2013a) (Pub) 
MAP@5 
0.960 
0.910 
0.257 
0.713 
MAP@10 
0.803 
0.836 
0.224 
0.541 
MAP@15 
0.665 
0.799 
0.227 
0.514 
MAP@20 
0.569 
0.758 
0.212 
0.484 

</table></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> http://www.niemanlab.org/2015/02/ timeline-is-providing-historicalcontext-to-the-news-but-is-there-abusiness-model-to-support-it/.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="2"> Note that the date selection task uses dates as proxies for important events on that date.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="3"> Kessler et al. (2012) is also used in Nguyen et al. (2014)&apos;s system.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="4"> We set n=20 in practice. 5 We use the standard BM25 parameter settings k1 = 1.2 and b = 0.75</note>

			<note place="foot" n="6"> In the case of linear combinations we incorporate frequency into topical or temporal influence as described above.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="7"> Prior work also uses start and end date of timelines for delimiting input (Kessler et al., 2012; Tran et al., 2013a).</note>

			<note place="foot" n="8"> We could make these models supervised by tuning the damping factor via cross-validation. However, we found it encouraging that we were able to achieve competitive results without tuning-similar to links between web pages in the traditional PageRank algorithm, links between dates seem to embody strong relations, making the same damping factor suitable.</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>The work was partially funded by the Eu-ropean Commission for the FP7 project EUMSSI (611057) and the ERC Advanced Grant ALEXANDRIA (339233).</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Temporal summaries of new topics</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">James</forename><surname>Allan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rahul</forename><surname>Gupta</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Vikas</forename><surname>Khandelwal</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of SIGIR&apos;01</title>
		<meeting>SIGIR&apos;01</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="10" to="18" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Combining natural and artificial examples to improve implicit discourse relation identification</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chloé</forename><surname>Braud</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Pascal</forename><surname>Denis</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">COLING 2014: Technical Papers</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Dublin, Ireland</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1694" to="1705" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Query based event extraction along a timeline</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hai</forename><surname>Leong Chieu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yoong Keok</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of SIGIR&apos;04</title>
		<meeting>SIGIR&apos;04</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="425" to="432" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Lexrank: graph-based lexical centrality as salience in text summarization</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Günes</forename><surname>Erkan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dragomir</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Radev</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Artif. Int. Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="457" to="479" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Retrieving time from scanned books</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">John</forename><surname>Foley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">James</forename><surname>Allan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Advances in Information Retrieval</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="221" to="232" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Topic-sensitive pagerank</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Taher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Haveliwala</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">WWW</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="517" to="526" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Improving the estimation of word importance for news multidocument summarization</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kai</forename><surname>Hong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ani</forename><surname>Nenkova</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of EACL 2014</title>
		<meeting>EACL 2014</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="712" to="721" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Véronique Moriceau, and André Bittar. 2012. Finding salient dates for building thematic timelines</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Remy</forename><surname>Kessler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xavier</forename><surname>Tannier</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Caroline</forename><surname>Hagège</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of ACL</title>
		<meeting>ACL</meeting>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A pdtb-styled end-to-end discourse parser</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ziheng</forename><surname>Lin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hwee</forename><forename type="middle">Tou</forename><surname>Ng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Min-Yen</forename><surname>Kan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Natural Language Engineering</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="151" to="184" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Ani Nenkova, Barry Schiffman, and Sergey Sigelman. 2003. Columbia&apos;s newsblaster: New features and future directions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kathleen</forename><surname>Mckeown</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Regina</forename><surname>Barzilay</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">John</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Elson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><forename type="middle">Kirk</forename><surname>Evans</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Judith</forename><surname>Klavans</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">HLT-NAACL</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Machine learned sentence selection strategies for querybiased summarization</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Donald</forename><surname>Metzler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tapas</forename><surname>Kanungo</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2008 ACM SIGIR LR4IR Workshop</title>
		<meeting>the 2008 ACM SIGIR LR4IR Workshop</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Textrank: Bringing order into text</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rada</forename><surname>Mihalcea</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Paul</forename><surname>Tarau</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">EMNLP</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="404" to="411" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Ranking multidocument event descriptions for building thematic timelines</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kiem-Hieu</forename><surname>Nguyen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xavier</forename><surname>Tannier</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Véronique</forename><surname>Moriceau</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">COLING 2014</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1208" to="1217" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The pagerank citation ranking: Bringing order to the web</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lawrence</forename><surname>Page</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sergey</forename><surname>Brin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rajeev</forename><surname>Motwani</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Terry</forename><surname>Winograd</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>number = SIDL-WP-1999-0120</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1999-11" />
			<pubPlace>Stanford InfoLab</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
<note type="report_type">Technical report</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Mead-a platform for multidocument multilingual text summarization</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Dragomir</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Timothy</forename><surname>Radev</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sasha</forename><surname>Allison</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">John</forename><surname>Blairgoldensohn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Arda</forename><surname>Blitzer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Stanko</forename><surname>Celebi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Elliott</forename><surname>Dimitrov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ali</forename><surname>Drbek</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wai</forename><surname>Hakim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Danyu</forename><surname>Lam</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jahna</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hong</forename><surname>Otterbacher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Qi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of LREC&apos;04</title>
		<editor>Horacio Saggion, Simone Teufel, Michael Topper, Adam Winkel, and Zhu Zhang</editor>
		<meeting>LREC&apos;04</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Centroid-based summarization of multiple documents</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Dragomir</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hongyan</forename><surname>Radev</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Magorzata</forename><surname>Jing</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Daniel</forename><surname>Sty</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Tam</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="919" to="938" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Okapi at trec-3</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Stephen</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Robertson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Steve</forename><surname>Walker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Susan</forename><surname>Jones</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Micheline</forename><surname>Hancock-Beaulieu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mike</forename><surname>Gatford</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">TREC</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1994" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Heideltime: High quality rule-based extraction and normalization of temporal expressions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jannik</forename><surname>Strötgen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Gertz</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the SemEval &apos;10 Workshop</title>
		<meeting>the SemEval &apos;10 Workshop</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="321" to="324" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Timemine: visualizing automatically constructed timelines</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Russell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">James</forename><surname>Swan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Allan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">SIGIR</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
			<biblScope unit="page">393</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Predicting relevant news events for timeline summaries</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mohammad</forename><surname>Binh Giang Tran</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dat Quoc</forename><surname>Alrifai</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Nguyen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Leveraging learning to rank in an optimization framework for timeline summarization</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tuan</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Giang Binh Tran</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nam-Khanh</forename><surname>Tran</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mohammad</forename><surname>Tran</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nattiya</forename><surname>Alrifai</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Kanhabua</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">SIGIR 2013 Workshop TAIA</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Timeline summarization from relevent headlines</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Giang</forename><surname>Tran</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mohammad</forename><surname>Alrifai</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Eelco</forename><surname>Herder</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of ECIR&apos;2015</title>
		<meeting>ECIR&apos;2015</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Generating pictorial storylines via minimum-weight connected dominating set approximation in multiview graphs</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dingding</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tao</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mitsunori</forename><surname>Ogihara</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of AAAI</title>
		<meeting>AAAI</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Weighted pagerank algorithm</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wenpu</forename><surname>Xing</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ali</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Ghorbani</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">CNSR</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="305" to="314" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Summarize what you are interested in: An optimization framework for interactive personalized summarization</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rui</forename><surname>Yan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jian-Yun</forename><surname>Nie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xiaoming</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of EMNLP&apos;11</title>
		<meeting>EMNLP&apos;11</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Evolutionary timeline summarization: a balanced optimization framework via iterative substitution</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rui</forename><surname>Yan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xiaojun</forename><surname>Wan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jahna</forename><surname>Otterbacher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Liang</forename><surname>Kong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xiaoming</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yan</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of SIGIR&apos;11</title>
		<meeting>SIGIR&apos;11</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="745" to="754" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
