<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T12:59+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">A Web-based Collaborative Evaluation Tool for Automatically Learned Relation Extraction Patterns</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date>July 26-31, 2015. c 2015</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Leonhard</forename><surname>Hennig</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory">Language Technology Lab</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>DFKI</postCode>
									<settlement>Berlin</settlement>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hong</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory">Language Technology Lab</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>DFKI</postCode>
									<settlement>Berlin</settlement>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sebastian</forename><surname>Krause</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory">Language Technology Lab</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>DFKI</postCode>
									<settlement>Berlin</settlement>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Feiyu</forename><surname>Xu</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory">Language Technology Lab</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>DFKI</postCode>
									<settlement>Berlin</settlement>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hans</forename><surname>Uszkoreit</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory">Language Technology Lab</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>DFKI</postCode>
									<settlement>Berlin</settlement>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">A Web-based Collaborative Evaluation Tool for Automatically Learned Relation Extraction Patterns</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of ACL-IJCNLP 2015 System Demonstrations</title>
						<meeting>ACL-IJCNLP 2015 System Demonstrations <address><addrLine>Beijing, China</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="43" to="48"/>
							<date type="published">July 26-31, 2015. c 2015</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Patterns extracted from dependency parses of sentences are a major source of knowledge for most state-of-the-art relation extraction systems, but can be of low quality in distantly supervised settings. We present a linguistic annotation tool that allows human experts to analyze and categorize automatically learned patterns, and to identify common error classes. The annotations can be used to create datasets that enable machine learning approaches to pattern quality estimation. We also present an experimental pattern error analysis for three semantic relations, where we find that between 24% and 61% of the learned dependency patterns are defective due to preprocessing or parsing errors, or due to violations of the distant supervision assumption.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Dependency parse trees of sentences have been shown to be very useful structures for relation extraction (RE), since they often capture syntac- tic and semantic properties of a relation and its arguments more compactly than more surface- oriented representations <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Grishman, 2012)</ref>. Typ- ically, shortest-path or similar algorithms are used to extract a pattern from a sentence's dependency parse that connects the relation's arguments. Such patterns can be directly applied to parsed texts to identify novel instances of a relation ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Krause et al., 2012</ref>), or they can be used as features in a su- pervised learning approach ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Mintz et al., 2009)</ref>. They are also useful by themselves, as linguistic resources that capture the different ways in which a given human language expresses semantic rela- tions .</p><p>In recent years, distant supervision has be- come a very important approach to relation extrac- tion ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Mintz et al., 2009;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Surdeanu et al., 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Ritter et al., 2013)</ref>, due to the availability of large- scale structured knowledge bases such as Free- base ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Bollacker et al., 2008)</ref>. While typically yielding a high recall of relation mentions, dis- tant supervision makes several strong assumptions that may significantly affect the quality of ex- tracted dependency patterns. First, it assumes that for each relation tuple r i (e i 1 , . . . , e i k ) in a knowl- edge base, every sentence containing mentions of e i 1 , . . . , e i k (or a subset thereof) expresses the re- lation r i ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Surdeanu et al., 2012)</ref>. This assumption typically does not hold for most sentences, i.e., en- tity mentions may co-occur without the sentence expressing the target relation. Dependency pat- terns extracted from such sentences should be dis- carded to improve the precision of an RE system. Furthermore, distant supervision assumes that the knowledge base is complete: entity mention co- occurrences with no known relations are ignored or treated as negative training examples, lower- ing the discriminative capabilities of a learned model ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Ritter et al., 2013)</ref>.</p><p>Automatically estimating the quality of ex- tracted patterns, e.g., by using data-driven statisti- cal metrics, or by learning weights in a supervised setting, leads to indirect measures of pattern qual- ity, but tells us only very little about the (grammat- ical) correctness and the semantic appropriateness of the patterns themselves. We are hence inter- ested in a more direct, expert-driven analysis of dependency patterns and their properties, which will hopefully guide us towards better automatic quality metrics. To this end, we have developed a linguistic annotation tool, PatternJudge, that al- lows human experts to evaluate relation-specific dependency patterns and their associated source sentences. Our contributions in this paper are:</p><p>• We present a linguistic annotation tool for hu- man expert-driven quality control of depen- dency patterns (Section 3)</p><p>• We describe an annotation process for pattern evaluation and the guidelines we developed for it (Section 4)</p><p>• We present and discuss common error classes observed in an initial study of three semantic relations (Section 5)</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Pattern Extraction</head><p>In this section, we briefly describe our approach for extracting relation-specific dependency pat- terns in a distantly supervised setting, called Web- DARE ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Krause et al., 2012)</ref>. In contrast to most other approaches, we consider not only binary, but arbitrary n-ary relations, with n &gt;= 2. For exam- ple, we can define a 4-ary marriage relation with the spouses as essential (required) arguments, and optional arguments such as the wedding date and location. Given a knowledge base (KB) contain- ing such relations and their arguments, we select a set of seed relation instances from the KB. We then collect sentences from a large text corpus that mention at least the essential arguments of a given seed relation instance. Sentences are preprocessed with a standard NLP pipeline, including tokenization, named en- tity recognition (NER) and linking, lemmatiza- tion, part-of-speech tagging and word sense dis- ambiguation (WSD). <ref type="bibr">1</ref> We also apply a depen- dency parser producing Stanford dependency rela- tions. Given a preprocessed sentence and the seed relation instance which matches this sentence, the pattern extraction algorithm first identifies the ar- gument mentions of the seed relation instance oc- curring in the sentence, and then determines and composes the set of shortest paths connecting the arguments in the dependency parse in a bottom-up manner. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 1</ref> visualizes the pattern extraction process for an example sentence expressing the marriage relation. The extracted pattern is shown in attribute-value-matrix (AVM) notation in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Fig- ure 1c</ref>. For more details on the algorithm we refer the interested reader to the DARE pattern extrac- tion method described in <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Xu et al. (2007)</ref>. <ref type="bibr">1</ref> We use the Stanford CoreNLP pipeline (nlp.stanford.edu/software/corenlp.shtml), and our own implementation of Babelfy (babelfy.org) for WSD and entity linking. tation tool, dubbed PatternJudge. With Pattern- Judge, annotators can inspect patterns and source sentences for a given relation, and evaluate their grammatical and semantic correctness. The tool is realized as a browser-based client with a back end web server for data management. It is available online at http://sargraph.dfki.de/pattern judge. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Figure 2</ref> shows a screen shot of the user inter- face. The interface is split into three main com- ponents. The left part displays a list of avail- able relations and patterns, and allows searching for specific patterns or sentences. The center part visualizes the currently selected dependency pat- tern in AVM notation. In this notation, the IN- PUT element contains the dependency pattern, and the OUTPUT element lists the relation arguments extracted by this pattern. In the example pattern shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Figure 2</ref>, these correspond to the spouses and the wedding date. Thus, the patterns also con- tain the semantic role label information of the tar- get relation for the corresponding linguistic argu- ments, which is not included in most traditional pattern extraction approaches (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Stevenson and Greenwood (2005)</ref>).</p><p>The area below the representation of the pattern lists the source sentences that it was observed in, as well as some statistics about the frequency of the pattern. Sentences are formatted to highlight the important elements of the pattern. Relation arguments are marked in red, content words oc- curring in the pattern are marked in blue. Listing the source sentences is important because it en- ables the human expert to verify both the extracted dependency pattern (e.g., to detect a parse error), and the semantic correctness of the pattern, i.e., whether the sentences express the target relation.</p><p>The annotation tab on the right-hand side col- lects the human expert's feedback on the quality of the selected pattern. Currently available op- tions include labeling the pattern as "CORRECT", "CORRECT, BUT TOO SPECIFIC", "INCORRECT" or "UNCERTAIN/DON'T KNOW". We describe the intended scope and meaning of these feedback cat- egories in Section 4. Note that this set of cate- gories is not fixed, but simply reflects what we have found to be useful distinctions thus far for annotating patterns. Annotators can also provide a comment, and, if desired, view the annotations and comments of previous annotators of this pat- tern. Since multiple experts can collaboratively annotate the same pattern, these comments are Brad Pitt married Jennifer Aniston in a private wedding ceremony in Malibu on July <ref type="bibr">29, 2000.</ref> (a) Sentence with a mention of the marriage relation. Malibu (b) Dependency pattern extracted from the sentence in (a).   mainly used for discussion and clarification, but also for adding error class information in cases where an annotator decided to label a pattern as "INCORRECT". In a separate tab (not shown in the <ref type="figure">Figure)</ref>, an- notators can inspect the word senses of the pat- tern's lemmas. Per lemma, we display a distri- bution over word senses, since the sentence-level WSD decisions may differ from each other. Anno- tators can use this view to label the correct word senses for a pattern. Word senses are directly linked to BabelNet 2 for reference. The Pattern- 2 http://babelnet.org/ Judge tool also includes a basic user management component to keep track of different annotators, and for undoing or updating previous judgments. All pattern judgments are persisted in a NoSQL data base, and can be exported to CSV or other standard formats for statistical analysis.</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">                      head lemma marry POS V dobj type person role SPOUSE2 prep in      head lemma ceremony POS N prep in type location role CEREMONY      prep on type date role FROM nsubj type person role SPOUSE1                       (c) Generalized</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Expert-driven quality control</head><p>We use the PatternJudge tool for an experimental analysis of dependency patterns. The analysis has two major goals: to validate interesting, produc- tive dependency patterns, and to identify common error classes of defective patterns. In this section, we describe the guidelines that we developed for the manual evaluation process, and the experimen- tal dataset. We report the results of our analysis in Section 5.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">Quality control guidelines</head><p>We define three qualitative categories, "CORRECT", "CORRECT, BUT TOO SPECIFIC" and "INCORRECT", as well as a set of annotation guidelines for the evaluation of dependency patterns. We label a relation-specific pattern as "CORRECT" if it is grammatically and semanti- cally correct. A pattern is grammatically correct if there are no parsing or other preprocessing errors, and it is semantically correct if its source sentences express the target relation. Corre- spondingly, we label a dependency pattern as "INCORRECT" if it is grammatically incorrect, or if its sentences do not express the target relation. Typically, the annotators aim to identify one or more of the error classes discussed in Section 5 to decide whether a pattern is incorrect.</p><p>For deciding whether a sentence expresses a given relation, we use the ACE annotation guide- lines' conceptual definition of relations and their mentions ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Doddington et al., 2004</ref>), and define the semantics of relations based on Freebase descrip- tions. In contrast to the ACE tasks, we also con- sider n-ary relations in addition to binary relations. Sentences must express the target relation explic- itly, e.g., "Obama was awarded the Nobel Peace Prize." explicitly expresses the relation award honor. We treat implicit mentions as semantically incorrect, e.g., the previous example only implies an award nomination.</p><p>A third feedback category, "CORRECT, BUT TOO SPECIFIC", was added based on our initial analysis of the dataset, and applies to dependency patterns mostly found in the long tail of the fre- quency distribution. Too specific patterns, while both grammatically and semantically correct, are patterns that are overly complex and / or include irrelevant parts of the sentence specific to a partic- ular relation instance. Such patterns do not gener- alize well, and are unlikely to be very productive when applied to novel text.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">Dataset</head><p>We apply the pattern extraction approach de- scribed in Section 2 to create a dataset for 25 re- lations from the domains awards, business and personal relationships. We use Freebase as our knowledge base, and retrieve 200K relation in- stances as seed knowledge. We then create a text corpus by querying Bing with the seeds as input, and retrieving the top 100 results per query. From these documents, we extract more than 3M sen- tences mentioning a seed relation instance. The resulting pattern dataset contains 1.5M unique pat- terns. Since a manual evaluation of all these pat- terns would be too resource-intensive, we select a subset based on the pattern filtering algorithm pro- posed by <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Moro et al. (2013)</ref>.</p><p>We then sample a small set of sentences (3 − 5) for each pattern, and conduct an initial pass over the data with human annotators that judge whether these sentences express the target relation or not. We discard all patterns whose sentences do not ex- press the relation. The final dataset for manual evaluation consists of more than 8K patterns with all their source sentences.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Pattern observations</head><p>Three annotators evaluated 1185 patterns for the relations award honor (510 patterns), acquisition (224) and marriage (451), using the guidelines de- scribed in the previous section. Each annotator evaluated the patterns of a single relation. <ref type="bibr">3</ref> </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.1">Error classes</head><p>The annotators identified six main error classes, which are listed in <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>. Three of the classes re- late to preprocessing errors (PIPE-S, PIPE-NER, PIPE-PT), the other three encompass semantic mistakes in patterns or source sentences (NEX-P, NEX-S, IMP-S).</p><p>The error class PIPE-S is used for ungrammati- cal sentences and patterns resulting from sentence boundary detection errors. In example (1) in Ta- ble 1, the category label tokens "Personal life" are interpreted as relevant elements of the extracted pattern. PIPE-NER errors refer to patterns with arguments that are semantically or grammatically incongruent with the ones tagged in the sentence, as well as entity type errors. In example (2), the title of the book has not been recognized as an en- tity, and the lemmas "leave" and "us" are included as lexical elements in the pattern. The category PIPE-PT is applied to patterns derived from de- fective dependency parse trees. In example (3), 1 PIPE-S Sentence seg- mentation error Personal :::: life ::: On July 5, 2003, Banks :::::::: married sportswriter and producer Max Handelman, who had been her boyfriend since she met him on her first day at college, September 6, 1992. The category NEX-P is used for dependency patterns that do not include any relation-relevant content words. In example (4), the most explicit word expressing an acquisition is the lemma "pur- chase". The pattern, however, extracts other parts of the source sentence. NEX-S applies to patterns that are based on sentences which do not express the relation of interest. In example (5), the target relation award honor is not expressed, instead, the host of the ceremony is erroneously identified as the winner of the prize. Finally, the category IMP- S marks patterns that are derived from sentences in which a relation is expressed merely implicitly. Judging from the source sentence in example (6), we cannot be entirely sure whether or not an ac- quisition took place because "felt compelled to" might only express a momentary mindset of the company's leaders that was not followed by ac- tion. <ref type="table">Table 2</ref> summarizes the distribution of correct and incorrect dependency patterns for the three rela- tions marriage, award honor and acquisition. We find that between 24% and 61% of the learned de- pendency patterns are defective, between 21% and 55% are labeled as correct. For the relation acqui-  <ref type="table">Table 2</ref>: Distribution of pattern categories sition, more than 60% of the patterns are labeled as "INCORRECT", which is much higher than for the other two relations. "CORRECT, BUT TOO SPE- CIFIC" patterns make up between 12% and 30% of the total number of patterns. <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">Table 3</ref> gives details on the distribution of the error classes for the same relations. The two pre- dominant error classes are PIPE-NER and NEX- S. The distribution of error classes varies signifi- cantly between the different relations. PIPE-NER is the category most frequently found in award honor. Sentences in this category often men- tion the titles of works the prize was awarded for. If those titles are not recognized as entities by the NER tagger, the dependency parsing fails and parts of the title can erroneously end up in the pat- tern. For the acquisition relation, the vast majority of errors can be assigned to the category NEX-S. In these cases, a relation between two or more or-  ganizations is often expressed in the source sen- tences, e.g., that "company X is a subsidiary of company Y ", but no statement is made about the act of purchase. For the marriage relation, the most frequent error type was IMP-S, mainly re- sulting from sentences stating a divorce, which we do not consider as explicit mentions of the mar- riage relation. A final observation that can be made from <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">Table 3</ref> is that 42% of the errors are preprocessing pipeline errors.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.2">Pattern statistics</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Conclusions and future work</head><p>We presented PatternJudge, a linguistic annota- tion tool for manual evaluation of dependency pat- terns. The tool allows human experts to inspect dependency patterns and their associated source sentences, to categorize patterns, and to identify error classes. The annotated patterns can be used to create datasets that enable machine learning ap- proaches to pattern quality estimation and rela- tion extraction. We showed how the tool can be used to perform a pattern error analysis on three semantic relations. Our study indicates that tex- tual entailment may play an important role for re- lation extraction, since many relations are not ex- pressed explicitly in texts. We also observe that close interactions among semantically similar re- lations should be reflected in the pattern discov- ery approach. In future work, we will extend the PatternJudge tool to provide a better interface for defining and assigning error classes. In addition, our annotators are currently evaluating the pattern dataset for a larger set of semantic relations, which will allow us to extend the initial study presented in this work.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>dependency pattern derived from (b).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: Data flow for gathering dependency patterns from distantly labeled text.</figDesc><graphic url="image-1.png" coords="3,74.99,295.79,444.21,224.84" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>Figure 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2: User interface of the PatternJudge tool. The tool allows annotators to judge the quality of automatically learned dependency patterns.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>(marriage) 2 PIPE-NER NER tagging er- ror Rahna Reiko Rizzuto is the ::::::: author ::: of the :::::: novel, Why She :::: Left :::: Us, which ::: won an American Book Award ::: in 2000. (award honor) 3 PIPE-PT Dependency parsing error * Say ::: won a Caldecott Medal for his illustrations in Grandfather's Journey. (award honor) 4 NEX-P Relation is not expressed in pattern Julian :::::: joined Old Mutual in August 2000 as Group Finance Director, :::::: moving on to become :::: CEO ::: of Skandia following its purchase by Old Mutual in February 2006. (acquisition) 5 NEX-S Relation is not expressed in text The 69th Annual Peabody Awards ::::::::: ceremony will :: be ::::: held on May 17 at the Waldorf-Astoria in New York City and will be ::::::: hosted ::: by Diane Sawyer, the award-winning anchor of ABCs World News. (award honor) 6 IMP-S Relation is too implicit The looming expiration of Lipitors patent in 2012 is a big reason Pfizer ::::: felt ::::::::::: compelled to ::: buy a :::::::: company ::::: like Wyeth. (acquisition) Table 1: Common error classes of dependency patterns for the relations marriage, acquisition and award honor. Underlined token sequences denote relation arguments, ::::::: concepts ::::: with :: a ::::::: dashed ::::::::: underline are additional pattern elements. the parser interpreted the proper name Say as a fi- nite verb.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" validated="false"><head>Table 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Distribution of error classes 

</table></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="3"> Evaluation tool-PatternJudge To facilitate the manual evaluation of dependency patterns, we have developed a web-based anno</note>

			<note place="foot" n="3"> We used a separate relation, siblings, to establish a shared set of evaluation principles among the annotators. In future work, we plan to have multiple annotations per pattern, e.g., to analyze inter-annotator agreement.</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>This research was partially supported by the German Federal Ministry of Education and Research (BMBF) through the projects ALL SIDES (01IW14002) and BBDC (01IS14013E), by the German Federal Ministry of Economics and Energy (BMWi) through the project SDW (01MD15010A), and by Google through a Fo-cused Research Award granted in July 2013.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Freebase: A Collaboratively Created Graph Database for Structuring Human Knowledge</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kurt</forename><surname>Bollacker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Colin</forename><surname>Evans</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Praveen</forename><surname>Paritosh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tim</forename><surname>Sturge</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jamie</forename><surname>Taylor</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of SIGMOD</title>
		<meeting>of SIGMOD</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1247" to="1250" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Automatic Content Extraction (ACE) Program-Tasks, Data, and Evaluation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alexis</forename><surname>George R Doddington</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Mitchell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Mark</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Przybocki</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Stephanie</forename><surname>Lance A Ramshaw</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ralph M</forename><surname>Strassel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Weischedel</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of LREC</title>
		<meeting>of LREC</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Information Extraction: Capabilities and Challenges</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ralph</forename><surname>Grishman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>NYU Dept. CS</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
<note type="report_type">Technical report</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Large-Scale Learning of RelationExtraction Rules with Distant Supervision from the Web</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sebastian</forename><surname>Krause</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hong</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hans</forename><surname>Uszkoreit</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Feiyu</forename><surname>Xu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of ISWC</title>
		<meeting>of ISWC</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="263" to="278" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Distant Supervision for Relation Extraction Without Labeled Data</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mike</forename><surname>Mintz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Steven</forename><surname>Bills</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of ACLIJCNLP</title>
		<meeting>of ACLIJCNLP</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1003" to="1011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Rion Snow, and Dan Jurafsky</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Semantic Rule Filtering for Web-Scale Relation Extraction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Andrea</forename><surname>Moro</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hong</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sebastian</forename><surname>Krause</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Feiyu</forename><surname>Xu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Roberto</forename><surname>Navigli</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hans</forename><surname>Uszkoreit</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of ISWC</title>
		<meeting>of ISWC</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="347" to="362" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Modeling Missing Data in Distant Supervision for Information Extraction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alan</forename><surname>Ritter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Luke</forename><surname>Zettlemoyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mausam</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Oren</forename><surname>Etzioni</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">TACL</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="367" to="378" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A semantic approach to IE pattern induction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mark</forename><surname>Stevenson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mark</forename><surname>Greenwood</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of ACL</title>
		<meeting>of ACL</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="379" to="386" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Multi-instance Multi-label Learning for Relation Extraction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mihai</forename><surname>Surdeanu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Julie</forename><surname>Tibshirani</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ramesh</forename><surname>Nallapati</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christopher</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Manning</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of EMNLP</title>
		<meeting>of EMNLP</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="455" to="465" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">From Strings to Things-Sar-Graphs: A New Type of Resource for Connecting Knowledge and Language</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hans</forename><surname>Uszkoreit</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Feiyu</forename><surname>Xu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of WS on NLP and DBpedia</title>
		<meeting>of WS on NLP and DBpedia</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A Seed-driven Bottom-up Machine Learning Framework for Extracting Relations of Various Complexity</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Feiyu</forename><surname>Xu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hans</forename><surname>Uszkoreit</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hong</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of ACL</title>
		<meeting>of ACL</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="584" to="591" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
