<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T10:09+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Tea Party in the House: A Hierarchical Ideal Point Topic Model and Its Application to Republican Legislators in the 112 th Congress</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
				<availability status="unknown"><p>Copyright Association for Computational Linguistics</p>
				</availability>
				<date>July 26-31, 2015. 2015</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Viet-An</forename><surname>Nguyen</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep3">Linguistics &amp;</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep4">Government and Politics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">University of Maryland College Park</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">University of Colorado Boulder</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit3">UMIACS University of Maryland College Park</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit4">University of Maryland College Park</orgName>
								<address>
									<region>MD, CO, MD, MD</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jordan</forename><surname>Boyd-Graber</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep3">Linguistics &amp;</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep4">Government and Politics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">University of Maryland College Park</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">University of Colorado Boulder</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit3">UMIACS University of Maryland College Park</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit4">University of Maryland College Park</orgName>
								<address>
									<region>MD, CO, MD, MD</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jordan</forename><forename type="middle">Boyd</forename><surname>Graber</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep3">Linguistics &amp;</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep4">Government and Politics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">University of Maryland College Park</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">University of Colorado Boulder</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit3">UMIACS University of Maryland College Park</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit4">University of Maryland College Park</orgName>
								<address>
									<region>MD, CO, MD, MD</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Philip</forename><surname>Resnik</surname></persName>
							<email>resnik@umd.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep3">Linguistics &amp;</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep4">Government and Politics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">University of Maryland College Park</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">University of Colorado Boulder</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit3">UMIACS University of Maryland College Park</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit4">University of Maryland College Park</orgName>
								<address>
									<region>MD, CO, MD, MD</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kristina</forename><surname>Miler</surname></persName>
							<email>kmiler@umd.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep3">Linguistics &amp;</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep4">Government and Politics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">University of Maryland College Park</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">University of Colorado Boulder</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit3">UMIACS University of Maryland College Park</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit4">University of Maryland College Park</orgName>
								<address>
									<region>MD, CO, MD, MD</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Tea Party in the House: A Hierarchical Ideal Point Topic Model and Its Application to Republican Legislators in the 112 th Congress</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 53rd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics and the 7th International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing</title>
						<meeting>the 53rd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics and the 7th International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing <address><addrLine>Beijing, China</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="1438" to="1448"/>
							<date type="published">July 26-31, 2015. 2015</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>We introduce the Hierarchical Ideal Point Topic Model, which provides a rich picture of policy issues, framing, and voting behavior using a joint model of votes, bill text, and the language that legislators use when debating bills. We use this model to look at the relationship between Tea Party Republicans and &quot;establishment&quot; Republicans in the U.S. House of Representatives during the 112 th Congress.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Capturing Political Polarization</head><p>Ideal-point models are one of the most widely used tools in contemporary political science re- search ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">Poole and Rosenthal, 2007</ref>). These models estimate political preferences for legislators, known as their ideal points, from binary data such as leg- islative votes. Popular formulations analyze legis- lators' votes and place them on a one-dimensional scale, most often interpreted as an ideological spec- trum from liberal to conservative.</p><p>Moving beyond a single dimension is attractive, however, since people may lean differently based on policy issues; for example, the conservative movement in the U.S. includes fiscal conservatives who are relatively liberal on social issues, and vice versa. In multi-dimensional ideal point models, therefore, the ideal point of each legislator is no longer characterized by a single number, but by a multi-dimensional vector. With that move comes a new challenge, though: the additional dimensions are often difficult to interpret. To mitigate this problem, recent research has introduced methods that estimate multi-dimensional ideal points using both voting data and the texts of the bills being voted on, e.g., using topic models and associating each dimension of the ideal point space with a topic. The words most strongly associated with the topic can sometimes provide a readable description of its corresponding dimension.</p><p>In this paper, we develop this idea further by introducing HIPTM, the Hierarchical Ideal Point Topic Model, to estimate multi-dimensional ideal points for legislators in the U.S. Congress. HIPTM differs from previous models in three ways. First, HIPTM uses not only votes and associated bill text, but also the language of the legislators themselves; this allows predictions of ideal points from politi- cians' writing alone. Second, HIPTM improves the interpretability of ideal-point dimensions by incorporating data from the Congressional Bills Project ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Adler and Wilkerson, 2015)</ref>, in which bills are labeled with major topics from the Policy Agen- das Project Topic Codebook. <ref type="bibr">1</ref> And third, HIPTM discovers a hierarchy of topics, allowing us to ana- lyze both agenda issues and issue-specific frames that legislators use on the congressional floor, fol- lowing <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">Nguyen et al. (2013)</ref> in modeling framing as second-level agenda setting <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">(McCombs, 2005)</ref>.</p><p>Using this new model, we focus on Republican legislators during the 112 th U.S. Congress, from January 2011 until January 2013. This is a par- ticularly interesting session of Congress for politi- cal scientists, because of the rise of the Tea Party, a decentralized political movement with populist, libertarian, and conservative elements. Although united with "establishment" Republicans against Democrats in the 2010 midterm elections, lead- ing to massive Democratic defeats, the Tea Party was-and still is-wrestling with establishment Republicans for control of the Republican party.</p><p>The Tea Party is a new and complex phe- nomenon for political scientists; as <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Carmines and D'Amico (2015)</ref> observe: "Conventional views of ideology as a single-dimensional, left-right spec- trum experience great difficulty in understanding or explaining the Tea Party." Our model identifies legislators who have low (or high) levels of "Tea Partiness" but are (or are not) members of the Tea Party Caucus, and providing insights into the na-ture of polarization within the Republican party. HIPTM also makes it possible to investigate a num- ber of questions of interest to political scientists. For example, are there Republicans who identify themselves as members of the Tea Party, but whose votes and language betray a lack of enthusiasm for Tea Party issues? How well can we predict from someone's language alone whether they are likely to associate themselves with the Tea Party? Our computational modeling approach to "Tea Parti- ness", distinct from self-declared Tea Party Caucus membership, may have particular value in under- standing Republican party politics going forward because, despite the continued influence of the Tea Party, the official Tea Party Caucus in the House of Representatives is largely inactive and its future uncertain <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(Fuller, 2015</ref>).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Polarization across Dimensions</head><p>Ideal point models describe probabilistic rela- tionships between observed responses (votes) on a set of items (bills) by a set of responders (legis- lators) who are characterized by continuous latent traits <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Fox, 2010)</ref>. A popular formulation posits an ideal point u a for each lawmaker a, a polarity x b , and popularity y b for each bill b, all being values in (−∞, +∞) ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">Martin and Quinn, 2002;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Bafumi et al., 2005;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Gerrish and Blei, 2011)</ref>. Lawmaker a votes "Yes" on bill b with probability</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">p(v a,b = Yes | u a , x b , y b ) = Φ(u a x b + y b ) (1)</formula><p>where Φ(α) = exp(α)/(1 + exp(α)) is the logis- tic (or inverse-logit) function. <ref type="bibr">2</ref> Intuitively, most lawmakers vote "Yes" on bills with high popularity y b and "No" on bills with low y b . When a bill's popularity is lower, the outcome of the vote v a,b depends more on the interaction between the law- maker's ideal point u a and the bill's polarity x b .</p><p>Multi-dimensional ideal point models replace scalars u a and x b with K-dimensional vectors u a and x b ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">Heckman and Jr., 1997;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Jackman, 2001;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Clinton et al., 2004</ref>). Unfortunately, as <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">Lauderdale and Clark (2014)</ref> observe, the binary data used for these models are "insufficiently informative to sup- port analyses beyond one or two dimensions", and the additional dimensions are difficult to interpret. To address this lack of interpretability, recent work has proposed multi-dimensional ideal point models to jointly capture both binary votes and the associ-ated text <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(Gerrish and Blei, 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Gu et al., 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b23">Lauderdale and Clark, 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b36">Sim et al., 2015</ref>).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Hierarchical Ideal Point Topic Model</head><p>Bringing topic models <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Blei and Lafferty, 2009)</ref> into ideal-point modeling provides an interpretable, text-based foundation for political scientists to un- derstand why the models make the predictions they do. However, both the topic-what is discussed- and the framing-how it is discussed-also reveal political preferences. We therefore introduce frame- specific ideal points, using a hierarchy of topics to model issues and their issue-specific frames. Al- though the definition of "frame" is itself a moving target in political science <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Entman, 1993)</ref>, we adopt the theoretically motivated but pragmatic approach of <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">Nguyen et al. (2013)</ref>: just as agenda-issues map naturally to topics in probabilistic topic models (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Grimmer (2010)</ref>), the frames as second-level agenda-setting <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">(McCombs, 2005</ref>) map to second- level topics in a hierarchical topic model. Our model's inputs are votes {v a,b }, each the response of legislator a ∈ [1, A] to bill b ∈ <ref type="bibr">[1, B]</ref>. Two types of text supplement the votes: floor speeches (documents) {w d } from legislator a d , and the text w b of bill b. While congressional debates are typically about one piece of legislation, we make no assumptions about the mapping between w d and w b . In principle this allows w d to be any text by legislator a d (e.g., not just floor speeches about this bill, but blogs, social media, press re- leases) and-unlike Gerrish and Blei (2011)-this permits us to make predictions about individuals even without vote data for them. <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref> shows the plate notation diagram of HIPTM, which has the following generative process:</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">1. For each issue k ∈ [1, K] (a) Draw k's associated topic φ k ∼ Dir(β, φ k ) (b) Draw issue-specific distribution over frames ψ k ∼ GEM(λ0) (c) For each frame j ∈ [1, ∞) (specific to issue k) i. Draw j's associated topic φ k,j ∼ Dir(β, φ k ) ii. Draw j's regression weight η k,j ∼ N (0, γ) 2. For each document d ∈ [1, D] by legislator a d (a) Draw topic (i.e., issue) distribution θ d ∼ Dir(α) (b) For each issue k ∈ [1, K], draw frame distribu- tion ψ d,k ∼ DP(λ, ψ k ) (c) For each token n ∈ [1, N d ] i. Draw an issue z d,n ∼ Mult(θ d ) ii. Draw a frame t d,n ∼ Mult(ψ d,z d,n ) iii. Draw word w d,n ∼ Mult(φz d,n ,t d,n ) 3. For each legislator a ∈ [1, A] on each issue k ∈ [1, K] (a) Draw issue-specific ideal point u a,k ∼ N ( J k j=1ˆψ</formula><p>j=1ˆ j=1ˆψ a,k,j η k,j , ρ) weighting η k,j by how much the legislator talks about that frame * <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref>: Plate notation diagram of HIPTM.</p><p>Agriculture: food; agriculture; loan; farm; crop; dairy; rural; conserve; commodity; eligible; farmer; margin; milk; contract; nutrition; livestock; plant Health: drug; medicine; coverage; disease; public health; hospital; social security; health insurrance; patient; appli- cation; treatment; payment; physician; nurse; clinic Labor, Employment, and Immigration: employment; immigration; labor; paragraph; eligible; status; compen- sation; application; wage; homeland security; unemploy- ment; board; violation; file; perform; mine <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>: Examples of informed priors φ k for issues.</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">4. For each bill b ∈ [1, B] (a) Draw polarity x b ∼ N (0, σ) (b) Draw popularity y b ∼ N (0, σ) (c) Draw topic (i.e., issue) proportions ϑ b ∼ Dir(α) (d) For each token m ∈ [1, M b ] in the text of bill b i. Draw an issue z b,m ∼ Mult(ϑ b ) ii. Draw a word type w b,m ∼ Mult(φ z b,m ) 5. For each vote v a,b of legislator a on bill b (a) p(v a,b | ua, x b , y b , ˆ ϑ b ) = Φ x b k ˆ ϑ b,k u a,k + y b</formula><p>Topic Hierarchy. With the goal of analyzing agendas and frames in mind, our topic hierarchy has two levels: (1) issue nodes and (2) frame nodes.</p><p>(Look ahead to <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Figure 6</ref> for an illustration.) More specifically, there are K issue nodes, each with a topic φ k drawn from a Dirichlet distribution with concentration parameter β and a prior mean vector</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">φ k , i.e., φ k ∼ Dir(β, φ k ).</formula><p>In this hierarchical struc- ture, first-level nodes map to agenda issues, which we treat as non-polarized, and second-level nodes map to issue-specific frames, which we assume polarize on the issue-specific dimension. <ref type="bibr">3</ref> To improve topic interpretability, issue nodes have an informed prior from the Congressional Bills Project {φ k } <ref type="table">(Table 1</ref>). <ref type="bibr">4</ref> The frame topic φ k,j 3 Nguyen et al. <ref type="formula">(2013)</ref> allow first-level nodes to polarize but find first-level nodes are typically neutral. <ref type="bibr">4</ref> The Congressional Bills Project provides a large collec- tion of labeled congressional bill text. We compute {φ k } as at each frame node is a Dirichlet draw centered at the corresponding (parent) issue node. While the number of issues is fixed a priori, the number of second-level frames is unbounded. We also asso- ciate each second-level frame node with an ideal point η k,j ∼ N (0, γ). This resembles how su- pervised topic models ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Blei and McAuliffe, 2007;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b31">Nguyen et al., 2015</ref>) discover polarized topics' as- sociated response variables.</p><p>Generating Text from Legislators. One of our model's goal is to study how legislators frame pol- icy agenda issues. To achieve that, we analyze congressional speeches (documents) {w d }, each of which is delivered by a legislator <ref type="formula">(2)</ref> choose a frame t d,n from the set of infinitely many possi- ble frames of the given issue z d,n using the frame proportion ψ d,k drawn from a Dirichlet process, and finally <ref type="formula">(3)</ref>  Generating Roll Call Votes. Following recent work on multi-dimensional ideal points <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">(Lauderdale and Clark, 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b36">Sim et al., 2015)</ref>, we define the probability of legislator a voting "Yes" on bill</p><formula xml:id="formula_4">a d . To gen- erate each token w d,n of a speech d, legislator a d will (1) first choose an issue z d,n ∈ [1, K] from a document-specific multinomial θ d , then</formula><formula xml:id="formula_5">b as p(v a,b = Yes | u a , x b , y b , ˆ ϑ b ) = Φ x b K k=1ˆϑ k=1ˆ k=1ˆϑ b,k u a,k + y b (2)</formula><p>wherê ϑ b is the empirical distribution of bill b over the K issues and is defined asˆϑasˆ</p><formula xml:id="formula_6">asˆϑ b,k = M b,k M b,·</formula><p>. Here, M b,k is the number of times in which tokens in b the empirical word distribution from all bills labeled with k. K = 19, corresponding to 19 major topic headings in the Policy Agendas Project Topic Codebook. <ref type="bibr">5</ref> If we abandoned the labeled data from the Congressional Bills Project to obtain the prior means φ k , it would be rela- tively straightforward to extend to a fully nonparametric model with unbounded K ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Ahmed et al., 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b32">Paisley et al., 2014</ref>). are assigned to issue k and M b,· is the marginal count, i.e., the number of tokens in bill b.</p><p>The ideal point of legislator a specifically on is- sue k is u a,k and comes from a normal distribution</p><formula xml:id="formula_7">N ( ˆ ψ T a,k η k , ρ) ≡ N   J k j=1ˆψ j=1ˆ j=1ˆψ a,k,j η k,j , ρ   (3)</formula><p>where J k is the number of frames for topic k, which is unbounded. The mean of the Normal distribution is a linear combination of the ideal points {η k,j } of all issue k's frames, weighted by how much time legislator a spends on each frame when talking about issue k, i.e.,</p><formula xml:id="formula_8">ψ a,k,j = N a,k,j N a,k,·</formula><p>. Here, N a,k,j is the number of tokens authored by a that are assigned to frame j of issue k, and N a,k,· is the marginal count. When N a,k,· = 0, which means that legislator a does not talk about issue k, we back off to an uninformed zero mean.</p><p>Equation 3 resembles how supervised topic mod- els (SLDA) link topics with a response, in that the response-the issue-specific ideal point u a,k -is latent. It is similar to how <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Gerrish and Blei (2011)</ref> use the bill text to regress on the bill's latent polar- ity x b and popularity y b . In this paper, we only use text from congressional speeches for regression, as these can capture how legislators frame specific top- ics. Incorporating the bill text into the regression is an interesting direction for future work.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Inference</head><p>Given observed data of (1) votes {v a,b } by A legislators on B bills, (2) speeches {w d } from leg- islators, and (3) bill text {w b }, we estimate the latent variables using stochastic EM. In each itera- tion, we perform the following steps: (1) sampling issue assignments {z b,m } for bill text tokens, (2) sampling the issue assignments {z d,n } and frame assignments {t d,n } for speech tokens, (3) sampling the topics at first-level issue nodes {φ k }, (4) sam- pling the distribution over frames {ψ k } for all is- sues, (5) optimizing frames' regression parameters {η k,j } using L-BFGS ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Liu and Nocedal, 1989)</ref>, and (6) updating legislators' ideal points {u a,k } and bills' polarity {x b } and popularity {y b } using gra- dient ascent.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Sampling Issue Assignments for Bill Tokens</head><p>The probability of assigning a token w b,m in the bill text to an issue k is</p><formula xml:id="formula_9">p(z b,m = k | rest) ∝ M −b,m b,k + α M −b,m b,· + Kα · ˆ φ k,w b,m<label>(4)</label></formula><p>where M b,k denotes the number of tokens in bill text b assigned to issue k. The current estimated probability of word type v given issue k isˆφisˆ isˆφ k,v (Equation 7). Marginal counts are denoted by · and the superscript −b,m excludes the assignment for token w b,m from the corresponding count. Sampling Frame Assignments in Speeches To sample the assignments for tokens in the speeches, we first sample an issue using</p><formula xml:id="formula_10">p(z d,n = k | rest) ∝ N −d,n d,k + α N −d,n d,· + Kα · ˆ φ k,w d,n (5)</formula><p>where N d,k similarly denotes the number of times that tokens in d are assigned to issue k. Given the sampled issue k, we sample the frame as</p><formula xml:id="formula_11">p(t d,n = j | z d,n = k, a d = a, rest) ∝      N (u a,k ; µ a,k,j , ρ) · N −d,n d,k,j N −d,n d,k,j +λ + λ·ˆψλ·ˆ λ·ˆψ k,j N −d,n d,k,j +λ , N (u a,k ; µ a,k,j new , ρ) · λ N −d,n d,k,j +λ · ˆ ψ k,j new ,<label>(6)</label></formula><p>where µ a,k,j = (</p><formula xml:id="formula_12">J k j =1 η k,j N −d,n d,k,j + η k,j )/N d,k,·</formula><p>for an existing frame j, and for a newly created frame j new , we have µ a,k, <ref type="figure">prior N (0, γ)</ref>. Here, the estimated global probability of choosing a frame j of issue k isˆψisˆ isˆψ k,j .</p><formula xml:id="formula_13">j new = ( J k j =1 η k,j N −d,n d,k,j +η k,j new )/N d,k,· , where η k,j new is drawn from the Gaussian</formula><p>Sampling Issue Topics In the generative process of HIPTM, the topic φ k of issue k (1) generates tokens in the bill text and (2) provides the Dirichlet priors of the issue's frames. Rather than collapsing multinomials and factorizing (Hu and Boyd-Graber, 2012), we follow <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Ahmed et al. (2013)</ref> and samplêsamplê</p><formula xml:id="formula_14">φ k ∼ Dir(m k + ˜ n k + βφ k )<label>(7)</label></formula><p>where</p><formula xml:id="formula_15">m k ≡ (M k,1 , M k,2 , · · · , M k,V )</formula><p>is the token count vector from the bill text assigned to each issue. The vectorñvector˜vectorñ k ≡ ( ˜ N k,1 , ˜ N k,2 , · · · , ˜ N k,V ) denotes the token counts propagated from words assigned to topics that are associated with frames of issue k, approximated using minimal or maximal path assumptions <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Cowans, 2006;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b38">Wallach, 2008)</ref>.</p><p>Sampling Frame Proportions Following the di- rect assignment method described in <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">Teh et al. (2006)</ref>, we sample the global frame proportion asˆψ asˆ</p><formula xml:id="formula_16">asˆψ k ≡ ( ˆ ψ k,1 , ˆ ψ k,2 , · · · , ˆ ψ k,j new ) ∼ Dir( ˆ N ·,k,1 , ˆ N ·,k,2 , · · · , ˆ N ·,k,J k , λ 0 ) (8) wherê N ·,k,j = D d=1ˆN d=1ˆ d=1ˆN d,k,j andˆNandˆ andˆN d,k,j</formula><p>can be sampled effectively using the Antoniak distribu- tion <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Antoniak, 1974)</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Optimizing Frame Regression Parameters</head><p>We update the regression parameters η k of frames under issue k using L-BFGS ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Liu and Nocedal, 1989)</ref> to optimize L(η k )</p><formula xml:id="formula_17">− 1 2ρ A a=1 (u a,k − η T k ˆ ψ a,k ) − 1 2γ J k j=1 η 2 k,j<label>(9)</label></formula><p>Updating Ideal Points, Polarity and Popularity We update the multi-dimensional ideal point u a of each legislator a and the polarity x b and popularity y b of each bill b by optimizing the log likelihood using gradient ascent.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Data Collection</head><p>What makes a Tea Partier? To address that ques- tion, we use key votes identified by Freedom Works as the most important votes on issues of economic freedom. Led by former House Majority Leader Dick Armey (R-TX), Freedom Works is a con- servative non-profit organization which promotes "Lower Taxes, Less Government, More Freedom". 6 <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Karpowitz et al. (2011)</ref> report that Freedom Works endorsements are more effective than other Tea Party organizations at getting out votes for Repub- lican candidates in the 2010 midterms.</p><p>For the 112 th Congress, Freedom Works selected 60 key votes, 40 in 2011 and 20 in 2012. We are interested in ideal points with respect to the Tea Party movement, i.e., on the anti-pro Tea Party dimension: whether a legislator agrees with Free- dom Works on a bill. More specifically, we assign v a,b to be 1 if legislator a agrees with Freedom Works on bill b, and 0 otherwise. In addition to the votes, we obtained the bill text with labels from the Congressional Bills Project 7 and the congres- sional speeches from GovTrack. 8 In total, we have 240 Republicans, 60 who self-identify with the Tea Party Caucus, and 13,856 votes.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Predicting Tea Party Membership</head><p>To quantitatively evaluate the effectiveness of HIPTM in capturing "Tea Partiness", we predict Tea Party Caucus membership of legislators given their votes and text. This examines (1) how effective the baseline features extracted from the votes and text are in predicting the Caucus membership, and (2) how much prediction improves using features extracted from HIPTM. For baselines, we consider simple feature sets where each legislator is repre- sented by their speeches as either (1) a TF-IDF vector <ref type="bibr" target="#b35">(Salton, 1968)</ref>, (2) a normalized TF-IDF vector, or (3) a binary vector containing their votes. Our dataset for binary prediction comprises a set of 60 Republican representatives who self-identify as Tea Party Caucus members and 180 who do not. These are divided using 5-fold cross-validation with stratified sampling, which preserves the ratio of the two classes in both the training and test sets. We report performance using AUC-ROC <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">(Lusted, 1971</ref>) using SVM light (Joachims, 1999). <ref type="bibr">9</ref> After pre- processing, our vocabulary contains 5,349 unique word types.</p><p>Membership from Votes and Text. First, given the votes and text of all the legislators, we run HIPTM for 1,000 iterations with a burn-in period of 500 iterations. After burning in, we keep the sam- pled state of the model after every fifty iterations.</p><p>The feature values are obtained by averaging over the ten stored models as suggested in <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">Nguyen et al. (2014)</ref>. Each legislator a is represented by a vector concatenating:</p><p>• K-dimensional ideal point vector estimated from both votes and text u a,k • K-dimensional vector, estimating the ideal point using only text <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 2</ref> shows AUC-ROC results for our feature sets. VOTE-based features clearly outperform text- based features like TF and TF-IDF. Combining VOTE with either TF or TF-IDF does not improve the prediction performance much (i.e., VOTE-TF and VOTE-TF-IDF). Features extracted from our model, HIPTM, also outperform TF and TF-IDF significantly, but only slightly better than VOTE. However, HIPTM and VOTE together significantly outperform VOTE alone.</p><formula xml:id="formula_18">η T k ˆ ψ a,k • B probabilities estimating a's votes on B bills Φ(x b K k=1ˆϑ k=1ˆ k=1ˆϑ b,k u a,k + y b )</formula><p>Membership Prediction from Text Only. The results in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 2</ref> require both votes and legisla- tors' language. This is limiting, since it permits predictions of "Tea Partiness" only for people with an established congressional voting record. A po- tentially more interesting and practical task is pre- diction based on language alone. Thus, we first run our inference algorithm on the training data, which includes both votes and text. After training, using multiple models, we sample the issue and frame assignments for each token of the text authored by test lawmakers. Since the votes are not available, HIPTM's ex- tracted features here only consist of <ref type="formula">(1)</ref>  Figure 3 compares this approach with the two baselines capable of using text alone, TF and TF- IDF. Since HIPTM can no longer access the votes in the test data, its performance drops significantly compared with VOTE. However, it still quite strongly outperforms the two text-based baselines, showing that jointly modeling the voting behavior improves the text-based elements of the model.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7">How the Tea Party Votes</head><p>In this section, we examine legislators' ideal points. We first expose Tea Party-specific ideal points by examining one-dimensional ideal points and then move on to the issue-specific ideal points that HIPTM enables.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7.1">One-dimensional Ideal Points</head><p>First, as a baseline, we estimate the one- dimensional ideal points of the legislators in our dataset. 10 <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Figure 4</ref> shows the box plots of esti- mated Tea Party ideal points for both members and non-members. <ref type="bibr">11</ref> The Tea Party ideal points cor- relate with DW-NOMINATE (ρ = 0.91), and the median ideal point of Tea Party Caucus members is higher than non-members. This confirms that Tea Partiers are more conservative than other Re- publicans <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">(Williamson et al., 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Karpowitz et al., 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Gervais and Morris, 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Gervais and Morris, 2014</ref>).</p><p>Divergences involving these ideal points help demonstrate the face validity of our approach. For example, the model gives Jeff Flake (R-AZ) the sec- ond highest ideal point; he only disagrees with Free- dom Works position on one of 60 Freedom Works key votes, but he is not a member of the Tea Party Caucus. Another example is Justin Amash (R-MI), who founded and is the Chairman of the Liberty Caucus. Its members are conservative and liber- tarian Republicans, and Amash has agreed with Freedom Works on every single key vote selected by Freedom Works since 2011.</p><p>Conversely, some self-identified Tea Partiers of- ten disagree with Freedom Works and thus have relatively low ideal points. For example, Rodney Alexander (R-LA) only agrees with Freedom Works 48% of the time, and was a Democrat before 2004. Alexander and Ander Crenshaw (R-FL, 50% agree- ment) are categorized as "Green Tea" by <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Gervais and Morris (2014)</ref>, i.e. Republican legislators who are "associated with the Tea Party on their own initiative" but lack support from Tea Party organi- zations. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Ideal Points</head><p>Tea Party Caucus Member Non−member <ref type="figure">Figure 5</ref>: Box plots of ideal points dimensions, each corresponding to a major topic in the Policy Agendas Topics Codebook estimated by our model. On most issues the ideal point distributions over the two Republican groups (member vs. non-member of the Tea Party Caucus) overlap. The most polarized issues are Government Operations and Macroeconomics, which align well with the agenda of the Tea Party movement supporting small government and lower taxes.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7.2">Multi-dimensional Ideal Points</head><p>While it is interesting to compare holistic mea- sures of Tea Partiness, it doesn't reveal how leg- islators conform or deviate from what defines a mainstream Tea Partier. In this section, HIPTM reveals how issue-specific ideal points of the two groups of Republican representatives differ. <ref type="figure">Figure 5</ref> shows estimated ideal points for each policy agenda issue, sorted by the difference be- tween the median of the two groups' ideal points. On most issues, the ideal point distributions of the two Republican groups are nigh identical.</p><p>On several issues, though, the ideal point distri- butions of the two groups of legislators diverge. In the remainder of this section, we consider the Government Operation, Macroeconomics, and Transportation topics, and look at why HIPTM esti- mates these issues as the most polarized.</p><p>Government operations Tea Partiers differ from their Republican colleagues on reducing gov- ernment spending on the Economic Development Administration, the Energy Efficiency and Renew- able Energy Program and Fossil Fuel Research and Development. More specifically, for example, on the key vote to eliminate the Energy Efficiency and Renewable Energy Program, nearly 80% (41 out of 53) of Tea Partiers vote "Yea" (with Freedom Works) but only 43% of non-Tea Partiers agree.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Macroeconomics</head><p>Our model estimates Macroeconomics policies as being the sec- ond most polarizing topic for House Republicans, which is consistent with the emphasis that the Tea Party places on issues like a balanced budget and reduced federal spending. Indeed, we see that Tea Party Republicans have distinct preferences on these types of issues as compared to more mainstream Republican legislators. An illustration of this polarization can be seen in the intra-party fight over the budget. Roll call vote 275 in 2011 and roll call vote 149 in 2012 both would have replaced Paul Ryan's budget (the "establishment" Republican budget) with the Republican Study Committee's (RSC) "Back to Basics" budget that would cut spending more aggressively and balance the budget in a decade. In 2011, non-Tea Party Republicans were evenly split in their budget preferences, but three quarters of the Tea Party Caucus supported it, which illustrates the differ- ence between the two factions of the Republican party. Similarly, in 2012, more than 80% of Tea Partiers voted for the the RSC budget, but fewer than half of non-Tea Party Republicans did. Other polarizing votes in the Macroeconomics topic include votes to raise the debt ceiling and to avert the "fiscal cliff". In these cases, support for these votes was 25 percentage points higher among Tea Partiers than non-Tea Party Republicans, which again illustrates their distinct policy preferences.</p><p>Transportation Transportation is the third most polarized issue estimated by our model, with two key votes focusing on federal spending on trans- portation that illustrate some polarization, but also some shared preferences among Republicans. Con- sistent with the Tea Party's emphasis on reducing government spending, Tea Party Republicans voted differently from their non-Tea Party colleagues on these issues. The first key vote, roll call vote 378 in 2012, caps highway spending at the amount taken in by the gas tax. More than half of Tea Party Cau- cus members (32 out of 55) voted in favor, while non-members voted against it by a greater than 2:1 margin (122 of 172). Conversely, the second key vote (roll call vote 451 in 2012) authorizes fed- eral highway spending at a level that far exceeds its revenue from the gas tax, which was opposed by Freedom Works. This measure was broadly popular with Republicans regardless of Tea Party affiliation and a majority of both Tea Partiers and non-Tea Partiers opposed it.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="8">How the Tea Party Talks</head><p>Looking at HIPTM's induced topic hierarchy, us- ing labeled data to create informative priors pro- duces highly interpretable topics at the agenda- issue level; e.g., see the first-level nodes in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Figure 6</ref>, which capture key issue-level debates. For exam- ple, one major event during the 112 th Congress was the 2011 debt-ceiling crisis, which dominates dis- cussions in Macroeconomics. Similarly, Defense is dominated by withdrawing U.S. troops from Iraq.</p><p>Turning to framing, recall that second-level nodes of the hierarchy capture issue-specific frames of parent issues, each one associated with a frame- specific ideal point. To analyze intra-Republican polarization, we first compute, for each issue k, the span of ideal points the frames associated with k, i.e., the difference between the maximum and the minimum ideal points for frames under that issue. <ref type="bibr">12</ref> We then consider several issues with a large span, i.e. whose frames are highly polarized.</p><p>Macroeconomics. The HIPTM subtree for Macroeconomics, in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Figure 6</ref> (top), foregrounds <ref type="bibr">12</ref> The frame proportions Dirichlet process ψ k creates many frames with one or two observations <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">(Miller and Harrison, 2013)</ref>. We ignore those with posterior probability ψ k,j &lt; 0.1.</p><p>Republican polarization related to budget issues. The most Tea Party oriented frame node, M3, focuses on criticizing government overspending, a recurring Tea Party theme. <ref type="bibr">13</ref> In contrast, Frame M1, least oriented toward the Tea Party, focuses on the downsides of a government shutdown, highlighting establishment Republican concerns about being held responsible for the political and economic consequences.</p><p>Health. Healthcare was a central issue during the 112 th Congress, particularly the Affordable Care Act (Obamacare). Although all Republicans voted to repeal Obamacare, <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Figure 6</ref> (bottom) high- lights intra-party differences in framing the issue. Frame H1 leans strongest toward the establishment Republican end of the spectrum, and frames op- position in terms of the implementation of health care exchanges and the mandatory costs of the pro- gram. In contrast, H3 captures the more strident Tea Party framing of Obamacare as an unconstitu- tional government takeover. More neutral from an intra-party perspective, Frame H2 emphasizes Medicare, Medicaid, and the role of health care professionals within these systems. <ref type="bibr">14</ref> Labor, Employment and Immigration. The discussion of this issue illustrates how HIPTM some- times captures frames that are distinct from Tea Partiness, per se. For example, it discovered a strongly Tea Party oriented frame that focused on "union, south carolina, nlrb, boeing". On inspec- tion, this frame reflects a controversy in which the National Labor Relations Board accused airline manufacturer Boeing of violating Federal labor law by transferring production to a non-union facility in South Carolina "for discriminatory reasons", <ref type="bibr">15</ref> and surfaces mainly in speeches by four legislators from South Carolina, three of whom are from the Tea Party Caucus. This second-level topic illus- trates a limitation of HIPTM; it does not formally distinguish frames from other kinds of subtopics. We observe that modeling polarization on other kinds of sub-issues is nonetheless valuable: here it highlights a geographic locus of conflict involv-  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="9">Latent and Visible Disagreement</head><p>Our analyses suggest a novel framework for un- derstanding the political and policymaking impli- cations of the Tea Party in the 112 th Congress, il- lustrated in <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">Table 2</ref>. Each issue can be character- ized by two features: (1) the degree to which ideal points among Republican legislators are polarized, and (2) the degree to which the frames used are po- larized. From these two assessments, we can orga- nize all policy issues into four categories that have meaningful implications for congressional politics and policy outcomes. At upper left we will find issues where HIPTM indicates low intra-party po- larization between Tea Party and non-Tea Party, and all Republicans tend to frame the issue in sim- ilar ways; e.g., Civil Rights, Minority Issues, and Civil Liberties. In such cases, we expect cooper- ation among Republicans regardless of Tea Party status, therefore a greater likelihood of bill pas- sage in a majority-Republican House. In stark con- trast, issues at lower right involve polarized ideal points and polarized framing, e.g., the budget cri- sis, where many establishment Republicans balked at a government shutdown but hard-line Tea Party legislators did not. These issues pose the greatest challenge to Republican party leaders.</p><p>Between these extremes are the issues in which either Republicans' ideal points or their policy frames are polarized. Our model suggests that on issues at upper right, with similar framing, the Tea Party and establishment Republicans will appear to be in sync, and therefore it may seem to voters that legislative progress is likely, but the under- lying issue polarization will make it hard to find policy common ground, potentially increasing pub- lic frustration. Last, at lower left are issues where Republicans generally share similar ideal points and vote similarly, but frame the issue in distinct ways, e.g., Obamacare. Here legislative success may come despite the appearance that Republican factions are talking past each other, because the distribution of their ideal points on the policy is actually quite similar. Put differently, Republicans share policy goals on issues in this quadrant even if they frame those preferences differently, and this underlying agreement on the ideal point may al- low Republicans to reach consensus even when the political rhetoric suggests otherwise.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="10">Conclusion</head><p>We introduce HIPTM, which integrates hierarchi- cal topic modeling with multi-dimensional ideal points to jointly model voting behavior, the text content of bills, and the language used by legisla- tors. HIPTM is more effective than previous meth- ods on the task of predicting membership in the Tea Party Caucus. This improvement is especially consequential as the formal organization of the Tea Party Caucus is now defunct in the House, yet Tea Party legislators remain both numerous and influen- tial in Congress. In addition, unlike previous ideal- point methods, HIPTM makes it possible to make predictions for members of Congress who have not yet established a voting record. More intriguingly, this also suggests the possibility of assessing the "Tea Partiness" of candidates (or, anyone else, e.g., media outlets) based on language.</p><p>It is political conventional wisdom that the in- flux of Tea Party legislators in the 112 th Congress complicated the task of governance and policymak- ing for Republican leaders. By looking at issue- level ideal points and issue-specific framing using our model, we begin to address the complexity of this relationship, finding the model successful both in establishing face validity and in suggesting novel insights into the dynamics of a Republican Congress. In future work, we plan to pursue the new framework suggested by our analyses, inves- tigating the interaction of issue polarization and framing-based polarization. With the help of these new tools, we aim to both understand and predict substantive policy areas in which the Tea Party is likely to be most successful working with the Re- publican party, and, conversely, to flag ahead of time policy areas in which we can expect to see legislative gridlock and grandstanding.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2: Tea Party Caucus membership prediction results over five folds using AUC-ROC (higher is better, random baseline achieves 0.5). The features extracted from our model are estimated using both the votes and the text.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Figure 3: Tea Party Caucus membership prediction results over five folds using AUC-ROC (higher is better, random baseline achieves 0.5). The features extracted from our model for unseen legislators are estimated using their text only.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>the K- dimensional vector η T k ˆ ψ a,k estimating legislators' ideal point using text alone, and (2) the B proba- bilities Φ(x b K k=1ˆϑ k=1ˆ k=1ˆϑ b,k u a,k + y b ) estimating the votes.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>Figure 4 :</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Figure 4: Box plots of the one-dimensional Tea Party ideal points, estimated as a baseline in Section 7.1, for members and non-members of the Tea Party Caucus among Republican Representatives in the 112 th U.S. House. The median of members' ideal points is significantly higher than that of non-members'.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head>MacroeconomicsFigure 6 :</head><label>6</label><figDesc>Figure 6: Framing of Macroeconomics (top) and Health (bottom) among House Republicans, 2011-2012. Higher ideal point values are associated with the Tea Party.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3" validated="false"><head>Table 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Examples of agenda issues classified by polarization 
of ideal points and issue frames within the Republican party. 

ing South Carolina, where many representatives 
are Tea Party Caucus members. This may provide 
insight into how geography shapes Tea Party mem-
bership (Gervais and Morris, 2012). 

</table></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> http://www.policyagendas.org/</note>

			<note place="foot" n="2"> A probit function is also often used where Φ(α) is instead the cumulative distribution function of a Gaussian distribution (Martin and Quinn, 2002).</note>

			<note place="foot" n="6"> http://congress.freedomworks.org/ 7 http://congressionalbills.org/ 8 https://www.govtrack.us/data/us/112/</note>

			<note place="foot" n="9"> We use the default settings of SVM light , except that we set the cost-factor equal to the ratio between the number of negative examples (i.e., number of non-Tea Party Caucus members) and the number of positive examples (i.e., number of Tea Party Caucus members).</note>

			<note place="foot" n="10"> We use gradient ascent to optimize the likelihood of votes whose probabilities are defined in Equation 1. We also put a Gaussian prior N (0, σ) on ua, x b , and y b. 11 Estimated ideal point signs might be flipped, as uax b = (−ua)(−x b ), which makes no difference in Equation 1. To ensure that higher ideal points are &quot;pro-Tea Party&quot;, we first sort the legislators according to the fraction of votes for which they agree with Freedom Works and initialize the ideal points of the top and bottom five legislators with +3σ and-3σ, where σ is the variance of ua&apos;s Gaussian prior.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="13"> E.g., Scott Garrett (R-NJ): &quot;We will not compromise on our principles; our principles of defending the Constitution and defending Americans and making sure that our posterity does not have this excessive debt on it.&quot; 14 This does not mean that discussions using this frame lacked combative or partisan elements. For example, Glenn Thompson (R-PA) argues that &quot;on the Democratic side, they&apos;re just willing to pull the plug and let [Medicare] die&quot;. 15 http://www.nlrb.gov/news-outreach/fact-sheets/factsheet-archives/boeing-complaint-fact-sheet</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgements</head><p>This work was supported by the NSF Grant IIS-1211153 and IIS-1409287. Boyd-Graber is also supported by NSF grants IIS-1320538 and NCSE-1422492. Any opinions, findings, conclusions, or recommendations expressed here are those of the authors and do not necessarily reflect the view of the sponsor.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Scott</forename><surname>Adler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">John</forename><surname>Wilkerson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Congressional bills project. NSF 00880066 and</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
			<biblScope unit="page">880061</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Nested Chinese restaurant franchise process: Applications to user tracking and document modeling</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Amr</forename><surname>Ahmed</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Liangjie</forename><surname>Hong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alexander</forename><surname>Smola</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the International Conference of Machine Learning</title>
		<meeting>the International Conference of Machine Learning</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1426" to="1434" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Mixtures of Dirichlet processes with applications to Bayesian nonparametric problems</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Charles</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Antoniak</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The Annals of Statistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1152" to="1174" />
			<date type="published" when="1974" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Practical issues in implementing and understanding Bayesian ideal point estimation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Joseph</forename><surname>Bafumi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Andrew</forename><surname>Gelman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>David</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Noah</forename><surname>Park</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Kaplan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Political Analysis</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="171" to="187" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Text Mining: Theory and Applications, chapter Topic Models</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>David</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">John</forename><surname>Blei</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Lafferty</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<publisher>Taylor and Francis</publisher>
			<pubPlace>London</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Supervised topic models</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>David</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jon</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Blei</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Mcauliffe</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of Advances in Neural Information Processing Systems</title>
		<meeting>Advances in Neural Information Processing Systems</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="121" to="128" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The new look in political ideology research</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Edward</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Carmines</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J D&amp;apos;</forename><surname>Nicholas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Amico</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Annual Review of Political Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">18</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The statistical analysis of roll call data</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Joshua</forename><surname>Clinton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Simon</forename><surname>Jackman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Douglas</forename><surname>Rivers</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">American Political Science Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">98</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">02</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="355" to="370" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Probabilistic Document Modelling</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Philip</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Cowans</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>University of Cambridge</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
<note type="report_type">Ph.D. thesis</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Framing: Toward clarification of a fractured paradigm</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Robert M Entman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Communication</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">43</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="51" to="58" />
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Bayesian item response modeling: Theory and applications</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jean-Paul</forename><surname>Fox</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">New Tea Party Caucus chairman: DHS fight could break the GOP. Roll Call</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Matt</forename><surname>Fuller</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://blogs.rollcall.com/218/new-tea-party-caucus-chairman-dhs-fight-could-break-the-gop/" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Predicting legislative roll calls from text</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sean</forename><surname>Gerrish</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Blei</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the International Conference of Machine Learning</title>
		<meeting>the International Conference of Machine Learning</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="489" to="496" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">How they vote: Issueadjusted models of legislative behavior</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sean</forename><surname>Gerrish</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>David</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Blei</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of Advances in Neural Information Processing Systems</title>
		<meeting>Advances in Neural Information Processing Systems</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2753" to="2761" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Reading the tea leaves: Understanding Tea Party Caucus membership in the US House of Representatives</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Bryan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Gervais</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Irwin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Morris</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">PS: Political Science &amp; Politics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">45</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">02</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="245" to="250" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Black Tea, Green Tea, White Tea, and Coffee: Understanding the variation in attachment to the Tea Party among members of Congress</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Bryan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Gervais</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Irwin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Morris</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Annual Meeting of the American Political Science Association</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A Bayesian hierarchical topic model for political texts: Measuring expressed agendas in Senate press releases</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Justin</forename><surname>Grimmer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Political Analysis</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">18</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="35" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Topic-factorized ideal point estimation model for legislative voting network</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yupeng</forename><surname>Gu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yizhou</forename><surname>Sun</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ning</forename><surname>Jiang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bingyu</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ting</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of International Conference on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining</title>
		<meeting>International Conference on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="183" to="192" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Linear probability models of the demand for attributes with an empirical application to estimating the preferences of legislators</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">James</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Heckman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">James</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Snyder</surname><genName>Jr</genName></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The RAND Journal of Economics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">28</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="142" to="189" />
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Efficient treebased topic modeling</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yuening</forename><surname>Hu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jordan</forename><surname>Boyd-Graber</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Multidimensional analysis of roll call data via Bayesian simulation: Identification, estimation, inference, and model checking</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Simon</forename><surname>Jackman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Political Analysis</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="227" to="241" />
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Making large-scale SVM learning practical</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Thorsten</forename><forename type="middle">Joachims</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Advances in Kernel Methods-SVM</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>Universität Dortmund</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Christopher F Karpowitz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Monson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jeremy</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Kelly D Patterson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Pope</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Tea time in America? The impact of the Tea Party movement on the 2010 midterm elections. PS: Political Science &amp; Politics</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">44</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="303" to="309" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Scaling politically meaningful dimensions using texts and votes</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Benjamin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tom</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Lauderdale</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Clark</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">American Journal of Political Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">58</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="754" to="771" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">On the limited memory BFGS method for large scale optimization</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Dong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jorge</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Nocedal</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Mathematical programming</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">45</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1-3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="503" to="528" />
			<date type="published" when="1989" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Signal Detectability and Medical Decision-Making</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lee</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Lusted</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">171</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1217" to="1219" />
			<date type="published" when="1971-03" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dynamic ideal point estimation via Markov chain Monte Carlo for the US Supreme Court</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Andrew</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kevin M</forename><surname>Martin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Quinn</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Political Analysis</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="134" to="153" />
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A look at agenda-setting: Past, present and future</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Maxwell</forename><surname>Mccombs</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journalism Studies</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="543" to="557" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A simple example of dirichlet process mixture inconsistency for the number of components</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Jeffrey</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Matthew T</forename><surname>Miller</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Harrison</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Advances in Neural Information Processing Systems</title>
		<editor>C.J.C. Burges, L. Bottou, M. Welling, Z. Ghahramani, and K.Q. Weinberger</editor>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Curran Associates, Inc</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="199" to="206" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Lexical and hierarchical topic regression</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jordan</forename><surname>Viet-An Nguyen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Philip</forename><surname>Boyd-Graber</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Resnik</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of Advances in Neural Information Processing Systems</title>
		<meeting>Advances in Neural Information Processing Systems</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1106" to="1114" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Sometimes average is best: The importance of averaging for prediction using MCMC inference in topic modeling</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jordan</forename><surname>Viet-An Nguyen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Philip</forename><surname>Boyd-Graber</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Resnik</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of Emperical Methods in Natural Language Processing</title>
		<meeting>Emperical Methods in Natural Language Processing</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1752" to="1757" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Is your anchor going up or down? Fast and accurate supervised topic models</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Thang</forename><surname>Nguyen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jordan</forename><surname>Boyd-Graber</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jeff</forename><surname>Lund</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kevin</forename><surname>Seppi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Eric</forename><surname>Ringger</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">North American Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Nested hierarchical Dirichlet processes</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">John</forename><surname>Paisley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chong</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>David</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michael I Jordan</forename><surname>Blei</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE Transactions on Pattern Analysis and Machine Intelligence</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A spatial model for legislative roll call analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Keith</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Howard</forename><surname>Poole</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Rosenthal</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">American Journal of Political Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="357" to="384" />
			<date type="published" when="1985" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Ideology and Congress</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Keith</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Howard L</forename><surname>Poole</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Rosenthal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
			<publisher>Transaction Publishers</publisher>
			<pubPlace>New Brunswick, NJ</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Automatic Information Organization and Retrieval</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Gerard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Salton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1968" />
			<publisher>McGraw Hill Text</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The utility of text: The case of Amicus briefs and the Supreme Court</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yanchuan</forename><surname>Sim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bryan</forename><surname>Routledge</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Noah A</forename><surname>Smith</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Association for the Advancement of Artificial Intelligence</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Hierarchical Dirichlet processes</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yee Whye</forename><surname>Teh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michael</forename><forename type="middle">I</forename><surname>Jordan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Matthew</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Beal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David M</forename><surname>Blei</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of the American Statistical Association</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="issue">476</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">101</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Structured Topic Models for Language</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Hanna M Wallach</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>University of Cambridge</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
<note type="report_type">Ph.D. thesis</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Tea Party and the remaking of Republican conservatism</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Vanessa</forename><surname>Williamson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Theda</forename><surname>Skocpol</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">John</forename><surname>Coggin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Perspectives on Politics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">01</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="25" to="43" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
