<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T12:06+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Semantic Interpretation of Superlative Expressions via Structured Knowledge Bases</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
				<availability status="unknown"><p>Copyright Association for Computational Linguistics</p>
				</availability>
				<date>July 26-31, 2015. 2015</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sheng</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">ICST</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Peking University</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Beijing</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yansong</forename><surname>Feng</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">ICST</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Peking University</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Beijing</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Songfang</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">IBM China Research Lab</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Beijing</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kun</forename><surname>Xu</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">ICST</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Peking University</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Beijing</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Zhe</forename><surname>Han</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">ICST</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Peking University</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Beijing</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dongyan</forename><surname>Zhao</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">ICST</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Peking University</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Beijing</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Semantic Interpretation of Superlative Expressions via Structured Knowledge Bases</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 53rd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics and the 7th International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing</title>
						<meeting>the 53rd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics and the 7th International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing <address><addrLine>Beijing, China</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="225" to="230"/>
							<date type="published">July 26-31, 2015. 2015</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>This paper addresses a novel task of semantically analyzing the comparative constructions inherent in attributive superlative expressions against structured knowledge bases (KBs). The task can be defined in twofold: first, selecting the comparison dimension against a KB, on which the involved items are compared; and second , determining the ranking order, in which the items are ranked (ascending or descending). We exploit Wikipedia and Freebase to collect training data in an un-supervised manner, where a neural network model is then learnt to select, from Freebase predicates, the most appropriate comparison dimension for a given superlative expression, and further determine its ranking order heuristically. Experimental results show that it is possible to learn from coarsely obtained training data to semantically characterize the comparative constructions involved in attributive superlative expressions.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Superlatives are fairly common in natural lan- guages and play an essential role in daily commu- nications, when in conveying comparisons among a set of items or degrees of certain properties. Properly analyzing superlative expressions holds the promise for many applications such as ques- tion answering (QA), text entailment, sentiment analysis and so on. In literature, analysis of superlatives has drawn more interests from both formal linguistics and semantics <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">(Szabolcsi, 1986;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Gawron, 1995;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Heim, 1999;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Farkas and Kiss, 2000</ref>), but relatively less attention from the com- putational linguistics and NLP communities <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Bos and Nissim, 2006</ref>; Jindal and <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Liu, 2006;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Scheible, 2007;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Scheible, 2009)</ref>.</p><p>Earlier computational treatments to superlatives focus on the categorizations of superlatives( <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Bos and Nissim, 2006;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Scheible, 2009)</ref>, where the most common but important type is being part of a noun phrase or describing certain properties or attributes of the subjects, named as attribu- tive superlatives or ISA-superlatives, accounting for around 90% of appearances in newswire. A typical example is Nile is the longest river in the world.</p><p>In most cases, the gist behind such superlative expressions is the comparative constructions that the utterance intends to convey to readers, e.g., in the Nile example, Nile is longer than any other rivers in the world. Semantically understanding such attributive superlative expressions boils down to interpreting the comparative construction in- volved in the utterance in the following four as- pects:</p><p>1. Target: one or more items that work as the protagonist of the utterance, and are being compared within the comparative construc- tion, e.g., Nile;</p><p>2. Comparison set: the set of items that are being compared against in the utterance( <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Bos and Nissim, 2006</ref>), e.g., all rivers in the world;</p><p>3. Comparison dimension: the attribute or property that the items are compared upon, e.g., the length of a river;</p><p>4. Ranking order: the order in which the items in the comparison set are sorted according to the dimension, in an ascending or descending order, e.g., we should rank all rivers regard- ing their lengths in a descending order to get the longest at the top.</p><p>So far, there have been only a few computa- tional treatments for superlatives, addressing the importance of categorizing superlatives, identify- ing the target and comparison set( <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Bos and Nissim, 2006;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Jindal and Liu, 2006;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Scheible, 2009)</ref>, while putting less attention on other aspects.</p><p>In fact, grounding the comparison dimension into a canonical predicate of a KB can help pro- vide more accurate interpretations for the involved comparative constructions. In question answering over structured KBs, accurate treatments for su- perlatives will not only help build more precise of structured queries, but also support shallow func- tional reasoning, e.g., formally analyzing the fifth longest river in the world, will explore the most of the structured nature of KBs, and is advantageous to traditional IR based methods.</p><p>However, selecting an appropriate comparison dimension against a structured KB is not a trivial task. Usually, the numbers of adjective superla- tives and gradable KB predicates are large, so that it is impossible to craft mapping rules to cover every pair of adjective superlative and predicate. Consequently, preparing wide-coverage annotated data to help automate this procedure is also labor- intensive and time consuming. Moreover, some adjectives are widely used, but often vague to de- cide a dimension by themselves( <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Bos and Nissim, 2006</ref>). One may need to draw support from their context and even common sense knowledge.</p><p>In this paper, we propose a novel task, se- mantically interpreting the comparative construc- tions inherent in attributive superlative expres- sions again structured KBs, e.g., Freebase <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Google, 2013)</ref>, specifically, focusing on selecting appro- priate comparison dimensions and corresponding ranking orders. To this end, we collect training data from roughly aligned Wikipedia resources and knowledge facts in Freebase, from which we build a neural network model to reveal the un- derlying correspondence between the comparative construction, as well as its context, and a Freebase predicate. Our method leverages the potentials of structured KBs and large amount of text resources in Wikipedia without relying on human annotated data.</p><p>We evaluate our interpretation of superlatives in two tasks, and experimental results show that it is possible to learn the comparison dimensions in form of canonical knowledge bases predicates from roughly collected training data, which is noisy in nature but provides the essentials to se- mantically characterize superlative expressions.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">The Task</head><p>Given a sentence with an attributive superlative ex- pression, our task is to find on which dimension the comparison happens against a KB and how the comparison results are arranged, i.e., (1) Dimen- sion Selection: decide the dimension on which the involved items are compared, and ground the selected dimension into Freebase predicates. (2) Ranking Order Determination: given the com- parison set and the selected dimension, determine the order in which the involved items are ranked within the comparisons, in an ascending or de- scending order? For superlatives coupled with or- dinals, we also need to assign the standing in the rankings.</p><p>In the Nile example, we expect to in- terpret the longest river into a vector &lt;fb:geography.river.length, descending, 1&gt;, where all rivers in the world are compared upon Freebase predicate fb:geography.river.length, sorted in a descending order and the referred target ranks the first.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">The WikiDiF Dataset</head><p>Previous superlative datasets are built to facili- tate superlative extraction, classification, and com- parison set identification( <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Bos and Nissim, 2006;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Scheible, 2012)</ref>. There are currently no available datasets that can be used directly for our task, es- pecially no annotations against structured KBs.</p><p>We therefore present a distantly supervised method to collect annotated training data from rich text resources of Wikipedia and the help of Free- base, without much human involvement. The key assumption behind our method is that if a superla- tive expression frequently appears in a context that may describe a KB predicate, then this predi- cate probably plays an important role in the com- parative construction triggered by this superlative. Inspired by recent advances in relation extrac- tion( <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Mintz et al., 2009)</ref>, given a Freebase predi- cate, we are able to collect many sentences from Wikipedia pages, which more or less describe this predicate, without extra human annotation. These sentences in turn can be used to collect the co- occurrences between a superlative expression and this predicate.</p><p>In more detail, we first find all Free- base predicates that may involve in compara- tive constructions, i.e., all gradable predicates, e.g., fb:geography.river.length, on which differ-ent rivers can be compared with each other. In practice, we simply treat all Freebase predicates that take objects of type ∈ {/type/int, /type/float, /type/datetime} as gradable predicates. In total, we collect 8,968,383 &lt;subj, rel, obj&gt; triples cov- ering all 1,795 gradable predicates from Freebase dump.</p><p>Next, we extract, from Wikipedia pages, all sen- tences containing superlative expressions, as well as their ±3 context sentences <ref type="bibr">1</ref> . To detect superla- tives, we rely on part-of-speech tags (JJS, RBS) which can achieve a high recall in practice accord- ing to <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Jindal and Liu, 2006</ref>). By doing so, we col- lect 7,734,006 sentences with superlative expres- sions from Wikipedia.</p><p>Finally, for each collected triple &lt;subj, rel, obj&gt; , we match subj and obj into our sentence collection, including those contextual sentences. This gives us 20,609 sentences with superlative expressions that potentially describe our collected knowledge triples with gradable predicates. For example, the following sentences from the page of Nile in Wikipedia may describes a Freebase fact &lt;Nile, fb:geography.river.length, 6,853&gt;:</p><p>"The Nile is a major north-flowing river in northeastern Africa, generally re- garded as the longest river in the world. It is 6,853 km (4,258 miles) long. "</p><p>where we can see that longest has implied a com- parative construction among all rivers in the world and fb:geography.river.length is the involved hid- den comparison dimension.</p><p>Our resulting dataset, WikiDiF, contains 20,609 sentences paired with Freebase predicates, cov- ering 2,335 superlative words and 340 Freebase predicates 2 . In WikiDiF, there are on average 8.8 sentences per superlative word targeting for about 2 predicates, and for commonly seen superlatives, e.g., largest or biggest, there are on average 70 sentences per superlative word targeting for 30 predicates. Compared to other human annotated datasets, WikiDiF is admittedly noisy in nature, <ref type="bibr">1</ref> In Wikipedia, sentences with superlative expressions may not always contain the knowledge facts that support the superlative constructions, which often appear in their neigh- bouring sentences. For example, highest, and its supporting fact, (Everest, 8,848 metres), are not in the same sentence, but indeed very near: Mount Everest, also known ..., is Earth's highest mountain. It is located in ... of the Himalayas. Its peak is 8,848 metres (29,029 ft) above sea level. <ref type="bibr">2</ref> We also filter out predicates whose objects are very com- mon in the documents, e.g., 1 or 2, which is difficult to collect training data. but exploits the underlying connections between knowledge facts and their possibly correspond- ing textual descriptions, where the pseudo co- occurrences of superlative expressions and Free- base predicates will work as a proxy for us to for- mally analyze the involved comparative construc- tions.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Comparison Dimension Selection</head><p>Our WikiDiF dataset contains utterances with roughly annotated superlative-predicate pairs, which helps us to model the dimension selection task as a classification problem. Given a superla- tive word S and its context C, our goal is to find a gradable Freebase predicate R that maximizes the conditional probability P (R | C, S):</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">R * = arg max R∈cand S P (R | C, S)</formula><p>where we can limit our search space to a candi- date set cand S according to the domain and type constraints regarding the comparison set.</p><p>Currently, our WikiDiF covers limited predi- cates and training instances for each superlative S, traditional classification models may suffer from the coverage and data sparsity issues. Here, we adopt a classic one-layer neural network (NN) model with the help of word embeddings to predict how likely a predicate R can work as the compar- ison dimension given S and its context vector.</p><p>We start by constructing vector representations of words and store them in a table L. We use the publicly available word embeddings trained by <ref type="bibr">SENNA (Collobert et al., 2011</ref>), with 50 dimen- sions throughout our experiments.</p><p>We construct the context vector for each in- stance by concatenating the vectors of context words within a window of ±k. If there are not enough words within the window, special filling vectors will be used. V = (w j S −k , ..., w j S −1 , w j S +1 , ..., w j S +k ) where j S is the index of superlative S in the sen- tence, and w is the vector of context word or spe- cial filling parameter.</p><p>The output layer of the NN model is a standard softmax function, which takes a sigmoid nonlin- earity of the context vectors as input. Therefore, the probability of ith predicate in Freebase is cho- sen as the comparison dimension given superlative S and its context C can be written as:</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">P (R i | C, S) = e z i q=1 n e zq i-th output is P(Ri | C, S) softmax W concatenated context vector V σ(W T V + b) vec(w jS−1 ) vec(w jS−k ) vec(w jS+k ) vec(w jS+1 )</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Input Layer</head><p>Sigmoind Layer where z i is estimated using a sigmoid function:</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">z i = σ i (W T m×n V + b)</formula><p>where n is the number of candidate predicates for superlative S, m is the length of concatenated vec- tor V , W m×n is the parameter matrix, b is the bias vector, and σ i is the sigmoid function that applies to the i-th element of argument vector. Training this standard one-layer neural network model can be straightforward, and the parame- ters W , b and filling vectors can be updated using stochastic gradient descent (SGD).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Ranking Order Determination</head><p>To exploit the most from a structured KB, we use an effective heuristic method to decide the ranking order when a superlative expression S triggers a comparative construction regarding a KB predicate R. For each pair of (S, R), we first find from R's supporting sentences the ones that contain superlative S, and further trace the &lt;subj * , R, obj * &gt; tuples from the KB which these sentences are assumed to describe. We next look up into the KB, and find other tuples &lt;subj o , R, obj o &gt; with the same predicate R. If subj o and subj * are of the same type, and most obj o &lt; obj * , we will say the ranking order for ex- pression S is descending when implying predicate R, otherwise, ascending order.</p><p>In the Nile example, if we find in our KB that nearly all other entities of type river have smaller values than 6,853 in fb:geography.river.length , we can conclude that the ranking order for longest re- garding fb:geography.river.length is descending , i.e., we should rank all rivers descendingly to get the longest one at the top.</p><p>Ordinals are processed as a post-processing step to interpret ordinals into a numerical values.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Experiments</head><p>The main purposes of this work is to answer the following two questions: (1) can we learn from noisy training data without much human involve- ment to semantically interpret attributive superla- tive expressions via structured KBs? (2) can our semantic analysis help better understand utter- ances with superlative expressions?</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.1">Interpreting Superlative Comparisons</head><p>We first evaluate our models in the vanilla setup defined in Section 2 3 , in terms of accuracy of di- mension selection (Acc d ), precision of predicates covered by WikiDiF (P d ), and precision of rank- ing order determination (P o ). Datasets: We manually annotate superlative ex- pressions from QALD-4 evaluation dataset <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">(Unger et al., 2014</ref>) and TREC QA <ref type="bibr">(2002,</ref><ref type="bibr">2003)</ref> datasets <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(NIST, 2003)</ref>, and guarantee that all the labeled superlative instances can be grounded to gradable Freebase predicates. The resulting ques- tion dataset contains 135 questions covering 44 Freebase predicates. Additionally, we manu- ally annotate 77 declarative sentences covering 24 Freebase predicates from WSJ and Wikipedia as the declarative dataset.</p><p>We build a Na¨ıveNa¨ıve Bayes model using co- occurrences as a baseline to predict proper dimen- sions. We further implement a simple baseline to decide the ranking order, by measuring the relat- edness between a superlative word and two sets of seed words using word embeddings. The two seed sets, {most, more, much, many} and {least, less, few, little}, potentially indicate two ranking orders, respectively.</p><p>We can see in <ref type="table">Table 1</ref> that our method can better capture the underlying connections between su- perlative expressions and KB predicates. Com- paring with the baseline, our model benefits from the NN architecture and distributional word rep- resentations and avoids data sparsity to some ex-  <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>: Performances of superlative interpreta- tions on two datasets tent. Our model achieves over 90% of precision on the predicates covered by our training data, show- ing that it is possible to learn from noisy train- ing data to characterize comparison dimensions against a KB. However, the relatively lower ac- curacy is mainly due to that some predicates in the testing data are not covered by our WikiDiF, which only covers 19% of gradable Freebase pred- icates. Regarding the ranking order determination, our simple heuristic method makes the most of Freebase triples, and outperforms the relatedness based baseline, which does not take Freebase into account. By looking at the different performances on question and declarative sentences, we can see that our method performs better on relatively sim- pler and shorter questions, while a slightly worse on longer declarative sentences. This is not sur- prising, since questions are often simple in struc- ture and ask for a straightforward property about the target, while declarative sentences are usu- ally complicated in syntax, which a ±5 context words window may not be able to capture. An- other reason is that for newswire, there are many predicates that are similar in definitions but with tiny differences, which often confuse our methods, e.g., fb:business.business operation.assets and fb:business.business operation.current assets.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.2">Question Answering over Freebase</head><p>We also investigate how our semantic analysis for superlatives can help improve question an- swering on two benchmark datasets, <ref type="bibr">Free917(Cai and</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Yates, 2013) and</ref><ref type="bibr">WebQuestions(Berant et al., 2013)</ref>, which contain 35 questions with attributive superlative expressions in total. We inject our for- mal analysis as superlative-triggered aggregation operations into an existing system, Xu14( <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Xu et al., 2014</ref>). Note that we leave the comparison set to be decided by Xu14's parser.</p><p>The 35 superlative-triggered complex questions can not be correctly answered by most state- of-the-art systems <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Berant et al., 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Yao and Van Durme, 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Xu et al., 2014</ref>), since they can not properly analyze the superlative-triggered functions. When integrated with our analysis, Xu14 is able to correctly answer 14 out of 35 such questions (40%), significantly outperform- ing other systems. The remaining 21 questions are mainly idiomatic usage, e.g., the Best Actor Award, or with predicates not covered by WikiDiF.</p><p>The result shows that our analysis can help QA systems better handle superlative-triggered aggre- gation functions, which previous works fail to do. This also gives a good reason to introduce the analysis for comparison constructions into the QA community, which will leverage the potentials of structured KBs to better deal with complex ques- tions.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7">Conclusion</head><p>In this paper, we present a novel attempt to se- mantically analyze the comparisons involved in attributive superlative expressions by investigat- ing on which dimension the comparative construc- tion works and how the comparison results are ar- ranged. We leverage Freebase and their roughly aligned textural descriptions from Wikipedia, and learn from such training data to characterize a comparative construction in two aspects, the di- mension of the comparison and its ranking order.</p><p>Currently, our analysis suffers from the limited coverage of our WikiDiF. In the future, it would be interesting to improve our method to cover more KB predicates, and extend our NN model with more advanced structures to further improve the performances and also simultaneously character- ize the target and comparison set involved.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: Neural network for dimension selection.</figDesc></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="3"> We assume that the domain and type constraints regarding the comparison set are known</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>We would like to thank Heng Ji, Benjamin Van Durme, Liwei Chen and Bingfeng Luo for their helpful discussions and three anonymous review-ers for their insightful comments that greatly im-proved the work. This work was supported by Na-tional High Technology R&amp;D Program of China <ref type="bibr">(Grant No. 2015AA015403, 2014AA015102)</ref>, Natural Science Foundation of China <ref type="bibr">(Grant No. 61202233, 61272344, 61370055)</ref> and the joint project with IBM Research. Any correspondence please refer to Yansong Feng.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Semantic parsing on freebase from question-answer pairs</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jonathan</forename><surname>Berant</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Andrew</forename><surname>Chou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Roy</forename><surname>Frostig</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Percy</forename><surname>Liang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">EMNLP</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1533" to="1544" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">An empirical approach to the interpretation of superlatives</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Johan</forename><surname>Bos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Malvina</forename><surname>Nissim</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">EMNLP 2007, Proceedings of the 2006 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Sydney, Australia</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006-07" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="9" to="17" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Semantic Parsing Freebase: Towards Open-domain Semantic Parsing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Qingqing</forename><surname>Cai</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alexander</forename><surname>Yates</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Second Joint Conference on Lexical and Computational Semantics (*SEM)</title>
		<meeting>the Second Joint Conference on Lexical and Computational Semantics (*SEM)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Natural language processing (almost) from scratch</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ronan</forename><surname>Collobert</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jason</forename><surname>Weston</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Léon</forename><surname>Bottou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Karlen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Koray</forename><surname>Kavukcuoglu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Pavel</forename><surname>Kuksa</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The Journal of Machine Learning Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2493" to="2537" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">On the comparative and absolute readings of superlatives</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Donka</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Katalinékatalin´kataliné</forename><surname>Farkas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Kiss</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Natural Language &amp; Linguistic Theory</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">18</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="417" to="455" />
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Comparatives, superlatives, and resolution</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jean</forename><surname>Mark Gawron</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Linguistics and Philosophy</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">18</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="333" to="380" />
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Freebase data dumps</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Google</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Notes on superlatives</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Irene</forename><surname>Heim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Mining comparative sentences and relations</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nitin</forename><surname>Jindal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bing</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings, The Twenty-First National Conference on Artificial Intelligence and the Eighteenth Innovative Applications of Artificial Intelligence Conference</title>
		<meeting>The Twenty-First National Conference on Artificial Intelligence and the Eighteenth Innovative Applications of Artificial Intelligence Conference<address><addrLine>Boston, Massachusetts, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1620" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1331" to="1336" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Distant supervision for relation extraction without labeled data</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mike</forename><surname>Mintz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Steven</forename><surname>Bills</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rion</forename><surname>Snow</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dan</forename><surname>Jurafsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>ACL &apos;09</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Joint Conference of the 47th Annual Meeting of the ACL and the 4th IJCNLP of the AFNLP</title>
		<meeting>the Joint Conference of the 47th Annual Meeting of the ACL and the 4th IJCNLP of the AFNLP</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1003" to="1011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Text retrieval conference question answering track</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nist</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Towards a computational treatment of superlatives</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Silke</forename><surname>Scheible</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 45th Annual Meeting of the ACL: Student Research Workshop, ACL &apos;07</title>
		<meeting>the 45th Annual Meeting of the ACL: Student Research Workshop, ACL &apos;07<address><addrLine>Stroudsburg, PA, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="67" to="72" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">A Computational Treatment of Superlatives</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Silke</forename><surname>Scheible</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>University of Edinburgh</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
<note type="report_type">Ph.D. thesis</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Textwiki: a superlative resource</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Silke</forename><surname>Scheible</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Language Resources and Evaluation</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">46</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="635" to="666" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Comparative superlatives. MIT Working papers in Linguistics</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Anna</forename><surname>Szabolcsi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1986" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="245" to="265" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Question answering over linked data (qald-4)</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christina</forename><surname>Unger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Corina</forename><surname>Forascu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Vanessa</forename><surname>Lopez</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Axel Cyrille Ngonga</forename><surname>Ngomo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Elena</forename><surname>Cabrio</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Philipp</forename><surname>Cimiano</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sebastian</forename><surname>Walter</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the CLEF 2014</title>
		<meeting>the CLEF 2014</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1172" to="1180" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Answering natural language questions via phrasal semantic parsing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kun</forename><surname>Xu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sheng</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yansong</forename><surname>Feng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dongyan</forename><surname>Zhao</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2014 Conference on Natural Language Processing and Chinese Computing (NLPCC)</title>
		<meeting>the 2014 Conference on Natural Language Processing and Chinese Computing (NLPCC)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="333" to="344" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Information extraction over structured data: Question answering with freebase</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xuchen</forename><surname>Yao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Benjamin</forename><surname>Van Durme</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of ACL</title>
		<meeting>ACL</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
