<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T11:54+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Improving Pivot Translation by Remembering the Pivot</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
				<availability status="unknown"><p>Copyright Association for Computational Linguistics</p>
				</availability>
				<date>July 26-31, 2015. 2015</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Akiva</forename><surname>Miura</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Graduate School of Information Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Nara Institute of Science and Technology</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>8916-5 Takayama-cho, Ikoma-shi</addrLine>
									<settlement>Nara</settlement>
									<country key="JP">Japan</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Graham</forename><surname>Neubig</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Graduate School of Information Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Nara Institute of Science and Technology</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>8916-5 Takayama-cho, Ikoma-shi</addrLine>
									<settlement>Nara</settlement>
									<country key="JP">Japan</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sakriani</forename><surname>Sakti</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Graduate School of Information Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Nara Institute of Science and Technology</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>8916-5 Takayama-cho, Ikoma-shi</addrLine>
									<settlement>Nara</settlement>
									<country key="JP">Japan</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tomoki</forename><surname>Toda</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Graduate School of Information Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Nara Institute of Science and Technology</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>8916-5 Takayama-cho, Ikoma-shi</addrLine>
									<settlement>Nara</settlement>
									<country key="JP">Japan</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Satoshi</forename><surname>Nakamura</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Graduate School of Information Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Nara Institute of Science and Technology</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>8916-5 Takayama-cho, Ikoma-shi</addrLine>
									<settlement>Nara</settlement>
									<country key="JP">Japan</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Improving Pivot Translation by Remembering the Pivot</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 53rd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics and the 7th International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing</title>
						<meeting>the 53rd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics and the 7th International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing <address><addrLine>Beijing, China</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="573" to="577"/>
							<date type="published">July 26-31, 2015. 2015</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Pivot translation allows for translation of language pairs with little or no parallel data by introducing a third language for which data exists. In particular, the trian-gulation method, which translates by combining source-pivot and pivot-target translation models into a source-target model, is known for its high translation accuracy. However, in the conventional triangulation method, information of pivot phrases is forgotten and not used in the translation process. In this paper, we propose a novel approach to remember the pivot phrases in the triangulation stage, and use a pivot language model as an additional information source at translation time. Experimental results on the Europarl corpus showed gains of 0.4-1.2 BLEU points in all tested combinations of languages 1 .</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>In statistical machine translation (SMT) <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Brown et al., 1993)</ref>, it is known that translation with mod- els trained on larger parallel corpora can achieve greater accuracy <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Dyer et al., 2008)</ref>. Unfor- tunately, large bilingual corpora are not readily available for many language pairs, particularly those that don't include English. One effective so- lution to overcome the scarceness of bilingual data is to introduce a pivot language for which parallel data with the source and target languages exists (de <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Gispert and Mariño, 2006</ref>).</p><p>Among various methods using pivot languages, the triangulation method ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Cohn and Lapata, 2007;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Utiyama and Isahara, 2007;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Zhu et al., 2014)</ref>, which translates by combining source-pivot and pivot-target translation models into a source-target model, has been shown to be one of the most effec- tive approaches. However, word sense ambiguity and interlingual differences of word usage cause difficulty in accurately learning correspondences between source and target phrases. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref> (a) shows an example of three words in German and Italian that each correspond to the English polysemic word "approach." In such a case, finding associated source-target phrase pairs and estimating translation probabilities properly becomes a complicated problem. Furthermore, in the conventional triangulation method, informa- tion about pivot phrases that behave as bridges be- tween source and target phrases is lost after learn- ing phrase pairs, as shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1 (b)</ref>.</p><p>To overcome these problems, we propose a novel triangulation method that remembers the pivot phrase connecting source and target in the records of phrase/rule table, and estimates a joint translation probability from the source to target and pivot simultaneously. We show an example in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref> (c). The advantage of this approach is that generally we can obtain rich monolingual resources in pivot languages such as English, and SMT can utilize this additional information to im- prove the translation quality.</p><p>To utilize information about the pivot language at translation time, we train a Multi-Synchronous Context-free Grammar (MSCFG) ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Neubig et al., 2015)</ref>, a generalized extension of synchronous CFGs (SCFGs) <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Chiang, 2007)</ref>, that can gener- ate strings in multiple languages at the same time.</p><p>To create the MSCFG, we triangulate source-pivot and pivot-target SCFG rule tables not into a single source-target SCFG, but into a source-target-pivot MSCFG rule table that remembers the pivot. Dur- ing decoding, we use language models over both the target and the pivot to assess the naturalness of the derivation. We perform experiments on pivot translation of Europarl proceedings, which show that our method indeed provide significant gains in accuracy (of up to 1.2 BLEU points), in all com- binations of 4 languages with English as a pivot language.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Translation Formalisms</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">Synchronous Context-free Grammars</head><p>First, we cover SCFGs, which are widely used in machine translation, particularly hierarchical phrase-based translation <ref type="bibr">(Hiero;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Chiang (2007)</ref>).</p><p>In SCFGs, the elementary structures are rewrite rules with aligned pairs of right-hand sides:</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">X → s, t<label>(1)</label></formula><p>where X is the head of the rewrite rule, and s and t are both strings of terminals and non-terminals in the source and target side respectively. Each string in the right side tuple has the same number of in- dexed non-terminals, and identically indexed non- terminals correspond to each-other. For example, a synchronous rule could take the form of:</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">X → ⟨X 0 of the X 1 , X 1 X 0 ⟩ .<label>(2)</label></formula><p>In the SCFG training method proposed by <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Chiang (2007)</ref>, SCFG rules are extracted based on parallel sentences and automatically obtained word alignments. Each extracted rule is scored with phrase translation probabilities in both direc- tions φ(s|t) and φ(t|s), lexical translation proba- bilities in both directions φ lex (s|t) and φ lex (t|s), a word penalty counting the terminals in t, and a constant phrase penalty of 1.</p><p>At translation time, the decoder searches for the target sentence that maximizes the derivation probability, which is defined as the sum of the scores of the rules used in the derivation, and the log of the language model probability over the tar- get strings. When not considering an LM, it is pos- sible to efficiently find the best translation for an input sentence using the CKY+ algorithm <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Chappelier et al., 1998</ref>). When using an LM, the ex- panded search space is further reduced based on a limit on expanded edges, or total states per span, through a procedure such as cube pruning <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Chiang, 2007</ref>).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">Multi-Synchronous CFGs</head><p>MSCFGs ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Neubig et al., 2015</ref>) are a generalization of SCFGs that are be able to generate sentences in multiple target languages simultaneously. The sin- gle target side string t in the SCFG production rule is extended to have strings for N target languages:</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">X → s, t 1 , ..., t N .<label>(3)</label></formula><p>Performing multi-target translation with MSCFGs is quite similar to translating using standard SCFGs, with the exception of the ex- panded state space caused by having one LM for each target. <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Neubig et al. (2015)</ref> propose a sequential search method, that ensures diversity in the primary target search space by first expanding with only primary target LM, then additionally expands the states for other LMs, a strategy we also adopt in this work.</p><p>In the standard training method for MSCFGs, the multi-target rewrite rules are extracted from multilingual line-aligned corpora by applying an extended version of the standard SCFG rule ex- traction method, and scored with features that con- sider the multiple targets. It should be noted that this training method requires a large amount of line-aligned training data including the source and all target languages. This assumption breaks down when we have little parallel data, and thereby we propose a method to generate MSCFG rules by triangulating 2 SCFG rule tables in the following section.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Pivot Translation Methods</head><p>Several methods have been proposed for SMT us- ing pivot languages. These include cascade meth- ods that consecutively translate from source to pivot then pivot to target <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(de Gispert and Mariño, 2006</ref>), synthetic data methods that machine- translate the training data to generate a pseudo- parallel corpus (de <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Gispert and Mariño, 2006</ref>), and triangulation methods that obtain a source- target phrase/rule table by merging source-pivot and pivot-target table entries with identical pivot language phrases <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Cohn and Lapata, 2007)</ref>. In par- ticular, the triangulation method is notable for pro- ducing higher quality translation results than other pivot methods <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Utiyama and Isahara, 2007)</ref>, so we use it as a base for our work.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Traditional Triangulation Method</head><p>In the triangulation method by <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Cohn and Lapata (2007)</ref>, we first train source-pivot and pivot-target rule tables, then create rules:</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">X → s, t<label>(4)</label></formula><p>if there exists a pivot phrase p such that the pair ⟨s, p⟩ is in source-pivot </p><formula xml:id="formula_4">φ t|s = p∈T SP ∩T P T φ t|p φ (p|s) ,<label>(5)</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_5">φ s|t = p∈T SP ∩T P T φ (s|p) φ p|t ,<label>(6)</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_6">φ lex t|s = p∈T SP ∩T P T φ lex t|p φ lex (p|s) ,<label>(7)</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_7">φ lex s|t = p∈T SP ∩T P T φ lex (s|p) φ lex p|t .<label>(8)</label></formula><p>The equations <ref type="formula" target="#formula_4">(5)</ref>- <ref type="formula" target="#formula_7">(8)</ref> are based on the memo- ryless channel model, which assumes φ t|p, s = φ t|p and φ s|p, t = φ (s|p). Unfortunately, these equations are not accurate due to polysemy and disconnects in the grammar of the languages. As a result, pivot translation is significantly more ambiguous than standard translation.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Proposed Triangulation Method</head><p>To help reduce this ambiguity, our proposed tri- angulation method remembers the corresponding pivot phrase as additional information to be uti- lized for disambiguation. Specifically, instead of marginalizing over the pivot phrase p, we create an MSCFG rule for the tuple of the connected source- target-pivot phrases such as:</p><formula xml:id="formula_8">X → s, t, p .<label>(9)</label></formula><p>The advantage of translation with these rules is that they allow for incorporation of additional fea- tures over the pivot sentence such as a strong pivot LM.</p><p>In addition to the equations <ref type="formula" target="#formula_4">(5)</ref>- <ref type="formula" target="#formula_7">(8)</ref>, we also es- timate translation probabilities φ(t, p|s), φ(s|p, t) that consider both target and pivot phrases at the same time according to:</p><formula xml:id="formula_9">φ t, p|s = φ t|p φ (p|s) ,<label>(10)</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_10">φ s|p, t = φ (s|p) .<label>(11)</label></formula><p>Translation probabilities between source and pivot phrases φ(p|s), φ(s|p), φ lex (p|s), φ lex (s|p) can also be used directly from the source-pivot rule ta- ble. This results in 13 features for each MSCFG rule: 10 translation probabilities, 2 word penalties counting the terminals in t and p, and a constant phrase penalty of 1. It should be noted that remembering the pivot results in significantly larger rule tables. To save computational resources, several pruning methods are conceivable. <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Neubig et al. (2015)</ref> show that an effective pruning method in the case of a main tar- get T 1 with the help of target T 2 is the T 1 -pruning method, namely, using L candidates of t 1 with the highest translation probability φ(t 1 |s) and select- ing t 2 with highest φ(t 1 , t 2 |s) for each t 1 . We fol- low this approach, using the L best t, and the cor- responding 1 best p .</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Experiments</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">Experimental Setup</head><p>We evaluate the proposed triangulation method through pivot translation experiments on the Eu- roparl corpus, which is a multilingual corpus in- cluding 21 European languages ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Koehn, 2005)</ref> widely used in pivot translation work. In our work, we perform translation among German (de), Spanish (es), French (fr) and Italian (it), with En- glish (en) as the pivot language. To prepare the data for these 5 languages, we first use the Gale- Church alignment algorithm ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Gale and Church, 1993)</ref> to retrieve a multilingual line-aligned cor- pus of about 900k sentences, then hold out 1,500 sentences each for tuning and test. In our basic   <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Papineni et al., 2002</ref>) and we tuned to maxi- mize BLEU scores using MERT <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Och, 2003)</ref>. For trained and triangulated TMs, we use T 1 rule prun- ing with a limit of 20 rules per source rule. For decoding using MSCFG, we adopt the sequential search method.</p><note type="other">27.82 22.57 25.11 25.01 25.18 ‡ 25.64 de 19.69 18.01 18.73 18.77 18.87 † 19.19 fr es 34.36 27.26 30.31 30.53 † 30.73 ‡ 31.00 it 28.48 22.73 25.31 25.50 † 25.72 ‡ 26.22 de 19.09 14.03 17.35 † 17.99 ‡ 18.17 ‡ 18.52 it es 31.99 25.64 28.85 28.83 29.01 † 29.31 fr 31.39 25.87 28.48 28.40 28.63 † 29.02</note><p>We evaluate 6 translation methods:</p><p>Direct: Translating with a direct SCFG trained on the source-target parallel corpus (not using a pivot language) for comparison.</p><p>Cascade: Cascading source-pivot and pivot- target translation systems.</p><p>Tri. SCFG: Triangulating source-pivot and pivot-target SCFG TMs into a source-target SCFG TM using the traditional method.</p><p>Tri. MSCFG: Triangulating source-pivot and pivot-target SCFG TMs into a source- target-pivot MSCFG TM in our approach. -PivotLM indicates translating without a pivot LM and +PivotLM 100k/2M indicates a pivot LM trained using 100k/2M sentences respectively.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">Experimental Results</head><p>The result of experiments using all combinations of pivot translation tasks for 4 languages via En- glish is shown in <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table 1</ref>. From the results, we can see that the proposed triangulation method consid- ering pivot LMs outperforms the traditional trian- gulation method for all language pairs, and trans- lation with larger pivot LMs improves the BLEU scores. For all languages, the pivot-remembering triangulation method with the pivot LM trained with 2M sentences achieves the highest score of the pivot translation methods, with gains of 0.4- 1.2 BLEU points from the baseline method. This shows that remembering the pivot and using it to disambiguate results is consistently effective in improving translation accuracy. We can also see that the MSCFG triangulated model without using the pivot LM slightly outper- forms the standard SCFG triangulation method for the majority of language pairs. It is conceivable that the additional scores of translation probabil- ities with pivot phrases are effective features that allow for more accurate rule selection.</p><p>Finally, we show an example of a translated sen- tence for which pivot-side ambiguity is resolved in the proposed triangulation method:</p><p>Input (German): ich bedaure , daß es keine gemeinsame annäherung gegeben hat .</p><p>Reference (Italian): sono spiacente del mancato approccio comune .</p><p>Tri. SCFG: mi rammarico per il fatto che non si ravvicinamento comune . (BLEU+1: 13.84)</p><p>Tri. MSCFG+PivotLM 2M:</p><p>mi dispiace che non esiste un approccio co- mune . (BLEU+1: 25.10) i regret that there is no common approach .</p><p>(Generated English Sentence)</p><p>The derivation uses an MSCFG rule connecting "approccio" to "approach" in the pivot, and we can consider that appropriate selection of English words according to the context contributes to se- lecting relevant vocabulary in Italian.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Conclusion</head><p>In this paper, we have proposed a method for pivot translation using triangulation of SCFG rule ta- bles into an MSCFG rule table that remembers the pivot, and performing translation with pivot LMs. In experiments, we found that these models are effective in the case when a strong pivot LM ex- ists. In the future, we plan to explore more refined methods to devising effective intermediate expres- sions, and improve estimation of probabilities for triangulated rules.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: An example of (a) triangulation and the resulting phrases in the (b) traditional method of forgetting pivots and (c) our proposed method of remembering pivots.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" validated="false"><head>table T SP</head><label>T</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>and the pair 
p, t 
is in pivot-target table T P T . Source-target 

table T ST is created by calculation of the trans-
lation probabilities using phrase translation prob-
abilities φ(·) and lexical translation probabilities 
φ lex (·) for all connected phrases according to the 
following equations (Cohn and Lapata, 2007): 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" validated="false"><head>Table 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Results for each method. Bold indicates the highest BLEU score in pivot translation, and 
daggers indicate statistically significant gains over Tri. SCFG ( † : p &lt; 0.05,  ‡ : p &lt; 0.01) 

training setup, we use 100k sentences for train-
ing both the TMs and the target LMs. We as-
sume that in many situations, a large amount of 
English monolingual data is readily available and 
therefore, we train pivot LMs with different data 
sizes up to 2M sentences. 
As a decoder, we use Travatar (Neubig, 2013), 
and train SCFG TMs with its Hiero extraction 
code. Translation results are evaluated by BLEU 
(</table></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> Code to replicate the experiments can be found at https://github.com/akivajp/acl2015</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgements</head><p>The authors thank anonymous reviewers for help-ful suggestions. This work was supported in part by the Microsoft CORE project.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Peter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Vincent</forename><forename type="middle">J Della</forename><surname>Brown</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Stephen</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Pietra</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Robert</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Della Pietra</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Mercer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">The Mathematics of Statistical Machine Translation: Parameter Estimation. Computational Linguistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="263" to="312" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A Generalized CYK Algorithm for Parsing Stochastic CFG</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jean-Cédric</forename><surname>Chappelier</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Martin</forename><surname>Rajman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">TAPD</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">98</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">5</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Hierarchical phrase-based translation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Chiang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Computational Linguistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">33</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="201" to="228" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Machine Translation by Triangulation: Making Effective Use of Multi-Parallel Corpora</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Trevor</forename><surname>Cohn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mirella</forename><surname>Lapata</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. ACL</title>
		<meeting>ACL</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007-06" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="728" to="735" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">CatalanEnglish Statistical Machine Translation without Parallel Corpus: Bridging through Spanish</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">José</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Adrì A De Gispert</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Mariño</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of LREC 5th Workshop on Strategies for developing machine translation for minority languages</title>
		<meeting>of LREC 5th Workshop on Strategies for developing machine translation for minority languages</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Fast, easy, and cheap: construction of statistical machine translation models with MapReduce</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christopher</forename><surname>Dyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Aaron</forename><surname>Cordova</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alex</forename><surname>Mont</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jimmy</forename><surname>Lin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. WMT</title>
		<meeting>WMT</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="199" to="207" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A program for aligning sentences in bilingual corpora</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>William</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kenneth W</forename><surname>Gale</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Church</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Computational linguistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="75" to="102" />
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Europarl: A parallel corpus for statistical machine translation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Philipp</forename><surname>Koehn</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">MT summit</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="79" to="86" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Multi-Target Machine Translation with MultiSynchronous Context-free Grammars</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Graham</forename><surname>Neubig</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Philip</forename><surname>Arthur</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kevin</forename><surname>Duh</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. NAACL</title>
		<meeting>NAACL</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Travatar: A Forest-to-String Machine Translation Engine based on Tree Transducers</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Graham</forename><surname>Neubig</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. ACL Demo Track</title>
		<meeting>ACL Demo Track</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="91" to="96" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Minimum Error Rate Training in Statistical Machine Translation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Franz Josef</forename><surname>Och</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. ACL</title>
		<meeting>ACL</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="160" to="167" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">BLEU: a method for automatic evaluation of machine translation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kishore</forename><surname>Papineni</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Salim</forename><surname>Roukos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Todd</forename><surname>Ward</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Weijing</forename><surname>Zhu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. ACL</title>
		<meeting>ACL</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="311" to="318" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A Comparison of Pivot Methods for Phrase-Based Statistical Machine Translation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Masao</forename><surname>Utiyama</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hitoshi</forename><surname>Isahara</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. NAACL</title>
		<meeting>NAACL</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="484" to="491" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Improving Pivot-Based Statistical Machine Translation by Pivoting the Co-occurrence Count of Phrase Pairs</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xiaoning</forename><surname>Zhu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Zhongjun</forename><surname>He</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hua</forename><surname>Wu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Conghui</forename><surname>Zhu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Haifeng</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tiejun</forename><surname>Zhao</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. EMNLP</title>
		<meeting>EMNLP</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
