<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T12:08+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Implicit Role Linking on Chinese Discourse: Exploiting Explicit Roles and Frame-to-Frame Relations</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
				<availability status="unknown"><p>Copyright Association for Computational Linguistics</p>
				</availability>
				<date>July 26-31, 2015. 2015</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ru</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">School of Computer and Information Technology</orgName>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="laboratory">Key Laboratory of Ministry of Education for Computation Intelligence and Chinese Information Processing</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Juan</forename><surname>Wu</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">School of Computer and Information Technology</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Zhiqiang</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">School of Computer and Information Technology</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Qinghua</forename><surname>Chai</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="department">School of Foreign Languages</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Shanxi University</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Taiyuan</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Implicit Role Linking on Chinese Discourse: Exploiting Explicit Roles and Frame-to-Frame Relations</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 53rd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics and the 7th International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing</title>
						<meeting>the 53rd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics and the 7th International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing <address><addrLine>Beijing, China</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="1263" to="1271"/>
							<date type="published">July 26-31, 2015. 2015</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>There is a growing interest in researching null instantiations, which are those implicit semantic arguments. Many of these implicit arguments can be linked to referents in context, and their discoveries are of great benefits to semantic processing. We address the issue of automatically identifying and resolving implicit arguments in Chinese discourse. For their resolutions, we present an approach that combines the information about overtly labeled arguments and frame-to-frame relations defined by FrameNet. Experimental results on our created corpus demonstrate the effectiveness of our approach.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>In natural discourse, only a small proportion of the theoretically possible semantic arguments of predicates tend to be locally instantiated. Other locally unrealized semantic roles are called null instantiations (NIs). Nevertheless, many of these implicit roles, while linguistically unexpressed, can often be bound to antecedent referents in the discourse context. What's more, capturing such implicit semantic roles and linking them to their antecedents can dramatically help text understanding.</p><p>Example <ref type="formula">(1)</ref> shows an analyzed result <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Li, 2012)</ref> by employing Chinese FrameNet ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Liu, 2011)</ref>, which is a lexical semantic knowledge base based on the frame semantics of <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Fillmore (1982)</ref> and takes Berkeley's FrameNet Project ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Baker et al., 1998</ref>) as the reference. In Chinese FrameNet, the predicates, called lexical units (LU), evoke frames which roughly correspond to different events or scenarios. Each frame defines a set of arguments called Frame Elements (FE). The set of FEs is further split into core FEs and non-core FEs. Particularly, the core FEs are the essential components of a frame and can be defined by themselves. However, not all core FEs of a frame can be realized simultaneously in a sentence. These non-instantiated FEs are considered as null instantiations of the frame elements. Depending on the interpretation type of the omission, Chinese FrameNet divides the NIs into two categories: 1) Indefinite Null Instantiations (INIs), the missing element which can be understood given interpre- tational conventions and do not need resolution, and 2) Definite Null Instantiations (DNIs), the missing element which is something that can be understood in the linguistic or discourse context, and the fillers need to be inferred from the context through resolutions. The purpose is different, specially used for storing the urn; due to the different heights, generally launched Cause_motion into [the orbit over 3000 kilo- meters away from the surface of earth] Goal . <ref type="bibr">[</ref> Particularly, in example (1), lexical unit (or target) launched/u evokes the semantic frame Cause_motion, which has nine core FEs, namely Agent, Theme, Source, Path, Goal, Area, Cause, Result, Initial_State, but only one of them is instantiated, i.e. Goal, whose filler is [the orbit over 3000 kilometers away from the surface of earth/å/¥L¡3000 õúp?‚¥;þ]. For another core FE Theme, it is filled by [The celestial burial satellite/U:¥(] that occurs in the previous sentence.</p><p>Clearly, human beings have no problem to infer these uninstantiated roles and find the cor- responding fillers based on the relevant context information, but this is beyond the capacity of state-of-the-art semantic role labeling systems.</p><p>Next, we formalize the problem as follows: given a discourse D = {S 1 , S 2 , ..., S n }, where S k (k ∈ <ref type="bibr">[1, n]</ref>) is the k-th sentence in D. The lexical unit set in S k is T k = {T k1 , T k2 , ..., T kp }, and F k = {F k1 , F k2 , ..., F kp } is relevant frame set. For a particular frame F ki (i ∈ <ref type="bibr">[1, p]</ref>), its core FE set is E ki = {e 1 , e 2 , ..., e m }, but it is possible that only part of core FEs C ki appears in S k , i.e. C ki ⊆ E ki . Apparently the set E ki − C ki includes the uninstantiated core FEs. Thus, we need to determine which elements in E ki − C ki are null instantiations. If e m (e m ∈ E ki − C ki ) has been identified as a null instantiated FE, we should determine whether e m is a DNI. If so, we need to find the corresponding antecedent d m in context.</p><p>The major contributions of this paper can be summarized as follows:</p><p>(i) We have created a null instantiation (NI) annotations corpus, consisting of 164 Chinese discourses across different fields.</p><p>(ii) We use frame-to-frame relations to find antecedents from those explicit semantic roles.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Related Work</head><p>Among the researches of null instantiation on English, the most representative work is the task "Linking Events and Their Participants in Discourse" shared by the <ref type="bibr">SemEval-2010</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(Ruppenhofer et al., 2010</ref>). The two systems participated in the NI resolution task, VENSES++ and SE- MAFOR, took very different approaches.</p><p>Tonelli and Delmonte (2010) develop a knowledge-based system called VENSES++, and describe two strategies depending on the predicate class (either nominal or verbal). For verbal predicates, they try to map the predicate argument structure extracted by VENSES with the valence patterns generated from FrameNet data, to identify missing arguments. And NIs are resolved by reasoning about the semantic similarity between an NI and a potential filler using WordNet. For nominal predicates, they resolve NIs by utilizing a common sense reasoning module that builds on ConceptNet ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Liu and Singh, 2004</ref>). The final Precision and Recall are 4.62% and 0.86% respectively.</p><p>Later on, Tonelli and Delmonte (2011) propose a simpler role linking strategy that based on computing a relevancy score for the nominal head of each potential antecedent. The intuition is that heads which often serve as role fillers and occur close to the target NI are more likely to function as antecedents for the NI. Finally they reported an F-score of 8% for role linking. However, being strongly lexicalized, their trained model seems heavily dependent on the training data.</p><p>The second system ) is statistical based and extends an existing semantic role labeler ( . Resolving DNIs is modeled in the same way as labeling overt arguments, with the search space being extended to nouns, pronouns, and noun phrases from the previous three sentences. When evaluating a potential filler, the syntactic features used in argument labeling of overt arguments are replaced by two semantic features: firstly the system checks whether a potential filler fills the null instantiated role overtly in at least one of the FrameNet sen- tences and train data, if not, the system calculates the distributional similarity between filler and role. While this system achieved 5% in F-score, data sparseness is a potential limiting factor.</p><p>Also closely related studies are as follows. <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Silberer and Frank (2012)</ref> cast NI resolution as a coreference resolution (CR) task, and employ an entity-mention model. They experiment with features of SRL and CR, and automatically expand the training set with examples generated from coreference corpus to avoid data sparseness, ulti- mately achieving F-score of 7.1%. <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Gorinski et al. (2013)</ref> present a weakly su- pervised approach that investigates and combines a number of linguistically motivated strategies, which consist of four basic NI resolvers that exploit different types of linguistic knowledge, and achieve F-score of 12%.  conduct DNI resolution on SemEval2010 task10 data. They considered the task as a classified problem, by adding new features such as the information of head word and frame to traditional features, proposed a rule to choose the best candidate words set and combination of features, achieving F-score of 14.65% finally.</p><p>Laparra and <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Rigau (2013)</ref> present an attempt to apply a set of features that have been traditionally used to model anaphora and coreference resolu- tion tasks to implicit argument resolution, and got the best results: F-score of 18%.</p><p>For nominal predicates, Gerber and Chai (2010) investigate the linking of implicit arguments using the PropBank role labeling scheme. In contrast to the SemEval task, which focuses on a verbs and nouns, their system is only applied to nouns and is restricted to 10 predicates with 120 annotated instances per predicate on average. They propose a discriminative model that selects an antecedent for an implicit role from an extended context window. The approach incorporates some aspects relating to CR that go beyond the SRL oriented SemEval systems: A candidate representation includes information about all the candidates' coreferent mentions (determined by automatic CR), in particular their semantic roles (provid- ed by gold annotations) and WordNet synsets. Patterns of semantic associations between filler candidates and implicit roles are learned for all mentions contained in the candidate's entity chain. They achieve an F-score of 42.3%, which is noticeably higher than those obtained on the SemEval data.</p><p>And Gerber (2011) presents an extended model that incorporates strategies suggested in <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Burchardt et al. (2005)</ref>: using frame relations as well as coreference patterns acquired from large corpora. This model achieves an F-score of 50.3%.  conduct DNI identification on SemEval2010 task10 data. They adopt the method of combining rules and machine learning. Differ- ent from them, we conduct two-level identifying for NI detection and use more features on Chinese data.  take noun phrases and pronoun as candidate words for DNI filler. We use several similar features with them. The differences are that 1) we take the fillers of overt instantiated FE as candidate words and 2) we use Frame-to- Frame relations. And Gerber (2011) also used frame relations. Different from them, we limit relation paths to 2.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Null Instantiation Detection</head><p>Now, we are ready to address the first subtask, i.e. null instantiation detection.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Frame element relations</head><p>Not all core arguments of all frames can be realized simultaneously. Some frames involve core FEs that are mutually exclusive. In example (2), in the Amalgamation frame, there are four core FEs, namely Part_1, Part_2, Parts and Whole, in which the first two FEs are mutually exclusive with Parts, thus formed an Excludes relation (relation 1). At the same time, Part_1 and Part_2 are in a Requires relation (relation 2), which means that if one of these two core FEs is present, then the other must occur as well. FE Whole, the result of the Amalgamation, is only existentially bound within the discourse, annotated as NI.</p><p>CoreSet (relation 3) specifies that at least one of the set must be instantiated overtly, though more of them can also be instantiated. As shown in example (3), in the Awareness frame, the two FEs Content and Topic are in one CoreSet. As Content is overtly realized, we consider Topic is not annotated as NI. The frame owning this relation is complicated. Sometimes, if one FE of this set is explicit, the absence of the other FEs in the set is not annotated as NI, but sometimes it is not true. </p><formula xml:id="formula_0">(2) [ÎN›]P art_1 Ú[#N›]P art_2 ( ( (Ü Ü Ü ( ( (Ü Ü Ü 3˜å"</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Modeling Null Instantiation detection</head><p>As shown in example (1), given a frame F ki (e.g. Cause_motion evoked by launched/u ), NI detector needs to determine whether core FEs in E F ki − subE F ki are missing, relying on information about the three types of the relations among core FEs: CoreSet F ki , Excludes F ki , Requires F ki (as discussed in Section 3.1). In Cause_motion, the core FEs Initial_State, Goal, Path, Source and Result belong to the same CoreSet, and Goal is instantiated, thus Initial_State, Path, Source and Result are not annotated as NIs. Meanwhile core FEs Goal and Area are connected by the Excludes relation, so do Cause and Agent. Therefore, according to the context, Area and Cause are not annotated as NIs.</p><p>Our approach for performing this detection is described as follows. For the first-level of detection, we make full use of the three types of relations, and adopt a rule-based strategy proposed by  to detect NIs. As for CoreSet relation, in particular, as long as one of the FEs in this set is expressed overtly, NIs are not annotated for the absence of the other FEs in the set. If none of CoreSet is expressed, the contextually most relevant one should be annotated as a NI. However, this is difficult for automatic detector, which inevitably introduces some false detected NIs.</p><p>Thus, we conduct a second-level identifying. To be specific, for the current lexical unit, i.e. the target word, we collect its frame element patterns from the training dataset. Frame element patterns are annotated semantic roles, which include the roles annotated as NIs. Taking lexical unit launched/u as an example, <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Table 1</ref> shows its frame element patterns in our data. Depending on this kind of patterns, we are able to filter out some false NIs effectively.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Patte1</head><p>Time AgentINI Theme GoalINI Patte2 Agent Theme GoalINI </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Definite Null Instantiation Identification</head><p>In this section, we focus on our second task of definite null instantiation (DNI) identification. Before performing the implicit argument reso- lution in discourse, we have to decide which null instantiated frame elements should be selected, i.e. which null instantiations are definite. As shown in example <ref type="formula">(1)</ref>   We treat this issue as a classification problem, and build a binary maximum entropy model to predict the null instantiation type of e m . <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">Table   2</ref> lists all features used for training our models. In addition, we employ some similar features that were used in . Meanwhile, we choose to learn a SVM classifier for comparison purpose.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Definite Null Instantiation Resolution</head><p>In this section, we tackle the last subtask, namely definite null instantiation resolution.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.1">Frame-to-Frame Relations</head><p>The relations of Frame-to-Frame and FE-to-FE in FrameNet, serve as important information sources, to be leveraged for DNI resolutions.</p><p>FrameNet arranges frames into a net by defining frame-to-frame relations, including Inheritance, Inchoative Of, Subframe, Causative Of, Precedes, Using, See_also and Perspective On. In the case of Inheritance relation, it defines two frames, i.e. one more general frame and the other more specific frame. The specific frame Commerce buy, for example, is inherited from the general frame Getting.</p><p>As <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref> shows, the inheritance relation allows a general frame (e.g., Getting) to be specialized with a particular semantic interpreta- tion (e.g., Commerce buy). Also the inheritance relation exists between the frame elements of two related frames. Each of the inheriting FEs contains all semantic properties of the inherited general frame elements and also owns its additional pri- vate properties.  We implement two semantic resolvers based on different methods. For either of these two resolvers, if two or more candidates score equally well, the one closest to the target predicate is chosen.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Getting</head><p>OvertFE is based on machine learning, and FFR is an inference method. As the inherent difficulty of task, it's difficult to find all fillers for DNIs only using one of them. Thus finally we simultaneously employ OvertFE and FFR to find as many fillers for DNIs as possible. Overt Frame Elements Based Resolver (OvertFE) This resolver is based on the assumption that the filler of DNI can be found among the overt FE content set in context. Given a DNI e m , DNI linking can be treated as a classification problem to judge whether a candidate overt FE content d (d ∈ ϕ m ) could be taken as filler of a DNI. Therefore, we employ a classification method to solve the problem. Clearly, the performance of classifiers largely depends on constructed features. Since corresponding antecedent of DNI is not overtly expressed, it is difficult to get some information from context to describe them. What we take as features is the information of candidate frame element contents and frame information. <ref type="table" target="#tab_5">Table 3</ref> lists all features used for training our models. Some similar features were employed by  where they also considered DNI linking as a classification problem.</p><p>Then maximum entropy models, widely used in natural language processing (such as Chinese word segmentation and machine translation), are employed to predict whether a candidate FE content is the filler of DNI. Frame-to-Frame Relations Based Resolver (F- FR) Another way of finding the correct filler is through searching Frame-to-Frame relations in a given context window. This is because Frame-to-Frame relations and FE-to-FE relations can provide rel- evant information for finding DNI filler among candidate frame element contents. Specifically, for one frame f 1 that contains a DNI, firstly we need to find related frame f 2 with it from context. Then, if DNI frame element in f 1 has relation with the frame element (marked with f e 2 ) of f 2 , the filler of f e 2 is the corresponding filler of this DNI. The detailed steps are reported in Algorithm 1.</p><p>If frame names are the same, we think they are related, and <ref type="figure">Figure 2</ref> illustrates this case. As the frames evoked in two sentences are both Arriving, we link the antecedent of Goal in the second sentence to [Tiananmen Square/US €2|], which is the content of Goal in the first sentence.</p><p>For other cases, we use the related frames which at most contain two relation paths (e.g., the paths from Event to Process_start to Activity_start in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 3</ref>). As shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 3</ref>, the target initiated/u å in the first sentence evokes the Activity_start frame, in which the two frame elements (Agent, Place) is expressed in a single constituent [our country/· I], i.e. the phenomenon of frame element fusion arises. Frame Event is evoked by the target happened/Ñ y in the second sentence, where Time and Event FEs are expressed overt- ly, except the core FE Place. In the net of FrameNet, frame Activity_start inherits from the frame Process_start which further inherits from the Event frame. These inheritance relationships also hold between the frame ele- ments of the related frames. According to the FE- to-FE relations, the content of FE Place in the first sentence, [our country/·I], is the corresponding filler of implicit FE Place in the second sentence. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Event</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Time Agent Place</head><p>In the 50's, our country initiated the movement of killing sparrows.</p><p>However, in the years after the vastly killing of sparrows, a plague of insects happened.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Time Event</head><p>Activity Activity_start</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Process_start</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Time</head><p>Place Event Place DNI </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Experiments</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.1">Experimental Settings</head><p>Data: Experimental data set comes from Semantic Computing and Chinese FrameNet Research Cen- tor of Shanxi University <ref type="bibr">1</ref> . Because of the current low performance of CFN automatic semantic anal- ysis systems, all discourses are labeled semantic roles manually, and the process is similar with the FrameNet annotation. First, the ICTCLAS are used for part-of-speech tagging (omitted in examples), and we treat verbs, adjectives and nouns in each sentence as potential targets. As not all potential targets can be annotated, it is necessary to identify those targets which can evoke frames.</p><p>Then, we choose corresponding frames for those targets. For one verb target launched/u in example (1), we find its evoked frame Cause_motion.</p><p>Then annotate semantic roles for those con- stituents which share syntactical relations with this target, so the span [the orbit over 3000 kilometers away from the surface of earth/å/¥L¡3000 õúp?‚¥;þ] is annotated as role Goal, which is, however, the only one instantiated, out of nine Cause_motion's core frame elements. So according to the context and frame element relations, we need to determine whether each missing frame element should be annotated as DNI or INI.</p><p>Next, we generate the XML format for our annotated corpus, which is similar to the data format in SemEval-10 Task 10.</p><p>Our 164 discourses had been annotated by one person (to make it consistent), and they consist of 57 discourses from People's Daily and 107 discourses from Chinese reading comprehension, which cover technology, health care, social, geog- raphy and other fields. Each discourse contains 10 sentences in average. The data set contains about 37526 words in 1618 sentences; it has 175 frame types, including 2283 annotated frame instances. <ref type="table" target="#tab_8">Table 4</ref> shows the detailed statistics of our data set. we'll share our data in the website(http://sccfn.sxu.edu.cn/  Definite Null Instantiation identification and resolution model: Our maximum entropy classi- fication model uses the toolkit from <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">Zhang (2005)</ref> with the default parameter values. The SVM classifier for comparison was trained via SVM toolkit LIBSVM with the default parameter values too.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.2">Experimental Results</head><p>Based on the experimental methods described in the previous section, we have systematically evaluated our approach on the constructed Chinese null instantiation corpus. Note all the perfor- mances are achieved using 5-fold cross validation. Null Instantiation Detection <ref type="table" target="#tab_10">Table 5</ref> gives the performance of NI detection, which achieves 72.71%, 86.12% and 78.84% in precision, recall and F-score, respectively. Here, the relatively lower precision is mainly due to the heuristic rules used to detect NIs. However, it is worth to point out that lower precision and higher recall is highly beneficial, as higher recall means less filtering of true NIs.  To illustrate the effectiveness of our method, we compare it with the Lei et al.'s method on our data, as shown in the <ref type="table" target="#tab_10">Table 5</ref>. The F-score of our method is 78.84%, which is 9% higher than that of Lei et al.'s method. Clearly, these experimental results further prove that our second- level identification is very effective. Definite Null Instantiation Identification <ref type="table" target="#tab_12">Table 6</ref> provides the performance of DNI iden- tification on our automatic NI detection results. It shows that DNI identification based on max- imum entropy model achieves the performance of 67.86%, 69.93% and 68.88% in terms of precision, recall and F-score respectively, which are better than the results using SVM classifier, as well as the results employing Lei et al.'s method on our data.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>P%</head><p>We observe, from <ref type="table" target="#tab_12">Table 6</ref>, that the performance of DNI identification is not high, possibly due to the poorer results of NI detection in the previous step. Moreover, because of the diversity of NI distribution, the difference of frames, and target words or missing core frame elements, the interpretation of NI types may be quite different. Thus it is difficult to build a suitable and accurate uniform classification model.  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>P%</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Resolution on golden Definite Null Instantiation</head><p>In order to select the most effective features for OvertFE resolver and choose the best search space, we assume perfect results for the first two steps, that is, we perform DNI resolution experiment just with the correct DNIs in discourse.</p><p>After extensive experiments employing different sets of features in different window sizes, we conclude that combining all features can achieve the best performance. <ref type="table" target="#tab_14">Table 7</ref> shows the results on correct DNIs using the best feature set in the window of 2, 3 and 4 sentences containing and before the target predicate (Win2, Win3, Win4 for short). For OvertFE resolver, it shows that the F-score with Win2 is higher than that in other windows, because the bigger the window size, the more the candidate fillers for DNI, and the more difficult for   OvertFE classifier to find right fillers. For FFR resolver, it needs to find related frames, and we find that its resolved DNIs are less than that by OvertFE resolver, thereby resulting in the lower precision of OvertFE than FFR.</p><p>Though performances of OvertFE and FFR both are relatively low, FFR can resolve several DNIs that OvertFE can not. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figures 2 and 3</ref> both are such cases. So when combining the two resolvers, the final result of OvertFE+FFR outper- forms that of each individual resolver. Meanwhile, as shown in <ref type="table" target="#tab_14">Table 7</ref>, for the combined resolver OvertFE+FFR, the F-score is the highest when the window size is 3 (i.e. Win3). <ref type="table" target="#tab_16">Table 8</ref> gives the performance of overall null instantiations resolution with automatic NI detec- tion and automatic DNI determination. It shows that our resolver OvertFE+FFR achieves 40.53%, 21.54% and 28.13% in terms of precision, recall and F-score. In comparison with the results (52.41%, 32.02% and 39.75% in P, R and F) in Win3 of <ref type="table" target="#tab_14">Table 7</ref>  For comparison, we also conduct DNI reso- lution on our constructed corpus employing the method proposed by . Since our corpus does not contain annotation of head words, the results are obtained by using their features without head word information. As the last line of <ref type="table" target="#tab_16">Table 8</ref> shows, the performance behaves similarly with our OvertFE resolver. In addition, we notice current state-of-the-art approach of Laparra and Rigau (2013) employs coreference models, although our corpus does not contain coreference annotation information. As such, we are not able to conduct experiments on our dataset using their method for comparison purpose.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Overall: Null Instantiation Resolution</head><p>Overall, the relatively low performance of res- olution reflects the inherent difficulty of this task, also reveals that further research is needed.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7">Conclusion and Future Work</head><p>Apparently, linking implicit participants of a pred- icate is a challenging problem. We have presented a study for identifying implicit arguments and finding their antecedents in Chinese discourse.</p><p>As shown in this paper, we split the difficult task into three subtasks: null instantiation detec- tion, definite null instantiation identification and definite null instantiation resolution. Among the three subtasks, the third is our major focus. For the third subtask, we build two different resolvers: 1) OvertFE resolver, which represents that the filler of a DNI can be found among those overt FE content set in context, by employing classification methods; 2) FFR resolver, which is the frame- related search, leverages rich network of frame- frame relations to find antecedents. We have proved that these two resolvers are very useful for the third subtask, and a combination of two resolvers produced the best results.</p><p>In the near future, we plan to create and release a larger null instantiation corpus. As null instantiation detection and definite null instantia- tion identification are the foundation of resolving definite null instantiation, it is critical to improve the performance of both subtasks. Moreover, as different information sources have been used in our study, we cannot directly compare with some of the existing methods. For our future work, we plan to manually annotate coreference information so that we can compare with more methods. Finally, we hope to exploit some additional knowl- edge resources, such as HowNet, which could potentially further improve the performance of our proposed method.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>( 1 )</head><label>1</label><figDesc>[U:¥(]Entity•´ ´ ´ á á áu u u, , ,a a a [&lt;E¥(]Category, Ú ¥(!Ï&amp;¥(!í-¥(Óá˜a" [The celestial burial satellite] Entity is Being_in_category [artificial satellite] Category , and belongs to the same category with reconnaissance, communications and meteorological satellite. ØÓ´^åˆÉ §´;€^5•˜•Ý ¶pÝ ½ØÓ §˜"u u u ¦ ¦ ¦ £ £ £ [å/¥L¡3000õúp? ‚¥;þ] Goal "[Theme DNI] [Agent INI]</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>[</head><label></label><figDesc>Whole INI] [The old system] P art_1 and [the new system] P art_2 are combined Amalgamation together. [Whole INI] (3) [\P †]Cognizer • • • • • • [\?Ö]Content" [Your boss] Cognizer is aware Awareness [of your com- mitment ] Content .</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Figure 3: Two consecutive sentences owing related frames. Bold fonts represent lexical units or frames. Dashed boxes represent FEs.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>Win2</head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" validated="false"><head>Table 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Frame element patterns for the target u 

/launched in our data 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3" validated="false"><head>Table 2 : Features description in DNI Identification</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4" validated="false"><head>Core Recipient Core Theme Ncore Explanation Ncore Manner Ncore Means Ncore Place Ncore Purpose Ncore Source Ncore Time Commerce buy Core Goods Core Buyer Ncore Explanation Ncore Time Ncore Manner Ncore Means Ncore Place Ncore Purpose Ncore Seller Ncore Result Ncore Money Rate Ncore Figure 1: FE-FE relations of frame Getting and</head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Commerce buy Number 

Features Name 
Features Description 

F1 
DistCT 
The number of sentences between candidate FE content and target 

T1 F2 
CanFEcon 
Candidate frame element content 

F3 
CanFEpt 
The phrase type or POS of candidate frame element content 

F4 
Frame 
The frame that target predicate evokes 

T2 F5 
FEDNI 
DNI frame element 

F6 
Target 
Target predicate 

F7 
TargetPOS 
The part of speech of target 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_5" validated="false"><head>Table 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Features description in Overt Frame Elements Based Resolver 

5.2 Modeling Definite Null Instantiation 
Resolution 

After accomplishing the previous processes, we 
can perform DNI resolutions. If the uninstantiated 
FE e m (e.g., Theme in example (1)) has been 
identified as DNI previously, we need to find the 
corresponding antecedent mention d m (e.g., [The 
celestial burial satellite/U : ¥ (] in example 
(1)). Due to having fine-grained frame semantic 
role labeled for each sentence, we think the filler 
of DNI maybe also instantiates the FE of other 
annotated frames in the context. Therefore, we 
collect the overt FE content set ϕ instantiated in 
the discourse, and this set forms the overall set of 
candidates for DNI linking. Then, for DNI e m , a 
subset of candidates ϕ m (ϕ m ⊆ ϕ) is chosen as 
candidate search space for resolving e m . 
</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_6" validated="false"><head>Arriving Time Thm Goal DNI</head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Algorithm 1 : Frame-to-Frame Relations Based 
Resolver 
Input: The frame set in discourse is F = 
{f 1 , f 2 , ..., f n }; overt core frame element set 
for frame f i is E i = {e 1 , e 2 , ..., e m }, its corre-
sponding filler set is A i = {a 1 , a 2 , ..., a m }; one 
frame that contains DNI e  *  is f  *  , target t evokes 
the frame f  *  ; dis (a i , t) is the distance between 
DNI filler a i and target t; relationpath (f i , f  *  ) 
are the relation paths from f i to f  *  ; A temp is 
temporary DNI filler set 
Output: the filler a  *  of DNI e  *  
A temp = φ 
for each f i ∈ F do 
if f i has frame relation with f  *  AND 
relationpath (f i , f  *  ) ≤ 2 then 
for each e i ∈ E i , a i ∈ A i do 
if e i has relation with e  *  then 
a i ∈ A temp 
end if 
end for 
else if f i = f  *  then 
a i ∈ A temp 
end if 
end for 
if A temp = φ then 
for a i ∈ A temp do 
if dis (a i , t) is minimum then 
a  *  = a i 
end if 
end for 
end if 
return a  *  ; 



@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@ 


@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@ 

Time 
Thm 
Goal 
Arriving 

Figure 2: Two consecutive sentences owning the 

same frame. Bold fonts represent lexical units or 
frames. Dashed boxes represent FEs. 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_8" validated="false"><head>Table 4 : Corpus Statistics</head><label>4</label><figDesc></figDesc><table></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_10" validated="false"><head>Table 5 : Performance of NI Detection</head><label>5</label><figDesc></figDesc><table></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_12" validated="false"><head>Table 6 : Performance of DNI Identification</head><label>6</label><figDesc></figDesc><table></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_14" validated="false"><head>Table 7 :</head><label>7</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Results on golden DNI 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_15" validated="false"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>, it shows that the errors caused by automatic NI detection and automatic DNI determination decrease the performance of overall NI resolution by about 11% in terms of F-score.</figDesc><table>P% 
R% 
F% 

OvertFE 
33.28 13.78 19.49 

FFR 
52.95 9.71 
16.41 

OvertFE+FFR 40.53 21.54 28.13 

Wang et al. 
31.93 12.76 18.23 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_16" validated="false"><head>Table 8 :</head><label>8</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Performance of NI resolution for our models 

and comparative systems 

</table></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> http://sccfn.sxu.edu.cn/</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>We would like to thank anonymous reviewers and the mentor Jacob Eisenstein for their valuable comments and suggestions, and Xiaoli Li for help-ing us polish the paper. This work was supported by the National Natural Science Foundation of China <ref type="table">(No.61373082</ref> </p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The berkeley framenet project</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Collin</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Baker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Charles</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Fillmore</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">John</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Lowe</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of COLING/ACL</title>
		<meeting>COLING/ACL</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Building text meaning representations from contextually related frames-a case study</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Aljoscha</forename><surname>Burchardt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Anette</forename><surname>Frank</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Manfred</forename><surname>Pinkal</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 6th International Workshop on Computational Semantics (IWCS-6)</title>
		<meeting>the 6th International Workshop on Computational Semantics (IWCS-6)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="66" to="77" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Semafor: Frame argument resolution with log-linear models</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Desai</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nathan</forename><surname>Schneider</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dipanjan</forename><surname>Das</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Noah A</forename><surname>Smith</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 5th international workshop on semantic evaluation</title>
		<meeting>the 5th international workshop on semantic evaluation</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="264" to="267" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Probabilistic frame-semantic parsing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dipanjan</forename><surname>Das</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nathan</forename><surname>Schneider</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Desai</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Noah A</forename><surname>Smith</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Human language technologies: The 2010 annual conference of the North American chapter of the association for computational linguistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="948" to="956" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Frame semantics. Linguistics in the morning calm</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Charles</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Fillmore</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1982" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="111" to="137" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Beyond nombank: a study of implicit arguments for nominal predicates</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Matthew</forename><surname>Gerber</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Joyce</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Chai</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 48th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the 48th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1583" to="1592" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Semantic Role Labeling of Implicit Arguments for Nominal Predicates</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Matthew Steven</forename><surname>Gerber</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>Michigan State University</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
<note type="report_type">Ph.D. thesis</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Towards weakly supervised resolution of null instantiations</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Philip</forename><surname>Gorinski</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Josef</forename><surname>Ruppenhofer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Caroline</forename><surname>Sporleder</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 10th International Conference on Computational Semantics (IWCS 2013)-Long Papers</title>
		<meeting>the 10th International Conference on Computational Semantics (IWCS 2013)-Long Papers</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="119" to="130" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Sources of evidence for implicit argument resolution</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Egoitz</forename><surname>Laparra</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">German</forename><surname>Rigau</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 10th International Conference on Computational Semantics (IWCS 2013)-Long Papers</title>
		<meeting>the 10th International Conference on Computational Semantics (IWCS 2013)-Long Papers</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="155" to="166" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Definite null instantiation recognizing in framenet</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Zhangzhang</forename><surname>Lei</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ning</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ru</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Zhiqiang</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Chinese Information</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">27</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="107" to="112" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Research on Frame Semantic Structure Analysis Technology for Chinese Sentences</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ru</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<pubPlace>ShanXi university</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
<note type="report_type">Ph.D. thesis</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Conceptnet: a practical commonsense reasoning tool-kit</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hugo</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Push</forename><surname>Singh</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">BT technology journal</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="211" to="226" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Research on chinese framenet construction and application technologies</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kaiying</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Chinese Information Processing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">6</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Semeval-2010 task 10: Linking events and their participants in discourse</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Josef</forename><surname>Ruppenhofer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Caroline</forename><surname>Sporleder</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Roser</forename><surname>Morante</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Collin</forename><surname>Baker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Martha</forename><surname>Palmer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 5th International Workshop on Semantic Evaluation</title>
		<meeting>the 5th International Workshop on Semantic Evaluation</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="45" to="50" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Casting implicit role linking as an anaphora resolution task</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Carina</forename><surname>Silberer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Anette</forename><surname>Frank</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the First Joint Conference on Lexical and Computational Semantics</title>
		<meeting>the First Joint Conference on Lexical and Computational Semantics</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="10" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Proceedings of the Sixth International Workshop on Semantic Evaluation</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Venses++: Adapting a deep semantic processing system to the identification of null instantiations</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sara</forename><surname>Tonelli</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rodolfo</forename><surname>Delmonte</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 5th international workshop on semantic evaluation</title>
		<meeting>the 5th international workshop on semantic evaluation</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="296" to="299" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Desperately seeking implicit arguments in text</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sara</forename><surname>Tonelli</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rodolfo</forename><surname>Delmonte</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the ACL 2011 workshop on relational models of semantics</title>
		<meeting>the ACL 2011 workshop on relational models of semantics</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="54" to="62" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Document oriented gap filling of definite null instantiation in framenet</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ning</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ru</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Zhangzhang</forename><surname>Lei</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Zhiqiang</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jingpan</forename><surname>Jin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Chinese Computational Linguistics and Natural Language Processing Based on Naturally Annotated Big Data</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="85" to="96" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Maximum entropy modeling toolkit for python and c++</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Le</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://homepages.inf.ed.ac.uk/lzhang10/maxent_toolkit.html" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
