<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T11:30+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Domain-Specific Paraphrase Extraction</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date>July 26-31, 2015</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ellie</forename><surname>Pavlick</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Computer and Information Science Department</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Pennsylvania</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Juri</forename><surname>Ganitkevitch</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Center for Language and Speech Processing</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Johns Hopkins University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tsz</forename><forename type="middle">Ping</forename><surname>Chan</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="department">Bloomberg L.P</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>New York</settlement>
									<region>NY</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xuchen</forename><surname>Yao</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff3">
								<orgName type="department">kitt.ai *</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Seattle</settlement>
									<region>WA</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Benjamin</forename><surname>Van Durme</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Center for Language and Speech Processing</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Johns Hopkins University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff4">
								<orgName type="department">Human Language Technology Center of Excellence</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Johns Hopkins University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chris</forename><surname>Callison-Burch</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Computer and Information Science Department</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Pennsylvania</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Domain-Specific Paraphrase Extraction</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 53rd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics and the 7th International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing</title>
						<meeting>the 53rd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics and the 7th International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing <address><addrLine>Beijing, China</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="57" to="62"/>
							<date type="published">July 26-31, 2015</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>The validity of applying paraphrase rules depends on the domain of the text that they are being applied to. We develop a novel method for extracting domain-specific paraphrases. We adapt the bilingual pivoting paraphrase method to bias the training data to be more like our target domain of biology. Our best model results in higher precision while retaining complete recall, giving a 10% relative improvement in AUC.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Many data-driven paraphrase extraction algo- rithms have been developed in recent years ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Madnani and Dorr, 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr">Androutsopoulos and Malakasiotis, 2010)</ref>. These algorithms attempt to learn paraphrase rules, where one phrase can be replaced with another phrase which has equiv- alent meaning in at least some context. Deter- mining whether a paraphrase is appropriate for a specific context is a difficult problem <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Bhagat and Hovy, 2013)</ref>, encompassing issues of syntax <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Callison-Burch, 2008)</ref>, word sense ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Apidianaki et al., 2014)</ref>, and style ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Xu et al., 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Pavlick and Nenkova, 2015)</ref>. To date, the question of how do- main effects paraphrase has been left unexplored.</p><p>Although most paraphrase extraction algo- rithms attempt to estimate a confidence with which a paraphrase rule might apply, these scores are not differentiated by domain, and instead corre- spond to the general domain represented by the model's training data. As illustrated by Table 1, paraphrases that are highly probable in the gen- eral domain (e.g. hot = sexy) can be extremely improbable in more specialized domains like biol- ogy. Dominant word senses change depending on * Incubated by the Allen Institute for Artificial Intelli- gence.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>General</head><p>Biology hot warm, sexy, exciting heated, warm, thermal treat address, handle, buy cure, fight, kill head leader, boss, mind skull, brain, cranium domain: the verb treat is used in expressions like treat you to dinner in conversational domains ver- sus treat an infection in biology. This domain shift changes the acceptability of its paraphrases.</p><p>We address the problem of customizing para- phrase models to specific target domains. We ex- plore the following ideas:</p><p>1. We sort sentences in the training corpus based on how well they represent the target domain, and then extract paraphrases from a subsample of the most domain-like data.</p><p>2. We improve our domain-specific paraphrases by weighting each training example based on its domain score, instead of treating each ex- ample equally.</p><p>3. We dramatically improve recall while main- taining precision by combining the subsam- pled in-domain paraphrase scores with the general-domain paraphrase scores.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Background</head><p>The paraphrase extraction algorithm that we cus- tomize is the bilingual pivoting method <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Bannard and Callison-Burch, 2005</ref>) that was used to create PPDB, the paraphrase database ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Ganitkevitch et al., 2013)</ref>. To perform the subsampling, we adapt and improve the method that Moore and Lewis (2010) originally developed for domain-specific language models in machine translation.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">Paraphrase extraction</head><p>Paraphrases can be extracted via bilingual pivot- ing. Intuitively, if two English phrases e 1 and e 2 translate to the same foreign phrase f , we can as- sume that e 1 and e 2 have similar meaning, and thus we can "pivot" over f and extract e 1 , e 2 as a paraphrase pair. Since many possible paraphrases are extracted in this way, and since they vary in quality (in PPDB, the verb treat has 1,160 poten- tial paraphrases, including address, handle, deal with, care for, cure him, 'm paying, and 's on the house), it is necessary to assign some measure of confidence to each paraphrase rule. Bannard and Callison-Burch (2005) defined a conditional para- phrase probability p(e 2 |e 1 ) by marginalizing over all shared foreign-language translations f :</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">p(e 2 |e 1 ) ≈ f p(e 2 |f )p(f |e 1 ) (1)</formula><p>where p(e 2 |f ) and p(f |e 1 ) are translation model probabilities estimated from the bilingual data. Equation 1 approximates the probability with which e 1 can paraphrase as e 2 , but its estimate in- evitably reflects the domain and style of the bilin- gual training text. If e 1 is a polysemous word, the highest probabilities will be assigned to para- phrases of the most frequently occurring sense of e 1 , and lower probabilities to less frequent senses. This results in inaccurate probability estimates when moving to a domain with different sense dis- tributions compared to the training corpus.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">Sorting by domain specificity</head><p>The crux of our method is to train a paraphrase model on data from the same domain as the one in which the paraphrases will be used. In practice, it is unrealistic that we will be able to find bilingual parallel corpora precompiled for each domain of interest. We instead subsample from a large bitext, biasing the sample towards the target domain.</p><p>We adapt and extend a method developed by Moore and Lewis (2010) (henceforth M-L), which builds a domain-specific sub-corpus from a large, general-domain corpus. The M-L method assigns a score to each sentence in the large corpus based on two language models, one trained on a sam- ple of target domain text and one trained on the general domain. We want to identify sentences which are similar to our target domain and dissim- ilar from the general domain. M-L captures this notion using the difference in the cross-entropies according to each language model (LM). That is, for a sentence s i , we compute</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">σ i = H tgt (s i ) − H gen (s i )<label>(2)</label></formula><p>where H tgt is the cross-entropy under the in- domain language model and H gen is the cross- entropy under the general domain LM. Cross- entropy is monotonically equivalent to LM per- plexity, in which lower scores imply a better fit.</p><p>Lower σ i signifies greater domain-specificity.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Domain-Specific Paraphrases</head><p>To apply the M-L method to paraphrasing, we need a sample of in-domain monolingual text. This data is not directly used to extract para- phrases, but instead to train an n-gram LM for the target domain. We compute σ i for the English side of every sentence pair in our bilingual data, using the target domain LM and the general domain LM. We sort the entire bilingual training corpus so that the closer a sentence pair is to the top of the list, the more specific it is to our target domain. We can apply Bannard and Callison-Burch (2005)'s bilingual pivoting paraphrase extraction algorithm to this sorted bitext in several ways:</p><p>1. By choosing a threshold value for σ i and dis- carding all sentence pairs that fall outside of that threshold, we can extract paraphrases from a subsampled bitext that approximates the target domain.</p><p>2. Instead of simply extracting from a subsam- pled corpus (where each training example is equally weighted), we can weight each train- ing example proportional to σ i when comput- ing the paraphrase scores.</p><p>3. We can combine multiple paraphrase scores: one derived from the original corpus and one from the subsample. This has the advantage of producing the full set of paraphrases that can be extracted from the entire bitext.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Experimental Conditions</head><p>Domain data We evaluate our domain-specific paraphrasing model in the target domain of biol- ogy. Our monolingual in-domain data is a com- bination of text from the GENIA database ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Kim et al., 2003)</ref> and text from an introductory biology textbook. Our bilingual general-domain data is the 10 9 word parallel corpus <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Callison-Burch et al., 2009</ref>), a collection of French-English parallel data covering a mix of genres from legal text <ref type="bibr">(Steinberger et al., 2006</ref>) to movie subtitles <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">(Tiedemann, 2012)</ref>. We use 5-gram language models with Kneser-Ney discounting ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Heafield et al., 2013</ref>).</p><p>Evaluation We measure the precision and recall of paraphrase pairs produced by each of our mod- els by collecting human judgments of what para- phrases are acceptable in sentences drawn from the target domain and in sentences drawn from the general domain. We sample 15K sentences from our biology data, and 10K general-domain sen- tences from Wikipedia. We select a phrase from each sentence, and show the list of candidate para- phrases 1 to 5 human judges. Judges make a binary decision about whether each paraphrase is appro- priate given the domain-specific context. We con- sider a paraphrase rule to be good in the domain if it is judged to be good in least one context by the majority of judges. See Supplementary Materials for a detailed description of our methodology.</p><p>Baseline We run normal paraphrase extraction over the entire 10 9 word parallel corpus (which has 828M words on the English side) without any attempt to bias it toward the target domain. We refer this system as General.</p><p>Subsampling After sorting the 10 9 word paral- lel corpus by Equation 2, we chose several thresh- old values for subsampling, keeping only top- ranked τ words of the bitext. We train models on for several values of τ (1.5M, 7M, 35M, and 166M words). We refer to these model as M-L,T=τ .</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>M-L Change Point</head><p>We test a model where τ is set at the point where σ i switches from negative to positive. This includes all sentences which look more like the target domain than the general. This threshold is equivalent to sampling 20M words.</p><p>Weighted Counts Instead of weighting each subsampled sentence equally, we test a novel ex- tension of M-L in which we weight each sentence proportional to σ i when computing p(e 2 |e 1 ).</p><p>Combined Models We combine the subsam- pled models with the general model, using binary logistic regression to combine the p(e 2 |e 1 ) esti- mate of the general model and that of the domain- specific model. We use 1,000 labeled pairs from the target domain to set the regression weights. This tuning set is disjoint from the test set.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Experimental Results</head><p>What is the effect of subsampling? <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref> compares the precision and recall of the differ- ent subsampling methods against the baseline of training on everything, when they are evaluated on manually labeled test paraphrases from the bi- ology domain. All of subsampled models have a higher precision than the baseline General model, except for the largest of the subsampled models (which was trained on sentence pairs with 166M words -many of which are more like the general domain than the biology domain). The subsampled models have reduced recall since many of the paraphrases that occur in the full 10 9 word bilingual training corpus do not occur in the subsamples. As we increase τ we improve re- call at the expense of precision, since we are in- cluding training data that is less and less like our target domain. The highest precision model based on the vanilla M-L method is M-L Change Point, which sets the subsample size to include exactly those sentence pairs that look more like the target domain than the general domain.</p><p>Our novel extension of the M-L model (M-L Weighted) provides further improvements. Here, we weight each sentence pair in the bilingual train- ing corpus proportional to σ i when computing the paraphrase scores. Specifically, we weight the counting during the bilingual pivoting so that rather than each occurrence counting as 1, each occurrence counts as the ratio of the sentence's cross-entropies:</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Hgen</head><p>Htgt . The top-ranked sentence pairs receive an exaggerated count of 52, while the bottom ones receive a tiny factional count of 0.0068. Thus, paraphrases extracted from sen- tence pairs that are unlike the biology domain re- ceive very low scores. This allows us to achieve higher recall by incorporating more training data, while also improving the precision.</p><p>What is the benefit of combining models? We have demonstrated that extracting paraphrases from subsampled data results in higher precision domain-specific paraphrases. But these models extract only a fraction of the paraphrases that are extracted by a general model trained on the full bitext, resulting in a lower recall.</p><p>We dramatically improve the recall of our domain-specific models by combining the small subsampled models with the large general-domain model. We use binary logistic regression to com- bine the p(e 2 |e 1 ) estimate of the general model with that of each domain-specific model. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure  2</ref>(a) shows that we are able to extend the recall of our domain-specific models to match the recall of the full general-domain model. The precision scores remain higher for the domain-specific mod- els. Our novel M-L Weighted model performs the best. <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">Table 3</ref> gives the area under the curve (AUC). The best combination improves AUC by more than 4 points absolute (&gt;10 points relative) in the biology domain.    <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 2</ref>(a).</p><p>model for biology versus the baseline model.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Related Work</head><p>Domain-specific paraphrasing has not received previous attention, but there is relevant prior work on domain-specific machine translation (MT). We build on the Moore-Lewis method, which has been used for language models <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(Moore and Lewis, 2010</ref>) and translation models <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Axelrod et al., 2011</ref>). Similar methods use LM perplexity to rank sentences ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Gao et al., 2002;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b21">Yasuda et al., 2008)</ref>, rather than the difference in cross-entropy. <ref type="bibr">Within MT, Foster and Kuhn (2007)</ref> used log- linear weightings of translation probabilities to combine models trained in different domains, as we do here. Relevant to our proposed method of fractional counting, ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Madnani et al., 2007</ref>) used introduced a count-centric approach to paraphrase probability estimation. <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Matsoukas et al. (2009)</ref> and <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Foster et al. (2010)</ref> explored weighted training sentences for MT, but set weights discriminatively based on sentence-level features.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7">Conclusion</head><p>We have discussed the new problem of extracting domain-specific paraphrases. We adapt a method from machine translation to the task of learn- ing domain-biased paraphrases from bilingual cor- pora. We introduce two novel extensions to this method. Our best domain-specific model dramat- ically improves paraphrase quality for the target domain.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: Precision-recall curves for paraphrase pairs extracted by models trained on data from each of the described subsampling methods. These curves are generated using the 15k manually annotated sentences in the biology domain.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2: Performance of models build by combining small domain-specific models trained on subsampled data with general domain models trained on all the data. Performance in the general domain are shown as a control.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" validated="false"><head>Table 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Examples of domain-sensitive paraphrases. Most 
paraphrase extraction techniques learn paraphrases for a mix 
of senses that work well in general. But in specific domains, 
paraphrasing should be sensitive to specialized language use. 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" validated="false"><head>Table 2 provides</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>examples of 
paraphrases extracted using our domain-specific 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" validated="false"><head>Table 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Top paraphrase under the general and the best 
domain-specific model, General+M-L Weighted. 

AUC ∆ absolute ∆ relative 
General 
39.5 
-
-
Gen.+M-L,T=1 
40.8 
+1.3 
+3.3 
Gen.+M-L,T=145 
40.8 
+1.3 
+3.3 
Gen.+M-L,T=29 
41.2 
+1.7 
+4.3 
Gen.+M-L CP 
41.9 
+2.4 
+6.1 
Gen.+M-L,T=6 
42.3 
+2.8 
+7.1 
Gen.+M-L Weighted 43.7 
+4.2 
+10.6 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3" validated="false"><head>Table 3 : AUC (× 100) for each model in the biology domain from</head><label>3</label><figDesc></figDesc><table></table></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> The candidates paraphrases constitute the full set of paraphrases that can be extracted from our training corpus.</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A survey of paraphrasing and textual entailment methods</title>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">JAIR</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="135" to="187" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Ion Androutsopoulos and Prodromos Malakasiotis</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Semantic clustering of pivot paraphrases</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marianna</forename><surname>Apidianaki</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Emilia</forename><surname>Verzeni</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Diana</forename><surname>Mccarthy</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">LREC</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Domain adaptation via pseudo in-domain data selection</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Amittai</forename><surname>Axelrod</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xiaodong</forename><surname>He</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jianfeng</forename><surname>Gao</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">EMNLP</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="355" to="362" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Paraphrasing with bilingual parallel corpora</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Colin</forename><surname>Bannard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chris</forename><surname>Callison-Burch</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ACL</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="597" to="604" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">What is a paraphrase? Computational Linguistics</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rahul</forename><surname>Bhagat</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Eduard</forename><surname>Hovy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">39</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="463" to="472" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Findings of the 2009 Workshop on Statistical Machine Translation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chris</forename><surname>Callison-Burch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Philipp</forename><surname>Koehn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christof</forename><surname>Monz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Josh</forename><surname>Schroeder</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Fourth Workshop on Statistical Machine Translation</title>
		<meeting>the Fourth Workshop on Statistical Machine Translation</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Syntactic constraints on paraphrases extracted from parallel corpora</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chris</forename><surname>Callison-Burch</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="196" to="205" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>EMNLP</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Mixturemodel adaptation for smt</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">George</forename><surname>Foster</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Roland</forename><surname>Kuhn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Discriminative instance weighting for domain adaptation in statistical machine translation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">George</forename><surname>Foster</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Cyril</forename><surname>Goutte</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Roland</forename><surname>Kuhn</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">EMNLP</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="451" to="459" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">PPDB: The paraphrase database</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Juri</forename><surname>Ganitkevitch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Benjamin</forename><surname>Van Durme</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chris</forename><surname>Callison-Burch</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">NAACL-HLT</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Atlanta, Georgia</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013-06" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="758" to="764" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Toward a unified approach to statistical language modeling for chinese</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jianfeng</forename><surname>Gao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Joshua</forename><surname>Goodman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mingjing</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kaifu</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">ACM Transactions on Asian Language Information Processing (TALIP)</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3" to="33" />
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Scalable modified kneser-ney language model estimation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kenneth</forename><surname>Heafield</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ivan</forename><surname>Pouzyrevsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jonathan</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Clark</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Philipp</forename><surname>Koehn</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ACL</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Genia corpusa semantically annotated corpus for bio-textmining</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J-D</forename><surname>Kim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tomoko</forename><surname>Ohta</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yuka</forename><surname>Tateisi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Junichi</forename><surname>Tsujii</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Bioinformatics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="180" to="182" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>suppl</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Generating phrasal and sentential paraphrases: A survey of datadriven methods</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nitin</forename><surname>Madnani</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Bonnie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Dorr</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Computational Linguistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page">36</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Using paraphrases for parameter tuning in statistical machine translation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nitin</forename><surname>Madnani</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Philip</forename><surname>Necip Fazil Ayan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bonnie</forename><surname>Resnik</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Dorr</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Workshop on Machine Translation</title>
		<meeting>the Workshop on Machine Translation</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Discriminative corpus weight estimation for machine translation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Spyros</forename><surname>Matsoukas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bing</forename><surname>Antti-Veikko I Rosti</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">EMNLP</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="708" to="717" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Intelligent selection of language model training data</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Robert</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">William</forename><surname>Moore</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Lewis</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ACL</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="220" to="224" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Inducing lexical style properties for paraphrase and genre differentiation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ellie</forename><surname>Pavlick</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ani</forename><surname>Nenkova</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">NAACL</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Tomaz Erjavec, Dan Tufis, and Dániel Varga. 2006. The jrc-acquis: A multilingual aligned parallel corpus with 20+ languages</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ralf</forename><surname>Steinberger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bruno</forename><surname>Pouliquen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Anna</forename><surname>Widiger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Camelia</forename><surname>Ignat</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
<note type="report_type">arXiv preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Parallel data, tools and interfaces in opus</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jörg</forename><surname>Tiedemann</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">LREC</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2214" to="2218" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Paraphrasing for style</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wei</forename><surname>Xu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alan</forename><surname>Ritter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bill</forename><surname>Dolan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ralph</forename><surname>Grishman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Colin</forename><surname>Cherry</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">COLING</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2899" to="2914" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Method of selecting training data to build a compact and efficient translation model</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Keiji</forename><surname>Yasuda</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ruiqiang</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hirofumi</forename><surname>Yamamoto</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Eiichiro</forename><surname>Sumita</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">IJCNLP</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="655" to="660" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
