<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T11:06+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Successful Data Mining Methods for NLP</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
				<availability status="unknown"><p>Copyright Association for Computational Linguistics</p>
				</availability>
				<date>July 26-31, 2015. 2015</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jiawei</forename><surname>Han</surname></persName>
							<email>hanj@cs.uiuc.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Dept. of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Computer Science Dept</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Univ. of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign Urbana</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>61801</postCode>
									<region>IL</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Heng</forename><surname>Ji</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">College of Computer and Information Science Northeastern University Boston</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute Troy</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>12180, 02115</postCode>
									<region>NY, MA</region>
									<country>USA, USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yizhou</forename><surname>Sun</surname></persName>
							<email>yzsun@ccs.neu.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="department">Overview</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Successful Data Mining Methods for NLP</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the Tutorials of the 53rd Annual Meeting of the ACL and the 7th IJCNLP</title>
						<meeting>the Tutorials of the 53rd Annual Meeting of the ACL and the 7th IJCNLP <address><addrLine>Beijing, China</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="4"/>
							<date type="published">July 26-31, 2015. 2015</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Historically Natural Language Processing (NLP) focuses on unstructured data (speech and text) understanding while Data Mining (DM) mainly focuses on massive, structured or semi-structured datasets. The general research directions of these two fields also have followed different philosophies and principles. For example, NLP aims at deep understanding of individual words, phrases and sentences (&quot;micro-level&quot;), whereas DM aims to conduct a high-level understanding, discovery and synthesis of the most salient information from a large set of documents when working on text data (&quot;macro-level&quot;). But they share the same goal of distilling knowledge from data. In the past five years, these two areas have had intensive interactions and thus mutually enhanced each other through many successful text mining tasks. This positive progress mainly benefits from some innovative intermediate representations such as &quot;heterogeneous information net-works&quot; [Han et al., 2010, Sun et al., 2012b]. However, successful collaborations between any two fields require substantial mutual understanding , patience and passion among researchers. Similar to the applications of machine learning techniques in NLP, there is usually a gap of at least several years between the creation of a new DM approach and its first successful application in NLP. More importantly, many DM approaches such as gSpan [Yan and Han, 2002] and RankClus [Sun et al., 2009a] have demonstrated their power on structured data. But they remain relatively unknown in the NLP community , even though there are many obvious potential applications. On the other hand, compared to DM, the NLP community has paid more attention to developing large-scale data annotations, resources, shared tasks which cover a wide range of multiple genres and multiple domains. NLP can also provide the basic building blocks for many DM tasks such as text cube construction [Tao et al., 2014]. Therefore in many scenarios, for the same approach the NLP experiment setting is often much closer to real-world applications than its DM counterpart. We would like to share the experiences and lessons from our extensive inter-disciplinary collaborations in the past five years. The primary goal of this tutorial is to bridge the knowledge gap between these two fields and speed up the transition process. We will introduce two types of DM methods: (1). those state-of-the-art DM methods that have already been proven effective for NLP; and (2). some newly developed DM methods that we believe will fit into some specific NLP problems. In addition, we aim to suggest some new research directions in order to better marry these two areas and lead to more fruitful outcomes. The tutorial will thus be useful for researchers from both communities. We will try to provide a concise roadmap of recent perspectives and results, as well as point to the related DM software and resources, and NLP data sets that are available to both research communities. 2 Outline We will focus on the following three perspectives. 2.1 Where do NLP and DM Meet We will first pick up the tasks shown in Table 1 that have attracted interests from both NLP and DM, and give an overview of different solutions to these problems. We will compare their fundamental differences in terms of goals, theories, principles and methodologies.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Overview</head><p>Historically Natural Language Processing (NLP) focuses on unstructured data (speech and text) understanding while Data Mining (DM) mainly focuses on massive, structured or semi-structured datasets. The general research directions of these two fields also have followed different philoso- phies and principles. For example, NLP aims at deep understanding of individual words, phrases and sentences ("micro-level"), whereas DM aims to conduct a high-level understanding, discovery and synthesis of the most salient information from a large set of documents when working on text data ("macro-level"). But they share the same goal of distilling knowledge from data. In the past five years, these two areas have had in- tensive interactions and thus mutually enhanced each other through many successful text mining tasks. This positive progress mainly benefits from some innovative intermediate representa- tions such as "heterogeneous information net- works" <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">[Han et al., 2010</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b15">, Sun et al., 2012b</ref>.</p><p>However, successful collaborations between any two fields require substantial mutual under- standing, patience and passion among research- ers. Similar to the applications of machine learn- ing techniques in NLP, there is usually a gap of at least several years between the creation of a new DM approach and its first successful appli- cation in NLP. More importantly, many DM ap- proaches such as gSpan <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">[Yan and Han, 2002]</ref> and RankClus <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">[Sun et al., 2009a</ref>] have demon- strated their power on structured data. But they remain relatively unknown in the NLP communi- ty, even though there are many obvious potential applications. On the other hand, compared to DM, the NLP community has paid more atten- tion to developing large-scale data annotations, resources, shared tasks which cover a wide range of multiple genres and multiple domains. NLP can also provide the basic building blocks for many DM tasks such as text cube construction <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">[Tao et al., 2014]</ref>. Therefore in many scenarios, for the same approach the NLP experiment set- ting is often much closer to real-world applica- tions than its DM counterpart. We would like to share the experiences and les- sons from our extensive inter-disciplinary col- laborations in the past five years. The primary goal of this tutorial is to bridge the knowledge gap between these two fields and speed up the transition process. We will introduce two types of DM methods: (1). those state-of-the-art DM methods that have already been proven effective for NLP; and (2). some newly developed DM methods that we believe will fit into some specif- ic NLP problems. In addition, we aim to suggest some new research directions in order to better marry these two areas and lead to more fruitful outcomes. The tutorial will thus be useful for researchers from both communities. We will try to provide a concise roadmap of recent perspec- tives and results, as well as point to the related DM software and resources, and NLP data sets that are available to both research communities.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Outline</head><p>We will focus on the following three perspec- tives.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">Where do NLP and DM Meet</head><p>We will first pick up the tasks shown in <ref type="table">Table 1</ref> that have attracted interests from both NLP and DM, and give an overview of different solutions to these problems. We will compare their funda- mental differences in terms of goals, theories, principles and methodologies.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Tasks</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>DM Methods NLP Methods Phrase mining / Chunk- ing</head><p>Statistical pattern mining <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">[El-Kishky et al., 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Danilevsky et al., 2014;</ref> We will synthesize the important aspects learned from these successes.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3">New DM Methods Promising for NLP</head><p>Then we will introduce a wide range of new DM methods which we believe are promising to NLP. We will align the problems and solutions by cat- egorizing their special characteristics from both the linguistic perspective and the mining per- spective. One thread we will focus on is graph mining. We will recommend some effective graph pattern mining methods <ref type="bibr">Han, 2002&amp;2003;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Yan et al., 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Chen et al., 2010]</ref> and their potential applications in cross- document entity clustering and slot filling. Some recent DM methods can also be used to capture implicit textual cues which might be difficult to generalize using traditional syntactic analysis. For example, <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">[Kim et al., 2011</ref>] developed a syn- tactic tree mining approach to predict authors from papers, which can be extended to more general stylistic analysis. We will carefully sur- vey the major challenges and solutions that ad- dress these adoptions.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.4">New Research Directions to Integrate NLP and DM</head><p>We will conclude with a discussion of some key new research directions to better integrate DM and NLP. What is the best framework for inte- gration and joint inference? Is there an ideal common representation, or a layer between these two fields? Is Information Networks still the best intermediate step to accomplish the Language-to- Networks-to-Knowledge paradigm?</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.5">Resources</head><p>We will present an overview of related systems, demos, resources and data sets. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Tutorial Instructors</head></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" validated="false"><head>]</head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Supervised chunking trained 
from Penn Treebank 

Topic hierarchy / Tax-
onomy construction 

Combine statistical pattern mining with 
information networks [Wang et al., 
2014] 

Lexical/Syntactic patterns (e.g., 
COLING2014 workshop on 
taxonomy construction) 
Entity Linking 
Graph alignment [Li et al., 2013] 
TAC-KBP Entity Linking meth-
ods and Wikification 
Relation discovery 
Hierarchical clustering [Wang et al., 
2012] 

ACE relation extraction, boot-
strapping 
Sentiment Analysis 
Pseudo-friendship network analysis 
[Deng et al., 2014] 

Supervised methods based on 
linguistic resources 

Table 1. Examples for Tasks Solved by Different NLP and DM Methods 

2.2 Successful DM Methods Applied for 
NLP 

Then we will focus on introducing a series of 
effective DM methods which have already been 
adopted for NLP applications. The most fruitful 
research line exploited Heterogeneous Infor-
mation Networks [Tao et al., 2014; Sun et al., 
2009ab, 2011, 2012ab, 2013, 2015]. For exam-
ple, the meta-path concept and methodology 
[Sun et al., 2011] has been successfully used to 
address morph entity discovery and resolution 
[Huang et al., 2013] and Wikification [Huang et 
al., 2014]; the Co-HITS algorithm [Deng et al., 
2009] was applied to solve multiple NLP prob-
lems including tweet ranking [Huang et al., 
2012] and slot filling validation [Yu et al., 2014]. 
</table></figure>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Graph OLAP: A Multi-Dimensional Framework for Graph Data Analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Reference [chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Knowledge and Information Systems</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<publisher>KAIS</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Automatic Construction and Ranking of Topical Keyphrases on Collections of Short Documents</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">[</forename><surname>Danilevsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. 2014 SIAM Int. Conf. on Data Mining (SDM&apos;14)</title>
		<meeting>2014 SIAM Int. Conf. on Data Mining (SDM&apos;14)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A Generalized Co-HITS algorithm and its Application to Bipartite Graphs</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Deng</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. KDD2009</title>
		<editor>Deng. Michael R. Lyu and Irwin King</editor>
		<meeting>KDD2009</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Exploring and Inferring User-User PseudoFriendship for Sentiment Analysis with Heterogeneous Networks. Statistical Analysis and Data Mining</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Deng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014-02" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Scalable Topical Phrase Mining from Text Corpora</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>El-Kishky</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proc. PVLDB</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="305" to="316" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Mining Heterogeneous Information Networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">[</forename><surname>Han</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Tutorial at the 2010 ACM SIGKDD Conf. on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining (KDD&apos;10)</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Washington, D.C.</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010-07" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">[</forename><surname>Han</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Bringing Structure to Text: Mining Phrases, Entity Concepts, Topics, and Hierarchies. KDD2014 conference tutorial</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Resolving Entity Morphs in Censored Data</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. the 51st Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL2013)</title>
		<meeting>the 51st Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL2013)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Collective Tweet Wikification based on Semi-supervised Graph Regularization</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. the 52nd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL2014)</title>
		<meeting>the 52nd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL2014)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Authorship Classification: A Discriminative Syntactic Tree Mining Approach</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">[</forename><surname>Kim</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of 2011 Int. ACM SIGIR Conf. on Research &amp; Development in Information Retrieval (SIGIR&apos;11)</title>
		<meeting>of 2011 Int. ACM SIGIR Conf. on Research &amp; Development in Information Retrieval (SIGIR&apos;11)<address><addrLine>Beijing, China</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011-07" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Mining Evidences for Named Entity Disambiguation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">[</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of 2013 ACM SIGKDD Int. Conf. on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining (KDD&apos;13)</title>
		<meeting>of 2013 ACM SIGKDD Int. Conf. on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining (KDD&apos;13)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1070" to="1078" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">RankClus: Integrating Clustering with Ranking for Heterogeneous Information Network Analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Sun</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. the 12th International Conference on Extending Database Technology: Advances in Database Technology</title>
		<meeting>the 12th International Conference on Extending Database Technology: Advances in Database Technology</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Ranking-Based Clustering of Heterogeneous Information Networks with Star Network Schema</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Sun</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. 2009 ACM SIGKDD Int. Conf. on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining (KDD&apos;09)</title>
		<meeting>2009 ACM SIGKDD Int. Conf. on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining (KDD&apos;09)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">PathSim: Meta Path-Based Top-K Similarity Search in Heterogeneous Information Networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Sun</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. International Conference on Very Large Data Bases (VLDB2011)</title>
		<meeting>International Conference on Very Large Data Bases (VLDB2011)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Integrating Meta-Path Selection with User Guided Object Clustering in Heterogeneous Information Networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Sun</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of 2012 ACM SIGKDD Int. Conf. on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining (KDD&apos;12)</title>
		<meeting>of 2012 ACM SIGKDD Int. Conf. on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining (KDD&apos;12)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Sun</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Mining Heterogeneous Information Networks: Principles and Methodologies</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Morgan &amp; Claypool Publishers</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">PathSelClus: Integrating Meta-Path Selection with User-Guided Object Clustering in Heterogeneous Information Networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Sun</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">ACM Transactions on Knowledge Discovery from Data (TKDD)</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">11</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">CoEvolution of Multi-Typed Objects in Dynamic Heterogeneous Information Networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Sun</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE Trans. on Knowledge and Data Engineering</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">NewsNetExplorer: Automatic Construction and Exploration of News Information Networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">[</forename><surname>Tao</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of 2014 ACM SIGMOD Int. Conf. on Management of Data</title>
		<meeting>of 2014 ACM SIGMOD Int. Conf. on Management of Data<address><addrLine>Xiang Ren, Yizhou Sun</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>SIGMOD&apos;14</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Learning Hierarchical Relationships among Partially Ordered Objects with Heterogeneous Attributes and Links</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">[</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Constructing Topical Hierarchies in Heterogeneous Information Networks. Proc. Knowledge and Information Systems (KAIS)</title>
		<editor>Wang, Jialu Liu, Nihit Desai, Marina Danilevsky, and Jiawei Han</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Proc. 2012 SIAM International Conference on Data Mining</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Mining Significant Graph Patterns by Scalable Leap Search</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">[</forename><surname>Yan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. 2008 ACM SIGMOD Int. Conf. on Management of Data (SIGMOD&apos;08)</title>
		<meeting>2008 ACM SIGMOD Int. Conf. on Management of Data (SIGMOD&apos;08)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">gSpan: Graph-Based Substructure Pattern Mining</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yan</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Han ; Xifeng</forename><surname>Yan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jiawei</forename><surname>Han</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. 2002 of Int. Conf. on Data Mining (ICDM&apos;02)</title>
		<meeting>2002 of Int. Conf. on Data Mining (ICDM&apos;02)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">CloseGraph: Mining Closed Frequent Graph Patterns</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yan</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Han ; Xifeng</forename><surname>Yan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jiawei</forename><surname>Han</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. 2003 ACM SIGKDD Int. Conf. on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining (KDD&apos;03)</title>
		<meeting>2003 ACM SIGKDD Int. Conf. on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining (KDD&apos;03)<address><addrLine>Washington, D.C.</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003-08" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Wisdom of Minority: Unsupervised Slot Filling Validation based on Multi-dimensional TruthFinding</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">[</forename><surname>Yu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. The 25th International Conference on Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>The 25th International Conference on Computational Linguistics</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
