<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T10:24+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">What You Need to Know about Chinese for Chinese Language Processing</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
				<availability status="unknown"><p>Copyright Association for Computational Linguistics</p>
				</availability>
				<date>July 26-31, 2015. 2015</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chu-Ren</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
							<email>churen.huang@inet.polyu.edu.hk</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">The Hong Kong Polytechnic University Hung Hom</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Kowloon, Hong Kong</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Introduction</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">What You Need to Know about Chinese for Chinese Language Processing</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the Tutorials of the 53rd Annual Meeting of the ACL and the 7th IJCNLP</title>
						<meeting>the Tutorials of the 53rd Annual Meeting of the ACL and the 7th IJCNLP <address><addrLine>Beijing, China</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="23" to="24"/>
							<date type="published">July 26-31, 2015. 2015</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract/>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>The synergy between language sciences and lan- guage technology has been an elusive one for the computational linguistics community, especially when dealing with a language other than English. The reasons are two-fold: the lack of an accessi- ble comprehensive and robust account of a specific language so as to allow strategic linking between a processing task to linguistic devices, and the lack of successful computational studies taking advan- tage of such links. With a fast growing number of available online resources, as well as a rapidly increasing number of members of the CL commu- nity who are interested in and/or working on Chi- nese language processing, the time is ripe to take a serious look at how knowledge of Chinese can help Chinese language processing.</p><p>The tutorial will be organized according to the structure of linguistic knowledge of Chinese, start- ing from the basic building block to the use of Chi- nese in context. The first part deals with characters as the basic linguistic unit of Chinese in terms of phonology, orthography, and basic concepts. An ontological view of how the Chinese writing sys- tem organizes meaningful content as well as how this onomasiological decision affects Chinese text processing will also be discussed. The second part deals with words and presents basic issues in- volving the definition and identification of words in Chinese, especially given the lack of conven- tional marks of word boundaries. The third part deals with parts of speech and focuses on def- inition of a few grammatical categories specific to Chinese, as well as distributional properties of Chinese PoS and tagging systems. The fourth part deals with sentence and structure, focusing on how to identify grammatical relations in Chinese as well as a few Chinese-specific constructions. The fifth part deals with how meanings are rep- resented and expressed, especially how different linguistic devices (from lexical choice to informa- tion structure) are used to convey different infor- mation. Lastly, the sixth part deals with the ranges of different varieties of Chinese in the world and the computational approaches to detect and differ- entiate these varieties. In each topic, an empiri- cal foundation of linguistics facts are clearly expli- cated with a robust generalization, and the linguis- tic generalization is then accounted for in terms of its function in the knowledge representation sys- tem. Lastly this knowledge representation role is then exploited in terms of the aims of specific lan- guage technology tasks. In terms of references, in addition to language resources and various rel- evant papers, the tutorial will make reference to <ref type="bibr">Huang and Shi's (2016)</ref> reference grammar for a linguistic description of Chinese. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Resources</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Outline</head><p>The tutorial will have six components according to the nature of linguistic knowledge of Chinese: 1) characters, 2) words, 3) Parts of Speech, 4) Sen- tence and Structure, 5) Meaning: Representation and Expressive, and 6) Variations and Changes. Under each knowledge component, there will be 3 to 5 focus areas. In addition, relevant resources and language technology applications will be in- troduced together with the linguistic description or at the end of the lecture sections (for those lan- guage processing applications involving more than one linguistic issue.) Overall, two lecture sections of 80 minutes each will be given, each contain- ing 5 topical groups (each topical group covers 2-3 focus areas described above). It is estimated that each topic group will take about 15 minutes to cover. Although the 15 minutes will not be enough for explication of finer details, participants will be able to access and acquire additional details from a comprehensive list references. The three hour teaching plan is given below.</p><p>00:00-01:20 Characters, Words, and Parts-of- Speech</p><p>• -Component structure of Chinese characters: encoding and ontological issues</p><p>• -Writing system and processing of Chinese texts: myths and facts</p><p>• -Definition and identification of words in Chinese: with special foci on segmentation, and compounds</p><p>• -PoS and tagging in Chinese, with special foci on de, adjectives (or verbs), prepositions, and classifiers</p><p>• -Related issues and examples in Chinese Language processing 01:20-01:40: Coffee Break 01:40-03:00 Sentence, Meaning, and Variations</p><p>• -Aspectual and eventive systems of Chinese</p><p>• -Identification of grammatical relations: ba/bei, topic/argument, separable com- pounds and oblique arguments</p><p>• -Semantic relations and semantic selection</p><p>• -World Chineses: variations and changes and how to identify them </p></div>		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl/>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
