<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T11:00+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Robust Multi-Relational Clustering via 1-Norm Symmetric Nonnegative Matrix Factorization</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
				<availability status="unknown"><p>Copyright Association for Computational Linguistics</p>
				</availability>
				<date>July 26-31, 2015. 2015</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kai</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
							<email>kaliu@mines.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Colorado school of Mines Department of EECS Golden</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Colorado school of Mines Department of EECS Golden</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>80401, 80401</postCode>
									<region>Colorado, Colorado</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hua</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
							<email>HUAWANGCS@gmail.com</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Colorado school of Mines Department of EECS Golden</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Colorado school of Mines Department of EECS Golden</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>80401, 80401</postCode>
									<region>Colorado, Colorado</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Robust Multi-Relational Clustering via 1-Norm Symmetric Nonnegative Matrix Factorization</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 53rd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics and the 7th International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing</title>
						<meeting>the 53rd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics and the 7th International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing <address><addrLine>Beijing, China</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="397" to="401"/>
							<date type="published">July 26-31, 2015. 2015</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>In this paper, we propose an 1-norm Symmetric Nonnegative Matrix Tri-Factorization (1 S-NMTF) framework to cluster multi-type relational data by utilizing their interrelatedness. Due to introducing the 1-norm distances in our new objective function, the proposed approach is robust against noise and outliers, which are inherent in multi-relational data. We also derive the solution algorithm and rigorously analyze its correctness and convergence. The promising experimental results of the algorithm applied to text clustering on IMDB dataset validate the proposed approach.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Traditional clustering aims to partition data points into several groups, such that the data points in the same group can share some commonalities whilst those from different groups are dissimilar. With the recent progresses of Internet and compu- tational technologies, data have started to appear in much richer structures. To be more specific, in many real-world problems a pair of object can be related in several different ways, which inevitably complicates the problem and calls for new clus- tering algorithms for better understanding to the data. To address this new challenge, <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Wang et. al. (Wang et al., 2011c</ref>; <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Wang et al., 2011d</ref>) proposed nonnegative matrix factorization (NMF) ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Lee and Seung, 1999</ref>) based computational algorithms that have successfully solved the problems.</p><p>Due to its mathematical elegance and its equiv- alence to K-means clustering and spectral clus- tering ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Ding et al., 2005</ref>), NMF ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Lee and Seung, 1999</ref>) has been broadly studied in recent years and successfully solved a variety of practical problems in data mining and machine learning, such as those in computer vision ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Wang et al., 2011b</ref>), bioinfor- matics ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Wang et al., 2013)</ref>, natural language un- derstanding ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Wang et al., 2011a</ref>), to name a few. Compared to many traditional clustering meth- ods, such as K-means clustering, NMF has better mathematical interpretation, which usually lead to improved accuracy on clustering ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Ding et al., 2010)</ref>. Traditional clustering algorithms concen- trate on dealing with homogeneous data, in which all the data belong to one single type ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Wang et al., 2011d</ref>). To deal with the richer data structures in modern real-world applications, symmetric Non- negative Matrix Tri-Factorization (NMTF)( <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Wang et al., 2011c</ref>) have demonstrated its effectiveness on simultaneous clustering of multi-type relational data by utilizing the interrelatedness among differ- ent data types.</p><p>Traditional NMF algorithms routinely use the least square error functions, which are notably known to be sensitive against outliers <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Kong et al., 2011)</ref>. However, at the era of big data outliers are inevitable due to the ever increasing data sizes. As a result, developing a more robust NMF model for multi-relational data clustering has become more and more important. In this paper, we further de- velop the symmetric NMF clustering model pro- posed in ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Wang et al., 2011c</ref>) by using the 1 -norm distances, such that our new clustering model is more robust against outliers, which is of particular importance in multi-relational data.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Robust Multi-Relational Clustering via</head><p>1 -Norm Symmetric NMTF (S-NMTF)</p><p>In this section, we first introduce the backgrounds to use symmetric NMF to cluster multi-relational data. Then we develop our new 1 -norm symmet- ric NMF model for better robustness against outly- ing data. The solution algorithm to our new model will be proposed and analyzed in the next section. Notations. In this paper, we use upper case let- ters to denote matrices. Given a matrix M , its en- 397 try at the i-th row and j-th column is denoted as M (ij) . The Frobenius norm of a matrix M is de-</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">noted as M F = i j M 2 (ij)</formula><p>1/2 and its 1 - norm is denoted as</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">M 1 = i j |M (ij) |.</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">Problem Formalization</head><p>K-type relational data set can be denoted as χ = {χ 1 , χ 2 , . . . , χ K } , where</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">χ k = x k 1 , x k 2 , . . . , x k n k</formula><p>represents the data set of k-th type. Suppose we are given a set of relationship matrices {R kl ∈ n k ×n l } (1≤k≤K,1≤l≤K) between different types of data objects, then we have R kl = R T lk . Our goal is to simultaneously partition the data objects in χ 1 , χ 2 , . . . , χ K into c 1 , c 2 , . . . , c K disjoint clusters respectively.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">Our objective</head><p>To cluster multi-relation data, symmetric NMF has been taken advantage that solves the following op- timization problem ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Wang et al., 2008)</ref>:</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">min J = 1≤k&lt;l≤K R kl − G k S kl G T l 2 F , s.t. G k ≥ 0, ∀ 1 ≤ k ≤ K .<label>(1)</label></formula><p>It has also been shown that solving the above equation is equivalent to solve <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Long et al., 2006</ref>):</p><formula xml:id="formula_4">min J = R − GSG T 2 F , s.t. G ≥ 0,<label>(2)</label></formula><p>in which</p><formula xml:id="formula_5">R =       0 n 1 ×n 1 R n 1 ×n 2 12 · · · R n 1 ×n K 1K R n 2 ×n 1 21 0 n 2 ×n 2 · · · R n 2 ×n K 2K . . . . . . . . . . . . R n K ×n 1 K1 R n K ×n 2 K2 · · · 0 n K ×n K       , G =       G n 1 ×c 1 1 0 n 1 ×c 2 · · · 0 n 1 ×c K 0 n 2 ×c 1 G n 2 ×c 2 2 · · · 0 n 2 ×c K . . . . . . . . . . . . 0 n K ×c 1 0 n K ×c 2 · · · G n K ×c K K       , S =       0 c 1 ×c 1 S c 1 ×c 2 12 · · · S c 1 ×c K 1K S c 2 ×c 1 21 0 c 2 ×c 2 · · · S c 2 ×c K 2K . . . . . . . . . . . . S c K ×c 1 K1 S c K ×c 2 K2 · · · 0 c K ×c K       ,<label>(3)</label></formula><p>where</p><formula xml:id="formula_6">R ji = R T ij and S ij = S T ji .</formula><p>Despite its successfulness of the method pro- posed in ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Wang et al., 2011c</ref>) in multi-relational data clustering, the objectives in Equations <ref type="formula" target="#formula_3">(1-2)</ref> use the squared 2 -norm distances to measure the matrix approximation errors, which, though, are prone to outliers. As a result, the clustering re- sults could be heavily dominated by outlying data points with large approximation errors <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Kong et al., 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Nie et al., 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Wang et al., 2014</ref>). To improve the robustness of the clustering model, following prior works ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Kong et al., 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Nie et al., 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Wang et al., 2014</ref>) we propose to use the following 1 -norm symmetric NMTF model for multi-relational data clustering:</p><formula xml:id="formula_7">min J = R − GSG T 1 s.t. G ≥ 0, (4)</formula><p>In this new formulation, the approximation errors are measured by the 1 -norm distances, which are expected to be more insensitive to outlying data points. As shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref>, when there ex- ist outliers in the input data, traditional squared Frobenius-norm NMF are inclined to cluster in- correctly, while the 1 -norm NMF are more robust and can cluster more accurately. </p><formula xml:id="formula_8">D(i, i) = |R−GSG T | i R−GSG T 2 i . 4. Compute S = (G T G) −1 G T RG(G T G) −1 . 5. Update G (ij) ← G (ij) (RDGS) (ij) (GSG T DGS) (ij) 1 4 .</formula><p>until Converges 3 Algorithm to Solve 1 -Norm S-NMTF and its analysis</p><p>The computational algorithm for the proposed 1 - norm S-NMTF approach is summarized in Algo- rithm 1 (Due to space limit, the derivation of the algorithm is skipped and will be provided in our journal version of the paper). Upon solution, the 398 final cluster labels are obtained from the resulted G k .</p><p>The following theorems guarantee the correct- ness of Algorithm 1 (Due to space limit, the derivation of the algorithm is skipped and will be provided in our journal version of the paper). This is the fixed point relationships that the so- lution must satisfy.</p><p>The following lemmas and theorem guarantee the convergence of Algorithm 1 (Due to space limit, the derivation of the algorithm is skipped and will be provided in our journal version of the paper).  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Theorem 3.4 Let</head><formula xml:id="formula_9">J(G) = tr(−2RDGSG T + GSG T DGSG T ),<label>(5)</label></formula><p>then the following function</p><formula xml:id="formula_10">Z(G, G ) = − 2 ijkl G (ji) S (jk) G (kl) D (ll) R (li) (1 + log G (ji) G (kl) G (ij) G (kl) ) + ij (G SG T DG S) (ij) G 4 (ij) G 3 (ij)<label>(6)</label></formula><p>is an auxiliary function of J(G). Furthermore, it is a convex function in G and its global minimum is</p><formula xml:id="formula_11">G (ik) = G (ik) (RDGS) (ik) (GSG T DGS) (ik) 1 4 (7)</formula><p>Based on the property of auxiliary function and convex function, by updating G, we can always get the optimal solution to the object function, thus determining the final cluster label.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Experiments Result</head><p>In this section, We test our proposed algorithm on IMDB dataset by using its inter-type relationship information.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">Data set</head><p>We use the dataset from ACL-IMDB provided by <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Maas et al., 2011)</ref>. In this dataset, there is a sub- training set of 25000 highly polar movie reviews, in which positive and negative comments come up with one half(12500) each. The dataset also in- cludes the following two important files: the con- tent of each comment and the corresponding U RL 399 where each comment comes from. There are also some other files but not related with the experi- ment we conduct, thus we skip them.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">Experiments settings</head><p>In our experiment, we set the multi-type data as 3 types: author, comment and word. As it is discussed in the 3rd part, there are three rela- tionships we need to find, which correspond to three matrices we need to construct the multi-type data matrix:comment-author, comment-word and author-word. By making use of the U RL of ev- ery comment, we can find the author who posts the corresponding comment, thus we can build the author-comment matrix.Since each comment with content is given by the dataset file, we could there- fore construct the matrix of comment-word, and the author-word matrix is the product of author- comment matrix and comment-word matrix.</p><p>We could find the first 1500 authors who post comments most, since the comments from the same person are more likely to have some corre- lations, such as similar sentence structures, same words and etc. We also rule out the stop-words since they may disturb the clustering and they are meaningless to the property of comments. To make our experiments to be more persuasive, we also add some noise to the three relationship matri- ces with a ratio of 25 percentage(1/5 in amplitude). By randomly choosing 500 authors from 1500, we could generate many sub-datasets to conduct our experiments.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3">Experiments Results</head><p>We compare the performance of our proposed 1 - norm S-NMTF algorithm with other methods such as P-NMF, Frobenius norm S-NMTF, traditional NMF and K-means clustering. For simplicity, we only compare the clustering accuracy of comment- word matrix since its label (positive or negative) is fixed(the grounding label), thus could be com- pared with the clustering results by using the clus- tering algorithms. <ref type="table">Table 1</ref> shows that when the data is pure, in many cases(more than the listed), 1 -norm S- NMTF approach has better performance than oth- ers <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Table 2</ref> illustrates the situation when some noise is added to the data, it is easy to find that 1 -norm S-NMTF algorithm is the best in terms of cluster- ing accuracy. This meets our analysis in our Moti- vation part.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Alg L11</head><p>L22 PMF NMF Kms set 1 0.578 0.528 0.554 0.510 0.504 set 2 0.583 0.556 0.551 0.521 0.521 set 3 0.584 0.559 0.555 0.501 0.501 set 4 0.551 0.522 0.502 0.527 0.506 set 5 0.566 0.534 0.506 0.529 0.531 set 6 0.558 0.517 0.510 0.535 0.526 <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>  Careful examination in <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">Table 3</ref> reveals the fact that 1 -norm S-NMTF algorithm performs more robust than any other algorithm. Though the clus- tering accuracy of 1 -norm S-NMTF decreases when noise exists, still it reduces the least among the five algorithms. This result convincingly demonstrates the robustness of our proposed 1 - norm S-NMTF method.  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Alg</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Conclusion</head><p>In this paper, we presented an 1 -norm Symmet- ric Nonnegative Matrix Tri-Factorization Frame- work to cluster multi-type relational data simulta- neously. Our proposed approach clusters different types of data, using its inter-type relationship by transforming the original problem into a symmet- ric NMTF problem. We also presented an auxil- iary function and high order matrix inequality to derive the solution algorithm. The proposed algo- rithm not only makes use of the rich data struc- 400 ture to improve the clustering accuracy, but also remains robust when there is noise and outliers. Experimental results demonstrate the potential us- age and advantage of 1 -norm S-NMTF in cluster- ing especially when there are outliers, which is in accordance with our theory analysis.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: Clustering data in two clusters with some outliers (represented as triangle). Left: Clustering performance by using traditional squared Frobenius-norm NMF algorithm. Right: Clustering performance by using the proposed 1-norm NMF algorithm.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Theorem 3 . 1</head><label>31</label><figDesc>If the updating rules of G and S in Algorithm 1 converges, the final solution satisfies the KKT optimal condition.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Lemma 3 . 2</head><label>32</label><figDesc>(Lee and Seung, 1999) Z(h, h ) is an auxiliary function of F (h) if the conditions Z(h, h ) ≥ F (h) and Z(h, h ) = F (h) are sat- isfied.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>Lemma 3 .</head><label>3</label><figDesc>3 (Lee and Seung, 1999) If Z is an aux- iliary function for F , then F is non-increasing un- der the update h (t+1) = arg min h Z(h, h ).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>L11 L22 PMF NMF Kms s.1(P) 0.547 0.546 0.521 0.546 0.546 s.1(N) 0.546 0.525 0.516 0.540 0.545 s.2(P) 0.543 0.543 0.534 0.543 0.543 s.2(N) 0.543 0.539 0.531 0.513 0.531 s.3(P) 0.536 0.536 0.524 0.536 0.536 s.3(N) 0.536 0.534 0.522 0.517 0.508</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" validated="false"><head>Table 2 : Clustering Accuracy with Noise.</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" validated="false"><head>Table 3 : Clustering Accuracy Contrast.</head><label>3</label><figDesc></figDesc><table></table></figure>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">On the equivalence of nonnegative matrix factorization and spectral clustering</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Ding</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>He</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Simon</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">SDM</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Orthogonal nonnegative matrix t-factorizations for clustering</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Ding</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Peng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Park</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">SIGKDD</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Convex and semi-nonnegative matrix factorizations</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Ding</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">I</forename><surname>Jordan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE TPAMI</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">32</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="45" to="55" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Robust nonnegative matrix factorization using l21norm</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Deguang</forename><surname>Kong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chris</forename><surname>Ding</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Heng</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 20th ACM international conference on Information and knowledge management</title>
		<meeting>the 20th ACM international conference on Information and knowledge management</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="673" to="682" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Learning the parts of objects by non-negative matrix factorization</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Seung</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">401</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6755</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="788" to="791" />
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Spectral clustering for multitype relational data</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bo</forename><surname>Long</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Zhongfei</forename><forename type="middle">Mark</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xiaoyun</forename><surname>Wu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Philip S</forename><surname>Yu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 23rd international conference on Machine learning</title>
		<meeting>the 23rd international conference on Machine learning</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="585" to="592" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Learning word vectors for sentiment analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Andrew</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Maas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Raymond</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Daly</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Peter</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Pham</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dan</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Andrew</forename><forename type="middle">Y</forename><surname>Ng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christopher</forename><surname>Potts</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 49th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics: Human Language Technologies</title>
		<meeting>the 49th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics: Human Language Technologies<address><addrLine>Oregon, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011-06" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="142" to="150" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Portland. Association for Computational Linguistics</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Robust principal component analysis with non-greedy l1-norm maximization</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Feiping</forename><surname>Nie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Heng</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chris</forename><surname>Ding</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dijun</forename><surname>Luo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hua</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">IJCAI Proceedings-International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>page 1433. Citeseer</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Semi-supervised clustering via matrix factorization</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">SDM</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Cross-language web page classification via dual knowledge transfer using nonnegative matrix trifactorization</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Nie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Ding</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">SIGIR</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dyadic transfer learning for cross-domain image classification</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Nie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Ding</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ICCV</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Simultaneous clustering of multi-type relational data via symmetric nonnegative matrix tri-factorization</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hua</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Heng</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chris</forename><surname>Ding</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 20th ACM international conference on Information and knowledge management</title>
		<meeting>the 20th ACM international conference on Information and knowledge management</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="279" to="284" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Nonnegative matrix tri-factorization based high-order co-clustering and its fast implementation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hua</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Feiping</forename><surname>Nie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Heng</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chris</forename><surname>Ding</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Data Mining (ICDM), 2011 IEEE 11th International Conference on</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>IEEE</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="774" to="783" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Predicting protein-protein interactions from multimodal biological data sources via nonnegative matrix tri-factorization</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hua</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Heng</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chris</forename><surname>Ding</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Feiping</forename><surname>Nie</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Computational Biology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="344" to="358" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Robust distance metric learning via simultaneous l1norm minimization and maximization</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hua</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Feiping</forename><surname>Nie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Heng</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 31st International Conference on Machine Learning (ICML-14)</title>
		<meeting>the 31st International Conference on Machine Learning (ICML-14)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1836" to="1844" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
