<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T10:07+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Event Extraction via Dynamic Multi-Pooling Convolutional Neural Networks</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
				<availability status="unknown"><p>Copyright Association for Computational Linguistics</p>
				</availability>
				<date>July 26-31, 2015. 2015</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yubo</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Institute of Automation</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">National Laboratory of Pattern Recognition</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Chinese Academy of Sciences</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>100190</postCode>
									<settlement>Beijing</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Liheng</forename><surname>Xu</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Institute of Automation</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">National Laboratory of Pattern Recognition</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Chinese Academy of Sciences</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>100190</postCode>
									<settlement>Beijing</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kang</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Institute of Automation</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">National Laboratory of Pattern Recognition</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Chinese Academy of Sciences</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>100190</postCode>
									<settlement>Beijing</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Daojian</forename><surname>Zeng</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Institute of Automation</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">National Laboratory of Pattern Recognition</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Chinese Academy of Sciences</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>100190</postCode>
									<settlement>Beijing</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jun</forename><surname>Zhao</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Institute of Automation</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">National Laboratory of Pattern Recognition</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Chinese Academy of Sciences</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>100190</postCode>
									<settlement>Beijing</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Event Extraction via Dynamic Multi-Pooling Convolutional Neural Networks</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 53rd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics and the 7th International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing</title>
						<meeting>the 53rd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics and the 7th International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing <address><addrLine>Beijing, China</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="167" to="176"/>
							<date type="published">July 26-31, 2015. 2015</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Traditional approaches to the task of ACE event extraction primarily rely on elaborately designed features and complicated natural language processing (NLP) tools. These traditional approaches lack generalization , take a large amount of human effort and are prone to error propagation and data sparsity problems. This paper proposes a novel event-extraction method, which aims to automatically extract lexical-level and sentence-level features without using complicated NLP tools. We introduce a word-representation model to capture meaningful semantic regularities for words and adopt a framework based on a convolutional neural network (CNN) to capture sentence-level clues. However, CNN can only capture the most important information in a sentence and may miss valuable facts when considering multiple-event sentences. We propose a dynamic multi-pooling convolutional neu-ral network (DMCNN), which uses a dynamic multi-pooling layer according to event triggers and arguments, to reserve more crucial information. The experimental results show that our approach significantly outperforms other state-of-the-art methods.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Event extraction is an important and challenging task in Information Extraction (IE), which aims to discover event triggers with specific types and their arguments. Current state-of-the-art methods ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Li et al., 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Li et al., 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Hong et al., 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Liao and Grishman, 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Ji and Grishman, 2008)</ref> often use a set of elaborately designed features that are extracted by textual analysis and linguistic knowledge. In general, we can divide the features into two categories: lexical features and contex- tual features.</p><p>Lexical features contain part-of-speech tags (POS), entity information, and morphology fea- tures (e.g., token, lemma, etc.), which aim to cap- ture semantics or the background knowledge of words. For example, consider the following sen- tence with an ambiguous word beats:</p><p>S1: Obama beats McCain. S2: Tyson beats his opponent . In S1, beats is a trigger of type Elect. However, in S2, beats is a trigger of type Attack, which is more common than type Elect. Because of the am- biguity, a traditional approach may mislabel beats in S1 as a trigger of Attack. However, if we have the priori knowledge that Obama and McCain are presidential contenders, we have ample evidence to predict that beats is a trigger of type Elect. We call these knowledge lexical-level clues. To repre- sent such features, the existing methods <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Hong et al., 2011</ref>) often rely on human ingenuity, which is a time-consuming process and lacks general- ization. Furthermore, traditional lexical features in previous methods are a one-hot representation, which may suffer from the data sparsity problem and may not be able to adequately capture the se- mantics of the words ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">Turian et al., 2010)</ref>.</p><p>To identify events and arguments more pre- cisely, previous methods often captured contex- tual features, such as syntactic features, which aim to understand how facts are tied together from a larger field of view. For example, in S3, there are two events that share three arguments as shown in <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref>. From the dependency relation of nsubj between the argument cameraman and trig- ger died, we can induce a Victim role to cam- eraman in the Die event. We call such infor- mation sentence-level clues. However, the argu- ment word cameraman and its trigger word fired are in different clauses, and there is no direct de- pendency path between them. Thus it is difficult to find the Target role between them using tradi- tional dependency features. In addition, extracting such features depends heavily on the performance of pre-existing NLP systems, which could suffer from error propagation. S3: In Baghdad, a cameraman died when an American tank fired on the Palestine Hotel.</p><p>To correctly attach cameraman to fired as a Tar- get argument, we must exploit internal semantics over the entire sentence such that the Attack event results in Die event. Recent improvements of convolutional neural networks (CNNs) have been proven to be efficient for capturing syntactic and semantics between words within a sentence <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Collobert et al., 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Kalchbrenner and Blunsom, 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Zeng et al., 2014</ref>) for NLP tasks. CNNs typically use a max-pooling layer, which applies a max operation over the representation of an en- tire sentence to capture the most useful informa- tion. However, in event extraction, one sentence may contain two or more events, and these events may share the argument with different roles. For example, there are two events in S3, namely, the Die event and Attack event. If we use a traditional max-pooling layer and only keep the most impor- tant information to represent the sentence, we may obtain the information that depicts "a cameraman died" but miss the information about "American tank fired on the Palestine Hotel", which is impor- tant for predicting the Attack event and valuable for attaching cameraman to fired as an Target ar- gument. In our experiments, we found that such multiple-event sentences comprise 27.3% of our dataset, which is a phenomenon we cannot ignore.</p><p>In this paper, we propose a dynamic multi- pooling convolutional neural network (DMCNN) to address the problems stated above. To capture lexical-level clues and reduce human effort, we introduce a word-representation model <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">(Mikolov et al., 2013b)</ref>, which has been shown to be able to capture the meaningful semantic regularities of words ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Bengio et al., 2003;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Erhan et al., 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b18">Mikolov et al., 2013a</ref>). To capture sentence-level clues without using complicated NLP tools, and to reserve information more comprehensively, we devise a dynamic multi-pooling layer for CNN, which returns the maximum value in each part of the sentence according to event triggers and argu- ments. In summary, the contributions of this paper are as follows:</p><p>• We present a novel framework for event extraction, which can automatically induce lexical-level and sentence-level features from plain texts without complicated NLP prepro- cessing.</p><p>• We devise a dynamic multi-pooling convolu- tional neural network (DMCNN), which aims to capture more valuable information within a sentence for event extraction.</p><p>• We conduct experiments on a widely used ACE2005 event extraction dataset, and the experimental results show that our approach outperforms other state-of-the-art methods.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Event Extraction Task</head><p>In this paper, we focus on the event extraction task defined in Automatic Content Extraction 1 (ACE) evaluation, where an event is defined as a specific occurrence involving participants. First, we in- troduce some ACE terminology to understand this task more easily:</p><p>• Event mention: a phrase or sentence within which an event is described, including a trig- ger and arguments.</p><p>• Event trigger: the main word that most clearly expresses the occurrence of an event (An ACE event trigger is typically a verb or a noun).</p><p>• Event argument: an entity mention, tempo- ral expression or value (e.g. Job-Title) that is involved in an event (viz., participants).</p><p>• Argument role: the relationship between an argument to the event in which it participates.</p><p>Given an English text document, an event ex- traction system should predict event triggers with specific subtypes and their arguments for each sen- tence. The upper side of figure 1 depicts the event triggers and their arguments for S3 in Section 1. ACE defines 8 event types and 33 subtypes, such as Attack or Elect.</p><p>Although event extraction depends on name identification and entity mention co-reference, it is another difficult task in ACE evaluation and not the focus in the event extraction task. Thus, in this paper, we directly leverage the entity label pro- vided by the ACE, following most previous works <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Hong et al., 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Liao and Grishman, 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Ji and Grishman, 2008</ref>).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Methodology</head><p>In this paper, event extraction is formulated as a two-stage, multi-class classification via dynamic multi-pooling convolutional neural networks with the automatically learned features. The first stage is called trigger classification, in which we use a DMCNN to classify each word in a sentence to identify trigger words. If one sentence has trig- gers, the second stage is conducted, which applies a similar DMCNN to assign arguments to trig- gers and align the roles of the arguments. We call this argument classification. Because the second stage is more complicated, we first describe the methodology of argument classification in Section 3.1∼3.4 and then illustrate the difference between the DMCNNs that are used for trigger classifica- tion and those used for argument classification in Section 3.5. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 2</ref> describes the architecture of argu- ment classification, which primarily involves the following four components: (i) word-embedding learning, which reveals the embedding vectors of words in an unsupervised manner; (ii) lexical-level feature representation, which directly uses embed- ding vectors of words to capture lexical clues; (iii) sentence-level feature extraction, which proposes a DMCNN to learn the compositional semantic features of sentences; and (iv) argument classi- fier output, which calculates a confidence score for each argument role candidate.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Word Embedding Learning and Lexical-Level Feature Representation</head><p>Lexical-level features serve as important clues for event extraction <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Hong et al., 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Li et al., 2013)</ref>. Traditional lexical-level features primar- ily include lemma, synonyms and POS tag of the candidate words. The quality of such features depends strongly on the results of existing NLP tools and human ingenuity. Additionally, the tra- ditional features remain unsatisfactory for captur- ing the semantics of words, which are important in event extraction, as showed in S1 and S2. As Erhan et al. <ref type="formula">(2010)</ref> reported, word embeddings learned from a significant amount of unlabeled data are more powerful for capturing the mean- ingful semantic regularities of words. This paper uses unsupervised pre-trained word embedding as the source of base features. We select the word embeddings of candidate words (candidate trigger, candidate argument) and the context tokens (left and right tokens of the candidate words). Then, all of these word embeddings are concatenated into the lexical-level features vector L to represent the lexical-level features in argument classification.</p><p>In this work, we use the Skip-gram model to pre-train the word embedding. This model is the state-of-the-art model in many NLP tasks ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Baroni et al., 2014</ref>). The Skip-gram model trains the embeddings of words w 1 , w 2 ...w m by maximizing the average log probability,</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">1 m m t=1 −c≤j≤c,j =0 log p(w t+j |w t ) (1)</formula><p>where c is the size of the training window. Basi- cally, p(w t+j |w t ) is defined as,</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">p(w t+j |w t ) = exp(e T t+j e t ) m w=1 exp(e T w e t ) (2)</formula><p>where m is the vocabulary of the unlabeled text. e i is another embedding for e i , see Morin and Bengio (2005) for details. </p><formula xml:id="formula_2">. . . a d i e d w h e n a n A m e r i c a n t a n k o n . . . S e n t e n c e F e a t u r e I n p u t C o n v o l u t i o n a l D y n a m i c M u l t i - p o o l i n g F e a t u r e m a p 1 F e a t u r e m a p 2 F e a t u r e m a p 3 11 max(c ) 12 max(c ) 13 max(c ) E m b e d d i n g L e a r n i n g L e x i c a l L e v e l F e a t u r e R e p r e s e n t a t i o n C l a s s i f i e r O u t p u t C W F P F E F . . . . . . S e n t e n c e L e v e l F e a t u r e E x t r a c t i o n</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Extracting Sentence-Level Features Using a DMCNN</head><p>The CNN, with max-pooling layers, is a good choice to capture the semantics of long-distance words within a sentence <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Collobert et al., 2011</ref>). However, as noted in the section 1, traditional CNN is incapable of addressing the event extrac- tion problem. Because a sentence may contain more than one event, using only the most impor- tant information to represent a sentence, as in the traditional CNN, will miss valuable clues. To re- solve this problem, we propose a DMCNN to ex- tract the sentence-level features. The DMCNN uses a dynamic multi-pooling layer to obtain a maximum value for each part of a sentence, which is split by event triggers and event arguments. Thus, the DMCNN is expected to capture more valuable clues compared to traditional CNN meth- ods.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2.1">Input</head><p>This subsection illustrates the input needed for a DMCNN to extract sentence-level features. The semantic interactions between the predicted trig- ger words and argument candidates are crucial for argument classification. Therefore, we propose three types of input that the DMCNN uses to cap- ture these important clues:</p><p>• • Position feature (PF): It is necessary to spec- ify which words are the predicted trigger or candidate argument in the argument classi- fication. Thus, we proposed the PF, which is defined as the relative distance of the cur- rent word to the predicted trigger or candidate argument. For example, in S3, the relative distances of tank to the candidate argument cameraman is 5. To encode the position fea- ture, each distance value is also represented by an embedding vector. Similar to word em- bedding, Distance Values are randomly ini- tialized and optimized through back propaga- tion.</p><p>• Event-type feature (EF): The event type of a current trigger is valuable for argument clas- sification <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Ahn, 2006;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Hong et al., 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Liao and Grishman, 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Li et al., 2013</ref>), so we encode event type predicted in the trigger classification stage as an important clue for the DMCNN, as in the PF. </p><formula xml:id="formula_3">x 1:n = x 1 ⊕ x 2 ⊕ ... ⊕ x n (3)</formula><p>where ⊕ is the concatenation operator. Thus, combined word embedding, position embedding and event-type embedding transform an instance as a matrix X ∈ R n×d . Then, X is fed into the convolution part.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2.2">Convolution</head><p>The convolution layer aims to capture the compo- sitional semantics of a entire sentence and com- press these valuable semantics into feature maps. In general, let x i:i+j refer to the concatenation of words x i , x i+1 , ..., x i+j . A convolution operation involves a filter w ∈ R h×d , which is applied to a window of h words to produce a new feature. For example, a feature c i is generated from a window of words x i:i+h−1 by the following operator,</p><formula xml:id="formula_4">c i = f (w · x i:i+h−1 + b)<label>(4)</label></formula><p>where b ∈ R is a bias term and f is a non-linear function such as the hyperbolic tangent. This fil- ter is applied to each possible window of words in the sentence x 1:h , x 2:h+1 , ..., x n−h+1:n to produce a feature map c i where the index i ranges from 1 to n − h + 1.</p><p>We have described the process of how one fea- ture map is extracted from one filter. To capture different features, it usually use multiple filters in the convolution. Assuming that we use m filters W = w 1 , w 2 , ..., w m , the convolution operation can be expressed as:</p><formula xml:id="formula_5">c ji = f (w j · x i:i+h−1 + b j )<label>(5)</label></formula><p>where j ranges from 1 to m. The convolution result is a matrix C ∈ R m×(n−h+1) .</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2.3">Dynamic Multi-Pooling</head><p>To extract the most important features (max value) within each feature map, traditional CNNs ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Collobert et al., 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Kim, 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Zeng et al., 2014</ref>) take one feature map as a pool and only get one max value for each feature map. However, sin- gle max-pooling is not sufficient for event extrac- tion. Because in the task of this paper, one sen- tence may contain two or more events, and one argument candidate may play a different role with a different trigger. To make an accurate predic- tion, it is necessary to capture the most valuable information with regard to the change of the can- didate words. Thus, we split each feature map into three parts according to the candidate argu- ment and predicted trigger in the argument clas- sification stage. Instead of using one max value for an entire feature map to represent the sen- tence, we keep the max value of each split part and call it dynamic multi-pooling. Compared to tra- ditional max-pooling, dynamic multi-pooling can reserve more valuable information without miss- ing the max-pooling value. As shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 2</ref>, the feature map output c j is divided into three sections c j1 , c j2 , c j3 by "cam- eraman" and "fired". The dynamic multi-pooling can be expressed as formula 6,where 1 ≤ j ≤ m and 1 ≤ i ≤ 3.</p><formula xml:id="formula_6">p ji = max(c ji )<label>(6)</label></formula><p>Through the dynamic multi-pooling layer, we obtain the p ji for each feature map. Then, we concatenate all p ji to form a vector P ∈ R 3m , which can be considered as higher-level features (sentence-level features).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3">Output</head><p>The automatically learned lexical and sentence- level features mentioned above are concatenated into a single vector F = <ref type="bibr">[L, P ]</ref>. To compute the confidence of each argument role, the feature vec- tor F ∈ R 3m+d l , where m is the number of the feature map and d l is the dimension of the lexical- level features, is fed into a classifier.</p><formula xml:id="formula_7">O = W s F + b s<label>(7)</label></formula><p>W s ∈ R n 1 ×(3m+d l ) is the transformation ma- trix and O ∈ R n 1 is the final output of the net- work, where n 1 is equal to the number of the ar- gument role including the "None role" label for the candidate argument which don't play any role in the event. For regularization, we also employ dropout( <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Hinton et al., 2012</ref>) on the penultimate layer, which can prevent the co-adaptation of hid- den units by randomly dropping out a proportion p of the hidden units during forward and backprop- agation.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.4">Training</head><p>We define all of the parameters for the stage of argument classification to be trained as θ = (E, P F 1 , P F 2 , EF, W, b, W S , b s ). Specifically, E is the word embedding, P F 1 and P F 2 are the posi- tion embedding, EF is the embedding of the event type, W and b are the parameter of the filter, W s and b s are all of the parameters of the output layer.</p><p>Given an input example s, the network with pa- rameter θ outputs the vector O, where the i-th component O i contains the score for argument role i. To obtain the conditional probability p(i|x, θ), we apply a softmax operation over all argument role types:</p><formula xml:id="formula_8">p(i|x, θ) = e o i n 1 k=1 e o k<label>(8)</label></formula><p>Given all of our (suppose T) training examples (x i ; y i ), we can then define the objective function as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_9">J (θ) = T i=1 log p(y (i) |x (i) , θ)<label>(9)</label></formula><p>To compute the network parameter θ, we max- imize the log likelihood J (θ) through stochastic gradient descent over shuffled mini-batches with the Adadelta (Zeiler, 2012) update rule.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.5">Model for Trigger Classification</head><p>In the above sections, we presented our model and features for argument classification. The method proposed above is also suitable for trigger classi- fication, but the task only need to find triggers in the sentence, which is less complicated than argu- ment classification. Thus we can used a simplified version of DMCNN.</p><p>In the trigger classification, we only use the can- didate trigger and its left and right tokens in the lexical-level feature representation. In the feature representation of the sentence level, we use the same CWF as does in argument classification, but we only use the position of the candidate trigger to embed the position feature. Furthermore, instead of splitting the sentence into three parts, the sen- tence is split into two parts by a candidate trigger. Except for the above change in the features and model, we classify a trigger as the classification of an argument. Both stages form the framework of the event extraction.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Experiments</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">Dataset and Evaluation Metric</head><p>We utilized the ACE 2005 corpus as our dataset. For comparison, as the same as <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Li et al. (2013)</ref>, <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Hong et al. (2011)</ref> and <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Liao and Grishman (2010)</ref>, we used the same test set with 40 newswire articles and the same development set with 30 other docu- ments randomly selected from different genres and the rest 529 documents are used for training. Sim- ilar to previous work ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Li et al., 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Hong et al., 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Liao and Grishman, 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Ji and Grishman, 2008)</ref>, we use the following criteria to judge the correctness of each predicted event mention:</p><p>• A trigger is correct if its event subtype and offsets match those of a reference trigger.</p><p>• An argument is correctly identified if its event subtype and offsets match those of any of the reference argument mentions.</p><p>• An argument is correctly classified if its event subtype, offsets and argument role match those of any of the reference argument men- tions.</p><p>Finally we use Precision (P ), Recall (R) and F measure (F 1 ) as the evaluation metrics.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">Our Method vs. State-of-the-art Methods</head><p>We select the following state-of-the-art methods for comparison. 1) Li's baseline is the feature-based system pro- posed by <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Li et al. (2013)</ref>, which only employs human-designed lexical features, basic features and syntactic features.</p><p>2) Liao's cross-event is the method proposed by <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Liao and Grishman (2010)</ref>, which uses document- level information to improve the performance of ACE event extraction.</p><p>3) Hong's cross-entity is the method proposed by <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Hong et al. (2011)</ref>, which extracts event by using cross-entity inference. To the best of our knowl- edge, it is the best-reported feature-based system in the literature based on gold standards argument candidates. 4) Li's structure is the method proposed by <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Li et al. (2013)</ref>, which extracts events based on struc- ture prediction. It is the best-reported structure- based system. Following <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Li et al. (2013)</ref>, we tuned the model parameters on the development through grid search. Moreover, in different stages of event extraction, we adopted different parameters in the DMCNN. Specifically, in the trigger classification, we set the window size as 3, the number of the feature map as 200, the batch size as 170 and the dimension of the PF as 5. In the argument classi- fication, we set the window size as 3, the number of the feature map as 300, the batch size as 20 and the dimension of the PF and EF as 5. Stochastic gradient descent over shuffled mini-batches with the Adadelta update rule <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">(Zeiler, 2012</ref>) is used for training and testing processes. It mainly contains two parameters p and ε. We set p = 0.95 and ε = 1e −6 . For the dropout operation, we set the</p><formula xml:id="formula_10">Methods Trigger Identification(%) Trigger Identification + Classification(%) Argument Identification(%) Argument Role(%) P R F P R F P R F P R F Li's baseline</formula><p>76.2 60.5 67.4 74.5 59.1 65.9 74.1 37.4 49.7 65.4 33.1 43.9 Liao's cross-event N/A 68.7 68.9 68.8 50.9 49.7 50.3 45.1 44.1 44.6 Hong's cross-entity N/A 72.9 64.3 68.3 53.4 52.9 53.1 51.6 45.5 48.3 Li's structure 76.9 65.0 70.4 73.7 62.3 67.5 69.8 47.9 56.8 64.7 44.4 52.7 DMCNN model 80.4 67.7 73.5 75.6 63.6 69.1 68.8 51.9 59.1 62.2 46.9 53.5 <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>: Overall performance on blind test data rate = 0.5. We train the word embedding using the Skip-gram algorithm 2 on the NYT corpus 3 . <ref type="table">Table 1</ref> shows the overall performance on the blind test dataset. From the results, we can see that the DMCNN model we proposed with the automatically learned features achieves the best performance among all of the compared meth- ods. DMCNN can improve the best F 1 ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Li et al., 2013</ref>) in the state-of-the-arts for trigger clas- sification by 1.6% and argument role classifica- tion by 0.8%. This demonstrates the effective- ness of the proposed method. Moreover, a com- parison of Liao's cross-event with Li's baseline il- lustrates that Liao's cross-event achieves a better performance. We can also make the same obser- vation when comparing Hong's cross-entity with Liao's cross-event and comparing Li's structure with Hong's cross-entity. It proves that richer feature sets lead to better performance when us- ing traditional human-designed features. How- ever, our method could obtain further better re- sults on the condition of only using automatically learned features from original words. Specifically, compared to Hong's cross-entity, it gains 0.8% im- provement on trigger classification F 1 and 5.2% improvement on argument classification F 1 . We believe the reason is that the features we automati- cally learned can capture more meaningful seman- tic regularities of words. Remarkably, compared to Li's structure, our approach with sentence and lexical features achieves comparable performance even though we do not use complicated NLP tools.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3">Effect of The DMCNN on Extracting Sentence-Level Features</head><p>In this subsection, we prove the effectiveness of the proposed DMCNN for sentence-level feature extraction. We specifically select two methods as baselines for comparison with our DMCNN: Em- beddings+T and CNN. Embeddings+T uses word embeddings as lexical-level features and tradi- tional sentence-level features based on human de- sign ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Li et al., 2013)</ref>. A CNN is similar to a DMCNN, except that it uses a standard convolu- tional neural network with max-pooling to capture sentence-level features. By contrast, a DMCNN uses the dynamic multi-pooling layer in the net- work instead of the max-pooling layer in a CNN. Moreover, to prove that a DMCNN could capture more precise sentence-level features, especially for those sentences with multiple events, we divide the testing data into two parts according the event number in a sentence (single event and multiple events) and perform evaluations separately. <ref type="table">Table  2</ref> shows the proportion of sentences with multiple events or a single event and the proportion of argu- ments that attend one event or more events within one sentence in our dataset. <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">Table 3</ref> shows the re- sults.  <ref type="table">Table 2</ref>: The proportion of multiple events within one sentence. 1/1 means that one sentence only has one trigger or one argument plays a role in one sentence; otherwise, 1/N is used. <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">Table 3</ref> illustrates that the methods based on convolutional neural networks (CNN and DM- CNN) outperform Embeddings+T. It proves that convolutional neural networks could be more ef- fective than traditional human-design strategies for sentence-level feature extraction. In table 3, for all sentences, our method achieves improvements of approximately 2.8% and 4.6% over the CNN. The results prove the effectiveness of the dynamic multi-pooling layer. Interestingly, the DMCNN yields a 7.8% improvement for trigger classifica- tion on the sentences with multiple events. This improvement is larger than in sentences with a sin- gle event. Similar observations can be made for the argument classification results. This demon- strates that the proposed DMCNN can effectively capture more valuable clues than the CNN with max-pooling, especially when one sentence con- tains more than one event.  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.4">Effect of Word Embedding on Extracting Lexical-Level Features</head><p>This subsection studies the effectiveness of our word embedding for lexical features. For compar- ison purposes, we select the baseline described by <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Li et al. (2013)</ref> as the traditional method, which uses traditional lexical features, such as n-grams, POS tags and some entity information. In con- trast, we only use word embedding as our lexical feature. Moreover, to prove that word embedding could capture more valuable semantics, especially for those words in the test data that never appear to be the same event type or argument role in the training data, we divide the triggers and arguments in the testing data into two parts (1: appearing in testing data only, or 2: appearing in both testing and training data with the same event type or argu- ment role) and perform evaluations separately. For triggers, 34.9% of the trigger words in the test data never appear to be the same event type in the train- ing data. This proportion is 83.1% for arguments. The experimental results are shown in <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">Table 4</ref>. <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">Table 4</ref> illustrates that for all situations, our method makes significant improvements com- pared with the traditional lexical features in the classification of both the trigger and argument. For situation B, the lexical-level features extracted from word embedding yield a 18.8% improvement for trigger classification and an 8.5% improvement for argument classification. This occurs because the baseline only uses discrete features, so they suffer from data sparsity and could not adequately handle a situation in which a trigger or argument does not appear in the training data.   <ref type="table">Table 5</ref>: Comparison of the trigger-classification score and argument-classification score obtained by lexical-level features, sentence-level features and a combination of both</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Related Work</head><p>Event extraction is one of important topics in NLP. Many approaches have been explored for event ex- traction. Nearly all of the ACE event extraction use supervised paradigm. We further divide super- vised approaches into feature-based methods and structure-based methods. In feature-based methods, a diverse set of strate- gies has been exploited to convert classification clues (such as sequences and parse trees) into feature vectors. Ahn (2006) uses the lexical features(e.g., full word, pos tag), syntactic fea- tures (e.g., dependency features) and external- knowledge features(WordNet) to extract the event. Inspired by the hypothesis of "One Sense Per Dis-course" <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">(Yarowsky, 1995)</ref>, <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Ji and Grishman (2008)</ref> combined global evidence from related documents with local decisions for the event extraction. To capture more clues from the texts, <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Gupta and Ji (2009)</ref>, <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Liao and Grishman (2010)</ref> and <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Hong et al. (2011)</ref> proposed the cross-event and cross-entity inference for the ACE event task. Although these approaches achieve high performance, feature- based methods suffer from the problem of select- ing a suitable feature set when converting the clas- sification clues into feature vectors.</p><p>In structure-based methods, researchers treat event extraction as the task of predicting the struc- ture of the event in a sentence. <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">McClosky et al. (2011)</ref> casted the problem of biomedical event ex- traction as a dependency parsing problem. <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Li et al. (2013)</ref> presented a joint framework for ACE event extraction based on structured perceptron with beam search. To use more information from the sentence, <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Li et al. (2014)</ref> proposed to extract entity mentions, relations and events in ACE task based on the unified structure. These methods yield relatively high performance. However, the performance of these methods depend strongly on the quality of the designed features and endure the errors in the existing NLP tools.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Conclusion</head><p>This paper proposes a novel event extraction method, which can automatically extract lexical- level and sentence-level features from plain texts without complicated NLP preprocessing. A word- representation model is introduced to capture lex- ical semantic clues and a dynamic multi-pooling convolutional neural network (DMCNN) is de- vised to encode sentence semantic clues. The ex- perimental results prove the effectiveness of the proposed method.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 1: Event mentions and syntactic parser results of S3. The upper side shows two event mentions that share three arguments: the Die event mention, triggered by "died", and the Attack event mention, triggered by "fired". The lower side shows the collapsed dependency results.</figDesc><graphic url="image-1.png" coords="2,113.44,61.38,381.91,109.62" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2: The architecture for the stage of argument classification in the event extraction. It illustrates the processing of one instance with the predict trigger fired and the candidate argument cameraman.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Context-word feature (CWF): Similar to Kalchbrenner et al. (2014) and Collobert et al. (2011), we take all the words of the whole sentence as the context. CWF is the vector of each word token transformed by looking up word embeddings.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>Figure 2 assumes</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2 assumes that word embedding has size d w = 4, position embedding has size d p = 1 and event-type embedding has size d e = 1. Let x i ∈ R d be the d-dimensional vector representation corresponding to the i-th word in the sentence, where d = d w + d p * 2 + d e. A sentence of length n is represented as follows:</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" validated="false"><head>Table 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Comparison of the event extraction scores 
obtained for the Traditional, CNN and DMCNN 
models 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4" validated="false"><head>Table 4 :</head><label>4</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Comparison of the results for the tradi-
tional lexical feature and our lexical feature. A de-
notes the triggers or arguments appearing in both 
training and test datasets, and B indicates all other 
cases. 

4.5 Lexical features vs. Sentence Features 

To compare the effectiveness of different levels of 
features, we extract events by using lexical fea-
tures and sentence features separately. The results 
obtained using the DMCNN are shown in table 
5. Interestingly, in the trigger-classification stage, 
the lexical features play an effective role, whereas 
the sentence features play a more important role in 
the argument-classification stage. The best results 
are achieved when we combine lexical-level and 
sentence-level features. This observation demon-
strates that both of the two-level features are im-
portant for event extraction. 

Feature 
Trigger Argument 
F1 
F1 
Lexical 
64.9 
40.2 
Sentence 
63.8 
50.7 
Combine 
69.1 
53.5 

</table></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> http://projects.ldc.upenn.edu/ace/</note>

			<note place="foot" n="2"> https://code.google.com/p/word2vec/ 3 https://catalog.ldc.upenn.edu/LDC2008T19</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>This work was supported by the National Basic Research Program of China (No. 2014CB340503) and the National Natural Science Foundation of China <ref type="bibr">(No. 61272332 and No. 61202329)</ref> </p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The stages of event extraction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Ahn</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of ACL</title>
		<meeting>ACL</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="8" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dont count, predict! a systematic comparison of context-counting vs. context-predicting semantic vectors</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marco</forename><surname>Baroni</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Georgiana</forename><surname>Dinu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Germán</forename><surname>Kruszewski</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of ACL</title>
		<meeting>ACL</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="238" to="247" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A neural probabilistic language model</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yoshua</forename><surname>Bengio</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Réjean</forename><surname>Ducharme</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Pascal</forename><surname>Vincent</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christian</forename><surname>Jauvin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The Journal of Machine Learning Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1137" to="1155" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Joint modeling for chinese event extraction with rich linguistic features</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chen</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Incent</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of COLING</title>
		<meeting>COLING</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="529" to="544" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Natural language processing (almost) from scratch</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ronan</forename><surname>Collobert</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jason</forename><surname>Weston</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Léon</forename><surname>Bottou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Karlen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Koray</forename><surname>Kavukcuoglu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Pavel</forename><surname>Kuksa</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The Journal of Machine Learning Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2493" to="2537" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Why does unsupervised pre-training help deep learning?</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yoshua</forename><surname>Dumitru Erhan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Aaron</forename><surname>Bengio</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Pierre-Antoine</forename><surname>Courville</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Pascal</forename><surname>Manzagol</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Samy</forename><surname>Vincent</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Bengio</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The Journal of Machine Learning Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="625" to="660" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Predicting unknown time arguments based on cross-event propagation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Prashant</forename><surname>Gupta</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Heng</forename><surname>Ji</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of ACL-IJCNLP</title>
		<meeting>ACL-IJCNLP</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="369" to="372" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Improving neural networks by preventing coadaptation of feature detectors</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nitish</forename><surname>Geoffrey E Hinton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alex</forename><surname>Srivastava</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ilya</forename><surname>Krizhevsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Sutskever</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Salakhutdinov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:1207.0580</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
<note type="report_type">arXiv preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Using cross-entity inference to improve event extraction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yu</forename><surname>Hong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jianfeng</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bin</forename><surname>Ma</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jianmin</forename><surname>Yao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Guodong</forename><surname>Zhou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Qiaoming</forename><surname>Zhu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of ACL-HLT</title>
		<meeting>ACL-HLT</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1127" to="1136" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Refining event extraction through cross-document inference</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Heng</forename><surname>Ji</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ralph</forename><surname>Grishman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of ACL</title>
		<meeting>ACL</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="254" to="262" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nal</forename><surname>Kalchbrenner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Phil</forename><surname>Blunsom</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:1306.3584</idno>
		<title level="m">Recurrent convolutional neural networks for discourse compositionality</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
<note type="report_type">arXiv preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">A convolutional neural network for modelling sentences</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nal</forename><surname>Kalchbrenner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Edward</forename><surname>Grefenstette</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Phil</forename><surname>Blunsom</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:1404.2188</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
<note type="report_type">arXiv preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Convolutional neural networks for sentence classification</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yoon</forename><surname>Kim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:1408.5882</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
<note type="report_type">arXiv preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Recurrent convolutional neural networks for text classification</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Siwei</forename><surname>Lai</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Liheng</forename><surname>Xu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kang</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jun</forename><surname>Zhao</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of AAAI</title>
		<meeting>AAAI</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Joint event extraction via structured prediction with global features</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Qi</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ji</forename><surname>Heng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Liang</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of ACL</title>
		<meeting>ACL</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="73" to="82" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Constructing information networks using one single model</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Qi</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Heng</forename><surname>Ji</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yu</forename><surname>Hong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sujian</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of EMNLP</title>
		<meeting>EMNLP</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1846" to="1851" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Using document level cross-event inference to improve event extraction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Shasha</forename><surname>Liao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ralph</forename><surname>Grishman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of ACL</title>
		<meeting>ACL</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="789" to="797" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Event extraction as dependency parsing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Mcclosky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mihai</forename><surname>Surdeanu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christopher D</forename><surname>Manning</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of ACL-HLT</title>
		<meeting>ACL-HLT</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1626" to="1635" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Efficient estimation of word representations in vector space</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tomas</forename><surname>Mikolov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kai</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Greg</forename><surname>Corrado</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jeffrey</forename><surname>Dean</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:1301.3781</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
<note type="report_type">arXiv preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Distributed representations of words and phrases and their compositionality</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tomas</forename><surname>Mikolov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ilya</forename><surname>Sutskever</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kai</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Greg</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Corrado</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jeff</forename><surname>Dean</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of NIPS</title>
		<meeting>NIPS</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3111" to="3119" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Hierarchical probabilistic neural network language model</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Frederic</forename><surname>Morin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yoshua</forename><surname>Bengio</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of AISTATS</title>
		<meeting>AISTATS</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="246" to="252" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Word representations: a simple and general method for semi-supervised learning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Joseph</forename><surname>Turian</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lev</forename><surname>Ratinov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yoshua</forename><surname>Bengio</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of ACL</title>
		<meeting>ACL</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="384" to="394" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Unsupervised word sense disambiguation rivaling supervised methods</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Yarowsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of ACL</title>
		<meeting>ACL</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="189" to="196" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Adadelta: An adaptive learning rate method</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Matthew D Zeiler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:1212.5701</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
<note type="report_type">arXiv preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Relation classification via convolutional deep neural network</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Daojian</forename><surname>Zeng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kang</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Siwei</forename><surname>Lai</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Guangyou</forename><surname>Zhou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jun</forename><surname>Zhao</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of COLING</title>
		<meeting>COLING</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2335" to="2344" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
