<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T10:30+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">A Computational Approach to Automatic Prediction of Drunk-Texting</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
				<availability status="unknown"><p>Copyright Association for Computational Linguistics</p>
				</availability>
				<date>July 26-31, 2015. 2015</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Aditya</forename><surname>Joshi</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">IIT Bombay</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="IN">India</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">Monash University</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="AU">Australia</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="institution">IITB-Monash Research Academy</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="IN">India</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Abhijit</forename><surname>Mishra</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">IIT Bombay</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="IN">India</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Balamurali</forename><surname>Ar</surname></persName>
							<email>balamurali.ar@lif.univ-mrs.fr,mark.carman@monash.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff3">
								<orgName type="institution">Aix-Marseille University</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="FR">France</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Pushpak</forename><surname>Bhattacharyya</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">IIT Bombay</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="IN">India</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mark</forename><forename type="middle">James</forename><surname>Carman</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">Monash University</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="AU">Australia</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">A Computational Approach to Automatic Prediction of Drunk-Texting</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 53rd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics and the 7th International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing</title>
						<meeting>the 53rd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics and the 7th International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing <address><addrLine>Beijing, China</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="604" to="608"/>
							<date type="published">July 26-31, 2015. 2015</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Alcohol abuse may lead to unsociable behavior such as crime, drunk driving, or privacy leaks. We introduce automatic drunk-texting prediction as the task of identifying whether a text was written when under the influence of alcohol. We experiment with tweets labeled using hashtags as distant supervision. Our clas-sifiers use a set of N-gram and stylistic features to detect drunk tweets. Our observations present the first quantitative evidence that text contains signals that can be exploited to detect drunk-texting.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>The ubiquity of communication devices has made social media highly accessible. The content on these media reflects a user's day-to-day activities. This includes content created under the influence of alcohol. In popular culture, this has been re- ferred to as 'drunk-texting' <ref type="bibr">1</ref> . In this paper, we in- troduce automatic 'drunk-texting prediction' as a computational task. Given a tweet, the goal is to automatically identify if it was written by a drunk user. We refer to tweets written under the influ- ence of alcohol as 'drunk tweets', and the opposite as 'sober tweets'.</p><p>A key challenge is to obtain an annotated dataset. We use hashtag-based supervision so that the authors of the tweets mention if they were drunk at the time of posting a tweet. We create three datasets by using different strategies that are related to the use of hashtags. We then present SVM-based classifiers that use N-gram and stylis- tic features such as capitalisation, spelling errors, etc. Through our experiments, we make subtle points related to: (a) the performance of our fea- tures, (b) how our approach compares against 1 Source: http://www.urbandictionary.com human ability to detect drunk-texting, (c) most discriminative stylistic features, and (d) an error analysis that points to future work. To the best of our knowledge, this is a first study that shows the feasibility of text-based analysis for drunk-texting prediction.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Motivation</head><p>Past studies show the relation between alcohol abuse and unsociable behaviour such as aggres- sion <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Bushman and Cooper, 1990)</ref>, crime <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Carpenter, 2007)</ref>, suicide attempts ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Merrill et al., 1992)</ref>, drunk driving ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Loomis and West, 1958)</ref>, and risky sexual behaviour ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Bryan et al., 2005</ref>). <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Merrill et al. (1992)</ref> state that "those responsible for assess- ing cases of attempted suicide should be adept at detecting alcohol misuse". Thus, a drunk-texting prediction system can be used to identify individ- uals susceptible to these behaviours, or for inves- tigative purposes after an incident.</p><p>Drunk-texting may also cause regret. Mail Goggles 2 prompts a user to solve math questions before sending an email on weekend evenings. Some Android applications 3 avoid drunk-texting by blocking outgoing texts at the click of a button. However, to the best of our knowledge, these tools require a user command to begin blocking. An on- going text-based analysis will be more helpful, es- pecially since it offers a more natural setting by monitoring stream of social media text and not ex- plicitly seeking user input. Thus, automatic drunk- texting prediction will improve systems aimed to avoid regrettable drunk-texting. To the best of our knowledge, ours is the first study that does a quantitative analysis, in terms of prediction of the drunk state by using textual clues.</p><p>Several studies have studied linguistic traits associated with emotion expression and mental health issues, suicidal nature, criminal status, etc. <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Pennebaker, 1993;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Pennebaker, 1997)</ref>. NLP tech- niques have been used in the past to address so- cial safety and mental health issues <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Resnik et al., 2013</ref>).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Definition and Challenges</head><p>Drunk-texting prediction is the task of classifying a text as drunk or sober. For example, a tweet 'Feeling buzzed. Can't remember how the evening went' must be predicted as 'drunk', whereas, 'Re- turned from work late today, the traffic was bad' must be predicted as 'sober'. The challenges are:</p><p>1. More than topic categorisation: Drunk- texting prediction is similar to topic cate- gorisation (that is, classification of docu- ments into a set of categories such as 'news', 'sports', etc.). However, <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Borrill et al. (1987)</ref> show that alcohol abusers have more pro- nounced emotions, specifically, anger. In this respect, drunk-texting prediction lies at the confluence of topic categorisation and emo- tion classification.</p><p>2. Identification of labeled examples: It is dif- ficult to obtain a set of sober tweets. The ideal label can be possibly given only by the author. For example, whether a tweet such as 'I am feeling lonely tonight' is a drunk tweet is ambiguous. This is similar to sar- casm expressed as an exaggeration (for ex- ample, 'This is the best film ever!), where the context beyond the text needs to be consid- ered.</p><p>3. Precision/Recall trade-off: The goal that a drunk-texting prediction system must chase depends on the application. An application that identifies potential crimes must work with high precision, since the target popula- tion to be monitored will be large. On the other hand, when being used to avoid regret- table drunk-texting, a prediction system must produce high recall in order to ensure that a drunk message does not pass through.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Dataset Creation</head><p>We use hashtag-based supervision to create our datasets, similar to tasks like emotion classifica- tion (Purver and Battersby, 2012). The tweets are downloaded using Twitter API (https://dev.</p><p>twitter.com/). We remove non-Unicode characters, and eliminate tweets that contain hy- perlinks <ref type="bibr">4</ref> and also tweets that are shorter than 6 words in length. Finally, hashtags used to indi- cate drunk or sober tweets are removed so that they provide labels, but do not act as features. The dataset is available on request. As a result, we cre- ate three datasets, each using a different strategy for sober tweets, as follows:</p><p>Figure 1: Word cloud for drunk tweets</p><p>1. Dataset 1 (2435 drunk, 762 sober): We col- lect tweets that are marked as drunk and sober, using hashtags. Tweets containing hashtags #drunk, #drank and #imdrunk are considered to be drunk tweets, while those with #notdrunk, #imnotdrunk and #sober are considered to be sober tweets.</p><p>2. Dataset 2 (2435 drunk, 5644 sober): The drunk tweets are downloaded using drunk hashtags, as above. The list of users who cre- ated these tweets is extracted. For the nega- tive class, we download tweets by these users, which do not contain the hashtags that corre- spond to drunk tweets.</p><p>3. Dataset H (193 drunk, 317 sober): A sepa- rate dataset is created where drunk tweets are downloaded using drunk hashtags, as above.</p><p>The set of sober tweets is collected using both the approaches above. The resultant is the held-out test set Dataset-H that contains no tweets in common with Datasets 1 and 2.</p><p>The drunk tweets for Datasets 1 and 2 are the same. <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref> shows a word-cloud for these drunk tweets (with stop words and forms of the word 'drunk' removed), created using </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>N-gram Features Unigram &amp; Bigram (Presence) Boolean features indicating unigrams and bigrams Unigram &amp; Bigram (Count) Real-valued features indicating unigrams and bigrams Stylistic Features</head><note type="other">LDA unigrams (Presence/Count) Boolean &amp; real-valued features indicating unigrams from LDA POS Ratio Ratios of nouns, adjectives, adverbs in the tweet #Named Entity Mentions Number of named entity mentions #Discourse Connectors Number of discourse connectors Spelling errors Boolean feature indicating presence of spelling mistakes Repeated characters Boolean feature indicating whether a character is repeated three times consecutively Capitalisation Number of capital letters in the tweet Length Number of words Emoticon (Presence/Count) Boolean &amp; real-valued features indicating unigrams Sentiment Ratio</note><p>Positive and negative word ratios <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>: Our Feature Set for Drunk-texting Prediction</p><p>WordItOut <ref type="bibr">5</ref> . The size of a word indicates its fre- quency. In addition to topical words such as 'bar', 'bottle' and 'wine', the word-cloud shows senti- ment words such as 'love' or 'damn', along with profane words. Heuristics other than these hashtags could have been used for dataset creation. For example, timestamps were a good option to account for time at which a tweet was posted. However, this could not be used because user's local times was not available, since very few users had geolocation en- abled.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Feature Design</head><p>The complete set of features is shown in <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>. There are two sets of features: (a) N-gram fea- tures, and (b) Stylistic features. We use unigrams and bigrams as N-gram features-considering both presence and count. <ref type="table">Table 1</ref> shows the complete set of stylistic fea- tures of our prediction system. POS ratios are a set of features that record the proportion of each POS tag in the dataset (for example, the proportion of nouns/adjectives, etc.). The POS tags and named entity mentions are obtained from NLTK <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Bird, 2006</ref>). Discourse connectors are identified based on a manually created list. Spelling errors are identified using a spell checker by <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Aby (2014)</ref>. The repeated characters feature captures a situ- ation in which a word contains a letter that is repeated three or more times, as in the case of <ref type="bibr">5</ref> www.worditout.com happpy. Since drunk-texting is often associated with emotional expression, we also incorporate a set of sentiment-based features. These features in- clude: count/presence of emoticons and sentiment ratio. Sentiment ratio is the proportion of posi- tive and negative words in the tweet. To deter- mine positive and negative words, we use the sen- timent lexicon in <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Wilson et al. (2005)</ref>. To identify a more refined set of words that correspond to the two classes, we also estimated 20 topics for the dataset by estimating an LDA model ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Blei et al., 2003)</ref>. We then consider top 10 words per topic, for both classes. This results in 400 LDA-specific unigrams that are then used as features.  Using the two sets of features, we train SVM clas- sifiers (Chang and Lin, 2011) <ref type="bibr">6</ref> . We show the five-fold cross-validation performance of our fea- tures on Datasets 1 and 2, in Section 6.1, and on Dataset H in Section 6.2. Section 6.3 presents an error analysis. Accuracy, positive/negative preci- sion and positive/negative recall are shown as A, PP/NP and PR/NR respectively. 'Drunk' forms the positive class, while 'Sober' forms the nega- tive class.   <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Table 2</ref> shows the performance for five-fold cross- validation for Datasets 1 and 2. In case of Dataset 1, we observe that N-gram features achieve an ac- curacy of 85.5%. We see that our stylistic features alone exhibit degraded performance, with an ac- curacy of 75.6%, in the case of Dataset 1. <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">Ta- ble 3</ref> shows top stylistic features, when trained on the two datasets. Spelling errors, POS ratios for nouns (POS NOUN) <ref type="bibr">7</ref> , length and sentiment ratios appear in both lists, in addition to LDA- based unigrams. However, negative recall reduces to a mere 3.2%. This degradation implies that our features capture a subset of drunk tweets and that there are properties of drunk tweets that may be more subtle. When both N-gram and stylis- tic features are used, there is negligible improve- ment. The accuracy for Dataset 2 increases from 77.9% to 78.1%. Precision/Recall metrics do not change significantly either. The best accuracy of our classifier is 78.1% for all features, and 75.6% for stylistic features. This shows that text-based clues can indeed be used for drunk-texting predic- tion.   Using held-out dataset H, we evaluate how our system performs in comparison to humans. Three annotators, A1-A3, mark each tweet in the Dataset H as drunk or sober. <ref type="table" target="#tab_5">Table 4</ref> shows a moderate agreement between our annotators (for example, it is 0.42 for A1 and A2). <ref type="table" target="#tab_6">Table 5</ref> compares our classifier with humans. Our human annotators per- form the task with an average accuracy of 68.8%, while our classifier (with all features) trained on Dataset 2 reaches 64%. The classifier trained on Dataset 2 is better than which is trained on Dataset 1.</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">A (%) NP (%) PP (%) NR (%) PR (%) Dataset 1 N-</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>A1</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.3">Error Analysis</head><p>Some categories of errors that occur are:</p><p>1. Incorrect hashtag supervision: The tweet 'Can't believe I lost my bag last night, lit- erally had everything in! Thanks god the bar man found it' was marked with'#Drunk'. However, this tweet is not likely to be a drunk tweet, but describes a drunk episode in retro- spective. Our classifier predicts it as sober.</p><p>2. Seemingly sober tweets: Human annotators as well as our classifier could not identify whether 'Will you take her on a date? But really she does like you' was drunk, although the author of the tweet had marked it so. This example also highlights the difficulty of drunk-texting prediction.</p><p>3. Pragmatic difficulty: The tweet 'National dress of Ireland is one's one vomit.. my fam- ily is lovely' was correctly identified by our human annotators as a drunk tweet. This tweet contains an element of humour and topic change, but our classifier could not cap- ture it.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7">Conclusion &amp; Future Work</head><p>In this paper, we introduce automatic drunk- texting prediction as the task of predicting a tweet as drunk or sober. First, we justify the need for drunk-texting prediction as means of identifying risky social behavior arising out of alcohol abuse, and the need to build tools that avoid privacy leaks due to drunk-texting. We then highlight the chal- lenges of drunk-texting prediction: one of the challenges is selection of negative examples (sober tweets). Using hashtag-based supervision, we cre- ate three datasets annotated with drunk or sober labels. We then present SVM-based classifiers which use two sets of features: N-gram and stylis- tic features. Our drunk prediction system obtains a best accuracy of 78.1%. We observe that our stylistic features add negligible value to N-gram features. We use our heldout dataset to compare how our system performs against human annota- tors. While human annotators achieve an accuracy of 68.8%, our system reaches reasonably close and performs with a best accuracy of 64%. Our analysis of the task and experimental find- ings make a case for drunk-texting prediction as a useful and feasible NLP application.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" validated="false"><head>Table 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Performance of our features on Datasets 
1 and 2 

606 </table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3" validated="false"><head>Table 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Top stylistic features for Datasets 1 and 2 
obtained using Chi-squared test-based ranking 

6.1 Performance for Datasets 1 and 2 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_5" validated="false"><head>Table 4 :</head><label>4</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Cohen's Kappa for three annotators (A1-
A3) 

A 
(%) 
NP 
(%) 
PP 
(%) 
NR 
(%) 
PR 
(%) 
Annotators 
68.8 71.7 61.7 83.9 43.5 
Training 
Dataset 
Our classifiers 

Dataset 1 
47.3 70 
40 
26 
81 
Dataset 2 
64 
70 
53 
72 
50 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_6" validated="false"><head>Table 5 :</head><label>5</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Performance of human evaluators and our 
classifiers (trained on all features), for Dataset-H 
as the test set 

6.2 Performance for Held-out Dataset H 

</table></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="2"> http://gmailblog.blogspot.in/2008/10/new-in-labs-stopsending-mail-you-later.html 3 https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.oopsapp</note>

			<note place="foot" n="4"> This is a rigid criterion, but we observe that tweets with hyperlinks are likely to be promotional in nature.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="6"> We also repeated all experiments for Na¨ıveNa¨ıve Bayes. They do not perform as well as SVM, and have poor recall. 7 POS ratios for nouns, adjectives and adverbs were nearly similar in drunk and sober tweets-with the maximum difference being 0.03%</note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Nltk: the natural language toolkit</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Aby</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the COLING/ACL on Interactive presentation sessions</title>
		<meeting>the COLING/ACL on Interactive presentation sessions</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="69" to="72" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Aby word processing website</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>David</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Blei</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Andrew</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michael I Jordan</forename><surname>Ng</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Latent dirichlet allocation. the Journal of machine Learning research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="993" to="1022" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The influence of alcohol on judgement of facial expressions of emotion</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Josephine</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Borrill</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Angela</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Bernard K Rosen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Summerfield</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">British Journal of Medical Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1987" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Condom use among high-risk adolescents: testing the influence of alcohol use on the relationship of cognitive correlates of behavior</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Angela</forename><surname>Bryan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Courtney</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Reuben</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Rocheleau</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kent</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Robbins</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Hutchinson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Health Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">133</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Effects of alcohol on human aggression: An intergrative research review</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Brad</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Harris M</forename><surname>Bushman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Cooper</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological bulletin</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">107</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">341</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1990" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Heavy alcohol use and crime: Evidence from underage drunk-driving laws</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christopher</forename><surname>Carpenter</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Law and Economics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">50</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="539" to="557" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Libsvm: a library for support vector machines</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chung</forename><surname>Chih</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chih-Jen</forename><surname>Chang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Lin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">ACM Transactions on Intelligent Systems and Technology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">27</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<publisher>TIST</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The influence of alcohol on automobile driving ability: An experimental study for the evaluation of certain medicological aspects</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Ted</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Loomis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>West</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Quarterly journal of studies on alcohol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="30" to="46" />
			<date type="published" when="1958" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Alcohol and attempted suicide</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">John</forename><surname>Merrill</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gabrielle</forename><surname>Milker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">John</forename><surname>Owens</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Allister</forename><surname>Vale</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">British journal of addiction</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">87</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="83" to="89" />
			<date type="published" when="1992" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Putting stress into words: Health, linguistic, and therapeutic implications. Behaviour research and therapy</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>James W Pennebaker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">31</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="539" to="548" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Writing about emotional experiences as a therapeutic process</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>James W Pennebaker</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="162" to="166" />
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Experimenting with distant supervision for emotion classification</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Matthew</forename><surname>Purver</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Stuart</forename><surname>Battersby</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 13th Conference of the European Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the 13th Conference of the European Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="482" to="491" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Using topic modeling to improve prediction of neuroticism and depression</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Philip</forename><surname>Resnik</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Anderson</forename><surname>Garron</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rebecca</forename><surname>Resnik</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2013 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural</title>
		<meeting>the 2013 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1348" to="1353" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Association for Computational Linguistics</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Recognizing contextual polarity in phraselevel sentiment analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Theresa</forename><surname>Wilson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Janyce</forename><surname>Wiebe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Paul</forename><surname>Hoffmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the conference on human language technology and empirical methods in natural language processing</title>
		<meeting>the conference on human language technology and empirical methods in natural language processing</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="347" to="354" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Association for Computational Linguistics</note>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
