<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T12:45+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">A Simultaneous Recognition Framework for the Spoken Language Understanding Module of Intelligent Personal Assistant Software on Smart Phones</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
				<availability status="unknown"><p>Copyright Association for Computational Linguistics</p>
				</availability>
				<date>July 26-31, 2015. 2015</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Changsu</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Computer Engineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Dong-A University</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>840 Hadan 2-dong, Saha-gu</addrLine>
									<postCode>604-714</postCode>
									<settlement>Busan</settlement>
									<country key="KR">Korea</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Youngjoong</forename><surname>Ko</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Computer Engineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Dong-A University</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>840 Hadan 2-dong, Saha-gu</addrLine>
									<postCode>604-714</postCode>
									<settlement>Busan</settlement>
									<country key="KR">Korea</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jungyun</forename><surname>Seo</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">Sogang University</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Sinsu-dong 1, Mapo-gu Seoul, 121-742</addrLine>
									<country key="KR">Korea</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">A Simultaneous Recognition Framework for the Spoken Language Understanding Module of Intelligent Personal Assistant Software on Smart Phones</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 53rd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics and the 7th International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing</title>
						<meeting>the 53rd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics and the 7th International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing <address><addrLine>Beijing, China</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="818" to="822"/>
							<date type="published">July 26-31, 2015. 2015</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>The intelligent personal assistant software such as the Apple&apos;s Siri and Sam-sung&apos;s S-Voice has been issued these days. This paper introduces a novel Spoken Language Understanding (SLU) module to predict user&apos;s intention for determining system actions of the intelligent personal assistant software. The SLU module usually consists of several connected recognition tasks on a pipeline framework, whereas the proposed SLU module simultaneously recognizes four recognition tasks on a recognition framework using Conditional Random Fields (CRF). The four tasks include named entity, speech-act, target and operation recognition. In the experiments, the new simultaneous recognition method achieves the higher performance of 4% and faster speed of about 25% than other method using a pipeline framework. By a significance test, this improvement is considered to be statistically significant as a p-value of smaller than 0.05.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Currently, one of the most issued and promising software is the intelligent personal assistant software such as Apple's Siri <ref type="bibr">(Wikipedia, 2011)</ref> and Samsung's S-Voice <ref type="bibr">(Wikipedia, 2012)</ref>. This kind of software provides users a natural lan- guage user interface to answer questions, make recommendations and perform actions. One of the core modules to develop this software is the Spoken Language Understanding (SLU) module. The SLU module predicts the user's intention of user utterance, and one of the various software actions is selected to provide appropriate infor- mation to a user ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Wang et al., 2005</ref>).</p><p>The SLU model of the intelligent personal as- sistant software has several different aspects from the previous other SLU modules, such as ones of ATIS (Automatic Terminal Information Service) and DARPA (Defense Advanced Re- search Project Agency) projects, which are based on rule-based methods ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Ward et al. 1994;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Wang et al. 2001</ref>) and statistical methods ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Wang et al. 2006;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Raymond et al. 2007</ref>). Because the SLU module is operated for various applications (Apps) of mobile devices such as weather, trans- portation, etc., it has to be able to deal with more heterogeneous domains than the ATIS and DARPA projects and it does more detailed anal- ysis for each domain in order to offer users accu- rate information. In addition, since the SLU module in the previous dialogue systems has a complicated architecture that is composes of many sub-modules, it is difficult for them to be directly applied into the SLU module of intelli- gent personal assistant software with those many domains for mobile devices. That is, building up a complicated architecture for each domain can make a heavy system and this kind of system is not proper to mobile devices.</p><p>In this paper, we propose a new SLU module with a simultaneous recognition framework for the intelligent personal assistant software. The proposed SLU module consists of four compo- nents: named entity (NE), speech-act, target and operator recognition. Each component of the proposed SLU module has different recognition unit, e.g. the named entity recognition is based on a morpheme/phrase unit, whereas the target, operator and speech-act are on an utterance unit. To integrate these recognition units into the same unit, we develop a new tag addition approach that represents a user utterance as a tag sequence for an input to CRF ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Lafferty et al. 2001</ref>).</p><p>In the experiments, the proposed simultaneous recognition module showed the better perfor- mance of 4% than a pipeline module. And it has an additional benefit that it is composed of a simple architecture with only one recognition module so it can be more efficient than other methods with respect to processing time, etc. As a result, the processing time of our system was reduced about 25% when compared to the pipe- line system.</p><p>The remainder of the paper is organized as the follows. Section 2 describes related work. In the section 3, we define four components of our SLU module for the intelligent personal assistant software. Section 4 introduces our simultaneous recognition framework in detail. Section 5 ex- plains our experimental settings and results. Fi- nally, section 6 draws conclusions.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Related Work</head><p>The approaches for developing the SLU mod- ules are largely divided into the rule-based meth- ods and the statistical methods. The rule-based modules have typically been implemented via hand-crafted semantic level grammar rules and some robust parsers <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(Seneff. 1992;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Ward et al. 1999</ref>). However, these semantic grammar ap- proaches carry a high development cost and they can also lead to fragile operations since users do not typically know what grammatical construc- tions are supported by the system. An alternative approach is to use some statistical methods to directly map from word strings to the intended meaning structures. Statistical methods are at- tractive because they can be easily adapted to new conditions using only annotated training data. Statistical methods for SLU have been stud- ied in a Hidden Vector State (HVS) <ref type="bibr">Model (He et al., 2005</ref>) and a data-driven statistical models ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Miller et al. 1994;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Pieraccini et al. 1992;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Wang et al. 2006</ref>). In addition, <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Jeong and Lee (2008)</ref> proposed a unified probabilistic model (triangu- lar-chain CRF) combining the named entity and dialog-act of SLU. This method achieved the high performance for SLU. But the triangular- chain CRF has a complicated architecture with a modified CRF. And this method was built only to combine the named entity and dialog-act, whereas we need to combine four components. In practical, the triangular-chain CRF showed low performance when combining four compo- nents in the experiments. As a result, the pro- posed SLU module achieved high performance in spite of its simple architecture.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Components of the Proposed SLU Module for the Intelligent Personal Assistant Software</head><p>Since the SLU module of intelligent personal assistant software needs to determine the actions of Apps of smart phone according to user needs, they require more elaborate user intent analysis. Thus we define four components of the SLU module. An analysis result of our SLU module is shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref> as follows: Target recognition: target describes the ob- ject of system action. In <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref>, the target is "Temperature_Information." By this recognized target, the software can offer users accurate in- formation.</p><p>Operator recognition: operator is to detect one of the various software actions (Lookup, Set, Delete, etc.). In <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref>, the operator is identi- fied as "Lookup".</p><p>Speech-act recognition: speech-act tries to designate a surface level speech-act. "Wh_Question" as speech-act in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref> pro- vides the user's intention of surface level to dia- logue systems.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Simultaneous Recognition Frame- work</head><p>We assume that four components of our SLU module are correlated with each other. In order to improve the performance and speed of the SLU module, we propose a new framework to simultaneously recognize the four components. But these components have different recognition units; NE has a morpheme/phrase unit and target, operator and speech-act have an utterance unit. A new tag addition method is proposed to solve this problem. Using this method, we can construct a novel simultaneous recognition framework for SLU.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">New tag addition method</head><p>Target, operator and speech-act are based on an utterance unit. In order to construct a simulta- neous recognition framework, we attach pseudo morphemes with target, operator and speech-act tags in front of each user utterance. Using these pseudo morphemes, target, operator and speech- act can utilize the features of NE, and NE can also do target, operator and speech-act infor- mation as additional features. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 2</ref> shows an example of the new tag addition method. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">Simultaneous recognition framework</head><p>On the simultaneous recognition framework with the new tag addition method, an input utter- ance is analyzed by a sequential labeling classifi- er, CRF. It is possible to use all of component labels as additional features in this classification method. We think that this is a main reason why the proposed method improves recognition per- formances.</p><p>Our framework needs only NE dictionary and BIO annotated training corpus; BIO tags were used in ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Ramshaw and Marcus. 1995)</ref>. It is very simple and fast because it can output all of four different SLU results in one classification execu- tion. The architecture of our framework is shown in <ref type="figure">Figure 3</ref>. Our SLU module is widely divided into a training step and a test step.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3">Feature Sets</head><p>The three feature sets are extracted for SLU: basis features ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Lee et al. 2010</ref>), NE dictionary features and target/operator/speech-act features.</p><p>All the basic and NE dictionary features are ana- lyzed based on the morpheme unit. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Experiments</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.1">Experimental settings</head><p>The MADS data set (Multi-Applications Dia- logues for Smart phones) was constructed and used to develop the SLU modules for the intelli- gent personal assistant software. The MADS data set was annotated by 8 NEs, 28 targets, 5 opera- tors and 6 speech-act tags. In addition, The MADS data set consists of 1,925 user utterance in 6 domains: weather, clock, alarm, schedule, exchange and traffic. The Mallet toolkit was chosen for our CRF model <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(McCallum. 2002)</ref>.</p><p>All experiments were evaluated by accuracy in the utterance level. When the proposed SLU module generates all the correct labels of NE, target, operator and speech-act of an input utter- ance, the utterance is considered as correct. The performance of the SLU module is averaged on 5-fold cross validation. In addition, we used the paired t-test and Wilcoxon singed rank test to <ref type="figure">Figure 3</ref>: Architecture for the simultaneous recognition framework verify statistically significant between our framework and compared baseline framework. The pipeline framework <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(Moreira et al., 2011</ref>) is used a baseline system in our experiments be- cause it is the most common method for multi- domains SLU module.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.2">Experimental results</head><p>Each component of the SLU module is first evaluated by comparison of accuracies between the proposed and baseline frameworks. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Figure 4</ref> illustrates the accuracies of each component. A pipeline framework commonly has some disadvantage that the errors of previous compo- nent are propagated to the next components. It can cause a cascade of performance degradation. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Figure 5</ref> shows the accuracies of entire SLU modules in an utterance level. The proposed framework achieved significant- ly better performance than the baseline frame- work.</p><p>To verify statistically significant on accuracy difference between the proposed and baseline frameworks, we performed significant test using the t-test and Wilcoxon singed rank test <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Demsar. 2006</ref> In both of two significance tests, our framework was statistically significantly better than the pipeline framework (p&lt;0.05).</p><p>In the comparison of processing time, our framework obtained faster processing speed than pipeline framework with about 25% reduction.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Test user utterance (388 utterances)</head><p>Our framework 15 sec.</p><p>Pipeline framework 19 sec. In addition, we tried to compare our module and the triangular-chain CRF <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Jeong and Lee, 2008)</ref>. <ref type="table">Table 3</ref> shows the performances when NE and speech-act recognition tasks are combined and all four recognition tasks are combined. As a re- sult, our module outperformed the triangular- chain CRF in both of cases.</p><p>NE+Speech-act All (four tasks)</p><p>Our framework 90.61 83.48</p><p>Triangular-chain CRF 87.07 16.4 <ref type="table">Table 3</ref>: comparison of our module and triangular- chain CRF</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Conclusions</head><p>In this paper, we have presented a novel SLU framework to predict user's intention for deter- mining system actions of the intelligent personal assistant software. The proposed SLU module with a simultaneous recognition framework achieved higher performance and faster pro- cessing speed than the existing pipeline system. In addition, our module outperformed other method, the triangular-chain CRF, especially when four components were all analyzed.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: Example of analysis results</figDesc><graphic url="image-1.png" coords="2,306.08,217.97,218.55,87.45" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2: Example of the new tag addition method</figDesc><graphic url="image-2.png" coords="3,70.88,360.62,217.60,84.40" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Basis features Current lexicon/POS tag information Based on the position of the current lexicon, lexicon contextual information. window size : -2~2 Based on the position of the current POS tag, POS tag contextual information. window size : -2~2 The words of Korean language can consist of one or more morphemes; -current morpheme position information in a word -current morpheme POS tag/word length information  NE dictionary features Based on current morpheme, NE tag information matched from NE dictionary  Target/operator/speech-act features Verb information in the utterance Lexicon unigram information in the utterance Lexicon &amp; POS tag bigram information in the utterance Lexicon &amp; POS tag trigram information in the utterance</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>Figure 4 :</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Figure 4: Comparison of the accuracies of each component for SLU</figDesc><graphic url="image-4.png" coords="4,70.88,233.22,217.95,139.30" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head>Figure 5 :</head><label>5</label><figDesc>Figure 5: Comparison of accuracies of entire SLU modules on the utterance level</figDesc><graphic url="image-5.png" coords="4,70.88,489.77,218.20,129.95" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" validated="false"><head>value &lt; 0.05 (95%)</head><label></label><figDesc>). Table 1 shows the results of significant test. p-</figDesc><table>Our framework 
vs. 
Pipeline framework 

paired t-test 
0.00001 

Wilcox signed rank test 
0.021 

Table 1: Results of significant tests 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" validated="false"><head>Table 2 : Results of processing time comparison</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table></table></figure>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgement</head><p>This research was supported by Basic Science Research Program through the National Research Foundation of Korea (NRF) funded by the Min-istry of Education, <ref type="bibr">Science and Technology (No. NRF-2013R1A1A2009937)</ref> </p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Statistical comparisons of classifiers over multiple data sets</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Janez</forename><surname>Demsar</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Machine Learning Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="30" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Semantic Processing using the Hidden Vector State Model</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yulan</forename><surname>He</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Steve</forename><surname>Young</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Computer Speech and Language</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="85" to="106" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Triangular-chain conditional random fields</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Minwoo</forename><surname>Jeong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gary-Geunbae</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE Transactions on Audio, Speech, and Language Processing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">16</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1287" to="1302" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Conditional random fields: Probabilistic models for segmenting and labeling sequence data</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">John</forename><surname>Lafferty</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Andrew</forename><surname>Mccallum</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Fernando</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Pereira</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Eighteenth International Conference on Machine Learning</title>
		<meeting>the Eighteenth International Conference on Machine Learning<address><addrLine>SanFrancisco, CA, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Morgan Kaufmann Publishers Inc</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="282" to="289" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Named Entity Recognition with Structural SVMs and Pegasos algorithm</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Changki</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Myung-Gil</forename><surname>Jang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Korean Journal of Cognitive Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">21</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="655" to="667" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Mallet: A machine learning for language kit</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Andrew</forename><surname>Mccallum</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://mallet.cs.umass.edu" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Hidden understanding models of natural language</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Scott</forename><surname>Miller</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Revert</forename><surname>Bobrow</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Robert</forename><surname>Ingria</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Robert</forename><surname>Schwartz</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the ACL</title>
		<meeting>the ACL</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1994" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="25" to="32" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Towards the rapid development of a natural language understanding module</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Catarina</forename><surname>Moreira</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ana</forename><forename type="middle">Cristina</forename><surname>Mendes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lu´ısa</forename><surname>Coheur</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bruno</forename><surname>Martins</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of 10th international conference on Intelligent virtual agents</title>
		<meeting>10th international conference on Intelligent virtual agents</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="309" to="315" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A speech understanding system based on statistical representation of semantics</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Roberto</forename><surname>Pieraccini</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Evelyne</forename><surname>Tzoukermann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Zakhar</forename><surname>Gorelov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jean-Luc</forename><surname>Gauvain</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Esther</forename><surname>Levin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chinehui</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jay</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Wilpon</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the ICASSP</title>
		<meeting>the ICASSP<address><addrLine>San Francisco, CA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1992" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Text Chunking using Transformation-Based Learning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Launce</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mitchell</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Ramshaw</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Marcus</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Third Workshop on Very Large Corpora</title>
		<meeting>the Third Workshop on Very Large Corpora</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="82" to="94" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Generative and discriminative algorithms for spoken language understanding</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christian</forename><surname>Raymond</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Giuseppe</forename><surname>Riccardi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Interspeech</title>
		<meeting>the Interspeech<address><addrLine>Antwerp, Belgium</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">TINA: A Natural Language System for Spoken Language Applications. Computational Linguistics</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Stephanie</forename><surname>Seneff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1992" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Robust Spoken Language Understanding in MiPad</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ye-Yi</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">proceedings of Eurospeech</title>
		<meeting>Eurospeech<address><addrLine>Aalborg, Denmark</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Discriminative models for spoken language understanding</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ye-</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yi</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alex</forename><surname>Acero</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the ICSLP</title>
		<meeting>the ICSLP<address><addrLine>Pittsburgh, PA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Spoken language understanding : an introduction to the statistical framework</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ye-Yi</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Li</forename><surname>Deng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alex</forename><surname>Acero</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE Signal Processing Magazine</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="16" to="31" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The CU Communicator System</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wayne</forename><surname>Ward</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bryan</forename><surname>Pellom</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sameer</forename><surname>Pradhan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">IEEE Workshop on ASRU Proc</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Keystone, Colorado</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Recent Improvements in the CMU Spoken language Understanding System</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wayne</forename><surname>Ward</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Human Language Technology Workshop</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Plainsboro, New Jersey</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1994" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<monogr>
				<title level="m">Wikipedia Contributors. 2011. Siri, Wikipedia, the Free Encyclopedia</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<monogr>
				<title level="m">Wikipedia Contributors. 2012. S-Voice, Wikipedia, the Free Encyclopedia</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
