<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T10:26+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Joint Case Argument Identification for Japanese Predicate Argument Structure Analysis</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
				<availability status="unknown"><p>Copyright Association for Computational Linguistics</p>
				</availability>
				<date>July 26-31, 2015. 2015</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hiroki</forename><surname>Ouchi</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Graduate School of Information and Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Nara Institute of Science and Technology</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>8916-5, 630-0192</postCode>
									<settlement>Takayama</settlement>
									<region>Ikoma, Nara</region>
									<country key="JP">Japan</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hiroyuki</forename><surname>Shindo</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Graduate School of Information and Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Nara Institute of Science and Technology</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>8916-5, 630-0192</postCode>
									<settlement>Takayama</settlement>
									<region>Ikoma, Nara</region>
									<country key="JP">Japan</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kevin</forename><surname>Duh</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Graduate School of Information and Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Nara Institute of Science and Technology</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>8916-5, 630-0192</postCode>
									<settlement>Takayama</settlement>
									<region>Ikoma, Nara</region>
									<country key="JP">Japan</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yuji</forename><surname>Matsumoto</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Graduate School of Information and Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Nara Institute of Science and Technology</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>8916-5, 630-0192</postCode>
									<settlement>Takayama</settlement>
									<region>Ikoma, Nara</region>
									<country key="JP">Japan</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Joint Case Argument Identification for Japanese Predicate Argument Structure Analysis</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 53rd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics and the 7th International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing</title>
						<meeting>the 53rd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics and the 7th International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing <address><addrLine>Beijing, China</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="961" to="970"/>
							<date type="published">July 26-31, 2015. 2015</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Existing methods for Japanese predicate argument structure (PAS) analysis identify case arguments of each predicate without considering interactions between the target PAS and others in a sentence. However , the argument structures of the predicates in a sentence are semantically related to each other. This paper proposes new methods for Japanese PAS analysis to jointly identify case arguments of all predicates in a sentence by (1) modeling multiple PAS interactions with a bipar-tite graph and (2) approximately searching optimal PAS combinations. Performing experiments on the NAIST Text Corpus , we demonstrate that our joint analysis methods substantially outperform a strong baseline and are comparable to previous work.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Predicate argument structure (PAS) analysis is a shallow semantic parsing task that identifies ba- sic semantic units of a sentence, such as who does what to whom, which is similar to semantic role labeling (SRL) <ref type="bibr">1</ref> .</p><p>In Japanese PAS analysis, one of the most prob- lematic issues is that arguments are often omitted in the surface form, resulting in so-called zero- pronouns. Consider the sentence of <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref>. "NOM" and "ACC" represents the nominative and accusative arguments, respectively. "ϕ i " is a zero- pronoun, referring to the antecedent "watashi i ".</p><p>The case role label "NOM" and "ACC" respec- tively represents the nominative and accusative roles, and ϕ i represents a zero-pronoun. There are two predicates "hiita (caught)" and "yasunda (skipped)". For the predicate "yasunda (skipped)", "watashi i -wa (I i )" is the "skipper", and "gakko-wo (school)" is the "entity skipped". It is easy to iden- tify these arguments, since syntactic dependency between an argument and its predicate is a strong clue. On the other hand, the nominative argument of the predicate "hiita (caught)" is "watashi i -wa (I i )", and this identification is more difficult be- cause of the lack of the direct syntactic depen- dency with "hiita (caught)". The original nomina- tive argument appears as a zero-pronoun, so that we have to explore the antecedent, an element re- ferred to by a zero-pronoun, as the argument. As the example sentence shows, we cannot use ef- fective syntactic information for identifying such arguments. This type of arguments is known as implicit arguments, a very problematic language 961 phenomenon for PAS analysis <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Gerber and Chai, 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Laparra and Rigau, 2013)</ref>.</p><p>Previous work on Japanese PAS analysis at- tempted to solve this problem by identifying argu- ments per predicate without considering interac- tions between multiple predicates and arguments <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Taira et al., 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Imamura et al., 2009)</ref>. How- ever, implicit arguments are likely to be shared by semantically-related predicates. In the above example <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">(Figure 1</ref>), the implicit argument of the predicate "hiita (caught)" is shared by the other predicate "yasunda (skipped)" as its nominative argument "watashi i (I i )".</p><p>Based on this intuition, we propose methods to jointly identify optimal case arguments of all pred- icates in a sentence taking their interactions into account. We represent the interactions as a bipar- tite graph that covers all predicates and candidate arguments in a sentence, and factorize the whole relation into the second-order relations. This in- teraction modeling results in a hard combinatorial problem because it is required to select the optimal PAS combination from all possible PAS combina- tions in a sentence. To solve this issue, we extend the randomized hill-climbing algorithm ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Zhang et al., 2014</ref>) to search all possible PAS in the space of bipartite graphs.</p><p>We perform experiments on the NAIST Text Corpus ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Iida et al., 2007</ref>), a standard bench- mark for Japanese PAS analysis. Experimental results show that compared with a strong base- line, our methods achieve an improvement of 1.0-1.2 points in F-measure for total case argu- ment identification, and especially improve per- formance for implicit argument identification by 2.0-2.5 points. In addition, although we exploit no external resources, we get comparable results to previous work exploiting large-scale external re- sources ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Taira et al., 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Imamura et al., 2009;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Sasano and Kurohashi, 2011</ref>). These results sug- gest that there is potential for more improvement by adding external resources.</p><p>The main contributions of this work are: (1) We present new methods to jointly identify case ar- guments of all predicates in a sentence. (2) We propose global feature templates that capture inter- actions over multiple PAS. (3) Performing experi- ments on the NAIST Text Corpus, we demonstrate our methods are superior to a strong baseline and comparable to the methods of representative pre- vious work.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Japanese Predicate Argument</head><p>Structure Analysis</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">Task Overview</head><p>In Japanese PAS analysis, we identify arguments taking part in the three major case roles, nomina- tive (NOM), accusative (ACC) and dative (DAT) cases, for each predicate. Case arguments can be divided into three categories according to the posi- tions relative to their predicates (Hayashibe et al., 2011):</p><p>Dep: The arguments that have direct syntactic de- pendency with the predicate.</p><p>Zero: The implicit arguments whose antecedents appear in the same sentence and have no di- rect syntactic dependency with the predicate.</p><p>Inter-Zero: The implicit arguments whose an- tecedents do not appear in the same sentence.</p><p>For example, in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref>, the accusative argu- ment "gakko-wo (school)" of the predicate "ya- sunda (skipped)" is regarded as Dep, and the nominative argument "watashi i -wa (I)" (the an- tecedent of zero-pronoun "ϕ i ") of the predicate "hiita (caught)" is Zero.</p><p>In this paper, we focus on the analysis for intra- sentential arguments <ref type="bibr">(Dep and Zero)</ref>. In order to identify inter-sentential arguments (Inter-Zero), it is required to search a much broader space, such as the whole document, resulting in a much harder analysis than intra-sentential arguments. <ref type="bibr">2</ref> There- fore, we believe that quite different approaches are necessary to realize an inter-sentential PAS analy- sis with high accuracy, and leave it for future work.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">Related Work</head><p>For Japanese PAS analysis research, the NAIST Text Corpus has been used as a standard bench- mark ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Iida et al., 2007)</ref>. One of the representa- tive researches using the NAIST Text Corpus is <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Imamura et al. (2009)</ref>. They built three distinct models corresponding to the three case roles by extracting features defined on each pair of a predi- cate and a candidate argument. Using each model, they select the best candidate argument for each case per predicate. Their models are based on maximum entropy model and can easily incorpo- rate various features, resulting in high accuracy. While in <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Imamura et al. (2009)</ref> one case ar- gument is identified at a time per predicate, the method proposed by <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Sasano and Kurohashi (2011)</ref> simultaneously determines all the three case argu- ments per predicate by exploiting large-scale case frames obtained from large raw texts. They fo- cus on identification of implicit arguments (Zero and Inter-Zero), and achieves comparable results to <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Imamura et al. (2009)</ref>.</p><p>In these approaches, case arguments were iden- tified per predicate without considering interac- tions between multiple predicates and candidate arguments in a sentence. In the semantic role la- beling (SRL) task, Yang and Zong (2014) pointed out that information of different predicates and their candidate arguments could help each other for identifying arguments taking part in semantic roles. They exploited a reranking method to cap- ture the interactions between multiple predicates and candidate arguments, and jointly determine ar- gument structures of all predicates in a sentence <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Yang and Zong, 2014)</ref>. In this paper, we propose new joint analysis methods for identifying case ar- guments of all predicates in a sentence capturing interactions between multiple predicates and can- didate arguments.</p><p>3 Graph-Based Joint Models</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">A Predicate-Argument Graph</head><p>We define predicate argument relations by exploit- ing a bipartite graph, illustrated in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 2</ref>. The nodes of the graph consist of two disjoint sets: the left one is a set of candidate arguments and the right one is a set of predicates. In this paper, we call it a predicate-argument (PA) graph.</p><p>Each predicate node has three distinct edges corresponding to nominative (NOM), accusative (ACC), and dative (DAT) cases. Each edge with a case role label joins a candidate argument node with a predicate node, which represents a case ar- gument of a predicate. For instance, in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 2</ref> a 1 is the nominative argument of p 1 , and a 3 is the accusative argument of p 2 .</p><p>Formally, a PA graph is a bipartite graph ⟨A, P, E⟩, where A is the node set consisting of candidate arguments, P the node set consisting of predicates, and E the set of edges subject to that there is exactly one edge e with a case role label c outgoing from each of the predicate nodes p to a candidate argument node a. A PA graph is defined as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">A = {a 1 , ..., a n , a n+1 = NULL} P = {p 1 , ..., p m } E = {⟨a, p, c⟩ | deg(p, c) = 1, ∀a ∈ A, ∀p ∈ P, ∀c ∈ C }</formula><p>where deg(p, c) is the number of edges with a case role c outgoing from p, and C is the case role label set. We add a dummy node a n+1 , which is defined for the cases where the predicate requires no case argument or the required case argument does not appear in the sentence. An edge e ∈ E is repre- sented by a tuple ⟨a, p, c⟩, indicating the edge with a case role c joining a candidate argument node a and a predicate node p. An admissible PA graph satisfies the constraint deg(p, c) = 1, representing that each predicate node p has only one edge with a case role c.</p><p>To identify the whole PAS for a sentence x, we predict the PA graph with an edge set correspond- ing to the correct PAS from the admissible PA graph set G(x) based on a score associated with a PA graph y as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">˜ y = argmax y∈G(x) Score(x, y)</formula><p>A scoring function Score(x, y) receives a sen- tence x and a candidate graph y as its input, and returns a scalar value.</p><p>In this paper, we propose two scoring functions as analysis models based on different assumptions: (1) Per-Case Joint Model assumes the interac- tion between multiple predicates (predicate inter- action) and the independence between case roles, and (2) All-Cases Joint Model assumes the in- teraction between case roles (case interaction) as well as the predicate interaction. 963</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Per-Case Joint Model</head><p>Per-Case Joint Model assumes that different case roles are independent from each other. However, for each case, interactions between multiple pred- icates are considered jointly.</p><p>We define the score of a PA graph y to be the sum of the scores for each case role c of the set of the case roles C:</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">Score per (x, y) = ∑ c∈C Score c (x, y)<label>(1)</label></formula><p>The scores for each case role are defined as the dot products between a weight vector θ c and a feature vector ϕ c (x, E(y, c)):</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">Score c (x, y) = θ c · ϕ c (x, E(y, c))<label>(2)</label></formula><p>where E(y, c) is the edge set associated with a case role c in the candidate graph y, and the feature vector is defined on the edge set. The edge set E(y, c) in the equation <ref type="formula" target="#formula_3">(2)</ref> is uti- lized for the two types of features, the local fea- tures and global features, inspired by <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Huang, 2008)</ref>, defined as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_4">θ c · ϕ c (x, E(y, c)) = ∑ e∈E(y,c) θ c ϕ l (x, e) + θ c ϕ g (x, E(y, c)) (3)</formula><p>where ϕ l (x, e) denotes the local feature vector, and ϕ g (x, E(y, c)) the global feature vector. The local feature vector ϕ l (x, e) is defined on each edge e in the edge set E(y, c) and a sentence x, which captures a predicate-argument pair. Con- sider the example of <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 2</ref>. For Per-Case Joint Model, we use edges, e a 1 p 1 , e a 1 p 2 , and e a 2 p 3 , as local features to compute the score of the edge set with the nominative case.</p><p>In addition, the global feature vector ϕ g (x, E(y, c)) is defined on the edge set E(y, c), and enables the model to utilize lin- guistically richer information over multiple predicate-argument pairs. In this paper, we exploit second-order relations, similar to the second-order edge factorization of dependency trees <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(McDonald and Pereira, 2006</ref>). We make a set of edge pairs E pair by combining two edges e i , e j in the edge set E(y, c), as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_5">E pair = { {e i , e j } | ∀e i , e j ∈ E(y, c), e i ̸ = e j }</formula><p>For instance, in the PA graph in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 2</ref>, to com- pute the score of the nominative arguments, we make three edge pairs:</p><formula xml:id="formula_6">{{e a 1 p 1 , e a 1 p 2 }, {e a 1 p 1 , e a 2 p 3 }, {e a 1 p 2 , e a 2 p 3 }}</formula><p>Then, features are extracted from these edge pairs and utilized for the score computation. For the accusative and dative cases, their scores are com- puted in the same manner. Then, we obtain the resulting score of the PA graph by summing up the scores of the local and global features. If we do not consider the global features, the model re- duces to a per-case local model similar to previous work (Imamura et al., 2009).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3">All-Cases Joint Model</head><p>While Per-Case Joint Model assumes the predi- cate interaction with the independence between case roles, All-Cases Joint Model assumes the case interaction together with the predicate inter- action. Our graph-based formulation is very flex- ible and easily enables the extension of Per-Case Joint Model to All-Cases Joint Model. Therefore, we extend Per-Case Joint Model to All-Cases Joint Model to capture the interactions between predi- cates and all case arguments in a sentence.</p><p>We define the score of a PA graph y based on the local and global features as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_7">Score all (x, y) = ∑ e∈E(y) θ · ϕ l (x, e) + θ · ϕ g (x, E(y))<label>(4)</label></formula><p>where E(y) is the edge set associated with all the case roles on the candidate graph y, ϕ l (x, e) is the local feature vector defined on each edge e in the edge set E(y), and ϕ g (x, E(y)) is the global fea- ture vector defined on the edge set E(y).</p><p>Consider the PA graph in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 2</ref>. The local features are extracted from each edge:</p><formula xml:id="formula_8">Nominative : e a 1 p 1 , e a 1 p 2 , e a 2 p 3 Accusative : e a 2 p 1 , e a 3 p 2 , e a 3 p 3 Dative : e a 3 p 1 , e a 4 p 2 , e a 4 p 3</formula><p>For the global features, we make a set of edge pairs E pair by combining two edges e i , e j in the edge set E(y), like Per-Case Joint Model. How- ever, in the All-Cases Joint Model, the global fea- tures may involve different cases (i.e. mixing edges with different case roles). For the PA graph in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 2</ref>, we make the edge pairs {e a 1 p 1 , e a 2 p 1 }, {e a 3 p 1 , e a 1 p 2 }, {e a 3 p 2 , e a 4 p 3 }, and so on. From these edge pairs, we extract information as global features to compute a graph score. 964 <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>: Global feature templates. p i , p j is a predicate, a i is the argument connected with p i , and a j is the argument connected with p j . Feature conjunction is indicated by •; ax=auxiliary, rp=relative position, vo=voice, rf=regular form, dep=dependency. All the features are conjoined with the relative position and the case role labels of the two predicates.</p><formula xml:id="formula_9">Structure Name Description Diff-Arg PAIR ⟨ p i .rf • p j .rf • p i .vo • p j .vo ⟩, ⟨ a i .ax • a i .rp • p i .ax • p i .vo ⟩, ⟨ a j .ax • a j .rp • p j .ax • p j .vo ⟩ TRIANGLE ⟨ a i .ax • a i .ax • a i .rp • a j .rp • p i .ax • p i .vo ⟩, ⟨ a i .ax • a j .ax • a i .rp • a j .rp • p j .ax • p j .vo ⟩, QUAD ⟨ a i .ax • a j .ax • a i .rp • a j .rp • p i .vo • p j .vo ⟩ ⟨ a i .ax • a j .ax • p i .ax • p j .ax • a i .rp • a j .rp • p i .vo • p j .vo ⟩ ⟨ a i .ax • a j .ax • p i .rf • p j .rf • a i .rp • a i .rp • p i .vo • p i .vo ⟩ Co-Arg BI-PREDS ⟨ a i .rp • p i .rf • p j .rf ⟩, ⟨ a i .ax • a i .rp • p i .rf • p j .rf ⟩ DEP-REL ⟨ a i .ax • a i .rp • p i .ax • p j .ax • p i .vo • p j .vo • (x, y).dep ⟩ if x depends on y for x,y in (p i ,p j ), (a i ,p i ), (a i ,p j ), (p i ,a i ), (p j ,a i )</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Global Features</head><p>Features are extracted based on feature tem- plates, which are functions that draw information from the given entity. For instance, one feature template ϕ 100 = a.ax • p.vo is a conjunction of two atomic features a.ax and p.vo, representing an auxiliary word attached to a candidate argument (a.ax) and the voice of a predicate (p.vo). We design several feature templates for characterizing each specific PA graph. Consider the PA graph constructed from the sentence in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref>, and a candidate argument "kaze-wo (a cold)" and a pred- icate "hiita (caught)" are connected with an edge.</p><p>To characterize the graph, we draw some linguis- tic information associated with the edge. Since the auxiliary word attached to the candidate argument is "wo" and the voice of the predicate is "active", the above feature template ϕ 100 will generate a feature instance as follows.</p><p>(a.ax = wo) • (p.vo = active) Such features are utilized for the local and global features in the joint models.</p><p>We propose the global feature templates that capture multiple PAS interactions based on the Diff-Arg and Co-Arg structures, depicted in the right part of <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref>. The Diff-Arg structure rep- resents that the two predicates have different can- didate arguments, and the Co-Arg structure repre- sents that the two predicates share the same can- didate argument. Based on these structures, we define the global feature templates that receive a pair of edges in a PA graph as input and return a feature vector, shown in <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">Diff-Arg Features</head><p>The feature templates based on the Diff-Arg struc- ture are three types: PAIR (a pair of predicate- argument relation), TRIANGLE (a predicate and its two arguments relation), and QUAD (two predicate-argument relations).</p><p>PAIR These feature templates denote where the target argument is located relative to another argu- ment and the two predicates in the Diff-Arg struc- ture. We combine the relative position information (rp) with the auxiliary words (ax) and the voice of the two predicates (vo). TRIANGLE This type of feature templates cap- tures the interactions between three elements: two candidate arguments and a predicate. Like the PAIR feature templates, we encode the relative po- sition information of two candidate arguments and a predicate with the auxiliary words and voice.</p><p>QUAD When we judge if a candidate argu- ment takes part in a case role of a predicate, it would be beneficial to grasp information of an- other predicate-argument pair. The QUAD fea- ture templates capture the mutual relation between four elements: two candidate arguments and pred- icates. We encode the relative position informa- tion, the auxiliary words, and the voice.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">Co-Arg Features</head><p>To identify predicates that take implicit (Zero) ar- guments, we set two feature types, BI-PREDS and DEP-REL, based on the Co-Arg structure.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>BI-PREDS For identifying an implicit argu</head><p>Input: the set of cases to be analyzed C, parameter θ c , sentence x Output: a locally optimal PA graph˜ygraph˜ graph˜y Input: the set of cases to be analyzed C, parameter θ, sentence x Output: a locally optimal PA graph˜ygraph˜ graph˜y</p><formula xml:id="formula_10">1: Sample a PA graph y (0) from G(x) 2: t ← 0 3: repeat 4: Y ← N eighborG(y (t) ) ∪ y (t)</formula><p>5:</p><formula xml:id="formula_11">y (t+1) ← argmax y∈Y θ · ϕ(x, E(y)) 6: t ← t + 1 7: until y (t) = y (t+1) 8: returñ y ← y (t)</formula><p>Figure 4: Hill-Climbing for All-Cases Joint Model ment of a predicate, information of another semantically-related predicate in the sentence could be effective. We utilize bi-grams of the reg- ular forms (rf) of the two predicates in the Co-Arg structure to capture the predicates that are likely to share the same argument in the sentence.</p><p>DEP-REL We set five distinct feature templates to capture dependency relations (dep) between the shared argument and the two predicates. If two elements have a direct dependency relation, we encode its dependency relation with the auxiliary words and the voice.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Inference and Training</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.1">Inference for the Joint Models</head><p>Global features make the inference of finding the maximum scoring PA graph more difficult. For searching the graph with the highest score, we pro- pose two greedy search algorithms by extending the randomized hill-climbing algorithm proposed in ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Zhang et al., 2014)</ref>, which has been shown to achieve the state-of-the-art performance in depen- dency parsing. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 3</ref> describes the pseudo code of our pro- posed algorithm for Per-Case Joint Model. Firstly, we set an initial PA graph y (0) sampled uniformly from the set of admissible PA graphs G(x) (line 1 in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 3)</ref>. Then, the union Y c is constructed from the set of neighboring graphs with a case N eighborG(y (t) , c), which is a set of admissible graphs obtained by changing one edge with the case c in y (t) , and the current graph y (t) (line 5). The current graph y (t) is updated to a higher scor- ing graph y (t+1) selected from the union Y c (line 6). The algorithm continues until no more score improvement is possible by changing an edge with the case c in y (t) (line 8). This repetition is exe- cuted for other case roles in the same manner. As a result, we can get a locally optimal graph˜ygraph˜ graph˜y. <ref type="figure">Figure 4</ref> describes the pseudo code of the algo- rithm for All-Cases Joint Model. The large part of the algorithm is the same as that for Per-Case Joint Model. The difference is that the union Y consists of the current graph y (t) and the neighboring graph set obtained by changing one edge in y (t) regard- less of case roles (line 4 in <ref type="figure">Figure 4)</ref>, and that the iteration process for each case role (line 3 in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Fig- ure 3)</ref> is removed. The algorithm also continues until no more score improvement is possible by changing an edge in y (t) , resulting in a locally op- timal graph˜ygraph˜ graph˜y.</p><p>Following <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Zhang et al. (2014)</ref>, for a given sen- tence x, we repeatedly run these algorithms with K consecutive restarts. Each run starts with initial graphs randomly sampled from the set of admis- sible PA graphs G(x), so that we obtain K local optimal graphs by K restarts. Then the highest scoring one of K graphs is selected for the sen- tence x as the result. Each run of the algorithms is independent from each other, so that multiple runs are easily executable in parallel.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.2">Training</head><p>Given a training data set D = {(ˆ x, ˆ y)} N i , the weight vectors θ (θ c ) in the scoring functions of the joint models are estimated by using machine learning techniques. We adopt averaged percep- tron <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Collins, 2002</ref>) with a max-margin technique:</p><formula xml:id="formula_12">∀i ∈ {1, ..., N }, y ∈ G(x i ), Score(ˆ x i , ˆ y i ) ≥ Score(ˆ x i , y) + ∥ˆy∥ˆy i − y∥ 1 − ξ i</formula><p>where ξ i ≥ 0 is the slack variable and ∥ˆy∥ˆy i − y∥ 1 is the Hamming distance between the gold PA graphˆy graphˆ graphˆy i and a candidate PA graph y of the admissible PA graphs G(x i ). Following Zhang et al. <ref type="formula" target="#formula_2">(2014)</ref>, we select the highest scoring graph˜ygraph˜ graph˜y as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_13">TRAIN : ˜ y = argmax y∈G(ˆ x i ) {Score(ˆ x i , y)+∥ˆy+∥ˆy i −y∥ 1 } TEST : ˜ y = argmax y∈G(x)</formula><p>{Score(x, y)} Using the weight vector tuned by the training, we perform analysis on a sentence x in the test set.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Experiment</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.1">Experimental Settings</head><p>Data Set We evaluate our proposed methods on the NAIST Text Corpus 1.5, which consists of 40,000 sentences of Japanese newspaper text ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Iida et al., 2007)</ref>. While previous work has adopted the version 1.4 beta, we adopt the latest version.</p><p>The major difference between version 1.4 beta and 1.5 is revision of dative case (corresponding to Japanese case particle "ni"). In 1.4 beta, most of adjunct usages of "ni" are mixed up with the argu- ment usages of "ni", making the identification of dative cases seemingly easy. Therefore, our results are not directly comparable with previous work. We adopt standard train/dev/test split ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Taira et al., 2008)</ref> as follows:</p><p>Train Articles: Jan 1-11, Editorials: Jan-Aug Dev Articles: Jan 12-13, Editorials: Sept Test Articles: Jan 14-17, Editorials: Oct-Dec</p><p>We exclude inter-sentential arguments (Inter- Zero) in our experiments. Our features make use of the annotated POS tags, phrase boundaries, and dependency relations annotated in the NAIST Text Corpus. We do not use any external resources.</p><p>Baseline We adopt the pointwise method (using only local features) proposed by <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Imamura et al. (2009)</ref> as the baseline. They built three distinct models corresponding to the three case roles. By using each model, they estimate the likelihood that each candidate argument plays a case role of the target predicate as a score, and independently se- lect the highest scoring one per predicate.   <ref type="table">Table 2</ref>: Global vs Local features on the develop- ment sets in F-measures. "PC Joint" denotes the Per-Case Joint Model, and "AC Joint" denotes the All-Cases Joint Model.</p><p>Features The baseline utilizes the Baseline Fea- tures used in <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Imamura et al. (2009)</ref> and Grammat- ical features used in <ref type="bibr">Hayashibe et al. (2009)</ref>, as the "Local Features". In addition, the joint models utilize the "Global Features" in <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>.</p><p>Implementation Details For our joint models with hill-climbing, we report the average per- formance across ten independent runs with 10 restarts, which almost reaches convergence 3 . We train the baseline and our joint models for 20 iter- ations with averaged perceptron. <ref type="table">Table 2</ref> shows the effectiveness of the global fea- tures on the development sets. We incrementally add the global features to the both models that uti- lize only the local features. The results show that the global features improve the performance by about 1.0 point in F-measures in total. For and are particularly beneficial to the implicit (Zero) argument identification (an improvement of 1.99 points in Per-Case Joint Model and 3.12 points in All-Cases Joint Model).    <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Sasano &amp; Kurohashi (2011)</ref>. Their results are not directly comparable to ours since they use external resources and the NAIST Text Corpus 1.4 beta. the implicit arguments (Zero), one of the problem- atic issues in Japanese PAS analysis.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.2">Results</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Local Features vs Global Features</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Pointwise Methods vs Joint Methods</head><p>Comparing the joint methods, each of our two joint methods is effective for a different case role. Per-Case Joint Model is better at the ACC case, and All-Cases Joint Model is better at the NOM and DAT cases. One of the possible explanations is that the distribution of ACC cases is different from NOM cases. While the ratio of Dep and Zero argu- ments for ACC cases is 90:10, the ratio for NOM cases is 75:25. This might have some negative effects on the ACC case identification with All- Cases Joint Model. However, in total, All-Cases Joint Model achieves significantly better results. This suggests that capturing case interactions im- proves performance of Japanese PAS analysis.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Existing Methods vs Joint Methods</head><p>To compare our proposed methods with previous work, we pick the three pieces of representative previous work exploiting the NAIST Text Cor-  <ref type="formula" target="#formula_3">(2009)</ref> is the best for the NOM and ACC cases, and Sasano and Kurohashi (2011) the best for the DAT cases. Our joint methods achieve high performance comparable to <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Imamura et al. (2009)</ref>.</p><p>However, because they used additional exter- nal resources and a different version of the NAIST Text Corpus, the results of previous work are not directly comparable to ours. Our research direc- tion and contributions are orthogonal to theirs, and adding their external resources could potentially leads to much better results. 968</p><p>We have presented joint methods for Japanese PAS analysis, which model interactions between mul- tiple predicates and arguments using a bipartite graph and greedily search the optimal PAS combi- nation in a sentence. Experimental results shows that capturing the predicate interaction and case interaction is effective for Japanese PAS analy- sis. In particular, implicit (Zero) argument identi- fication, one of the problematic issues in Japanese PAS analysis, is improved by taking such interac- tions into account. Since this framework is appli- cable to the argument classification in SRL, apply- ing our methods to that task is an interesting line of the future research. In addition, the final results of our joint methods are comparable to represen- tative existing methods despite using no external resources. For future work, we plan to incorporate external resources for our joint methods.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: An example of Japanese PAS. The English translation is "Because ϕ i caught a cold, I i skipped school.". The upper edges are dependency relations, and the under edges are case arguments. "NOM" and "ACC" represents the nominative and accusative arguments, respectively. "ϕ i " is a zeropronoun, referring to the antecedent "watashi i ".</figDesc><graphic url="image-1.png" coords="1,301.75,291.72,212.72,76.00" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2: Intuitive image of a predicate-argument graph. This graph is factorized into the local and global features. The different line color/style indicate different cases.</figDesc><graphic url="image-2.png" coords="3,66.47,87.75,212.60,119.58" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Figure 3: Hill-Climbing for Per-Case Joint Model</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>feature</head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>pus: Taira et al. (2008) (TA08), Imamura et al. (2009) (IM09), and Sasano and Kurohashi (2011) (S&amp;K11). Sasano and Kurohashi (2011) focus on the analysis for the Zero and Inter-Zero arguments, and do not report the results on the Dep arguments. With respect to the Dep arguments, the All-Cases Joint Model achieves the best result for the NOM cases, Imamura et al. (2009) the best for the ACC cases, and Taira et al. (2008) the best for the DAT cases. In terms of the Zero arguments, Imamura et al.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" validated="false"><head>Table 3 presents</head><label>3</label><figDesc>the F-measures of the baseline and our joint methods on the test set of the NAIST Text Corpus. We used the bootstrap resampling method as the significance test. In most of the met- rics, our proposed joint methods outperform the baseline pointwise method. Note that since Per- Case Joint Model yields better results compared with the baseline, capturing the predicate inter- action is beneficial to Japanese PAS analysis. In addition, the joint methods achieve a considerable improvement of 2.0-2.5 points in F-measure for Case Type # of Args.</figDesc><table>Baseline 
PC Joint 
AC Joint 
NOM Dep 
14055 
86.50 
87.54  † 
88.13  †  ‡ 
Zero 
4935 
45.56 
47.62 
48.11 
Total 
18990 
77.31 
78.39  † 
79.03  †  ‡ 
ACC Dep 
9473 
92.84 
⋆ 93.09  † ⋆ 92.74 
Zero 
833 
21.38 
22.73 
24.43 
Total 
10306 
88.86 
⋆ 89.00  † ⋆ 88.47 
DAT 
Dep 
2518 
30.97 
34.29  † 
38.39  †  ‡ 
Zero 
239 
0.83 
0.83 
4.80 
Total 
2757 
29.02 
32.20  † 
36.35  †  ‡ 
ALL Dep 
26046 
85.06 
85.79  † 
86.07  †  ‡ 
Zero 
6007 
41.65 
43.60 
44.09 
Total 
32053 
78.15 
78.91  † 
79.23  †  ‡ 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" validated="false"><head>Table 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>F-measures of the three methods in the test sets. The bold values denote the highest F-measures 
among all the three methods. Statistical significance with p &lt; 0.05 is marked with  † compared with 
Baseline,  ‡ compared with PC Joint, and ⋆ compared with AC Joint. 

Dep 
Zero 
NOM ACC DAT NOM ACC DAT 
TA08 
75.53 88.20 89.51 30.15 11.41 3.66 
IM09 
87.0 
93.9 
80.8 
50.0 
30.8 
0.0 
S&amp;K11 
-
-
-
39.5 
17.5 
8.9 
PC Joint 87.54 93.09 34.19 47.62 22.73 0.83 
AC Joint 88.13 92.74 38.39 48.11 24.44 4.80 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3" validated="false"><head>Table 4 :</head><label>4</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Comparison with previous work using the NAIST Text Corpus in F-measure. TA08 is Taira et 
al. (2008), IM09 is Imamura et al. (2009), and S&amp;K11 is </table></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> We use &quot;PAS analysis&quot; in this paper following previous work on Japanese PAS analysis.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="2"> Around 10-20% in F measure has been achieved in previous work (Taira et al., 2008; Imamura et al., 2009; Sasano and Kurohashi, 2011).</note>

			<note place="foot" n="3"> Performance did not change when increasing the number of restarts</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>We are grateful to the anonymous reviewers. This work is partially supported by a JSPS KAKENHI Grant Number 26730121 and 15K16053.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Discriminative training methods for hidden markov models: Theory and experiments with perceptron algorithms</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Collins</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2002 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP)</title>
		<meeting>the 2002 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP)<address><addrLine>Philadelphia</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2002-07" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="8" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Beyond nombank: A study of implicit arguments for nominal predicates</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Matthew</forename><surname>Gerber</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Joyce</forename><surname>Chai</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 48th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the 48th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics<address><addrLine>Uppsala, Sweden</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010-07" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1583" to="1592" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Association for Computational Linguistics</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Japanese predicate argument structure analysis exploiting argument position and type</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yuta</forename><surname>Hayashibe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mamoru</forename><surname>Komachi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yuji</forename><surname>Matsumoto</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of 5th International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing</title>
		<meeting>5th International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing<address><addrLine>Chiang Mai, Thailand</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="201" to="209" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>November. Asian Federation of Natural Language Processing</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Forest reranking: Discriminative parsing with non-local features</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Liang</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of 46th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics: Human Language Technologies</title>
		<meeting>46th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics: Human Language Technologies<address><addrLine>Columbus, Ohio</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2008-06" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="586" to="594" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Annotating a japanese text corpus with predicate-argument and coreference relations</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ryu</forename><surname>Iida</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mamoru</forename><surname>Komachi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kentaro</forename><surname>Inui</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yuji</forename><surname>Matsumoto</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Linguistic Annotation Workshop</title>
		<meeting>the Linguistic Annotation Workshop<address><addrLine>Prague, Czech Republic</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2007-06" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="132" to="139" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Discriminative approach to predicateargument structure analysis with zero-anaphora resolution</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kenji</forename><surname>Imamura</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kuniko</forename><surname>Saito</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tomoko</forename><surname>Izumi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Joint Conference of the 47th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics and 4th International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing</title>
		<meeting>the Joint Conference of the 47th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics and 4th International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing<address><addrLine>Suntec, Singapore</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2009-08" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="85" to="88" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Impar: A deterministic algorithm for implicit semantic role labelling</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Egoitz</forename><surname>Laparra</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">German</forename><surname>Rigau</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 51st Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the 51st Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics<address><addrLine>Sofia, Bulgaria, August</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1180" to="1189" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Association for Computational Linguistics</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Online learning of approximate dependency parsing algorithms</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ryan</forename><surname>Mcdonald</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Fernando</forename><surname>Pereira</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 11th conference on European Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics (EACL)</title>
		<meeting>the 11th conference on European Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics (EACL)<address><addrLine>Trento, Italy</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006-04" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="81" to="88" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Association for Computational Linguistics</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A discriminative approach to japanese zero anaphora resolution with large-scale lexicalized case frames</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ryohei</forename><surname>Sasano</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sadao</forename><surname>Kurohashi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of 5th International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing</title>
		<meeting>5th International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing<address><addrLine>Chiang Mai, Thailand</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="758" to="766" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>November. Asian Federation of Natural Language Processing</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A japanese predicate argument structure analysis using decision lists</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hirotoshi</forename><surname>Taira</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sanae</forename><surname>Fujita</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Masaaki</forename><surname>Nagata</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2008 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP)</title>
		<meeting>the 2008 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="523" to="532" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Honolulu, Hawaii, October. Association for Computational Linguistics</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Multipredicate semantic role labeling</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Haitong</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chengqing</forename><surname>Zong</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2014 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP)</title>
		<meeting>the 2014 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP)<address><addrLine>Doha, Qatar, October</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="363" to="373" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Association for Computational Linguistics</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Greed is good if randomized: New inference for dependency parsing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yuan</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tao</forename><surname>Lei</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Regina</forename><surname>Barzilay</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tommi</forename><surname>Jaakkola</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2014 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP)</title>
		<meeting>the 2014 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP)<address><addrLine>Doha, Qatar</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014-10" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1013" to="1024" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Association for Computational Linguistics</note>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
