<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T11:47+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">A system for fine-grained aspect-based sentiment analysis of Chinese</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date>July 26-31, 2015. c 2015</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Janna</forename><forename type="middle">Lipenkova</forename><surname>Anacode</surname></persName>
							<email>janna.lipenkova@anacode.de</email>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">A system for fine-grained aspect-based sentiment analysis of Chinese</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of ACL-IJCNLP 2015 System Demonstrations</title>
						<meeting>ACL-IJCNLP 2015 System Demonstrations <address><addrLine>Beijing, China</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="55" to="60"/>
							<date type="published">July 26-31, 2015. c 2015</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>This paper presents a pipeline for aspect-based sentiment analysis of Chinese texts in the automotive domain. The input to the pipeline is a string of Chinese characters; the output is a set of relationships between evaluations and their targets. The main goal is to demonstrate how knowledge about sentence structure can increase the precision, insight value and granularity of the output. We formulate the task of sentiment analysis in two steps, namely unit identification and relation extraction. In unit identification, we identify fairly well-delimited linguistic units which describe features, emotions and evaluations. In relation extraction, we discover the relations between evaluations and their &quot;target&quot; features.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Whereas most work on sentiment analysis, and es- pecially on less covered languages such as Chi- nese, is based on probabilistic models and the use of general sentiment lexica, we believe that a holistic approach should also take into ac- count general linguistic knowledge. On the one hand, this allows to leverage the results of several decades of research in theoretical linguistics. On the other hand, the hard-coding of general prin- ciples of language structure allows us to create a linguistically adequate training space for further application of probabilistic models.</p><p>In the following, we present the "bottom-up" component of our sentiment system which builds opinion representations by a progression along three levels -the lexical, the phrasal and the sen- tence level. The system has been conceptualized manually and bootstrapped on a corpus of about 1 mio. automotive reviews with an average length of 135 Chinese characters. <ref type="bibr">1</ref> We use a prebuilt lex- <ref type="bibr">1</ref> The reviews were crawled from popular automo- icon with ca. 2000 entries which contains opin- ion words, their modifiers, car features as well as a large number of functional categories relevant for the syntactic analysis of phrases and sentences. The performance of the system is evaluated on a testset of 800 annotated sentences. In practice, the presented model is complemented by a probabilis- tic model which performs topic and polarity clas- sification on the sentence and the document levels; this component will not be described below due to space limitations.</p><p>The basic assumption on which the model builds is that language follows rules. Many of these rules have been extensively studied in the linguistic literature and have been taken to a level of abstraction which allows for a straightforward encoding. Incorporating these rules spares us the construction of probabilistic models for the dis- covery of already established general knowledge about linguistic structure. For example, it has long been observed that Chinese phrase struc- ture is largely head-final <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Huang 1982</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b7">, Li 1990</ref>, i. a.): nominal modifiers precede their head nouns, whereas degree and negation adverbs normally precede the adjectives or verbs they modify. Due to the relative rigidity of word order in Chinese on the phrasal level, a small set of correspond- ing phrase-level rules achieves a high coverage on our dataset. Rules do not perform as well on sen- tence level; nevertheless, some general observa- tions are possible: for example, AP targets precede their APs. These high-level observations form the basis of a sequence classifier which determines whether a sequence of words between two syntac- tic phrases establishes or disrupts one of the target relations between these phrases.</p><p>The paper is structured as follows: after a very brief review of research on aspect-based senti- ment analysis (henceforth ABSA), we formulate tive sites: http://www.autohome.com.cn, http:// auto.16888.com, http://auto.qq.com. our task and, specifically, present the output for- mat of the system (Section 3). In the second step, we briefly describe the categories used in our lex- ical resources (Section 4). In the third step, we describe the three levels of processing (Section 5). Finally, we present the evaluation of our system (Section 6).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Previous work</head><p>ABSA has been exploited as a refined alternative to sentiment analysis on the sentence and the doc- ument level: whereas the latter targets the general sentiment or polarity of a piece of text, ABSA out- puts a mapping from specific aspects of the dis- cussed topic to their evaluations. Different ABSA approaches have been exploited; thus, <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Popescu and Etzioni (2005)</ref> and <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Kim and Hovy (2006)</ref> present unsupervised algorithms for extracting as- pects and determining sentiment in review text. <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Ding et al. (2008)</ref> and Liu (2012) describe ap- proaches based on rules of semantic composition and distance metrics for the identification of rela- tions between aspects and their opinions. Due to the relatively fine granularity of the task, parsing- based approaches have been proposed to capture the aspect/sentiment relations based on sentence structure ( <ref type="bibr">Jiang et al. 2011, Boiy and</ref><ref type="bibr">Moens 2009, i. a.)</ref>. Further, the SemEval-2014 task on ABSA ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Pontiki et al., 2014</ref>) has been addressed with a number of promising approaches and also signif- icantly contributed to a unified understanding of ABSA.</p><p>Still, most research is focussed on the English language; for Chinese, most approaches to senti- ment analysis are targeted on lexicon construction (e. g. <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Liu et al. 2013</ref>) or sentence/document-level sentiment classification. <ref type="bibr">2</ref> Only few contributions aim at a finer-grained analysis at the aspect level ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Ku et al. (2009)</ref>, <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Su et al. (2008)</ref>).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Task</head><p>The goal of aspect-based sentiment analysis is to derive the opinions of a speaker about an entity and its features (Liu, 2012, p. 58). In our frame- work, opinions can be subclassified into evalua- tions and emotions. Evaluations express how the author evaluates a specific feature (e. g. good, ex- pensive), whereas emotions express how the au-thor feels about a specific feature (e. g. to please, angry).</p><p>We formulate the task in two stages -the iden- tification of syntactic units and the extraction of relations between the syntactic units. Thus, given an opinion statement on a specific product, we "translate" the statement into a set of (f eature, &lt; evaluation|emotion &gt; ) pairs in two processing steps:</p><p>1. Build three sets of syntactic units F (fea- tures), EV (evaluations) and EM (emo- tions). For convenience, we will use E = EM ∪ EV in cases where the evalua- tion/emotion distinction is not relevant.</p><p>2. For each e ∈ E, find whether it has an opin- ion target f ∈ F .</p><p>A word is in place about the semantic orga- nization of evaluations and emotions in our sys- tem. It has long been observed that many evalu- ation words come with implicit features; for ex- ample, the evaluation beautiful implicitly contains the feature VisualAppearance. In order to preserve this meaning, we adopt a scalar representation of evaluations (cf. <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Kennedy and McNally (2005)</ref> for a linguistic analysis of scalar expressions): eval- uations are represented as pairs of a feature and a numerical value which "maps" the evaluation to some point on the feature scale <ref type="bibr">[-3, 3]</ref>. Thus, beautiful gets the representation (VisualAppear- ance, 2), whereas ugly gets the representation (Vi- sualAppearance, -2). Similarly, emotions are also represented as pairs of the emotion concept and a numerical value representing the intensity of the emotion (e. g. angry: (Anger, 2)).</p><p>The final mapping goes from sequences of fea- tures to numerical evaluations. In a feature se- quence [f 1 , f 2 . . . f n ], features are ordered by the subfeature relation, such that f i (with i &gt; 0) is a subfeature of f i−1 . Consider the following feature expression:</p><p>(1) steering.wheel DE indicator the indicator of the steering wheel Our representation is <ref type="bibr">[SteeringWheel, Indicator]</ref>, whereby Indicator is interpreted as a subfea- ture of SteeringWheel.</p><p>Further, implicit features that are contained in associated evaluations are also "moved" into the feature sequence: <ref type="bibr">(2)</ref> steering.wheel DE indicator very precise The indicator of the steering wheel is very precise.</p><p>This sentence contains the evaluation 'precise'. According to the above description, it is decom- posed into a feature (Precision) and a positive eval- uation. The feature is moved into the feature se- quence. The resulting mapping is as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">(3) [SteeringWheel, Indicator, Precision] → +2</formula><p>Thus, instead of limiting ourselves to entities and restricted sets of their immediate features, we adapt a "higher-order" view and allow a hierarchi- cal feature sequence of arbitrary depth. This struc- ture seamlessly integrates implicit features and flexibly captures any granularity that is intended by the author of the text. At the same time, the value of the evaluation is reduced to a single nu- merical value, which allows for a straightforward aggregation of the final results.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Lexical basis</head><p>Out lexical resources contain functional and se- mantic categories. Members of "functional" cat- egories (e. g. conjunctions, phrase-final markers) are only relevant for the syntactic analysis. Se- mantic categories are relevant for the interpreta- tion of opinions. The top-level semantic categories are:</p><p>• Features, e. g. ('look'), ('seat'), ('color')</p><p>• Evaluations:</p><p>-with implicit features, e. g. ('beautiful' → VisualAppearance), ('cheap' → Price) -without implicit features, e. g.</p><p>('not bad'), ('ordinary'), ('OK')</p><p>• Emotions, e. g. ('admire'), ('an- noying')</p><p>• Degree adverbs and negation words, e. g. ('very'), ('a little bit'), ('not')</p><p>Each of these categories is in turn subclassified into more fine-grained classes which capture in- formation about the linguistic use of the subclass members.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Processing steps</head><p>Figure illustrates the in-and output, the three processing steps as well as the resources involved in these steps.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.1">Preprocessing</head><p>We use the third-party tool jieba 3 for word seg- mentation and POS tagging; both steps are cus- tomized in order to achieve a better performance on domain-and task-specific data. Specifically, the dictionary provided by the tool is inter- sected with a user-specified dictionary. This user- specified dictionary contains all words from our lexical resources. The user-added words are anno- tated with customized POS tags, such as 'F' for feature, 'EV' for evaluation etc. The following two examples depict the same sentence as output by jieba without and with customization:</p><p>(4) a. original jieba output without cus- tomization:</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">/vn rear.row /n space /d already /v make /ud DE /d very /a not.bad /ul PFV /x</formula><p>The rear space is already quite not bad.</p><p>b. after customization:</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">/F rear.space /d already /v make /ud DE /D very /EV not.bad /ul PFV /x</formula><p>The rear space is already quite not bad.</p><p>Thus, we see that the two words ('rear row') and ('space') are merged into one word in the customized output since this combination occurs frequently in automotive texts and has a quasi-lexicalized meaning; the resulting word gets our custom POS tag 'F' (feature). Further, the POS tag of is changed from the original jieba tag 'a' to the custom tag 'EV' (evaluation).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.2">Unit identification</head><p>In the next step, we identify phrasal units corre- sponding to features, evaluations, emotions. We use a phrase rule grammar which is based on reg- ular expressions involving the POS tags of the  <ref type="figure">Figure 2</ref> shows the parsed version of ex- ample (4b).</p><p>In the following, we present some of the most common phrase structures for features and evalu- ations/emotions that are used in our system. front.row / (and) rear.row the front and the rear row Evaluation and emotion chunks The class of evaluations consists of adjectives, whereas the class of emotions consists both of adjectives and verbs. However, evaluations and emotions get a unified treatment at the unit level, since Chinese stative verbs behave similarly to adjectives: they can also be modified by degree adverbs, used in comparative constructions etc.</p><p>Besides simple lexical units, the following are the most frequent phrase types for the E class: (8) a. Verb or adjective preceded by nega- tion or degree adverb: very difficult.to.bear very difficult to bear b. Adjective followed by degree adverb: small PFV a.bit a bit small Evaluations can be coordinated in various ways; for example, coordination can be expressed by simple juxtaposition, with a comma or in the E1 E2 construction:</p><p>(9) a. juxtaposition / punctuation: precise () <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">(,)   flexible  precise and flexible b. E1 E2:    CONJ    precise    CONJ    flexible  both precise and flexible</ref> Besides, evaluations are often expressed by so- called "possessed features": the evaluation value is derived from the "amount" to which a feature is possessed by the discussed entity:</p><p>(10) <ref type="bibr">NEG</ref> have vigor not vigorous</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.3">Relation extraction</head><p>After identifying the syntactic units of interest, we proceed with identifying sentence-level relations between these units. In the literature, there are two major approaches to the identification of rela- tions between evaluations and their targets. On the one hand, some authors recur to parsing and iden- tify evaluation targets based on dependency rela- tions ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Wu et al. 2009</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b3">, Jiang et al. 2011</ref>. On the other hand, distance metrics can be used ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Ding et al., 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Liu, 2012)</ref>. Since we want to avoid the overhead of full-fledged syntactic parsing, but also want to improve the accuracy of simple distance metrics, we develop a sequence classifier which determines whether a given sequence of words be- tween a feature and an evaluation/emotion phrase indicates a target relation.</p><p>The two semantic relations of interest are the causer and the theme relation. Additionally, the system analyzes a third non-semantic relation - the topic -which provides relevant discourse- structural information on the overall aspect dis- cussed in a sentence.</p><p>The causer relation The causer relation is a fairly well-delimited relation which describes the causer of some state of event. In our model, it is applied to emotions caused by specific features. In the most basic cases, the causer is expressed as subject of one of the causative verbs (, etc.):</p><p>(11) power CAUS me very desperate The power really makes me desperate.</p><p>The theme relation The theme relation is ex- pressed differently for evaluations and emotions. In the case of evaluations, it can be realized as the single argument of an AP or the nominal head of an adjectival modifier:  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.4">Relation extraction</head><p>In the above examples, relations hold between ad- joined constituents and can thus be easily recog- nized. However, in many cases, several words oc- cur between the evaluation/emotion and its target: <ref type="bibr">(14)</ref> rear.row space already make DE very not.bad PFV The rear space is already quite not bad.</p><p>From our corpus, we bootstrap the most fre- quent sequences that occur between themes and emotions/evaluations, emotions and themes as well as causers and emotions. We then apply a simple classifier for the classification of unseen se- quences.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Evaluation</head><p>The system is evaluated on a testset of 800 sen- tences annotated for feature, evaluation and emo- tion phrases and for relations between them. The annotation was carried out according to previously developed annotation guidelines; we worked with Precision Recall F-phrases 87.43% 85.37% EV-phrases 89.21 % 84.29% EM-phrases 88.56%</p><p>85.32%  two independent annotators -a native Chinese stu- dent without specialized linguistic knowledge and a non-native linguist with very good mastery of the Chinese language. They proceeded in three steps: at the phrase level, the total F-score of inter- annotator agreement was 91.3%. The diverging items were discussed with a third team member to create a unified phrase-level annotation. The re- viewed corpus was then annotated for relations be- tween opinion and their targets; in this step, inter- annotator agreement reached 93.4%. <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Table 1</ref> shows the results achieved in unit iden- tification; table 2 shows the results achieved for relation extraction on the test set with finalized an- notation of F/EV/EM phrases.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: Overall architecture of the system</figDesc><graphic url="image-2.png" coords="4,83.36,249.59,428.00,112.00" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Feature phrases Besides simple NPs consisting only of one feature word, the most frequent types of feature phrases are phrases with nominal mod- ifiers, coordinated NPs and NPs with pronominal modifiers: (5) NP modifier: seat DE material the material of the seats (6) it DE design its design (7)</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>(</head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" validated="true"><head>Table 1 : Results of unit identification</head><label>1</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Precision Recall 
F-EV relations -theme 89.2% 
87.33% 
F-EM relations -theme 84.01% 
83.10% 
F-EM relations -causer 86.49% 
87.90% 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" validated="false"><head>Table 2 : Results of relation extraction</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table></table></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="2"> Cf. Proceedings of the evaluation task on polarity analysis organized by the Professional Committee of Information Retrieval () 2008-2014.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="3"> https://github.com/fxsjy/jieba</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7">Outlook</head><p>We have shown that the use of a prebuilt lexicon together with the application of general language rules allows to achieve a considerable accuracy in ABSA for Chinese. Currently, the presented sys-tem is being extended with a number of more com-plex sentence-level relations, specifically compar-ative structures and modal operators. Further,</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A machine learning approach to sentiment analysis in multilingual Web texts</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Erik</forename><surname>Boiy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marie-Francine</forename><surname>Moens</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Inf. Retr</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="526" to="558" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A Holistic Lexicon-based Approach to Opinion Mining</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Ding</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Xiaowen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bing</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yu</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Philip</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of WSDM&apos;08, WSDM &apos;08</title>
		<meeting>WSDM&apos;08, WSDM &apos;08</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="231" to="240" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Logical relations in Chinese and the theory of grammar</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">James</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">-T</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1982" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Ph. D.thesis, MIT, Massachusetts</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Target-dependent Twitter Sentiment Classification</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Long</forename><surname>Jiang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Yu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Mo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Zhou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Ming</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Xiaohua</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tiejun</forename><surname>Zhao</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of ACL&apos;11</title>
		<meeting>ACL&apos;11</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="151" to="160" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Scale structure, degree modification, and the semantics of gradable predicates</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christopher</forename><surname>Kennedy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Louise</forename><surname>Mcnally</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Language</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">81</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="345" to="381" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Extracting Opinions, Opinion Holders, and Topics Expressed in Online News Media Text</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Soo-Min</forename><surname>Kim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Eduard</forename><surname>Hovy</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Workshop on Sentiment and Subjectivity in Text, SST &apos;06</title>
		<meeting>the Workshop on Sentiment and Subjectivity in Text, SST &apos;06</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="8" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Using Morphological and Syntactic Structures for Chinese Opinion Analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lunwei</forename><surname>Ku</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chen</forename><surname>Tinghao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hsinhsi</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of EMNLP&apos;09</title>
		<meeting>EMNLP&apos;09</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1260" to="1269" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Order and Constituency in Mandarin Chinese</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Audrey</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Yen-Hui</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Studies in Natural Language and Linguistic Theory</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Dordrecht</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Kluwer Academic Publishers</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1990" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Sentiment Analysis and Opinion Mining</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bing</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Combining Domain-Specific Sentiment Lexicon with Hownet for Chinese Sentiment Analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lizhen</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Lei</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Mengyun</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hanshi</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Computers</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">SemEval2014 Task 4: Aspect Based Sentiment Analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Maria</forename><surname>Pontiki</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Galanis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Dimitris</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Pavlopoulos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>John</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Papageorgiou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Androutsopoulos</forename><surname>Harris</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Ion</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Manandhar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Suresh</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the SemEval&apos;14</title>
		<meeting>the SemEval&apos;14<address><addrLine>Dublin, Ireland</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="27" to="35" />
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>ACL and Dublin City University</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Extracting Product Features and Opinions from Reviews</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ana</forename><surname>Popescu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Maria</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Oren</forename><surname>Etzioni</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of HLT &amp; EMNLP&apos;05</title>
		<meeting>HLT &amp; EMNLP&apos;05<address><addrLine>Stroudsburg, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="339" to="346" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Hidden Sentiment Association in Chinese Web Opinion Mining</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Qi</forename><surname>Su</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Xu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Xinying</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Guo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Honglei</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Guo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Zhili</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Wu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Xian</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Xiaoxun</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Swen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Bin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Su</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Zhong</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of WWW&apos;08</title>
		<meeting>WWW&apos;08</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Phrase Dependency Parsing for Opinion Mining</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yuanbin</forename><surname>Wu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Qi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Xuanjing</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lide</forename><surname>Wu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of EMNLP&apos;09</title>
		<meeting>EMNLP&apos;09<address><addrLine>Stroudsburg, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1533" to="1541" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
