<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T12:42+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">The Discovery of Natural Typing Annotations: User-produced Potential Chinese Word Delimiters</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date>July 26-31, 2015</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dakui</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Beijing Institute of Technology</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Beijing</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yu</forename><surname>Mao</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Beijing Institute of Technology</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Beijing</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yang</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Beijing Institute of Technology</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Beijing</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hanshi</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">Capital Normal University</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Beijing</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chuyuan</forename><surname>Wei</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Beijing Institute of Technology</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Beijing</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Shiping</forename><surname>Tang</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Beijing Institute of Technology</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Beijing</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">The Discovery of Natural Typing Annotations: User-produced Potential Chinese Word Delimiters</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 53rd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics and the 7th International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing</title>
						<meeting>the 53rd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics and the 7th International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing <address><addrLine>Beijing, China</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="662" to="667"/>
							<date type="published">July 26-31, 2015</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Human labeled corpus is indispensable for the training of supervised word segmenters. However, it is time-consuming and labor-intensive to label corpus manually. During the process of typing Chinese text by Pingyin, people usually need to type &quot;space&quot; or numeric keys to choose the words due to homo-phones, which can be viewed as a cue for segmentation. We argue that such a process can be used to build a labeled corpus in a more natural way. Thus, in this paper, we investigate Natural Typing Annotations (NTAs) that are potential word delimiters produced by users while typing Chinese. A detailed analysis on over three hundred user-produced texts containing NTAs reveals that high-quality NTAs mostly agree with gold seg-mentation and, consequently, can be used for improving the performance of supervised word segmentation model in out-of-domain. Experiments show that a classification model combined with a voting mechanism can reliably identify the high-quality NTAs texts that are more readily available labeled corpus. Furthermore, the NTAs might be particularly useful to deal with out-of-vocabulary (OOV) words such as proper names and neo-logisms.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Unlike English text in which sentences are se- quences of words delimited by white spaces, in Chinese text, sentences are usually represented and stored as strings of Chinese characters with- out similar natural delimiters. To find the basic language units, i.e. words, segmentation is a nec- essary initial step for Chinese language pro- cessing.</p><p>Currently most of state-of-the-art methods for Chinese word segmentation (CWS) are based on supervised learning, which depend on large scale annotated corpus. These supervised methods ob- tain high accuracies on newswire <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">(Xue and Shen, 2003;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Zhang and Clark, 2007;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Jiang et al., 2009;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Zhao et al., 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Sun and Xu, 2011</ref>). However, manually annotated training data mostly come from the news domain, and the performance can drop severely when the test data shift from newswire to blogs, computer forums, and Inter- net literature ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Liu and Zhang, 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr">)</ref>.Supervised approaches often have a high requirement on the quality and quantity of annotated corpus, which is always not easy to build. As a result, many previous methods utilize the information of free data which contain limited but useful segmenta- tion information over the Internet, including large-scale unlabeled data, domain-specific lexi- cons and semi-annotated web pages such as Wik- ipedia. There has been work on making use of both unlabeled data ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Li and Sun, 2009;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Sun and Xu, 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Wang et al., 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Qiu et al., 2014</ref>) and Wikipedia ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Jiang et al., 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Liu et al., 2014;</ref>) to improve segmentation. But none of them notice the segmentation information pro- duced by users while typing Chinese.</p><p>Chinese is unique due to its logographic writ- ing system. Chinese users cannot directly type in Chinese words using a QWERTY keyboard. In- put methods have been proposed to assist users to type in Chinese words <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Chen, 1997)</ref>. Substan- tial information has been produced, but not rec- orded and stored during text typing process. method (Sogou-Pinyin). The typical way to type in Chinese words is in a sequential manner ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Wang et al., 2001</ref>). iRearch <ref type="bibr">(2009)</ref> showed that Pinyin input methods have the biggest share of Chinese speakers. We take one of them for example. Suppose users want to type in Chinese word " 今天(today)". Firstly, they mentally generate and physically type in corresponding Pinyin "jintian". Then, a Chinese Pinyin input method displays a list of Chinese homophones, as shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref>. Finally, users visually search the target word from candidates and select numeric key, e.g. '1'-'9'(&lt;NUM#1&gt;- &lt;NUM#9&gt;) or space key (&lt;SPACE&gt;, a shortcut for numeric key '1') to get the target word <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">(Zheng et al., 2011</ref>). Other Chinese input methods, like Wubi, also take these three steps. Typing English words does not involve the last two steps, which indicates that it is on one side more complicated for Chinese users to type in Chinese words than English, but on the other side more convenient for us to obtain additional information produced by users in typing process. We define numeric keys and the space key as selection keys for choosing the target word. For sentence "今天天 气不错。(Nice weather today.)"，one general sequence with selection keys is like " 今天 (today)&lt;SPACE&gt;天气(weather)&lt;NUM#2&gt;不错 (not bad)&lt;SPACE&gt;。" or "今天 (today) &lt;SPA- CE&gt;天气不错 (weather is not bad) &lt;SPACE&gt;。" In a certain sense, these user-produced selection keys play a role of word delimiters in a very nat- ural way.</p><p>In this paper, we propose the concept of Natu- ral Typing Annotations (NTAs) that are potential word delimiters produced by users while typing Chinese words, and verify that it is plausible to automatically generate labeled data for CWS by exploiting NTAs. According to the principle of statistical sampling, texts with NTAs are gath- ered from 384 users. Specifically, since the ul- timate goal is to exploit NTAs to automatically generate labeled data for word segmentation, the main task is to select high-quality NTAs, which largely overlap with gold segmentation. We do this by 1) training a classifier to distinguish ac- ceptable-quality NTAs from low-quality ones, and then 2) using a voting mechanism to further locate the high-quality NTAs among those iden- tified by the classifier in the first step. Experi- ments show that Support Vector Machine (SVM) and voting mechanism are effective for this work and the high-quality NTAs texts can be used as the training data for improving the performance of supervised word segmentation model in out- of-domain. In addition, some evidence is provid- ed that user-produced NTAs might be particular- ly useful to deal with out-of-vocabulary (OOV) words.</p><p>In the rest of the paper, we briefly introduce the gold standard and baseline segmenter of our work in section 2, then describe the definition and characteristic of natural typing annotations (NTAs) in section 3, and finally elaborate on the strategy of locating high-quality NTAs texts in section 4.After giving the experimental results and analysis in section 5, we come to the conclu- sion and the implication of future work.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Gold Standard and Baseline segment- er</head><p>There are many different standards for word segmentation, and different tasks usually need different standards. The Sighan Bakeoff uses four well-known standards made by four differ- ent organizations: Academia Sinica (AS), City University of Hong Kong (CU), Peking Univer- sity (PKU), and Microsoft Research (MSR). In this study, we take MSR segmentation standard as gold standard. Following the work of <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Zhao et al. (2010)</ref> and Sun and Xu (2011), a Conditional Random Fields (CRF) model ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Lafferty et al., 2001</ref>) is trained with the training corpus of MSR from Sighan Bakeoff-2, to be a baseline seg- menter. This general-purpose segmenter is called as CRF+MSR in this paper.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Natural Typing Annotations Texts</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Formulation</head><p>A Chinese sentence is represented as <ref type="bibr">12</ref> </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>... N S c c c  ( i c stands for a Chinese character,</head><p>N is the length of sentence S ). One of the possi- ble sequences with selection keys is defined as</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">1 1 2 1 1 1 1 ( ) | ... | ... | ...| ... | i i i n N S c c c c c c    .</formula><p>Here, we use the symbol "|" instead of each selection key. "|" is the "Natural Typing Annotation (NTA)", which is naturally annotated by users when typ- ing Chinese words. Between the two neighboring "|"s is a segment. Then the user-produced</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">12 ( ) | | | ... | | M segment segment segment S   ( MN  , M</formula><p>is the number of segments in sen- tence S ) is called as NTAs text or NTAs corpus.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Collection of NTAs Texts</head><p>We need to collect user-produced NTAs texts independently because there are no similar or alternative open corpora. We posted a public no- tice on the Internet to gather volunteer partici- pants. For comparison, they were told to type in the same assigned test text while our software recorded the character sequence with NTAs. Two explanations are given as followed. First, to get more users' feedback and keep the signifi- cance level of the experiment, we only have 365 Chinese characters in the test text, which con- tains words with ambiguous meaning, named entities (NEs), neo-logisms and typo-prone words. Even the state-of-the-art segmenters can- not handle this test text very well. Second, ac- cording to statistical sampling theory, if we want a 95% confidence interval to have a margin of error less than 5%, the sample size should be no less than 384. Therefore, we randomly accept 384 volunteers to join our typing experiment and get user-produced NTAs texts from them.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3">Analysis of Collected NTAs Texts</head><p>Users' overall typing habit can be drawn through the analysis of the collected NTAs texts. We firstly focus on segment, because it is the basic unit in our texts. A total of 66,232 segments are obtained from all texts, but only 883 of them are not repeated. Using () Length seg to represent the length of a segment is easy to get a frequency distribution of different () Length seg and find that the length of frequent segments is largely con- centrated during 1 to 4. The same statistics can be conducted separately with the word segmenta- tion results by gold standard and CRF+MSR. We use relative frequencies to illustrate the overall trend of three results, as shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 2</ref>. from three segmentation. The results suggest that most Chinese speakers are reluctant to put a long text string into one segment, which is roughly consistent with behav- ioral economics and psycho-linguistic. Users consciously avoid the mistakes that might be brought by typing in long sequence at a time. Besides, people seldom put illogical sequence of characters into one segment. Taking "主人公严 守 一 把 手 机 给 扔 了 。 (The leading character Yan Shouyi has thrown his cellphone away.) " for example, when participants input "给扔了 (have thrown) ", they choose to type in the mate- rial as "|给|扔|了|", "|给|扔了|" or "|给扔了|". No one types in the material as "|给扔|了|", because "| 给扔|" has no logical meaning in Chinese. Consequently, the constitution of segment is a reflection of natural language logic.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">High-quality NTAs Texts</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">User's Typing Patterns</head><p>In this section, we investigate the collected NTAs texts at the sentence level. Direct visual impression is that different users use different typing patterns to input Chinese. 1 S = "不过评价 在三星级以上的这几款电脑(However, these several computers are assessed with more than 3 stars) " is taken as an example to explain the dif- ferent situations. Just as what is shown in the following, We discover three typing patterns of users. The first one is Discrete Pattern, where the characters belonging to one segment in the light of gold standard are separated into several seg- ments, such as 51 () S  . The second is Adhesive Pattern, which suggests that two or more adja- cent individual words by gold standard come together to form one segment, like 31 () S  and 41 () S  . The third is Acceptable Pattern, where user-produced segmentation is largely or exactly the same with the gold standard, such as 11 () S  and 21 () S  . We find that discrete pattern and adhesive pattern are useless for word segmenta- tion. So we call those NTAs texts that follow acceptable pattern acceptable-quality NTAs texts, and others low-quality ones. Furthermore, among acceptable-quality NTAs texts, some of them are more close to gold standard, which is called as high-quality NTAs texts. Our strategy is 1) to use a classifier to find all acceptable- quality NTAs texts, and then 2) to further locate the high-quality NTAs texts among those identi- fied by the classifier in the previous step.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">The Classification Approach</head><p>Identification of acceptable-quality NTAs texts is a typical binary classification problem. Effective and logical features should be identified to model a classifier. We select the following five features because they are simple but outstanding against other alternatives for this work.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Len, SegNum, SingleSegNum, MaxConSingleSegNum, MaxSegLen</head><formula xml:id="formula_2">Features                   </formula><p>Len is the abbreviation for length of a sen- tence, and SegNum(SN) stands for the number of the segments in a sentence. These two features can be used to determine whether the percentage of character number of a sentence and the seg- ment number of a sentence is in a proper range.</p><p>SingleSegNum(SSN) stands for the number of the segments whose length equals 1 in a sentence. MaxConSingleSegNum(MCSSN) is the maxi- mum number of continuous segments whose length is 1. MaxSegLen(MSL) means the length of segment with most characters. These three features can be used to identify whether discrete or adhesive phenomena prevail in a sentence.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3">The Voting Mechanism</head><p>As the classification approach brings lots of ac- ceptable-quality NTAs texts, voting mechanism is introduced to further locate the high-quality NTAs texts. For a sentence i S , there possibly exist different user-produced segmentations This score helps us to identify high-quality NTAs texts from all acceptable-quality ones.</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">1 () i S  , 2 () i S  , … , () ki S  (k</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Experiments</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.1">Identification of High-quality NTAs Texts</head><p>In this experiment, we verify the effectiveness of classifier and voting mechanism on locating high-quality NTAs texts from 384 collected ones. You can download part of our collected texts from https://github.com/dakuiz/NTAs.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.1.1">The Classification Experiment</head><p>We randomly select 32 NTAs texts that contain 1,089 sentences, and then manually label them to form training set. Taking 1 S mentioned in 4.1 as an example, the manual-labeled training data are shown in table 1. The label 1 and 0 represent ac- ceptable-quality and low-quality NTAs sentence separately.   </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Len SN SSN MCSSN MSL label</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.1.2">The Voting Experiment</head><p>According to voting mechanism in section 4.3, every acceptable-quality NTAs text can get a score to rank itself. Table3 shows top three high- quality NTAs texts with their user-produced word segmentation results compared with that of CRF+MSR. Because CRF+MSR is a general-purpose segmenter and test data does not come from news wire, its performance drops signifi- cantly in out-of-domain. <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">Table 3</ref> suggests that high-quality NTAs texts are very close to gold standard of word segmen- tation. To discover the causes of errors, we man- ually inspected these three texts and found the major error is adhesive phenomenon between simple words. For example, gold segmentation "|这|几|款|" is formed as "|这几款|" by users. This is an error in word segmentation competi- tion, but in some application scenarios, like ma- chine translation, "|这几款|"is better than "|这|几 |款|". Similar phenomena shed light on under- standing what a "word" really is.  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.2">Effectiveness of High-quality NTAs Corpus on Improving Word Segmenta- tion</head><p>It is generally agreed among researchers that us- ers' behavioral patterns maintain consistent over a long period of time ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Zhang et al., 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Stephane, 2009)</ref>. In table 3, we listed top 3 high- quality NTAs texts. Users who generated these three NTAs texts are stable sources to provide more well-segmented texts.</p><p>To evaluate the effectiveness of high-quality NTAs corpus on building training data for seg- menter, we use a web crawler to get 40k Micro- blog (weibo.com) corpus and randomly divided it into 4 equal shares, i.e. A, B, C, T text. The provider of top1 text is invited to retype A text to produce A NTAs text. B and C NTAs texts are separately obtained from other two providers. We use A, B, C NTAs texts as training data to get a CRF segmentation model, which is called as CRF+NTAs. Then we train anther CRF seg- menter with a combination of A, B, C NTAs texts and the training corpus of MSR from Bakeoff-2, called as CRF+MSR+NTAs. We select 1,000 sentences from T text to manually segment by gold standard, and use them to form our test set that contains 6528 characters. The results of the three segmenters on this Micro- blog test set is shown in table 4. The model directly trained by Micro-blog high-quality NTAs corpus is better than general- purpose segmenter but far from the model trained by the combination of MSR and Micro- blog high-quality NTAs corpus. This is the most compelling evidence to show that high-quality NTAs corpus can be used for improving word segmentation model in out-of-domain.  <ref type="table">Table 4</ref>: Segmenters' results on test data. We also find out that the NTAs might be par- ticularly useful to identify OOV words, such as proper names and neo-logisms. If users frequent- ly put some characters in one segment, this seg- ment may be some new word or the new internet slang, such as "白富美(white, rich and pretty) ", " 萌萌哒(very cute)", " 十 动 然 拒 (someone is moved but refuses to become girl/boyfriend)", etc.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Conclusion and Future Work</head><p>In this paper, we investigate Natural Typing An- notations (NTAs) that are potential word delimit- ers generated by Chinese speakers while typing Chinese words. The effectiveness of high-quality NTAs corpus on improving word segmentation is evaluated.</p><p>Though it is convenient for users to read, se- quence of pure characters, namely without any recorded delimiters produced by inputters, loses lots of valuable information, e.g. NTAs. We strongly recommend that NTAs can be recorded in an invisible manner for normal users by domi- nant text editors, such as MS Word, Notepad, vi, emacs, etc.</p><p>In future, we will: 1) collect more NTAs texts from various users; 2) do further work on how to fully leverage NTAs to improve word segmenta- tion; 3) call for dominant text editors to record NTAs.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: Typical Chinese Pinyin input method (Sogou-Pinyin). The typical way to type in Chinese words is in a sequential manner (Wang et al., 2001). iRearch (2009) showed that Pinyin input methods have the biggest share of Chinese speakers. We take one of them for example. Suppose users want to type in Chinese word " 今天(today)". Firstly, they mentally generate and physically type in corresponding Pinyin "jintian". Then, a Chinese Pinyin input method displays a list of Chinese homophones, as shown in Figure 1. Finally, users visually search the target word from candidates and select numeric key, e.g. '1'-'9'(&lt;NUM#1&gt;&lt;NUM#9&gt;) or space key (&lt;SPACE&gt;, a shortcut</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2: Relative frequencies of segment length from three segmentation. The results suggest that most Chinese speakers are reluctant to put a long text string into one segment, which is roughly consistent with behavioral economics and psycho-linguistic. Users consciously avoid the mistakes that might be brought by typing in long sequence at a time. Besides, people seldom put illogical sequence of characters into one segment. Taking "主人公严 守 一 把 手 机 给 扔 了 。 (The leading character Yan Shouyi has thrown his cellphone away.) " for example, when participants input "给扔了 (have thrown) ", they choose to type in the material as "|给|扔|了|", "|给|扔了|" or "|给扔了|". No one types in the material as "|给扔|了|", because "| 给扔|" has no logical meaning in Chinese. Consequently, the constitution of segment is a reflection of natural language logic.</figDesc><graphic url="image-2.png" coords="3,87.75,343.05,184.50,99.50" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" validated="false"><head>Table 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>examples of training data for classifier. Package of libSVM (Chang and Lin, 2011) is used here. Radial basis function is adopted as the kernel function where gamma value is set to 1/num_features and cost value is 1. 10-fold cross validation is used to validate the results. The 1,089 sentences are partitioned into ten parts randomly. Ten runs are performed with each run using a different part as the testing set. It is conducted ten times and every part should be testing set once. Classification accuracy of the experiment is listed in the table 2.</figDesc><table>Num 
Accuracy(%) 
1 
96.33 
2 
97.22 
3 
97.25 
4 
97.25 
5 
89.91 
6 
98.17 
7 
94.50 
8 
94.59 
9 
94.55 
10 
98.11 
Average 
95.79 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" validated="false"><head>Table 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>10-fold cross validation results. Since the results indicate the validity of our classification approach, we use this classifier to handle collected NTAs texts. If 85% of sentences in a text are acceptable-quality, we select this text as acceptable-quality NTAs text. Finally, we obtain 211 acceptable-quality NTAs texts from all 384 collected ones.</figDesc><table></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4" validated="false"><head>Table 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Test text word segmentation results from general-purpose segmenter and top 3 texts.</figDesc><table></table></figure>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>Sincere thanks to the three anonymous re-viewers for their thorough reviewing and valua-ble suggestions! The authors were supported by the National Strategic Basic Research Program ("973" Program) of the Ministry of Science and Technology of <ref type="bibr">China (No. 2012CB720702 and</ref><ref type="bibr">2013CB329303)</ref> and National Science Founda-tion of China (No. 61303105).</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">LIBSVM: A library for support vector machines</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chih-Chung</forename><surname>Chang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chih-Jen</forename><surname>Lin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">TIST</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Chinese Language Processing. Shanghai Education publishing company</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yuan</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
				<ptr target="http://report.iresearch.c-n/1290.html" />
		<title level="m">China Desktop Software Development Research Report</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Automatic adaptation of annotation standards: Chinese word segmentation and pos tagging-a case study</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wenbin</forename><surname>Jiang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Liang</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Qun</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<editor>ACL-AFNLP</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Conditional random fields: Probabilistic models for segmenting and labeling sequence data</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">John</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Lafferty</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Andrew</forename><surname>Mccallum</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Fernando</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Pereira</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ICML</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Punctuation as Implicit Annotations for Chinese Word Segmentation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Zhongguo</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Maosong</forename><surname>Sun</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Computational Linguistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Discriminative Learning with Natural Annotations: Word Segmentation as a Case Study</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wenbin</forename><surname>Jiang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Meng</forename><surname>Sun</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yajuan</forename><surname>Lü</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yating</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Qun</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ACL</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Unsupervised domain adaptation for joint segmentation and POS-tagging</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yang</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yue</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">COLING</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Domain Adaptation for CRF-based Chinese Word Segmentation using Free Annotations</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yijia</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yue</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wanxiang</forename><surname>Che</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ting</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Fan</forename><surname>Wu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">EMNLP</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Automatic Corpus Expansion for Chinese Word Segmentation by Exploiting the Redundancy of Web Information</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xipeng</forename><surname>Qiu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chaochao</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xuanjing</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">COLING</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Enhancing chinese word segmentation using unlabeled data</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Weiwei</forename><surname>Sun</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jia</forename><surname>Xu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">EMNLP</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">User Behavior Patterns: Gathering, Analysis, Simulation and Prediction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lucas</forename><surname>Stephane</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">HCI</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Chinese input with keyboard and eye-tracking: an anatomical study</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jingtao</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Shumin</forename><surname>Zhai</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hui</forename><surname>Su</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">CHI</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Improving chinese word segmentation and pos tagging with semi-supervised methods using large auto-analyzed data</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yiou</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yoshimasa</forename><surname>Jun&amp;apos;ichi Kazama</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wenliang</forename><surname>Tsuruoka</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yujie</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">IJCNLP</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Kentaro Torisawa</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Chinese word segmentation as lmr tagging</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nianwen</forename><surname>Xue</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Libin</forename><surname>Shen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">SIGHAN</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Temporal Pattern of User Behavior in Micro-blog</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chunhong</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yaxi</forename><surname>He</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yang</forename><surname>Ji</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>In JSW</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Chinese segmentation with a word-based perceptron algorithm</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yue</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Stephen</forename><surname>Clark</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ACL</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A unified character-based tagging framework for chinese word segmentation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hai</forename><surname>Zhao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chang-Ning</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mu</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bao-Liang</forename><surname>Lu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ACM</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Why Press Backspace? Understanding User Input Behaviors in Chinese Pinyin Input Method</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yabin</forename><surname>Zheng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lixing</forename><surname>Xie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Zhiyuan</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Maosong</forename><surname>Sun</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yang</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Liyun</forename><surname>Ru</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ACL</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
