<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T13:03+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Improving Evaluation of Machine Translation Quality Estimation</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
				<availability status="unknown"><p>Copyright Association for Computational Linguistics</p>
				</availability>
				<date>July 26-31, 2015. 2015</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yvette</forename><surname>Graham</surname></persName>
							<email>yvette.graham@scss.tcd.ie</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">ADAPT Centre School of Computer Science and Statistics Trinity College Dublin</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Improving Evaluation of Machine Translation Quality Estimation</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 53rd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics and the 7th International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing</title>
						<meeting>the 53rd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics and the 7th International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing <address><addrLine>Beijing, China</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="1804" to="1813"/>
							<date type="published">July 26-31, 2015. 2015</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Quality estimation evaluation commonly takes the form of measurement of the error that exists between predictions and gold standard labels for a particular test set of translations. Issues can arise during comparison of quality estimation prediction score distributions and gold label distributions , however. In this paper, we provide an analysis of methods of comparison and identify areas of concern with respect to widely used measures, such as the ability to gain by prediction of aggregate statistics specific to gold label distributions or by optimally conservative variance in prediction score distributions. As an alternative, we propose the use of the unit-free Pear-son correlation, in addition to providing an appropriate method of significance testing improvements over a baseline. Components of WMT-13 and WMT-14 quality estimation shared tasks are replicated to reveal substantially increased conclusivity in system rankings, including identification of outright winners of tasks.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Machine Translation (MT) Quality Estimation (QE) is the automatic prediction of machine trans- lation quality without the use of reference trans- lations ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Blatz et al., 2004;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Specia et al., 2009)</ref>. Human assessment of translation quality in theory provides the most meaningful evaluation of sys- tems, but human assessors are known to be incon- sistent and this causes challenges for quality es- timation evaluation. For instance, there is a gen- eral lack of consensus both with respect to what provides the most meaningful gold standard rep- resentation, as well as best method of compari- son of gold labels and system predictions. For ex- ample, in the 2014 Workshop on Statistical Ma- chine Translation (WMT), which since 2012 has provided a main venue for evaluation of systems, sentence-level systems were evaluated with re- spect to three distinct gold standard representa- tions and each of those compared to predictions using four different measures, resulting in a total of 12 different system rankings, 6 identified as of- ficial rankings ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Bojar et al., 2014)</ref>.</p><p>Although the aim of several methods of evalua- tion is to provide more insight into performance of systems, this also produces conflicting results and raises the question which method of evaluation re- ally identifies the system(s) or method(s) that best predicts translation quality. For example, an ex- treme case in WMT-14 occurred for sentence-level quality estimation for English-to-Spanish. In each of the 12 system rankings, many systems were tied and this resulted in a total of 22 official winning systems for this language pair. Besides leaving po- tential users of quality estimation systems at a loss as to what the best system may be, a large number of inconclusive evaluation methodologies is also likely to lead to confusion about which evaluation methods should be applied in general in QE re- search, or worse still, researchers simply choos- ing the methodology that favors their system from among the many different methodologies.</p><p>In this paper, we provide an analysis of each of the methodologies used in WMT and widely ap- plied to evaluation of quality estimation systems in general. Our analysis reveals potential flaws in existing methods and we subsequently provide de- tail of a single method that overcomes previous challenges. To demonstrate, we replicate com-ponents of evaluations previously carried out at WMT-13 and WMT-14 sentence-level quality es- timation shared tasks. Results reveal substantially more conclusive system rankings, revealing out- right winners that had not previously been identi- fied.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Relevant Work</head><p>The Workshop on Statistical Machine Transla- tion (WMT) provides a main venue for evalua- tion of quality estimation systems, in addition to the rare and highly-valued effort of provision of publicly available data sets to facilitate further re- search. We provide an analysis of current evalu- ation methodologies applied not only in the most recent WMT shared task but also widely within quality estimation research.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">WMT-style Evaluation</head><p>WMT-14 quality estimation evaluation at the sentence-level, Task 1, is comprised of three sub- tasks. In Task 1.1, human gold labels comprise three levels of translation quality or "perceived post-edit effort" (1 = perfect translation; 2 = near miss translation; 3 = very low quality translation). A possible downside of the evaluation methodol- ogy applied in Task 1.1 is firstly that the gold stan- dard representation may be overly coarse-grained. Considering the vast range of possible errors oc- curring in translations, limiting the levels of trans- lation quality to only three may impact negatively on systems' ability to discriminate between trans- lations of various quality.</p><p>More importantly, however, the combination of such coarse-grained gold labels (1, 2 or 3) and comparison of gold labels and system predictions by mean absolute error (MAE) has a counter- intuitive effect on system rankings, as systems that produce continuous predictions are at an advan- tage over those that produce discrete predictions even though gold labels are also discrete. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure  1</ref>(a) shows discrete gold label distributions for the scoring variant of Task 1.1 in WMT-14 and <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure  1</ref>(b) prediction distributions for an example sys- tem that was at a disadvantage because it restricted its predictions to discrete ratings like those of gold labels, and <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref>(c) a system that achieves ap- parent better performance (lower MAE) despite prediction representations mismatching the dis- crete nature of gold labels.</p><p>Evaluation of the ranking variant of Task 1.1 r Post-edit Time 0.36 Post-edit Rate 0.69 * * * <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>: Pearson correlation with HTER scores of post-edit times (PETs) and post-edit rates (PERs) for WMT-14 Task 1.2 and Task 1.3 gold labels, correlation marked with * * * is significantly greater at p &lt; 0.001.</p><p>again includes a significant mismatch between representations used as gold labels, which again were limited to the ratings 1, 2 or 3, while sys- tems were required to provide a total-order rank- ing of test set translations, for example ranks 1- 600 or 1-450, depending on language pair. Evalu- ation methodologies applied to ranking tasks may be better facilitated by application of more fine- grained gold standard labels that more closely rep- resent total-order rankings of system predictions. Evaluation methodologies applied in Task 1.3 employ the more fine-grained post-edit times (PETs) as translation quality gold labels. PETs potentially provide a good indication of the un- derlying quality of translations, as a translation that takes longer to manually correct is thought to have lower quality. However, we propose what may correspond more directly to translation qual- ity is an alteration of this, a post-edit rate (PER), where PETs are normalized by the number of words in translations. This takes into account the fact that, all else being equal, longer translations simply take a greater amount of time to post-edit than shorter ones. To investigate to what degree PERs may correspond better to translation quality than PETs, we compute correlations of each with HTER gold labels of translations from Task 1.2. <ref type="table">Table 6</ref> reveals a significantly higher correlation that exists between PER and HTER compared to PET and HTER (p &lt; 0.001) , and we conclude therefore that the PER of a translation provides a more faithful representation of translation quality than PET, and convert PETs for both predictions and gold labels to PERs (in seconds per word) in our later replication of Task 1.3.</p><p>In Task 1.2 of WMT-14, gold standard labels used to evaluate systems were in the form of hu- man translation error rates (HTERs) <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(Snover et al., 2009)</ref>. HTER scores provide an effective representation for evaluation of quality estima-   <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref>: WMT-14 English-to-German quality estimation Task 1.1 where mismatched prediction/gold labels achieves apparent better performance, where (a) gold label distribution; (b) example system disad- vantaged by its discrete predictions; (c) example system gaining advantage by its continuous predictions. tion systems, as scores are individually computed per translation using custom post-edited reference translations, avoiding the bias that can occur with metrics that employ generic reference translations. In our later evaluation, we therefore use HTER scores in addition to PERs as suitable gold stan- dard labels.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">Mean Absolute Error</head><p>Mean absolute error is likely the most widely ap- plied comparison measure of quality estimation system predictions and gold labels, in addition to being the official measure applied to scoring vari- ants of tasks in WMT ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Bojar et al., 2014</ref>). MAE is the average absolute difference that exists between a system's predictions and gold standard labels for translations, and a system achieving a lower MAE is considered a better system. Significant issues arise for evaluation of quality estimation systems with MAE when comparing distributions for pre- dictions and gold labels, however. Firstly, a sys- tem's MAE can be lowered not only by individ- ual predictions closer to corresponding gold la- bels, but also by prediction of aggregate statistics specific to the distribution of gold labels in the par- ticular test set used for evaluation. MAE is most susceptible in this respect when gold labels have a unimodal distribution with relatively low stan- dard deviation. For example, <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 2</ref>(a) shows test set gold label HTER distribution for Task 1.2 in WMT-14 where the bulk of HTERs are located around one main peak with relatively low variance in the distribution. Unfortunately with MAE, a system that correctly predicts the location of the mode of the test set gold distribution and centers predictions around it with an optimally conserva- tive variance can achieve lower MAE and appar- ent better performance. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 2</ref>(b) shows a lower MAE can be achieved by rescaling the original prediction distribution for an example system to a distribution with lower variance.</p><p>A disadvantage of an ability to gain in perfor- mance by prediction of such features of a given test set is that prediction of aggregates is, in gen- eral, far easier than individual predictions. In ad- dition, inclusion of confounding test set aggre- gates such as these in evaluations will likely lead to both an overestimate of the ability of some sys- tems to predict the quality of unseen translations and an underestimate of the accuracy of systems that courageously attempt to predict the quality of translations in the tails of gold distributions, and it follows that systems optimized for MAE can be expected to perform badly when predicting the quality of translations in the tails of gold label dis- tributions ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Moreau and Vogel, 2014)</ref>. <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Table 2</ref> shows how MAEs of original predicted score distributions for all systems participating in Task 1.2 WMT-14 can be reduced by shifting and rescaling the prediction score distribution accord- ing to gold label aggregates. <ref type="table">Table 3</ref> shows that for similar reasons other measures commonly ap- plied to evaluation of quality estimation systems, such as root mean squared error (RMSE), that are also not unit-free, encounter the same problem.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3">Significance Testing</head><p>In quality estimation, it is common to apply boot- strap resampling to assess the likelihood that a de- crease in MAE (an improvement) has occurred by chance. In contrast to other areas of MT, where the accuracy of randomized methods of signifi-    <ref type="table">Table 3</ref>: RMSE of WMT-14 Task 1.2 systems for original HTER prediction distributions and when distributions are shifted and rescaled to the mean and half the standard deviation of the gold label distribution.</p><note type="other">FBK-UPV-UEDIN-nowp 0.181 0.180 SHEFF-lite-sparse 0.184 0.179 baseline 0.195 0.194 DFKI-svr-xdata 0.195 0.187 Multilizer 0.209 0.181 SHEFF-lite 0.234 0.216</note><p>cance testing such as bootstrap resampling in com- bination with BLEU and other metrics have been empirically evaluated <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(Koehn, 2004;</ref>), to the best of our knowledge no re- search has been carried out to assess the accuracy of similar methods specifically for quality estima- tion evaluation. In addition, since data used for evaluation of quality estimation systems are not independent, methods of significance testing dif- ferences in performance will be inaccurate unless the dependent nature of the data is taken into ac- count.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Quality Estimation Evaluation by Pearson Correlation</head><p>The Pearson correlation is a measure of the linear correlation between two variables, and in the case of quality estimation evaluation this amounts to the linear correlation between system predictions and gold labels. Pearson's r overcomes the out- lined challenges of previous approaches, such as mean absolute error, for several reasons. Firstly, Pearson's r is a unit-free measure with a key prop- erty being that the correlation coefficient is invari- ant to separate changes in location and scale in either of the two variables. This has the obvious advantage over MAE that the coefficient cannot be altered by shifting or rescaling prediction score distributions according to aggregates specific to the test set. To illustrate, <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Figure 3</ref> depicts a pair of systems for which the baseline system appears to outper- form the other when evaluated with MAE, but this is only due to the conservative variance in its pre-0.0 0.2 0.4 0.6 0.8 1.0 0.0 0. <ref type="bibr">2</ref>   numbers of standard deviations from the mean of each distribution, where CMU-ISL-FULL in fact achieves a significantly higher correlation than the baseline system at p &lt; 0.001.</p><p>An additional advantage of the Pearson corre- lation is that coefficients do not change depend- ing on the representation used in the gold standard in the way they do with MAE, making possible a comparison of performance across evaluations that employ different gold label representations. Addi- tionally, there is no longer a need for training and test representations to directly correspond to one another. To demonstrate, in our later evaluation we include the evaluation of systems trained on both HTER and PETs for prediction of both HTER and PERs.</p><p>Finally, when evaluated with the Pearson cor- relation significance tests can be applied without resorting to randomized methods, in addition to taking into account the dependent nature of data used in evaluations.</p><p>The fact that the Pearson correlation is invariant to separate shifts in location and scale of either of the two variables is nonproblematic for evaluation of quality estimation systems. Take, for instance, the possible counter-argument: a pair of systems, one of which predicts the precise gold distribution, and another system predicting the gold distribution + 1, would unfairly receive the same Pearson cor- relation coefficient. Firstly, it is just as difficult to predict the gold distribution + 1, as it is to pre- dict the gold distribution itself. More importantly, however, the scenario is extremely unlikely to oc- cur in practice, it is highly unlikely that a system would ever accurately predict the gold distribution + 1, as opposed to the actual gold distribution un- less training labels were adjusted in the same man- ner, or indeed predict the gold distribution shifted or rescaled by any other constant value. It is im- portant to understand that invariance of the Pear-son correlation to a shift in location or scale means that the measure is only invariant to a shift in loca- tion or scale applied to the entire distribution (of either of the two variables), such as the shift in location and scale that can be used to boost appar- ent performance of systems when measures like MAE and RMSE, that are not unit-free, are em- ployed. Increasing the distance between system predictions and gold labels for anything less than the entire distribution, a more realistic scenario, or by something other than a constant across the entire distribution, will result in an appropriately weaker Pearson correlation.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Quality Estimation Significance Testing</head><p>Previous work has shown the suitability of Williams significance test <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(Williams, 1959)</ref> for evaluation of automatic MT metrics ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Graham et al., 2015)</ref>, and, for sim- ilar reasons, Williams test is appropriate for signif- icance testing differences in performance of com- peting quality estimation systems which we detail further below. Evaluation of a given quality estimation system, P new , by Pearson correlation takes the form of quantifying the correlation, r(P new , G), that ex- ists between system prediction scores and corre- sponding gold standard labels, and contrasting this correlation with the correlation for some baseline system, r(P base , G).</p><p>At first it might seem reasonable to perform sig- nificance testing in the following manner when an increase in correlation with gold labels is ob- served: apply a significance test separately to the correlation of each quality estimation system with gold labels, with the hope that the new system will achieve a significant correlation where the base- line system does not. The reasoning here is flawed however: the fact that one correlation is signifi- cantly higher than zero (r(P new , G)) and that of another is not, does not necessarily mean that the difference between the two correlations is signif- icant. Instead, a specific test should be applied to the difference in correlations on the data. For this same reason, confidence intervals for individ- ual correlations with gold labels are also not use- ful.</p><p>In psychology, it is often the case that sam- ples that data are drawn from are independent, and differences in correlations are computed on independent data sets. In such cases, the Fisher r to z transformation is applied to test for sig- nificant differences in correlations. Data used for evaluation of quality estimation systems are not independent, however, and this means that if r(P base , G) and r(P new , G) are both &gt; 0, the cor- relation between both sets of predictions them- selves, r(P base , P new ), must also be &gt; 0. The strength of this correlation, directly between pre- dictions of pairs of quality estimation systems, should be taken into account using a signifi- cance test of the difference in correlation between r(P base , G) and r(P new , G).</p><p>Williams test <ref type="bibr">1 (Williams, 1959)</ref> evaluates the significance of a difference in dependent correla- tions <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">(Steiger, 1980)</ref>. It is formulated as follows as a test of whether the population correlation be- tween X 1 and X 3 equals the population correla- tion between X 2 and X 3 :</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">t(n − 3) = (r 13 − r 23 ) (n − 1)(1 + r 12 ) 2K (n−1) (n−3) + (r 23 +r 13 ) 2 4 (1 − r 12 ) 3 ,</formula><p>where r ij is the correlation between X i and X j , n is the size of the population, and: As part of this research, we have made avail- able an open-source implementation of statisti- cal tests tailored to the assessment of quality es- timation systems, at https://github.com/ ygraham/mt-qe-eval.</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">K = 1 −</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Evaluation and Discussion</head><p>To demonstrate the use of the Pearson correlation as an effective mechanism for evaluation of quality estimation systems, we rerun components of pre- vious evaluations originally carried out at WMT- 13 and WMT-14. <ref type="table">Table 4</ref> shows Pearson correlations for systems participating in WMT-13 Task 1.1 where gold la- bels were in the form of HTER scores. System rankings diverge considerably from original rank- ings, notably the top system according to the Pear- son correlation is tied in fifth place when evaluated with MAE.  of systems.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.1">Significance Tests</head><p>When an increase in correlation with gold labels is present for a pair of systems, significance tests provide insight into the likelihood that such an in- crease has occurred by chance. As described in detail in Section 4, the Williams test <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(Williams, 1959)</ref>, a test also appropriate for MT metrics eval- uated by the Pearson correlation ( , is appropriate for testing the sig- nificance of a difference in dependent correlations and therefore provides a suitable method of signif- icance testing for quality estimation systems. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Fig- ure 4</ref> provides an example of the strength of cor- relations that commonly exist between predictions of quality estimation systems. <ref type="figure">Figure 5</ref> shows significance test outcomes of the Williams test for systems originally taking part in WMT-13 Task 1.1, with systems ordered by strongest to least Pearson correlation with gold la- bels, where a green cell in (row i, column j) signi- fies a significant win for row i system over column j system, where darker shades of green signify conclusions made with more certainty. Test out- comes allow identification of significant increases  Figure 5: HTER prediction significance test out- comes for all pairs of systems from English-to- Spanish WMT-13 Task 1.1, colored cells denote a significant increase in correlation with gold labels for row i system over column j system.</p><p>in correlation with gold labels of one system over another, and subsequently the systems shown to outperform others. Test outcomes in <ref type="figure">Figure 5</ref> re- veal substantially increased conclusivity in sys- tem rankings made possible with the application of the Pearson correlation and Williams test, with almost an unambiguous total-order ranking of sys- tems and an outright winner of the task. <ref type="figure">Figure 6</ref> shows outcomes of Williams signifi- cance tests for prediction of HTER and <ref type="figure">Figure 7</ref> shows outcomes of tests for PER prediction for WMT-14 English-to-Spanish, again showing sub- stantially increased conclusivity in system rank- ings for tasks.</p><p>It is important to note that the number of com- peting systems a system significantly outperforms should not be used as the criterion for ranking competing quality estimation systems, since the power of the Williams test changes depending on the degree to which predictions of a pair of sys- tems correlate with each other. A system with pre- dictions that happen to correlate strongly with pre- dictions of many other systems would be at an un- fair advantage, were numbers of significant wins to be used to rank systems. For this reason, it is <ref type="figure">Figure 7</ref>: PER prediction significance test out- comes for all pairs of systems from English-to- Spanish WMT-14 Task 1.3, colored cells denote a significant increase in correlation with gold labels for row i system over column j system. best to interpret pairwise system tests in isolation.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Conclusion</head><p>We have provided a critique of current widely used methods of evaluation of quality estimation sys- tems and highlighted potential flaws in existing methods, with respect to the ability to boost scores by prediction of aggregate statistics specific to the particular test set in use or conservative variance in prediction distributions. We provide an alternate mechanism, and since the Pearson correlation is a unit-free measure, it can be applied to evaluation of quality estimation systems avoiding the previ- ous vulnerabilities of measures such as MAE and RMSE. Advantages also outlined are that training and test representations no longer need to directly correspond in evaluations as long as labels com- prise a representation that closely reflects transla- tion quality. We demonstrated the suitability of the proposed measures through replication of compo- nents of WMT-13 and WMT-14 quality estima- tion shared tasks, revealing substantially increased conclusivity of system rankings.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>1</head><label>1</label><figDesc></figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2: Comparison of example system from WMT-14 English-to-Spanish Task 1.2 (a) original prediction distribution and gold labels and (b) the same when the prediction distribution is rescaled to half its original standard deviation, showing a lower MAE can be achieved by reducing the variance in prediction distributions.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>Figure 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Figure 3: WMT-13 Task 1.1 systems showing baseline with better MAE than CMU-ISL-FULL only due to conservative variance in prediction distribution and despite its weaker correlation with gold labels.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head>Figure 4 :</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Figure 4: Pearson correlation between prediction scores for all pairs of systems participating in WMT-14 Task 1.2</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" validated="false"><head>Table 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>MAE of WMT-14 Task 1.2 systems for 
original HTER prediction distributions and when 
distributions are shifted and rescaled to the mean 
and half the standard deviation of the gold label 
distribution. 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4" validated="false"><head>Table 5 shows</head><label>5</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Pearson correlations of systems 
that took part in Task 1.2 of WMT-14, where gold 
labels were again in the form of HTER scores, </table></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> Also known as Hotelling-Williams.</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgements</head><p>We wish to thank the anonymous reviewers for their valu-able comments and WMT organizers for the provision of data sets. This research is supported by Science Foundation Ire-land through the CNGL Programme (Grant 12/CE/I2267) in the ADAPT Centre (www.adaptcentre.ie) at Trinity College Dublin.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>System</head><p>r MAE DCU-SYMC-rc 0.595 0.135 SHEFMIN-FS 0.575 0.124 DCU-SYMC-ra 0.572 0.135 CNGL-SVRPLS 0.560 0.133 CMU-ISL-noB 0.516 0.138 CNGL-SVR 0.508 0.138 CMU-ISL-full 0. <ref type="bibr">494</ref>   <ref type="table">Table 4</ref>: Pearson correlation and MAE of system HTER predictions and gold labels for English-to- Spanish WMT-13 Task 1.1.</p><p>and to demonstrate the ability of evaluation of sys- tems trained on a representation distinct from that of gold labels made possible by the unit-free Pear- son correlation, we also include evaluation of sys- tems originally trained on PET labels to predict HTER scores. Since PET systems also produce predictions in the form of PET, we convert pre- dictions for all systems to PERs prior to compu- tation of correlations, as PERs more closely cor- respond to translation quality. Results reveal that systems originally trained on PETs in general per- form worse than HTER trained systems, and this is not all that surprising considering the training representation did not correspond well to transla- tion quality. Again system rankings diverge from MAE rankings with the second best system ac- cording to MAE moved to the initial position. <ref type="table">Table 6</ref> shows Pearson correlations for predic- tions of PER for systems trained on either PETs or HTER, and predictions for systems trained on PETs are converted to PER for evaluation. Sys- tem rankings diverge most for this data set from the original rankings by MAE, as the system hold- ing initial position according to MAE moves to po- sition 13 according to the Pearson correlation.</p><p>Many of the differences in correlation between systems in Tables 4, 5 and 6 are small and instead of assuming that an increase in correlation of one system over another corresponds to an improve- ment in performance, we first apply significance testing to differences in correlation with gold la- bels that exist between correlations for each pair   <ref type="table">Table 6</ref>: Pearson correlation of system PER pre- dictions and gold labels for English-to-Spanish WMT-14 Task 1.2 and 1.3 systems trained on ei- ther HTER or PET labelled data, mean absolute error (MAE) provided are in seconds per word.</p></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Pet−fbk−upv−</forename><surname>Uedin−wp</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hter</forename><surname>Dfki−svr−xdata</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Pet</forename><surname>Dcu−rtm−rr</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hter−</forename><surname>Multilizer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hter−fbk−upv−</forename><surname>Uedin−nowp</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hter−</forename><surname>Sheff−lite−sparse</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hter−usheff Hter−</forename><surname>Dfki−svr</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hter</forename><surname>Dcu−rtm−tree</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hter−fbk−upv−</forename><surname>Uedin−wp</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hter</forename><surname>Dcu−rtm−svr</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">2, colored cells denote a significant increase in correlation with gold labels for row i system over column j system</title>
		<author>
			<orgName type="collaboration">HTER.FBK.UPV.UEDIN.wp PET.FBK.UPV.UEDIN.wp HTER.FBK.UPV.UEDIN.nowp HTER.USHEFF HTER.DCU.rtm.svr HTER.DCU.rtm.tree HTER.SHEFF.lite.sparse PET.DCU.rtm.rr PET.FBK.UPV.UEDIN.nowp HTER.DFKI.svr PET.USHEFF PET.baseline</orgName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">PET.DCU.rtm.svr HTER.Multilizer PET.SHEFF.lite.sparse PET.SHEFF.lite PET.Multilizer.1 HTER.baseline HTER.DFKI.svr.xdata PET.Multilizer.2 HTER.SHEFF.lite HTER−SHEFF−lite PET−Multilizer−</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>HTER prediction significance test outcomes for all pairs of systems from English-toSpanish WMT-14 Task 1.</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Hter−dfki−svr−xdata</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Pet−fbk−upv−</forename><surname>Hter−dfki−svr</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Pet</forename><surname>Uedin−nowp</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hter−</forename><surname>Dcu−rtm−rr</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hter</forename><surname>Sheff−lite−sparse</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hter</forename><surname>Dcu−rtm−tree</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hter−</forename><surname>Dcu−rtm−svr</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Usheff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Confidence estimation for machine translation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hter−fbk−upv−</forename><surname>Uedin−nowp</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Pet−fbk−upv−</forename><surname>Uedin−wp</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hter−fbk−upv−</forename><surname>Uedin−wp References</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Blatz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Fitzgerald</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Foster</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Gandrabur</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Goutte</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Kulesza</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Sanchis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Ueffing</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 20th international conference on Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the 20th international conference on Computational Linguistics</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="315" to="321" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Bojar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Buck</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Federmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Haddow</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Koehn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Leveling</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Monz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Pecina</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Post</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Saint-Amand</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Soricut</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Specia</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Tamchyna</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Findings of the 2014 Workshop on Statistical Machine Translation</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Proc. 9th</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Statistical Machine Translation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Wkshp</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Baltimore, MA</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Testing for significance of increased correlation with human judgment</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Graham</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Baldwin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</title>
		<meeting>the Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing<address><addrLine>Doha, Qatar</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="172" to="176" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Association for Computational Linguistics</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Randomized significance tests in machine translation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Graham</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Mathur</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Baldwin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<monogr>
				<title level="m">Proceedings of the ACL 2014 Ninth Workshop on Statistical Machine Translation</title>
		<meeting>the ACL 2014 Ninth Workshop on Statistical Machine Translation</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="266" to="274" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Association for Computational Linguistics</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Accurate evaluation of segment-level machine translation metrics</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yvette</forename><surname>Graham</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nitika</forename><surname>Mathur</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Timothy</forename><surname>Baldwin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2015 Conference of the North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics Human Language Technologies</title>
		<meeting>the 2015 Conference of the North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics Human Language Technologies<address><addrLine>Denver, Colorado</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Statistical significance tests for machine translation evaluation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Koehn</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</title>
		<meeting>of Empirical Methods in Natural Language essing<address><addrLine>Barcelona, Spain</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="388" to="395" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Association for Computational Linguistics</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Limitations of mt quality estimation supervised systems: The tails prediction problem</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Moreau</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Vogel</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of COLING 2014, the 25th International Conference on Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>COLING 2014, the 25th International Conference on Computational Linguistics</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2205" to="2216" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Fluency, adequacy, or hter?: exploring different human judgments with a tunable mt metric</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Snover</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Madnani</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Dorr</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Schwartz</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Fourth Workshop on Statistical Machine Translation</title>
		<meeting>the Fourth Workshop on Statistical Machine Translation</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="259" to="268" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Association for Computational Linguistics</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Estimating the sentence-level quality of machine translation systems</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Specia</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Turchi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Cancedda</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Dymetman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Cristianini</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">13th Conference of the European Association for Machine Translation</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="28" to="37" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Tests for comparing elements of a correlation matrix</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Steiger</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Bulletin</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">87</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">245</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1980" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Regression analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Williams</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1959" />
			<publisher>Wiley</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
			<pubPlace>New York</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
