<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T10:19+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">WriteAhead: Mining Grammar Patterns in Corpora for Assisted Writing</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date>July 26-31, 2015. c 2015</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tzu-Hsi</forename><surname>Yen</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">+National Academy for Educational Research Minstry of Education Taipei</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">National Tsing Hua University Hsinchu</orgName>
								<address>
									<postBox>R.O.C. 30013</postBox>
									<postCode>30013</postCode>
									<country>Taiwan, Taiwan, R.O.C</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jian-Cheng</forename><surname>Wu+</surname></persName>
							<email>{joe, jiancheng}@nlplab.cc</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">+National Academy for Educational Research Minstry of Education Taipei</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">National Tsing Hua University Hsinchu</orgName>
								<address>
									<postBox>R.O.C. 30013</postBox>
									<postCode>30013</postCode>
									<country>Taiwan, Taiwan, R.O.C</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Joanne</forename><surname>Boisson</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">+National Academy for Educational Research Minstry of Education Taipei</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">National Tsing Hua University Hsinchu</orgName>
								<address>
									<postBox>R.O.C. 30013</postBox>
									<postCode>30013</postCode>
									<country>Taiwan, Taiwan, R.O.C</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jim</forename><surname>Chang</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">+National Academy for Educational Research Minstry of Education Taipei</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">National Tsing Hua University Hsinchu</orgName>
								<address>
									<postBox>R.O.C. 30013</postBox>
									<postCode>30013</postCode>
									<country>Taiwan, Taiwan, R.O.C</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jason</forename><surname>Chang</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">+National Academy for Educational Research Minstry of Education Taipei</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">National Tsing Hua University Hsinchu</orgName>
								<address>
									<postBox>R.O.C. 30013</postBox>
									<postCode>30013</postCode>
									<country>Taiwan, Taiwan, R.O.C</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">WriteAhead: Mining Grammar Patterns in Corpora for Assisted Writing</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of ACL-IJCNLP 2015 System Demonstrations</title>
						<meeting>ACL-IJCNLP 2015 System Demonstrations <address><addrLine>Beijing, China</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="139" to="144"/>
							<date type="published">July 26-31, 2015. c 2015</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>This paper describes WriteAhead, a resource-rich, Interactive Writing Environment that provides L2 learners with writing prompts, as well as &quot;get it right&quot; advice, to helps them write fluently and accurately. The method involves automatically analyzing reference and learner corpora , extracting grammar patterns with example phrases, and computing dubious, overused patterns. At run-time, as the user types (or mouses over) a word, the system automatically retrieves and displays grammar patterns and examples, most relevant to the word. The user can opt for patterns from a general corpus, academic corpus, learner corpus, or commonly overused dubious patterns found in a learner corpus. WriteAhead proactively engages the user with steady, timely, and spot-on information for effective assisted writing. Preliminary experiments show that WriteA-head fulfills the design goal of fostering learner independence and encouraging self-editing, and is likely to induce better writing, and improve writing skills in the long run.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>The British Council has estimated that roughly a billion people are learning and using English around the world (British Council 1997), mostly as a second language, and the numbers are grow- ing. Clearly, many of L2 speakers of English feel themselves to be at a disadvantage in work that requires communication in English. For exam- ple, <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Flowerdew (1999)</ref> reports that a third of Hong Kong academics feel disadvantged in publishing a paper internationally, as compared to native speak- ers.</p><p>These L2 speakers and learners provide moti- vation for research and development of computer assisted language learning, in particular tools that help identify and correct learners' writing errors. Much work has been done on developing tech- nologies for automated gramatical error correc- tion (GEC) to assist language learners <ref type="bibr">(Leacock, Chodorow, Gamon, and Tetreault 2010)</ref>. How- ever, such efforts have not led to the development of a production system <ref type="bibr">(Wampler, 2002</ref>).</p><p>However, Milton (2010) pointed out that fo- cusing on fully-automatic, high quality GEC so- lutions has overlooked the long-term pedagogi- cal needs of L2 learner writers. Learners could be more effectively assisted in an interactive writring environment (IWE) that constantly pro- vides context-sensitive writing suggestions, right in the process of writing or self-editing.</p><p>Consider an online writer who starts a sentence with "This paper discusses ...." The best way the system can help is probably displaying the patterns related to the last word discuss such as discuss something and discusses with someone, that help the user to write accurately and fluently. If the user somehow writes or pastes in some incorrect sen- tence, "This paper discusses about the influence of interference and reflection of light." The best way the system can help is probably displaying the er- roneous or overused pattern, discuss about some- thing, that prompts the user to change the sentence to "This paper discusses the influence of interfer- ence and reflection of light."</p><p>Intuitively, by extracting and displaying such patterns and examples, distilled from a very large corpus, we can guide the user towards writing flu- ently, and free of grammatical errors.</p><p>We present a new system, WriteAhead, that proactively provides just-in-time writing sugges- tions to assist student writers, while they type away. Example WriteAhead suggestions for "We discussed ..." are shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref>. WriteAhead has determined the best patterns and examples ex- tracted from the underlying corpus. WriteAhead learns these patterns and examples automatically during training by analyzing annotated dictionary examples and automatically tagged sentences in a corpus. As will be described in Section 4, we used the information on collocation and syntax (ICS) for example sentences from online Macmillan En- glish Dictionary, as well as in the Citeseer x cor- pus, to develop WriteAhead.</p><p>At run-time, WriteAhead activates itself as the user types in yet another word (e.g., "discussed" in the prefix "We discussed ..."). WriteAhead then retrieves patterns related to the last word. WriteA- head goes one step further and re-ranks the sug- gestions, in an attempt to move most relevant sug- gestions to the top. WriteAhead can be accessed at http://writehead.nlpweb.org/.</p><p>In our prototype, WriteAhead returns the sug- gestions to the user directly (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1)</ref>; alterna- tively, the suggestions returned by WriteAhead can be used as input to an automatic grammar checker or an essay rater.</p><p>The rest of this paper is organized as follows.</p><p>We review the related work in the next section. Then we present our method for automatically learning normal and overused grammar patterns and examples for use in an interactive writing en- vironment (Section 3). Section 5 gives a demon- stration script of the interactive writing environ- ment.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Related Work</head><p>Much work described in a recent survey <ref type="bibr">(Leacock, Chodorow, Gamon, and Tetreault 2010)</ref> show that the elusive goal of fully-automatic and high-quality grammatical error correction is far from a reality. Moreover, Milton (2010) pointed out that we should shift the focus and responsi- bility to the learner, since no conclusive evidence shows explicit correction by a teacher or machine is leads to improved writing skills <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">(Truscott, 1996;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Ferris and Hedgcock, 2005)</ref>. In this paper, we develop an interactive writing environment (IWE) that constantly provides context-sensitive writing suggestions, right in the process of writing or self- editing. Autocompletion has been widely used in many language production tasks (e.g., search query and translation). Examples include Google Suggest and TransType, which pioneered the interactive user interface for statistical machine translation ( <ref type="bibr">Langlais et al., 2002;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Casacuberta et al. 2009</ref>). However, previous work focuses exclusively on 140 ------------------------- Procedure ExtractPatterns(Sent, Keywords, Corpus)</p><p>(1) Learning phrase templates for grammar patterns of content words (Section 3.1.1) (2) Extracting grammar patterns for all keywords in the given corpus based on phrase templates (Section 3.1.2) (3) Extracting exemplary instances for all patterns of all keywords (Section 3.1.3) ------------------------- <ref type="figure">Figure 2</ref>: Outline of the pattern extraction process providing surface suggestions lacking in general- ity to be truely effective for all users in different writing situation. In contrast, we provide sugges- tions in the form of theoretical and pedagogically sound language representation, in the form of Pat- tern Grammar (Hunston and Francis 2000). We also provide concise examples much like concor- dance advocated by <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">Sinclair (1991)</ref>.</p><p>Much work has been done in deriving context- free grammar from a corpus, while very little work has been done in deriving pattern grammar. Ma- son and Hunston (2004) reports on a pilot study to automatically recognize grammar patterns for verbs, using only limited linguistic knowledge. It is unclear whether their method can scale up and extend to other parts of speech. In contrast, we show it is feasible to extract grammar patterns for nouns, verbs, and adjectives on a large scale using a corpus with hundreds of million words.</p><p>Researchers have been extracting error patterns in the form of word or part of speech (POS) se- quencesto detect real-word spelling errors (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Golding and Schabes, 1996;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Verberne, 2002</ref>). For example, the sequence of det. det. n. definitely indicate an error, while v. prep. adv. might or might not indicate an error. For this reason, func- tion words (e.g., prepositions) are not necessarily reduced to POS tags (e.g., v. to adv.). Sometimes, even lexicalized patterns are necessary (e.g., go to adv.) <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Sun et al. (2007)</ref> extend n-grams to non- continuous sequential patterns allowing arbitrary gaps between words. In a recent study closer to our work, Gamon (2011) use high-order part-of- speech ngram to model and detect learner errors on the sentence level.</p><p>In contrast to the previous research in devel- oping computer assisted writing environment, we present a system that automatically learns gram- mar patterns and examples from an academic writ- ten corpus as well as learner corpus, with the goal of providing relevant, in-context suggestions.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Method</head><p>Non-native speakers often make grammatically er- ror, particularly in using some common words in writing (e.g., discuss vs. discuss *about). In addi- tion, using dictionaries or mere lexical suggestions to assist learner in writing is often not sufficient, and the information could be irrelevant at times. In this section, we address such a problem. Given various corpora (e.g., BNC or CiteseerX) in a spe- cific genre/domain and a unfinished or completed sentence, we intend to assist the user by retrieving and displaying a set of suggestions extracted from each corpus. For this, by a simple and intuitional method, we extract grammatical error patterns and correction such that the top ranked suggestions are likely to contain a pattern that fits well with the context of the unfinished sentence. We describe the stage of our solution to this problem in the sub- sections that followed.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Extracting Grammar Patterns</head><p>We attempt to extract grammatical error patterns and correction for keywords in a given corpus to provide writing suggestions, in order to assist ESL learners in an online writing session. Our extrac- tion process is shown in <ref type="figure">Figure 2</ref>.</p><p>3.1.1 Learning Extraction Templates In the first stage of the extraction process (Step (1) in <ref type="figure">Figure 2</ref>), we generate a set of phrase templates for identifying grammar patterns based on infor- mation on Collocation and Syntax (ICS) in an on- line dictionary.</p><p>For example, the dictionary entry of difficulty may provide examples with ICS pattern, such as have difficulty/problem (in) doing something: Six months after the accident, he still has difficulty walking. This complicated pattern with parenthet- ical and alternative parts can be expanded to yield patterns such as have difficulty in doing some- thing. By generalizing such a pattern into tem- plates with PoS and phrase tags (e.g., v. np prep. v np, we can identify instances of such a pattern in tagged and chunked sentences. For this, we ex- pand the parentheticals (e.g., (in)) and alternatives (e.g., difficulty/problem) in ICS.</p><p>Then, we replace (non-entry) words in ICS with the most frequent part of speech tags or phrase tags, resulting in sequences of POS and phrase la- bels (e.g., v. difficulty prep. v. np). Then, we take only the complementation part (e.g., prep. v. np). Finally, we convert each complementa-tion into a regular expression for a RegExp chunk parser.</p><p>Subsequently, we convert each template into a regular expression of chunk labels, intended to match instances of potential patterns in tagged sentences. The chunk labels typically are repre- sented using B-I-O symbols followed by phrase type, with each symbol denoting Beginning, Inside, and Outside of the phrase. Note that in or- der to identify the head of a phrase, we change the B-I-O representation to I-H-O, with H signifying the Head.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1.2">Extracting Patterns</head><p>In the second stage of the extraction process (Step (2) in <ref type="figure">Figure 2)</ref>, we identify instances of potential patterns for all keywords. These instances are generated for each tagged and chunked sentence in the given corpus and for each chunk templates obtained in the pre- vious stage.</p><p>We adopt the MapReduce framework to extract salient patterns. At the start of the Map Proce- dure, we perform part of speech, lemmatization, and base phrase tagging on the sentences. We then find all pattern instances anchoring at a key- word and matching templates obtained in the first stage. Then, from each matched instance, we ex- tract the tuple, (grammar pattern, collocation, and ngrams). Finally, we emit all tuples extracted from the tagged sentence. The map procedure is applied to every tagged sentence in the given corpus.</p><p>In the reduce part, the ReducePattern Proce- dure receives a batch of tuples, locally sorted and grouped by keyword, as is usually done in the MapReduce paradigm. At the start of the Redu- cePattern Procedure, we further group the tuple by pattern. Then we count the number of tuples of each pattern as well as within-group average and standard deviation of the counts. Finally, with these statistics, we filter and identify patterns more frequent than average by 1 standard deviation. The ReducePattern Procedure is applied to all tuples generated in the Map Procedure. Sample output of this stage is shown in <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1.3">Extracting Exemplary Phrases</head><p>In the third and final stage of extraction, we generate ex- emplary phrases for all patterns of all keywords of interest using the ReduceCollExm Procedure, which is done after the Map procedure, and essen- tially the same as the ReducePattern Procedure in the second stage (Section 3.1.2).</p><p>In the spirit of the GDEX method (Kilgarriff <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>: Example difficulty patterns extracted.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Pattern</head><p>Count Example difficulty of something 2169 of the problem difficulty in doing something 1790 in solving the problems difficulty of doing something 1264 of solving this problem difficulty in something 1219 in the previous analyses difficulty with something 755 with this approach difficulty doing something 718 using it</p><p>Note: There are 11200 instances of potential difficulty pat- terns with average count of 215 and a standard deviation of <ref type="bibr">318</ref> et al. 2008) of selecting good dictionary exam- ples for a headword via collocations, we propose a method for selection good example for a pattern. For this, we count and select salient collocations (e.g., the heads of phrases, difficulty in process in pattern instance difficulty in the optimization pro- cess). For each selected collocation, we choose the most frequent instance (augmented with con- text) to show the user the typical situation of using the collocation. These examples also facilitate the system in ranking patterns (as will be described in Section 3.2). For that, we add one chunk before, and one chunk after the collocational instance. For exam- ple, the collocation, method for solution of equa- tion is exemplified using the authentic corpus ex- ample, "method for exact solution of homogeneous linear differential equation" in the context of "re- port a new analytical ... with." We use a similar procedure as describe in Section 3.1.2 to extract examples.</p><p>After the grammar patterns are extracted from a reference corpus and a learner corpus, we normal- ize and compared the counts of the same pattern in the two corpora and compuate an overuse ratio for all patterns and retain patterns with a high overuse ratio.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Retrieving and Ranking Suggestions</head><p>Once the patterns and examples are automatically extracted for each keyword in the given corpus, they are stored and indexed by keyword. At run- time in a writing session, WriteAway constantly probes and gets the last keyword of the unfinished sentence Sent in the text box (or the word under the mouse when in editing mode). With the key- word as a query, WriteAway retrieves and ranks all relevant patterns and examples (Pat and Exm) aim- ing to move the most relevant information toward the top. We compute the longest common subse- quence (LCS) of Sent and an example, Exm. The examples and patterns are ranked by</p><note type="other">Score(Exm) = | LCS(Exm, Sent) | × Count(Exm).</note></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Score(Pat) = Score(E), where E is an example of Pat</head><p>To improve ranking, we also try to find the longest similar subsequence (LSS) between the user input, Sent and retrieved example, Exm based on distributional word similarity using the word2vec <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">(Mikolov et al., 2013)</ref> cosine distance. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Experiments and Results</head><p>For training, we used a collection of approxi- mately 3,000 examples for 700 headwords ob- tained from online Macmillan English Dictionary (Rundel 2007), to develop the templates of pat- terns. The headwords include nouns, verbs, ad- jectives, and adverbs. We then proceeded to ex- tract writing grammar patterns and examples from the British National Corpus (BNC, with 100 mil- lion words), CiteseerX corpus (with 460 million words) and Taiwan Degree Thesis Corpus (with 10 million words). First, we used Tsujii POS Tag- ger (Tsuruoka and Tsujii 2005) to generate tagged sentences. We applied the proposed method to generate suggestions for each of the 700 content keywords in Academic Keyword List.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">Technical Architecture</head><p>WriteAhead was implemented in Python and Flask Web framework. We stored the suggestions in JSON format using PostgreSQL for faster access. WriteAhead server obtains client input from a pop- ular browser (Safari, Chrome, or Firefox) dynam- ically with AJAX techniques. For uninterrupted service and ease of scaling up, we chose to host WriteAhead on Heroku, a cloud-platform-as-a- service (PaaS) site.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">Evaluating WriteAhead</head><p>To evaluate the performance of WriteAhead, we randomly sampled 100 sentences from a learner corpus with complementation errors. For each sentence, we identify the keyword related to the er- ror and checked whether we have identify an over- used pattern relevant to the error, and if positive the rank of this pattern. We then use the Mean Re- ciprocate Rank (MRR) to measure performance. Evaluation of WriteAhead showed a MMR rate of .30 and a recall rate of 24%. The Top 1, 2, 3 recall rates are 31%, 35%, and 38% respectively</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Demo script</head><p>In this demo, we will present a new writing assis- tance system, WriteAhead, which makes it easy to obtain writing tips as you type away. WriteAhead does two things really well. First, it examines the unfinished sentence you just typed in and then automatically gives you tips in the form of grammar patterns (accompanied with examples similar to those found in a good dictionary ) for continuing your sentence.</p><p>Second, WriteAhead automatically ranks sug- gestions relevant to your writing, so you spend less time looking at tips, and focus more on writing your text.</p><p>You might type in The paper present method and you are not sure about how to continue. You will instantly receive tips on grammar as well as content as shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref>. At a quick glance, you might find a relevant pattern, method for do- ing something with examples such as This paper presents/describes a method for generating solu- tions. That could tip you off as to change the sen- tence into This paper presents a method, thus get- ting rid of tense and article errors, and help you continue to write something like method for ex- tracting information.</p><p>Using WriteAhead this way, you could at once speed up writing and avoid making common writ- ing errors. This writing and tip-taking process re- peats until you finish writing a sentence. And as you start writing a new, the process starts all over again.</p><p>Most autocompletion systems such as Google Suggest and TransType offer word-level sugges- tions, while WriteAhead organizes, summarizes, and ranks suggestions, so you can, at a glance, grasp complex linguistic information and make quick decision. Our philosophy is that it is impor- tant to show information from general to specific to reduce the cognitive load, so while minding the form, you can still focus on the content of writing.</p><p>WriteAhead makes writing easy and fun, and it also turns writing into a continuous learning pro- cess by combining problem solving and informa- tion seeking together to create a satisfying user experience. WriteAhead can even help you beat Writers Block. WriteAhead can be accessed at http://writeahead.nlpweb.org/.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Conclusion</head><p>Many avenues exist for future research and im- provement of WriteAhead. For example, corpora for different language levels, genres (e.g., emails, news) could be used to make the suggestions more relevant to users with diverse proficiency levels and interests. NLP, IR, and machine learning techniques could be used to provide more rele- vant ranking, to pin-point grammatical errors, or to generate finer-grained semantic patterns (e.g., assist someone in something or attend activ- ity/institution) Additionally, an interesting direc- tion is identifying grammar patterns using a CRF sequence labeller.</p><p>In summary, in an attempt to assist learner writ- ers, we have proposed a method for providing writing suggestion as a user is typewriting. The method involves extracting, retrieving, and rank- ing grammar patterns and examples. We have im- plemented and evaluated the proposed method as applied to a scholarly corpus with promising re- sults.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: Example WriteAhead session where an user typed "This paper present method".</figDesc><graphic url="image-2.png" coords="2,172.38,198.94,252.57,118.86" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>The new score function is: Score(Exm) = LSS(Exm, Sent) × Count(Exm), LSS(Exm, Sent) = max sim(Exm sub , Sent sub ), sim(A, B) = 0, if |A| = |B|. sim(A, B) = word-sim(Ai, Bi), otherwise.</figDesc></figure>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Human interaction for high-quality machine translation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Francisco</forename><surname>Casacuberta</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Communications of the ACM</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">52</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="135" to="138" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Computer-aided error analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Estelle</forename><surname>Dagneaux</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sharon</forename><surname>Denness</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sylviane</forename><surname>Granger</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">System</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="163" to="174" />
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Problems in writing for scholarly publication in English: The case of Hong Kong</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">John</forename><surname>Flowerdew</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Second Language Writing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="243" to="264" />
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Teacher response to student writing: Issues in oral and written feedback</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dana</forename><surname>Ferris</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Hedgcock</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="184" to="222" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Teaching ESL composition: Purpose, process and practice</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The future of English?: A guide to forecasting the popularity of the English language in the 21st century</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Graddol</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Automatic profiling of learner texts</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sylviane</forename><surname>Granger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Paul</forename><surname>Rayson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Learner English on computer</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="119" to="131" />
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Connector usage in the English essay writing of native and nonnative EFL speakers of English</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sylviane</forename><surname>Granger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Stephanie</forename><surname>Tyson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">World Englishes</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="17" to="27" />
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Combining trigram-based and feature-based methods for context-sensitive spelling correction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Andrew</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Golding</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yves</forename><surname>Schabes</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 34th annual meeting on Association for Computational Linguistics. Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the 34th annual meeting on Association for Computational Linguistics. Association for Computational Linguistics</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">High-order sequence modeling for language learner error detection</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Gamon</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 6th Workshop on Innovative Use of NLP for Building Educational Applications</title>
		<meeting>the 6th Workshop on Innovative Use of NLP for Building Educational Applications</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Pattern grammar: A corpus-driven approach to the lexical grammar of English</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Susan</forename><surname>Hunston</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gill</forename><surname>Francis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
			<publisher>John Benjamins</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Amsterdam</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Automated grammatical error detection for language learners</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Claudia</forename><surname>Leacock</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Synthesis lectures on human language technologies</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="134" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A toolkit to assist L2 learners become independent writers</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">John</forename><surname>Milton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">Y</forename><surname>Vivying</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Cheng</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the NAACL HLT 2010 Workshop on Computational Linguistics and Writing: Writing Processes and Authoring Aids</title>
		<meeting>the NAACL HLT 2010 Workshop on Computational Linguistics and Writing: Writing Processes and Authoring Aids</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The automatic recognition of verb patterns: A feasibility study</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Oliver</forename><surname>Mason</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Susan</forename><surname>Hunston</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">International journal of corpus linguistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="253" to="270" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Distributed representations of words and phrases and their compositionality</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tomas</forename><surname>Mikolov</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Advances in Neural Information Processing Systems</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Detecting erroneous sentences using automatically mined sequential patterns</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Guihua</forename><surname>Sun</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Annual Meeting-Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">45</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The case against grammar correction in L2 writing classes</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">John</forename><surname>Truscott</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Language learning</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">46</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="327" to="369" />
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Chunk parsing revisited</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yoshimasa</forename><surname>Tsuruoka</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jun&amp;apos;ichi</forename><surname>Tsujii</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Ninth International Workshop on Parsing Technology. Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the Ninth International Workshop on Parsing Technology. Association for Computational Linguistics</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Context-sensitive spell checking based on word trigram probabilities</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Suzan</forename><surname>Verberne</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>University of Nijmegen</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
	<note>Unpublished masters thesis</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Corpus, Concordance, Collocation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Sinclair</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1991" />
			<publisher>Oxford University Press</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Hong Kong</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">TransType: a computer-aided translation typing system</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Langlais</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Foster</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Lapalme</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Workshop on Embedded Machine Translation Systems</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">CiteSeer x: A Scholarly Big Dataset</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Cornelia</forename><surname>Caragea</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Advances in Information Retrieval</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
