<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T10:03+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">If all you have is a bit of the Bible: Learning POS taggers for truly low-resource languageš languageš</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
				<availability status="unknown"><p>Copyright Association for Computational Linguistics</p>
				</availability>
				<date>July 26-31, 2015. 2015</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Zeljko</forename><forename type="middle">Agi´c</forename><surname>Agi´c</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Center for Language Technology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Copenhagen</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>140</postCode>
									<country>Denmark Njalsgade</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dirk</forename><surname>Hovy</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Center for Language Technology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Copenhagen</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>140</postCode>
									<country>Denmark Njalsgade</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Anders</forename><surname>Søgaard</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Center for Language Technology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Copenhagen</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>140</postCode>
									<country>Denmark Njalsgade</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">If all you have is a bit of the Bible: Learning POS taggers for truly low-resource languageš languageš</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 53rd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics and the 7th International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing</title>
						<meeting>the 53rd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics and the 7th International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing <address><addrLine>Beijing, China</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="268" to="272"/>
							<date type="published">July 26-31, 2015. 2015</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>We present a simple method for learning part-of-speech taggers for languages like Akawaio, Aukan, or Cakchiquel-languages for which nothing but a translation of parts of the Bible exists. By aggre-gating over the tags from a few annotated languages and spreading them via word-alignment on the verses, we learn POS taggers for 100 languages, using the languages to bootstrap each other. We evaluate our cross-lingual models on the 25 languages where test sets exist, as well as on another 10 for which we have tag dictionaries. Our approach performs much better (20-30%) than state-of-the-art unsu-pervised POS taggers induced from Bible translations, and is often competitive with weakly supervised approaches that assume high-quality parallel corpora, representative monolingual corpora with perfect to-kenization, and/or tag dictionaries. We make models for all 100 languages available .</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Most previous work in cross-lingual NLP has been limited to training and evaluating on no more than a dozen languages, typically all from the major Indo-European languages. While it has been ob- served repeatedly that using multiple source lan- guages improves performance ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Fossum and Abney, 2005;</ref>), most avail- able techniques work best for closely related lan- guages.</p><p>In contrast, this paper presents an effort to learn POS taggers for truly low-resource languages, with minimum assumptions about the available language resources. Most low-resource languages are non-Indo-European, and typically, their typo- logical and geographic neighbors have sparse re- sources as well. However, for a surprisingly large number of languages, translations of the Bible (or parts of it) exist. Due to the canonical nature and the verse format, these translations are viable par- allel data, albeit lacking annotation. In our exper- iments, we use word alignments across all pairs of 100 parallel Bible translations to bootstrap an- notation projections for those languages without any (even just weakly) supervised taggers. The projections provide both pseudo-annotated data as well as tag dictionaries for all languages. We use both resources to train semi-supervised POS tag- gers following <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Garrette and Baldridge (2013)</ref>.</p><p>Our contributionWe present a novel approach to learning POS taggers for truly low-resource lan- guages, where only a translation of (parts of) the Bible is available. We obtain results competi- tive with approaches that assume the availability of larger volumes of more representative paral- lel corpora, perfectly tokenized monolingual cor- pora, and/or tag dictionaries for the target lan- guages. Additionally, we make the POS tagging models for 100 languages publicly available and extend the mappings in  for six new languages (Hindi, Croatian, Icelandic, Nor- wegian, Persian, and Serbian). The models, map- pings, as well as a complete list of all the re- sources used in these experiments, are available at https://bitbucket.org/lowlands/.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Experiments</head><p>Our approach is a combination of simple tech- niques. Part of the process is depicted in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref>, and the algorithm is presented in Algorithm 1. As- sume we have n languages for which we assume the availability of m verses of the Bible. We run IBM-2 1 on all n(n − 1) pairs of languages. As- sume also manually POS-annotated training data  is available for the first k of these languages. We then run taggers for these languages on the corre- sponding translations of the Bible to predict tags for all tokens in these translations. We can think of this partially annotated multi- parallel corpus as a tensor object. Each column is a language l i , and each row a verse v j (triv- ially sentence-aligned to the corresponding verses in the other columns). In each cell of this ma- trix M (i, j, ·), we have a sequence of word tokens. For two languages, l 1 and l 2 , the word tokens in M (1, j, ·) can be aligned (by IBM-2) to multiple word tokens in M (2, j, ·), but not all words need to be aligned.</p><p>After running supervised POS taggers on the k languages for which we have training data, we have POS-annotated the word tokens in k columns of our tensor object. We then project the POS tag of each word token w to all other word tokens aligned to w. In our experiments, k = 17 or 18 (if the target language is not one of the languages for which we have training data), which means each word token will potentially have many POS tags projected onto it. Note that the number of tags can exceed 18, since many-to-many word alignments are allowed.</p><p>We now use these projections to train POS tag- gers for the remaining n − k languages. We use aggregated projected annotations as token- level supervision. We aggregate from the incom- ing projected POS tags by majority voting. We also use the complete set of projections onto each word type in the target language as a type-level tag dictionary. We combine the tag dictionary and the token-level projections to train discrimina- tive, type-constrained POS taggers <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Collins, 2002;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Täckström et al., 2013</ref>). Below we refer to these POS taggers as using k sources (k-SRC).</p><p>These n many POS taggers can now also be used to obtain predictions for all word tokens in our tensor object. This corresponds to doing the second loop over lines 8-17 in Algorithm 1. For each of our n languages, we thus complete the ten- sor by projecting tags into word tokens from the n − 1 remaining source languages. For the k su- pervised languages, we project the tags produced by the supervised POS taggers rather than the tags obtained by projection. We can then train our fi- nal POS taggers for all n languages -100, in our case -using projections from 99 languages (n-1- SRC). Note that we also train projected taggers for those languages for which we have annotated data. This is to enable us to evaluate our methodology on more languages.</p><p>Algorithm 1 Train n taggers with supervision for k 1: Let M be a tensor with M (i, j, ·) the word-aligned token sequence in the jth verse of the Bible in language i 2: for i ≤ k do 3:</p><p>Train TNT tagger for li using manually annotated data 4: for j ≤ m do 5:</p><p>Obtain POS predictions for M (i, j, ·) 6: end for 7: end for 8: for I ∈ {0, 1} do 9:</p><p>if i &gt; k, I = 1 then 10:</p><p>Train TNT tagger for li using projected annota- tions in M (i, ·, ·) 11:</p><p>end if 12:</p><p>Populate M (i, ·, ·) by propagating tags across align- ments 13:</p><p>for i ≤ n do 14:</p><p>Use majority voting to obtain one tag per word 15:</p><p>Obtain type-level tag dictionary from all the data 16:</p><p>Train TNT/GAR tagger for li using projected an- notations in M (i, ·, ·) and tag dictionary 17:</p><p>end for 18: end for DataWe use the 100 translations of (parts of) the Bible available as part of the Edinburgh Multi- lingual Parallel Bible Corpus ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Christodouloupoulos and Steedman, 2014</ref>). <ref type="bibr">2</ref> This dataset includes translations into languages such as Akawaio, Aukan or Cakchiquel. The majority of these lan- guages are non-Indoeuropean, and 39 of them have less than one million speakers. For 54 of UNSUPERVISED UPPER BOUNDS</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>BASELINES</head><p>OUR SYSTEMS WEAKLY SUP SUPERVISED OOV BROWN 2HMM TNT-k-SRC TNT-n-1-SRC GAR-k-SRC GAR-n-1-SRC DAS LI GAR TNT using k or n − 1 source languages, leading to four taggers in total.</p><p>Baselines Our baselines are two standard unsu- pervised POS induction algorithms: Brown clus- tering using the implementation by Percy Liang 4 and second-order unsupervised HMMs using lo- gistic regression for emission probabilities <ref type="bibr">(BergKirkpatrick et al., 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Li et al., 2012)</ref>, with and without our Bible tag dictionaries. 5</p><p>Upper bounds The weakly supervised system in Das and Petrov (2011) (DAS) relies on larger volumes of more representative and perfectly tok- enized parallel data than we assume, as well as a representative sample of unlabeled data. Such data is simply not available for many of the languages considered here. The weakly supervised system in <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Li et al. (2012)</ref> (LI) also relies on crowd-sourced type-level tag dictionaries, not available for most of the languages of concern to us. We present their reported results. Finally, we train the two base POS taggers (GAR and TNT) on the manually an- notated data available for 17 of our languages, to be able to compare against state-of-the-art perfor- mance of supervised POS taggers.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results</head><p>Our results on the 25 test languages are consistently better than the unsupervised base- lines, with the exceptions of Marathi and Persian, and by a very large margin. Our average per- formance across the languages with OOV rates smaller than 50% is above 70%. While previous papers on weakly supervised POS tagging (e.g., DAS and LI) have presented slightly better results for the small set of Indo-European languages in the CoNLL 2006-7 shared tasks, we emphasize again that our set-up requires fewer resources and does not rely on perfectly tokenized training data. Our parallel data also suffers from a severe, but more realistic domain bias. Note that doing the second round of projections (n-1-SRC) often im- proves performance by about a percentage point, but this improvement is not consistent across lan- guages. We observe that most errors are due to our systems predicting too many nouns. Note that for the two languages with underlined OOV rates (≥ 50), performance is very low. This is due to differences in orthography and tokenization. We leave out those results in the averages, but leave them in the results table.</p><p>To evaluate on more low-resource languages, we also extracted tag dictionaries from Wik- tionary for another 10 languages, from Afrikaans to Swahili. <ref type="figure">Figure 2</ref> presents the type-level in- vocabulary tag errors of the projected tags in the Bible. This figure is similar to the ones used in <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Li et al. (2012)</ref>. We also computed token-level ac- curacies, where every tag assignment licensed by Wiktionary counts as correct. For three languages, results were 80-90%: Afrikaans, Lithuanian, and Russian. For another three languages, results were 50-70%: Hebrew, Romanian, and Swahili. Results were 35-50% for the remaining four languages: Latin, Maori, Albanian, and Ewe.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Related work</head><p>The Bible has been used as a resource for ma- chine translation and multi-lingual information retrieval before, e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Chew et al., 2006</ref>). It has also been used in cross-lingual POS tagging ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Fossum and Abney, 2005</ref>), NP-chunking ( ) and cross-lingual dependency parsing (Sukhareva and Chiarcos, 2014) before.  and <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Fossum and Abney (2005)</ref>   <ref type="figure">Figure 2</ref>: Type-level in-vocabulary tag errors as the percentage of word types assigned a set of tags that is disjoint, identical to, overlaps, is a subset, or is a superset of the Wiktionary tags.</p><p>German, and Spanish to Czech and French. The resulting annotated target language corpora enable them to train POS taggers for these languages.  showed similar results using just the Hansards corpus on English to French and Chinese. Our work is inspired by these approaches, yet broader in scope on both the source and target side. Das and Petrov (2011) use word-aligned text to automatically create type-level tag dictionaries. Earlier work on building tag dictionaries from word-aligned text includes <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Probst (2003)</ref>. Their tag dictionaries contain target language trigrams to be able to disambiguate ambiguous target language words. To handle the noise in the automatically obtained dictionaries, they use label propagation on a similarity graph to smooth and expand the label distributions. Our approach is similar to theirs in using projections to obtain type-level tag dictionaries, but we keep the token supervision and type supervision apart and end up with a model more similar to that of <ref type="bibr">Täckström et al. (2013)</ref>, who combine word-aligned text with crowdsourced type-level tag dictionaries. <ref type="bibr">Täckström et al. (2013)</ref> constrain Viterbi search via type-level tag dictionaries, pruning all tags not licensed by the dictionary. For the remaining tags, they use high-confidence word alignments to further prune the Viterbi search. We follow <ref type="bibr">Täckström et al. (2013)</ref> in using our automatically created, not crowdsourced, tag dictionaries to prune tags during search, but we use word align- ments to obtain token-level annotations that we use as annotated training data, similar to Fossum and Abney (2005), . <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Duong et al. (2013)</ref> use word-alignment probabilities to select training data for their cross-lingual POS models. They consider a simple single-source training set-up. We also tried ranking projected training data by confidence, using an ensemble of projections from 17-99 source languages and majority voting to obtain probabilities for the token-level target-language projections, but this did not lead to improvements on the English development data.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Conclusions</head><p>We present a novel approach to learning POS taggers, assuming only that parts of the Bible are available for the target language. Our approach combines annotation projection, bootstrapping, and label propagation to learn POS taggers that perform significantly better than unsupervised baselines, and often competitive to state-of-the-art weakly supervised POS taggers that assume more and better resources are available.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: An illustration of our approach.</figDesc><graphic url="image-1.png" coords="2,117.58,136.40,129.42,86.09" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" validated="false"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>use word-aligned parallel translations of the Bible to project the predictions of POS taggers for several language pairs, including English,</figDesc><table>afr als ewe heb lat 
lit 
mri ron rus swh 
0 

20 

40 

60 

80 

100 

% entries 

disjoint 
identical 
overlap 
subset 
superset 

</table></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> github.com/clab/fast_align</note>

			<note place="foot" n="2"> homepages.inf.ed.ac.uk/s0787820/bible/</note>

			<note place="foot" n="4"> github.com/percyliang/brown-cluster 5 code.google.com/p/wikily-supervised-pos-tagger/</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgements</head><p>This research is funded by the ERC Starting Grant LOWLANDS No. 313695.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Painless unsupervised learning with features</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Taylor</forename><surname>Berg-Kirkpatrick</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alexandre</forename><surname>Bouchard-Cote</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">John</forename><surname>Denero</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dan</forename><surname>Klein</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of NAACL</title>
		<meeting>NAACL</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Tnt: a statistical part-ofspeech tagger</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Thorsten</forename><surname>Brants</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ANLP</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Evaluation of the bible as a resource for cross-language information retrieval</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Peter</forename><surname>Chew</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Steve</forename><surname>Verzi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Travis</forename><surname>Bauer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jonathan</forename><surname>Mcclain</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ACL Workshop on n Multilingual Language Resources and Interoperability</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">A massively parallel corpus: the bible in 100 languages. Language Resources and Evaluation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Cristos</forename><surname>Christodouloupoulos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mark</forename><surname>Steedman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Discriminative Training Methods for Hidden Markov Models: Theory and Experiments with Perceptron Algorithms</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Collins</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">EMNLP</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Unsupervised part-of-speech tagging with bilingual graph-based projections</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dipanjan</forename><surname>Das</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Slav</forename><surname>Petrov</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ACL</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Simpler unsupervised pos tagging with bilingual projections</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Long</forename><surname>Duong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Paul</forename><surname>Cook</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Steven</forename><surname>Bird</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Pavel</forename><surname>Pecina</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of ACL</title>
		<meeting>ACL</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Automatically inducing a part-of-speech tagger by projecting from multiple source languages across aligned corpora</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Victoria</forename><surname>Fossum</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Steven</forename><surname>Abney</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">IJCNLP</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Learning a part-of-speech tagger from two hours of annotation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dan</forename><surname>Garrette</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jason</forename><surname>Baldridge</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">NAACL</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Wiki-ly supervised part-of-speech tagging</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Shen</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">João</forename><surname>Graça</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ben</forename><surname>Taskar</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">EMNLP</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Multi-source transfer of delexicalized dependency parsers</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ryan</forename><surname>Mcdonald</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Slav</forename><surname>Petrov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Keith</forename><surname>Hall</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">EMNLP</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">A universal part-of-speech tagset</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Slav</forename><surname>Petrov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dipanjan</forename><surname>Das</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ryan</forename><surname>Mcdonald</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>CoRR abs/1104.2086</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Using &apos;smart&apos; bilingual projection to feature-tag a monolingual dictionary</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Katharina</forename><surname>Probst</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>In CoNLL</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Diachronic proximity vs. data sparsity in cross-lingual parser projection</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Maria</forename><surname>Sukhareva</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christian</forename><surname>Chiarcos</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">COLING Workshop on Applying NLP Tools to Similar Languages, Varieties and Dialects</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Token and type constraints for cross-lingual part-of-speech tagging</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Oscar</forename><surname>Täckström</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dipanjan</forename><surname>Das</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Slav</forename><surname>Petrov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ryan</forename><surname>Mcdonald</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Joakim</forename><surname>Nivre</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">TACL</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="12" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Inducing multilingual pos taggers and np brackets via robust projection across aligned corpora</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Yarowsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Grace</forename><surname>Ngai</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of NAACL</title>
		<meeting>NAACL</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Inducing multilingual text analysis tools via robust projection across aligned corpora</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Yarowsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Grace</forename><surname>Ngai</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Richard</forename><surname>Wicentowski</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the first international conference on Human language technology research</title>
		<meeting>the first international conference on Human language technology research</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
