<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T12:24+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">SCHN¨APPERSCHN¨ SCHN¨APPER: A Web Toolkit for Exploratory Relation Extraction</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date>July 26-31, 2015. c 2015</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Thilo</forename><surname>Michael</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Technische Universität Berlin</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Einsteinufer 17</addrLine>
									<postCode>10587</postCode>
									<settlement>Berlin</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alan</forename><surname>Akbik</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Technische Universität Berlin</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Einsteinufer 17</addrLine>
									<postCode>10587</postCode>
									<settlement>Berlin</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">SCHN¨APPERSCHN¨ SCHN¨APPER: A Web Toolkit for Exploratory Relation Extraction</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of ACL-IJCNLP 2015 System Demonstrations</title>
						<meeting>ACL-IJCNLP 2015 System Demonstrations <address><addrLine>Beijing, China</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="67" to="72"/>
							<date type="published">July 26-31, 2015. c 2015</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>We present SCHN¨APPERSCHN¨ SCHN¨APPER, a web toolkit for Exploratory Relation Extraction (ERE). The tool allows users to identify relations of interest in a very large text corpus in an exploratory and highly interactive fashion. With this tool, we demonstrate the ease-of-use and intuitive nature of ERE, as well as its applicability to large corpora. We show how users can formulate exploratory, natural language-like pattern queries that return relation instances. We also show how automatically computed suggestions are used to guide the exploration process. Finally, we demonstrate how users create extractors with SCHN¨APPERSCHN¨ SCHN¨APPER once a relation of interest is identified.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Relation Extraction (RE) is the task of extract- ing instances of semantic relations between enti- ties in unstructured data such as natural language text. Common examples are the BORNIN relation- ship between a person and its birthplace, or the CHILDOF relation between a parent and its child. A principal challenge in RE is how to build high quality extractors for a given set of relations at minimal effort.</p><p>One line of approaches to RE are rule-based, where users manually define rule-sets consisting of extraction patterns that if observed point to in- stances of a relation. Advantages associated with rule-based RE are a high level of direct control over the extraction process: Ideally, rule-writers build interpretable and maintainable rule-sets, en- abling both the extension and error analysis of rule-based extractors ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Chiticariu et al., 2013)</ref>. In- deed, in a number of recent works, rule-based RE approaches have been found to outperform previous machine-learning based state-of-the-art systems, for tasks such as temporal expression detection <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(Strötgen and Gertz, 2010)</ref> and Ope- nIE <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Del Corro and Gemulla, 2013)</ref>. Exploratory search for relations. Recently, in <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Akbik et al., 2014</ref>), we introduced the paradigm of Exploratory Relation Extraction (ERE). We ar- gued that workflows and tooling can be developed in such a way as to enable an interactive and open ended search for relations. With ERE, relations therefore do not need to be precisely defined in advance. Rather, users can start a process of ex- ploration for interesting relations even if their in- formation needs are only vaguely defined.</p><p>We outlined key ideas in order to enable the exploratory workflow: First, extraction patterns should be very easy to define and quick to test, much in the same way as exploratory keyword queries in a web search engine <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(Marchionini, 2006</ref>). Second, the exploration process should be guided through suggestions computed from the available data and previous user interactions. Third, there should be a high level of interactivity. Appropriate tooling is therefore required. Contributions. With this demo, we present SCHN¨APPERSCHN¨ SCHN¨APPER, a web-based tool for ERE that demonstrates the incremental, data-guided work- flow introduced in <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Akbik et al., 2014</ref>). The demo is intended to underline a central claim of ERE, which is that non-experts can use it to easily ex- plore a corpus for relational information and build extractors. Additionally, by using a large portion of the CLUEWEB09 1 corpus as dataset, we aim to highlight the applicability of such an approach to very large datasets. Paper outline. We first give a quick overview over the ERE workflow in Section 2. We then present SCHN¨APPERSCHN¨ SCHN¨APPER, our web interface (Section 3) and walk through an example workflow with the tool. We then briefly give an overview over related work and give an outlook of possible future additions to</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Pattern Suggestions</head><p>[X] launched from <ref type="bibr">[Y]</ref> [X] arrive at <ref type="bibr">[Y]</ref> [X] built by <ref type="bibr">[Y]</ref> Y_Type Suggestions</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Organization</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Location</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Celestrial_Object</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.">Launch Initial Query</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Initial Query</head><p>X_Type Spacecraft</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Y_Type</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Pattern</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Index</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.">Select from Suggestions</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Updated Suggestions</head><p>[X] mission to <ref type="bibr">[Y]</ref> [X] orbit <ref type="bibr">[Y]</ref> [X] fly by <ref type="bibr">[Y]</ref> select Upda <ref type="bibr">[X]</ref> [X]</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Updated Selection</head><p>X_Type Spacecraft</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Y_Type Celestrial_Object</head><p>Pattern <ref type="bibr">[X]</ref> arrive at <ref type="bibr">[Y]</ref> 3. Interact the toolkit and the method itself.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Exploratory Relation Extraction</head><p>We demonstrate an approach to finding binary re- lations in text that has been proposed in <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Akbik et al., 2014)</ref>. Each relation holds between two enti- ties: a subject and an object entity. Users explore a corpus for information by selecting and compos- ing extraction patterns.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">Pattern Language</head><p>Extraction patterns consist of two components: 1. Dependency subtrees. The first component is the lexico-syntactic pattern that connects two entities in a sentence. Here, we allow arbitrary subtrees in a sentence's dependency tree, as long as they span two entities of interest. To gener- alize the patterns, they are stemmed and the two entities are replaced by the placeholders " <ref type="bibr">[X]</ref> and <ref type="bibr">[Y]</ref>". Examples of subtree patterns are " <ref type="bibr">[X]</ref> and <ref type="bibr">[Y]</ref> married" and " <ref type="bibr">[X]</ref> 's father <ref type="bibr">[Y]</ref>" 2 . However, since any subtree is a possible pattern, many subtrees with less obvious meanings are also possible; in the end, it is up to the user to make the decision which patterns are relevant and which are not. 2. Entity type restrictions Optionally, patterns may be further restricted to match only entities of certain fine-grained types, such as PERSON, LO- CATION, LANGUAGE or MOVIE. The type restric- tions may be set individually for each subject and object entities. Since the subject is replaced with the placeholder <ref type="bibr">[X]</ref> in a pattern, its restriction is referred to as X Type, while the object restriction is referred to as Y Type. Preemptive pattern extraction.</p><p>Following the idea of preemptive Information Extrac- tion ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Shinyama and Sekine, 2006</ref>), we pre-extract and store all subtrees and entity types from a given corpus for each sentence with at least two named entities. This allows not only fast retrieval of matching entity pairs for a given set of subtrees and type restrictions, but also allows us to com- pute pattern correlations over the entire dataset for the presently selected setup. In the next section, we show how fast retrieval and pattern correlations are used to aid the exploration process.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">Example Workflow</head><p>We illustrate the exploration process with an ex- ample workflow, the first steps of which are de- picted in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref>. Assume that our user is inter- ested in relations that involve "spacecraft", but is unsure of what types of relations may be found for such entities in the given corpus. Initial query (1). The user starts by issuing an ini- tial query that is strongly underspecified: By set- ting X Type to SPACECRAFT and leaving the Pat- tern and Y Type fields in the query unspecified, the user searches for all sentences that contain at least one entity of the desired type. At this point, there are no other restrictions to the query with regards to patterns or object entity types. Explore by reacting to suggestions (2). After is- suing the query, the system responds with both a list of sentences that match the query (not illus- trated in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref>) and well as, more importantly, suggestions for patterns and object entity type re-strictions that correlate with the user query.</p><p>The user can now choose from the suggestions: For instance, by selecting the object type LOCA- TION and the pattern "[X] launched from <ref type="bibr">[Y]</ref>", the user may direct the exploration process towards relations that indicate locations (cities, countries, sites) from which a spacecraft was launched. Similarly, by choosing ORGANIZATION as object type and " <ref type="bibr">[X]</ref> built by <ref type="bibr">[Y]</ref>" as pattern, the user may select organizations (con- tractors, space agencies) that constructed or de- signed spacecraft as the focus of interest.</p><p>In the example shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref>, the user in- stead selects the object type CELESTIALOBJECT and the pattern " <ref type="bibr">[X]</ref> arrive at <ref type="bibr">[Y]</ref>". This directs the search towards relations that indicate spacecraft missions to celestial objects. User interactions (3). This user interaction up- dates both the query as well as the suggestions for patterns and restrictions. Now pattern sug- gestions are more specific to the previous selec- tion; For instance, by selecting either the pattern " <ref type="bibr">[X]</ref> orbit <ref type="bibr">[Y]</ref>" or " <ref type="bibr">[X]</ref> fly by <ref type="bibr">[Y]</ref>", the user can specify relations for spacecraft that have achieved orbit around celestial objects, or have made flybys. By following a process of querying, inspecting results, selecting and unse- lecting subtrees and restrictions, the user can in- teractively explore the given corpus for relations of interest. Once an interesting relation is iden- tified, the user utilizes the same approach to build an extractor by compiling a list of relevant patterns from the suggestions. Typically, the more patterns a user selects, the higher the recall of the created extractor will be. Store extractor. When the user has identified an interesting relation and selected a list of relevant patterns, she can export the extraction results (i.e. all relation instances found by the extractor). The user can also save the extractor and provide a de- scriptive name for the relation for possible later reuse.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Web Interface</head><p>In order to make the use of SCHN¨APPERSCHN¨ SCHN¨APPER as straightforward as possible, the user interface is clearly structured into four panels that fit onto one screen. The top half of the screen consists of three panels in which the user can select patterns and en- tity type restrictions. The bottom half of the screen is the result panel which displays a sample of ex- traction results for the currently selected patterns and entity type restrictions. See <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 2</ref> for the screen and a breakdown of the panels, which we explain in more detail in the following:</p><p>Pattern panel (1) Of the three panels in the up- per half of the screen, the pattern panel assumes the center stage. Here, the user can enter keywords in the search field to find appropriate patterns. If at least one user interaction has already been made (e.g. one pattern or type restriction selected), a list of pattern suggestions is presented in gray. Sin- gle clicking on a pattern suggestion gives a small number of example sentences and entity pairs for which this pattern holds (this is illustrated in field (6) in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 2</ref>). Double-clicking on a pattern adds it to the extractor; it is then highlighted blue and suggestions as well as the result panel are updated to reflect the selection. By double-clicking on a selected pattern, users may remove it again from the selection.</p><p>Entity type restriction panels (2) Extractors may also have entity type restrictions which re- strict lexico-syntactic patterns to only apply to en- tities of certain types. The top right and top left panels are used to define restrictions for the sub- ject and object of a binary relation respectively. Here, users have a choice between three differ- ent ways of selecting entity type restrictions. The first and default option is to use FREEBASE entity types ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Bollacker et al., 2008)</ref>. I.e. the user can select the subject of a relation to be only of the FREEBASE type SPACECRAFT, ORGANIZATION or CELESTIALOBJECT.</p><p>The user can also restrict a relation to one spe- cific entity. For instance, by restricting the object of a BORNIN relation to be the country "Finland", the extractor will only find persons born in Fin- land.</p><p>Finally, the user can restrict entities to those found with a previously created extractor. Users can embed extractors in this way to find more complex relations. For instance, an extractor that finds "Persons born in Finland" may be used to re- strict the subject entity of another extractor. The other extractor can then find a relation between "Persons born in Finland" and, for example, en- tities of type BUILDING ("Buildings designed by persons from Finland"). Similar to the pattern panel, double-clicking is used to select or unselect type restrictions. Upon each interaction, the suggestions as well as the re- sult panel are updated to reflect the current selec- tion.</p><p>Result panel <ref type="formula">(3)</ref> The lower half of the screen is the result panel which lists a set of entity pairs that are found with the presently selected patterns and restrictions. Each entity pair is displayed along with the sentence that matches the pattern. By clicking the magnifying glass symbol next to an entity pair, more details are shown, including the entity pair's FREEBASE ids and a list of sentences that match the selected patterns.</p><p>Storing and exporting extractors After finish- ing building an extractor, users can export the setup as a JSON by clicking the download button in the lower right corner of the screen (see field (5) in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 2</ref>). This exports the selected patterns and restrictions, together with a result list of entity pairs found with the extractor. In addition, users can generate a "permalink" by clicking the button in the lower left corner of the screen (see field (4) in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 2</ref>). This allows users to generate links to created extractors and share them electronically.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Example Usage</head><p>We now briefly give an example of using the tool. Assume a user is interested in a relation between persons and the companies they founded.</p><p>There are several entry points the user may choose from. For instance, the user might search for appropriate entity types in the X Type and Y Type panels. Another option is to start by look- ing for appropriate patterns. For this, the user can use the search box in the pattern panel (1) to search for the general term "found". This results in a list of patterns being displayed, which includes the pattern " <ref type="bibr">[X]</ref> found <ref type="bibr">[Y]</ref>". By single-clicking on it, the user can see a list of sentences that in- clude this pattern. This is illustrated in field (6) in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 2</ref>.</p><p>The user activates the pattern by double- clicking it. He sees the output of the extractor in the result panel (3) as well as patterns and en-tity types that are suggested based on the current selection. Scanning through the result panel, the user finds that while many matching sentences do indeed express the desired relation (like "Pierre Omidyar founded eBay"), some others do not ("Snape found Sirius Black").</p><p>The tool however also presents three sets of sug- gestions that the user can use to refine the pat- terns. For instance, for both X Type and Y Type a ranked list of suggestions highlighted gray appears (2). As illustrated in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 2</ref>, it suggests PER- SON as X Type and ORGANIZATION as Y Type. The user can affirm suggestions by double click- ing on them. When selecting ORGANIZATION as Y Type, the result panel is updated to reflect the most recent changes. Scanning through the results the user sees that the extraction quality has greatly improved as there are far fewer false positives in the list.</p><p>The user may now try to further improve the ex- tractor by selecting more specific patterns. The tool suggests the pattern "[X] be founder of <ref type="bibr">[Y]</ref>", which more accurately describes the relation the user wants to extract. Again by single- clicking on the suggestion, the user can see exam- ple sentences that match this pattern, as well as the selected entity type restrictions. Double-clicking on the pattern adds it to the extractor, which now consists of two patterns. With multiple patterns selected, the tool is now able to suggest patterns more accurately, offering patterns such as " <ref type="bibr">[Y]</ref> founded by <ref type="bibr">[X]</ref>", "[X] start <ref type="bibr">[Y]</ref>" and " <ref type="bibr">[X]</ref> co-found <ref type="bibr">[Y]</ref>". By selecting them and implicitly rejecting those suggestions that do not reflect the desired relation (like the correlated patterns "[X] president of <ref type="bibr">[Y]</ref>" or " <ref type="bibr">[X]</ref> CEO of <ref type="bibr">[Y]</ref>"), the user incrementally creates an extractor.</p><p>After multiple iterations of selecting suggested patterns and entity type restrictions the user is able to download the results of the extractor by using the download button (5) at the bottom of the page.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3">Implementation Details</head><p>We use CLUEWEB09 as corpus and make use of FACC1 annotations ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Gabrilovich et al., 2013</ref>) to determine entity mentions and their FREEBASE types. We extract all English sentences that con- tain at least 2 FREEBASE entities, yielding over 160 million sentences. We then parse these sen- tences using the CLEARNLP pipeline <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Choi and McCallum, 2013)</ref> and preemptively generate all subtrees for all entity pairs in all sentences. To- gether with information on the entity types, we store all information in a Lucene index for fast re- trieval.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.4">Hands-on Demonstration</head><p>We plan a hands-on demonstration in which users work with SCHN¨APPERSCHN¨ SCHN¨APPER to explore the CLUEWEB09 corpus for relations of interest. Our purpose is twofold: One the one hand we would like to make the case for the simplicity and in- tuitive nature of the proposed approach. One the other hand, we would like to gather feedback from the NLP community for possible future improve- ments to the approach. In particular some of the more advanced features such as embedding extrac- tors within other extractors may be interesting to discuss in a hands-on demo 4 .</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Previous Work</head><p>Recent work in the field of rule-based RE has in- vestigated workflows and tooling to facilitate the creation of extractors. ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Li et al., 2012</ref>) presented a wizard-like approach to guide users in the process of building extractors. In <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Akbik et al., 2013)</ref>, we presented an example-driven workflow that allows even users who are unfamiliar with NLP to write extractors using lexico-syntactic patterns over de- pendency trees. Similarly, <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Grishman and He, 2014</ref>) create a toolkit for persons who are experts in a domain of interest, but not in NLP. Users cre- ate extractors for pre-defined entities and relations by seeding example instances in a semi-supervised fashion. <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Gupta and Manning, 2014</ref>) use a similar bootstrapping approach and create a tool for vi- sualizing learned patterns for diagnostic purposes. Finally, <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(Freedman et al., 2011</ref>) focus on reduc- ing effort in a user-driven process by including el- ements from active learning and bootstrapping, but target their tool at NLP experts.</p><p>Unlike the approach presented with this demo, these approaches are mostly intended for tradi- tional RE in which relations of interest are spec- ified in advance. With this demo, we instead sup- port an exploratory workflow in which relations of interest may be discovered through user inter- actions with available data at little effort.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Outlook</head><p>While SCHN¨APPERSCHN¨ SCHN¨APPER is currently focused on binary relations only, we are investigating the application of comparable workflows at the entity level. Ide- ally, we would like to be able to create extractors that find named entities of custom types and em- bed them into custom relation extractors. While, as the demo shows, it is already possible to em- bed extractors into other extractors, more research is required fully develop the process of creating entity extractors, which possibly includes develop- ing a different pattern language for the entity level. With more extensive capabilities of creating cus- tom entity extractors, such tooling could conceiv- ably be used to use the approach for knowledge base population tasks ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Surdeanu and Ji, 2014</ref>). The approach could be also used to quickly cre- ate custom knowledge bases for specialized topics such as the biomedical domain <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(Hunter and Cohen, 2006</ref>). Another point of interest is that, since the tooling is Web-based, collaborative aspects of creating custom knowledge bases can be investi- gated in this context.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: Illustration of the Exploratory Relation Extraction example workflow discussed in Section 2.2.</figDesc><graphic url="image-10.png" coords="2,315.46,141.77,71.08,57.70" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2: Screen capture of the SCHN¨APPERSCHN¨ SCHN¨APPER tool showing the pattern panel (1) with an activated pattern showing a list of example sentences (6), the entity type restriction panels (2) and the result panel (3). The permalink button (4) and the download button (5) are located at the bottom.</figDesc><graphic url="image-43.png" coords="4,72.00,62.81,453.54,277.85" type="bitmap" /></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> http://www.lemurproject.org/clueweb09/index.php</note>

			<note place="foot" n="2"> For the purpose of readability, we do not display the deep syntactic information from the subtrees. Instead, we only show the lexical portion of the patterns. Here, some verbs, such as participles and gerunds, are not stemmed for readability purposes.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="3"> Web Demonstration We now present SCHN¨APPERSCHN¨ SCHN¨APPER 3 , our web toolkit for Exploratory Relation Extraction. 3 The tool was named after the Petroicidae famliy of birds, which in German are called Schnäpper. This name stems from the verb schnappen (Schmitthenner, 1837), which translates as &quot;to grab&quot; or &quot;to catch&quot;. We found this fitting since the tool is used to &quot;grab&quot; or &quot;catch&quot; information.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="4"> The tool is also publicly available online. It can be reached through Alan Akbik&apos;s web page.</note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Propminer: A workflow for interactive information extraction and exploration using dependency trees</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alan</forename><surname>Akbik</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Oresti</forename><surname>Konomi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michail</forename><surname>Melnikov</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ACL System Demonstrations</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Exploratory relation extraction in large text corpora</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alan</forename><surname>Akbik</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Thilo</forename><surname>Michael</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christoph</forename><surname>Boden</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">COLING 2014, 25th International Conference on Computational Linguistics, Proceedings of the Conference: Technical Papers</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Dublin, Ireland</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014-08-23" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2087" to="2096" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Freebase: a collaboratively created graph database for structuring human knowledge</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kurt</forename><surname>Bollacker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Colin</forename><surname>Evans</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Praveen</forename><surname>Paritosh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tim</forename><surname>Sturge</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jamie</forename><surname>Taylor</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2008 ACM SIGMOD international conference on Management of data</title>
		<meeting>the 2008 ACM SIGMOD international conference on Management of data</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1247" to="1250" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Rule-based information extraction is dead! long live rule-based information extraction systems!</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Laura</forename><surname>Chiticariu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yunyao</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Frederick R</forename><surname>Reiss</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2013 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</title>
		<meeting>the 2013 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="827" to="832" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Transition-based dependency parsing with selectional branching</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Jinho</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Andrew</forename><surname>Choi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Mccallum</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 51st Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the 51st Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Luciano</forename><surname>Del Corro</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rainer</forename><surname>Gemulla</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Clausie: clause-based open information extraction</title>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 22nd international conference on World Wide Web</title>
		<meeting>the 22nd international conference on World Wide Web</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="355" to="366" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>International World Wide Web Conferences Steering Committee</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Extreme extraction: machine reading in a week</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marjorie</forename><surname>Freedman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lance</forename><surname>Ramshaw</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Elizabeth</forename><surname>Boschee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ryan</forename><surname>Gabbard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gary</forename><surname>Kratkiewicz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nicolas</forename><surname>Ward</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ralph</forename><surname>Weischedel</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</title>
		<meeting>the Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1437" to="1446" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">FACC1: freebase annotation of ClueWeb corpora, version 1 (release date 2013-06-26</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Evgeniy</forename><surname>Gabrilovich</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Ringgaard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Amarnag</forename><surname>Subramanya</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>format version 1, correction level 0</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">An information extraction customizer</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ralph</forename><surname>Grishman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yifan</forename><surname>He</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Text, Speech and Dialogue</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3" to="10" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Spied: Stanford pattern-based information extraction and diagnostics. Sponsor: Idibon</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sonal</forename><surname>Gupta</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Christopher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Manning</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="page">38</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Biomedical language processing: what&apos;s beyond pubmed? Molecular cell</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lawrence</forename><surname>Hunter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Cohen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">21</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="589" to="594" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Wizie: a best practices guided development environment for information extraction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yunyao</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Laura</forename><surname>Chiticariu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Huahai</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Arnaldo</forename><surname>Frederick R Reiss</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Carreno-Fuentes</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the ACL 2012 System Demonstrations</title>
		<meeting>the ACL 2012 System Demonstrations</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="109" to="114" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Exploratory search: from finding to understanding</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gary</forename><surname>Marchionini</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Communications of the ACM</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">49</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="41" to="46" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Kurzes deutsches Wörterbuch für Etymologie, Synonymik und Orthographie</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Friedrich</forename><surname>Schmitthenner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1837" />
			<publisher>Jonghaus</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Preemptive information extraction using unrestricted relation discovery</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yusuke</forename><surname>Shinyama</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Satoshi</forename><surname>Sekine</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the main conference on Human Language Technology Conference of the North American Chapter of the Association of Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the main conference on Human Language Technology Conference of the North American Chapter of the Association of Computational Linguistics</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="304" to="311" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Heideltime: High quality rule-based extraction and normalization of temporal expressions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jannik</forename><surname>Strötgen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Gertz</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 5th International Workshop on Semantic Evaluation</title>
		<meeting>the 5th International Workshop on Semantic Evaluation</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="321" to="324" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Association for Computational Linguistics</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Overview of the english slot filling track at the tac2014 knowledge base population evaluation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mihai</forename><surname>Surdeanu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Heng</forename><surname>Ji</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. Text Analysis Conference (TAC2014)</title>
		<meeting>Text Analysis Conference (TAC2014)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
