<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T12:56+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Weakly Supervised Models of Aspect-Sentiment for Online Course Discussion Forums</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
				<availability status="unknown"><p>Copyright Association for Computational Linguistics</p>
				</availability>
				<date>July 26-31, 2015. 2015</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Arti</forename><surname>Ramesh</surname></persName>
							<email>artir@cs.umd.edu,</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">University of Maryland</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>College Park</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Shachi</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Kumar</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Santa Cruz</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of California</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">James</forename><surname>Foulds</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Santa Cruz</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of California</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lise</forename><surname>Getoor</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Santa Cruz</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of California</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Weakly Supervised Models of Aspect-Sentiment for Online Course Discussion Forums</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 53rd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics and the 7th International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing</title>
						<meeting>the 53rd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics and the 7th International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing <address><addrLine>Beijing, China</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="74" to="83"/>
							<date type="published">July 26-31, 2015. 2015</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Massive open online courses (MOOCs) are redefining the education system and transcending boundaries posed by traditional courses. With the increase in popularity of online courses, there is a corresponding increase in the need to understand and interpret the communications of the course participants. Identifying topics or aspects of conversation and inferring sentiment in online course forum posts can enable instructor interventions to meet the needs of the students, rapidly address course-related issues, and increase student retention. Labeled aspect-sentiment data for MOOCs are expensive to obtain and may not be transferable between courses, suggesting the need for approaches that do not require labeled data. We develop a weakly supervised joint model for aspect-sentiment in online courses, modeling the dependencies between various aspects and sentiment using a recently developed scal-able class of statistical relational models called hinge-loss Markov random fields. We validate our models on posts sampled from twelve online courses, each containing an average of 10,000 posts, and demonstrate that jointly modeling aspect with sentiment improves the prediction accuracy for both aspect and sentiment.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Massive Open Online Courses (MOOCs) have emerged as a powerful medium for imparting edu- cation to a wide geographical population. Discus- sion forums are the primary means of communica- tion between MOOC participants (students, TAs, and instructors). Due to the open nature of these courses, they attract people from all over the world leading to large numbers of participants and hence, large numbers of posts in the discussion forums. In the courses we worked with, we found that over the course of the class there were typically over 10,000 posts.</p><p>Within this slew of posts, there are valuable problem-reporting posts that identify issues such as broken links, audio-visual glitches, and in- accuracies in the course materials. Automati- cally identifying these reported problems is impor- tant for several reasons: i) it is time-consuming for instructors to manually screen through all of the posts due to the highly skewed instructor-to- student ratio in MOOCs, ii) promptly address- ing issues could help improve student retention, and iii) future iterations of the course could ben- efit from identifying technical and logistical is- sues currently faced by students. In this paper, we investigate the problem of determining the fine-grained topics of posts (which we refer to as "MOOC aspects") and the sentiment toward them, which can potentially be used to improve the course.</p><p>While aspect-sentiment has been widely stud- ied, the MOOC discussion forum scenario presents a unique set of challenges. Labeled data are expensive to obtain, and posts containing fine- grained aspects occur infrequently in courses and differ across courses, thereby making it expensive to get sufficient coverage of all labels. Few distinct aspects occur per course, and only 5-10% of posts in a course are relevant. Hence, getting labels for fine-grained labels involves mining and annotating posts from a large number of courses. Further, cre- ating and sharing labeled data is difficult as data from online courses is governed by IRB regula-tions. Privacy restrictions are another reason why unsupervised/weakly-supervised methods can be helpful. Lastly, to design a system capable of iden- tifying all possible MOOC aspects across courses, we need to develop a system that is not fine-tuned to any particular course, but can adapt seamlessly across courses.</p><p>To this end, we develop a weakly supervised system for detecting aspect and sentiment in MOOC forum posts and validate its effectiveness on posts sampled from twelve MOOC courses. Our system can be applied to any MOOC discus- sion forum with no or minimal modifications.</p><p>Our contributions in this paper are as follows:</p><p>• We show how to encode weak supervision in the form of seed words to extract ex- tract course-specific features in MOOCs us- ing SeededLDA, a seeded variation of topic modeling ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Jagarlamudi et al., 2012</ref>).</p><p>• Building upon our SeededLDA approach, we develop a joint model for aspects and sentiment using the hinge-loss Markov ran- dom field (HL-MRF) probabilistic modeling framework. This framework is especially well-suited for this problem because of its ability to combine information from multiple features and jointly reason about aspect and sentiment.</p><p>• To validate the effectiveness of our system, we construct a labeled evaluation dataset by sampling posts from twelve MOOC courses, and annotating these posts with fine-grained MOOC aspects and sentiment via crowd- sourcing. The annotation captures fine- grained aspects of the course such as content, grading, deadlines, audio and video of lec- tures and sentiment (i.e., positive, negative, and neutral) toward the aspect in the post.</p><p>• We demonstrate that the proposed HL-MRF model can predict fine-grained aspects and sentiment and outperforms the model based only on SeededLDA.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Related Work</head><p>To the best of our knowledge, the problem of pre- dicting aspect and sentiment in MOOC forums has not yet been addressed in the literature. We review prior work in related areas here. <ref type="table" target="#tab_10">It is  valuable to identify the sentiment of online re- views towards aspects such as hotel cleanliness  and cellphone screen brightness, and sentiment  analysis at the aspect-level has been studied ex- tensively in this context (Liu and Zhang, 2012)</ref>. Several of these methods use latent Dirichlet allo- cation topic models ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Blei et al., 2003</ref>) and variants of it for detecting aspect and sentiment <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">(Lu et al., 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Lin and He, 2009)</ref>. <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Liu and Zhang (2012)</ref> provide a comprehensive survey of techniques for aspect and sentiment analysis. Here, we discuss works that are closely related to ours. <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Titov and McDonald (2008)</ref> emphasize the im- portance of an unsupervised approach for aspect detection. However, the authors also indicate that standard LDA ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Blei et al., 2003</ref>) methods capture global topics and not necessarily pertinent aspects -a challenge that we address in this work. <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Brody and Elhadad (2010)</ref>, <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Titov and McDonald (2008)</ref>, and Jo and Oh (2011) apply variations of LDA at the sentence level for online reviews. We find that around 90% of MOOC posts have only one aspect, which makes sentence-level aspect modeling inap- propriate for our domain.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Aspect-Sentiment in Online Reviews</head><p>Most previous approaches for sentiment rely on manually constructed lexicons of strongly positive and negative words <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Fahrni and Klenner, 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Brody and Elhadad, 2010)</ref>. These methods are ef- fective in an online review context, however senti- ment in MOOC forum posts is often implicit, and not necessarily indicated by standard lexicons. For example, the post "Where is my certificate? Wait- ing over a month for it." expresses negative sen- timent toward the certificate aspect, but does not include any typical negative sentiment words. In our work, we use a data-driven model-based ap- proach to discover domain-specific lexicon infor- mation guided by small sets of seed words.</p><p>There has also been substantial work on joint models for aspect and sentiment <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Kim et al., 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Diao et al., 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b25">Zhao et al., 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Lin et al., 2012</ref>), and we adopt such an approach in this pa- per. <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Kim et al. (2013)</ref> use a hierarchical aspect- sentiment model and evaluate it for online reviews. Mukherjee and Liu (2012) use seed words for dis- covering aspect-based sentiment topics. Drawing on the ideas of Mukherjee and Liu (2012) and <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Kim et al. (2013)</ref>, we propose a statistical rela- tional learning approach that combines the advan- tages of seed words, aspect hierarchy, and flat Post 1: I have not received the midterm. Post 2: No lecture subtitles week, will they be uploaded? Post 3: I am ... and I am looking forward to learn more ... <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>: Example posts from MOOC forums. As- pect words are highlighted in bold.</p><p>aspect-sentiment relationships. It is important to note that a broad majority of the previous work on aspect sentiment focuses on the specific chal- lenges of online review data. As discussed in de- tail above, MOOC forum data have substantially different properties, and our approach is the first to be designed particularly for this domain.</p><p>Learning Analytics In another line of research, there is a growing body of work on the analy- sis of online courses. Regarding MOOC forum data, <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">Stump et al. (2013)</ref> propose a framework for taxonomically categorizing forum posts, lever- aging manual annotations. We differ from their approach in that we develop an automatic system to predict MOOC forum categories without using labeled training data. <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Ramesh et al. (2014b)</ref> cat- egorize forum posts into three broad categories in order to predict student engagement. Unlike this method, our system is capable of fine-grained cat- egorization and of identifying aspects in MOOCS. <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Chaturvedi et al. (2014)</ref> focus on predicting in- structor intervention using lexicon features and thread features. In contrast, our system is capable of predicting fine MOOC aspects and sentiment of discussion forum posts and thus provides a more informed analysis of MOOC posts.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Problem Setting and Data</head><p>MOOC participants primarily communicate through discussion forums, consisting of posts, which are short pieces of text. <ref type="table">Table 1</ref> provides examples of posts in MOOC forums. Posts 1 and 2 report issues and feedback for the course, while post 3 is a social interaction message. Our goal is to distinguish problem-reporting posts such as 1 and 2 from social posts such as 3, and to identify the issues that are being discussed.</p><p>We formalize this task as an aspect-sentiment prediction problem ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Liu and Zhang, 2012</ref>). The issues reported in MOOC forums can be related to the different elements of the course such as lec- tures and quizzes, which are referred to as aspects. The aspects are selected based on MOOC domain expertise and inspiration from <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">Stump et al. (2013)</ref>, aiming to cover common concerns that could ben- efit from intervention. The task is to predict these  <ref type="table">Table 2</ref>: Descriptions of coarse and fine aspects.</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">COARSE-ASPECT FINE-ASPECT</formula><p>aspects for each post, along with the sentiment po- larity toward the aspect, which we code as posi- tive, negative, or neutral. The negative-sentiment posts, along with their aspects, allow us to iden- tify potentially correctable issues in the course.</p><p>As labels are expensive in this scenario, we for- mulate the task as a weakly supervised prediction problem. In our work, we assume that a post has at most one fine-grained aspect, as we found that this was true for 90% of the posts in our data. This property is due in part to the brevity of fo- rum posts, which are much shorter documents than those considered in other aspect-sentiment scenar- ios such as product reviews.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Aspect Hierarchy</head><p>While we do not require labeled data, our ap- proaches allow the analyst to instead relatively easily encode a small amount of domain knowl- edge by seeding the models with a few words re- lating to each aspect of interest. Hence, we refer to our approach as weakly supervised. Our models can further make use of hierarchical structure be- tween the aspects. The proposed approach is flex- ible, allowing the aspect seeds and hierarchy to be selected for a given MOOC domain.</p><p>For the purposes of this study, we represent the MOOC aspects with a two-level hierarchy. We identify a list of nine fine-grained aspects, which are grouped into four coarse topics. The coarse aspects consist of LECTURE, QUIZ, CERTIFICATE, and SOCIAL topics. <ref type="table">Table 2</ref> provides a description of each of the aspects and also gives the number of posts in each aspect category after annotation.</p><p>As both LECTURE and QUIZ are key coarse- level aspects in online courses, and more nu- anced aspect information for these is important to facilitate instructor interventions, we iden- tify fine-grained aspects for these coarse aspects.</p><p>For LECTURE we identify LECTURE-CONTENT, LECTURE-VIDEO, LECTURE-AUDIO, LECTURE- SUBTITLES, and LECTURE-LECTURER as fine aspects. For QUIZ, we identify the fine as- pects QUIZ-CONTENT, QUIZ-GRADING, QUIZ- DEADLINES, and QUIZ-SUBMISSION. We use the label SOCIAL to refer to social interaction posts that do not mention a problem-related aspect.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Dataset</head><p>We construct a dataset by sampling posts from MOOC courses to capture the variety of aspects discussed in online courses. We include courses from different disciplines (business, technology, history, and the sciences) to ensure broad coverage of aspects. Although we adopt an approach that does not require labeled data for training, which is important for most practical MOOC scenarios, in order to validate our methods we obtain labels for the sampled posts using Crowdflower, 1 an online crowd-sourcing annotation platform. Each post was annotated by at least 3 annotators. Crowd- flower calculates confidence in labels by comput- ing trust scores for annotators using test questions. <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Kolhatkar et al. (2013)</ref> provide a detailed analysis of Crowdflower trust calculations and the relation- ship to inter-annotator agreement. We follow their recommendations and retain only labels with con- fidence &gt; 0.5.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Aspect-Sentiment Prediction Models</head><p>In this section, we develop models and feature- extraction techniques to address the challenges of aspect-sentiment prediction for MOOC forums. We present two weakly-supervised methods- first, using a seeded topic modeling approach <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Jagarlamudi et al., 2012</ref>) to identify aspects and sen- timent. Second, building upon this method, we then introduce a more powerful statistical rela- tional model which reasons over the seeded LDA predictions as well as sentiment side-information to encode hierarchy information and correlations between sentiment and aspect.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">Seeded LDA Model</head><p>Topic models ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Blei et al., 2003)</ref>, which identify latent semantic themes from text corpora, have previously been successfully used to discover as- pects for sentiment analysis ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Diao et al., 2014</ref>). By equating the topics, i.e. discrete distributions over words, with aspects and/or sentiment polarities, topic models can recover aspect-sentiment predic- tions. In the MOOC context we are specifically in- terested in problems with the courses, rather than general topics which may be identified by a topic model, such as the topics of the course material.</p><p>To guide the topic model to identify aspects of interest, we use SeededLDA ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Jagarlamudi et al., 2012</ref>), a variant of LDA which allows an analyst to "seed" topics by providing key words that should belong to the topics.</p><p>We construct SeededLDA models by providing a set of seed words for each of the coarse and fine aspects in the aspect hierarchy of <ref type="table">Table 2</ref>. We also seed topics for positive, negative and neutral sen- timent polarities. The seed words for coarse topics are provided in <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Table 3</ref>, and fine aspects in Ta- ble 4. For the sentiment topics <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">(Table 5)</ref>, the seed words for the topic positive are positive words of- ten found in online courses such as thank, congrat- ulations, learn, and interest. Similarly, the seed words for the negative topic are negative in the context of online courses, such as difficult, error, issue, problem, and misunderstand.</p><p>Additionally, we also use SeededLDA for iso- lating some common problems in online courses that are associated with sentiment, such as dif- ficulty, availability, correctness, and course- specific seed words from the syllabus as described in <ref type="table">Table 6</ref>. Finally, having inferred the Seed- edLDA model from the data set, for each post p we predict the most likely aspect and the most likely sentiment polarity according to the post's inferred distribution over topics θ <ref type="bibr">(p)</ref> .</p><p>In our experiments, we tokenize and stem the posts using NLTK toolkit <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">(Loper and Bird, 2002</ref>), and use a stop word list tuned to online course dis- cussion forums. The topic model Dirichlet hyper- parameters are set to α = 0.01, β = 0.01 in our ex- periments. For SeededLDA models corresponding to the seed sets in <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Tables 3, 4</ref>, and 5, the number of topics is equal to the number of seeded topics. For SeededLDA models corresponding to the seed words in <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Tables 6 and 3</ref>, we use 10 topics, allow- ing for some unseeded topics that are not captured by the seed words.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">Hinge-loss Markov Random Fields</head><p>The approach described in the previous section au- tomatically identifies user-seeded aspects and sen- timent, but it does not make further use of struc- 77 LECTURE: lectur, video, download, volum, low, headphon, sound, audio, transcript, subtitl, slide, note QUIZ: quiz, assignment, question, midterm,exam, submiss, answer, grade, score, grad, midterm, due, deadlin CERTIFICATE: certif, score, signatur, statement, final, course, pass, receiv, coursera, accomplish, fail SOCIAL: name, course, introduction, stud, group, everyon, student    <ref type="table">Table 6</ref>: Seed words for sentiment specific to online courses ture or dependencies between these values, or any additional side-information. To address this, we propose a more powerful approach using hinge- loss Markov random fields (HL-MRFs), a scalable class of continuous, conditional graphical mod- els ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Bach et al., 2013)</ref>. HL-MRFs have achieved state-of-the-art performance in many domains in- cluding knowledge graph identification ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Pujara et al., 2013)</ref>, understanding engagements in MOOCs ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">Ramesh et al., 2014a</ref>), biomedicine and multi- relational link prediction <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(Fakhraei et al., 2014)</ref>, and modelling social trust ( ). These models can be specified using Probabilistic Soft Logic (PSL) ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Bach et al., 2015</ref>), a weighted first order logical templating language. An exam- ple of a PSL rule is</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">λ : P (a) ∧ Q(a, b) → R(b),</formula><p>where P, Q, and R are predicates, a and b are vari- ables, and λ is the weight associated with the rule. The weight of the rule indicates its importance in the HL-MRF probabilistic model, which defines a probability density function of the form</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">P (Y|X) ∝ exp − M r=1 λ r φ r (Y, X) φ r (Y, X) = (max{l r (Y, X), 0}) ρr ,<label>(1)</label></formula><p>where φ r (Y, X) is a hinge-loss potential corre- sponding to an instantiation of a rule, and is spec- ified by a linear function l r and optional exponent ρ r ∈ {1, 2}. For example, in our MOOC aspect- sentiment model, if P and F denote post P and fine aspect F, then we have predicates SEEDLDA- FINE(P, F) to denote the value corresponding to topic F in SeededLDA, and FINE-ASPECT(P, F) is the target variable denoting the fine aspect of the post P. A PSL rule to encode that the SeededLDA topic F suggests that aspect F is present is λ : SEEDLDA-FINE(P, F ) → FINE-ASPECT(P, F ).</p><p>We can generate more complex rules connecting the different features and target variables, e.g.</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">λ : SEEDLDA-FINE(P, F ) ∧ SENTIMENT(P, S) → FINE-ASPECT(P, F ).</formula><p>This rule encodes a dependency between SENTI- MENT and FINE-ASPECT, namely that the Seed-edLDA topic and a strong sentiment score increase the probability of the fine aspect. The HL-MRF model uses these rules to encode domain knowl- edge about dependencies among the predicates. The continuous value representation further helps in understanding the confidence of predictions.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3">Joint Aspect-Sentiment Prediction using</head><p>Probabilistic Soft Logic (PSL-Joint)</p><p>In this section, we describe our joint approach to predicting aspect and sentiment in online discus- sion forums, leveraging the strong dependence be- tween aspect and sentiment. We present a system designed using HL-MRFs which combines differ- ent features, accounting for their respective uncer- tainty, and encodes the dependencies between as- pect and sentiment in the MOOC context. <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">Table 7</ref> provides some representative rules from our model. <ref type="bibr">2</ref> The rules can be classified into two broad categories-1) rules that combine multiple features, and 2) rules that encode the dependencies between aspect and sentiment.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3.1">Combining Features</head><p>The first set of rules in <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">Table 7</ref> combine different features extracted from the post. SEEDLDA-FINE, SEEDLDA-COARSE and SEEDLDA-SENTIMENT- COURSE predicates in rules refer to SeededLDA posterior distributions using coarse, fine, and course-specific sentiment seed words respectively. The strength of our model comes from its abil- ity to encode different combinations of features and weight them according to their importance. The first rule in <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">Table 7</ref> combines the SeededLDA features from both SEEDLDA-FINE and SEEDLDA- COARSE to predict the fine aspect. Interpreting the rule, the fine aspect of the post is more likely to be LECTURE-LECTURER if the coarse Seed- edLDA score for the post is LECTURE, and the fine SeededLDA score for the post is LECTURE- LECTURER. Similarly, the second rule provides combinations of some of the other features used by the model-two different SeededLDA scores for sentiment, as indicated by seed words in Ta- bles 5 and 6. The third rule states that certain fine aspects occur together with certain values of sen- timent more than others. In online courses, posts that discuss grading usually talk about grievances and issues. The rule captures that QUIZ-GRADING occurs with negative sentiment in most cases. <ref type="bibr">2</ref> Full model available at https://github.com/artir/ramesh-acl15</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3.2">Encoding Dependencies Between Aspect and Sentiment</head><p>In addition to combining features, we also en- code rules to capture the taxonomic dependence between coarse and fine aspects, and the depen- dence between aspect and sentiment ( <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">Table 7</ref>, bot- tom). Rules 4 and 5 encode pair-wise depen- dency between FINE-ASPECT and SENTIMENT, and COARSE-ASPECT and FINE-ASPECT respec- tively. Rule 4 uses the SeededLDA value for QUIZ-DEADLINES to predict both SENTIMENT, and FINE-ASPECT jointly. This together with other rules for predicting SENTIMENT and FINE- ASPECT individually creates a constrained satis- faction problem, forcing aspect and sentiment to agree with each other. Rule 5 is similar to rule 4, capturing the taxonomic relationship between tar- get variables COARSE-ASPECT and FINE-ASPECT.</p><p>Thus, by using conjunctions to combine fea- tures and appropriately weighting these rules, we account for the uncertainties in the underlying fea- tures and make them more robust. The combina- tion of these two different types of weighted rules, referred to below as PSL-Joint, is able to reason collectively about aspect and sentiment.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Empirical Evaluation</head><p>In this section, we present the quantitative and qualitative results of our models on the annotated MOOC dataset. Our models do not require labeled data for training; we use the label annotations only for evaluation. <ref type="table" target="#tab_5">Tables 8 -11</ref> show the results for the SeededLDA and PSL-Joint models. Sta- tistically significant differences, evaluated using a paired t-test with a rejection threshold of 0.01, are typed in bold.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.1">SeededLDA for Aspect-Sentiment</head><p>For SeededLDA, we use the seed words for coarse, fine, and sentiment given in <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Tables 3 -5</ref>. After training the model, we use the SeededLDA multinomial posterior distribution to predict the target variables. We use the maximum value in the posterior for the distribution over topics for each post to obtain predictions for coarse aspect, fine aspect, and sentiment. We then calculate pre- cision, recall and F1 values comparing with our ground truth labels.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>PSL-JOINT RULES</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Rules combining features</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>SEEDLDA-FINE(POST, LECTURE-LECTURER) ∧ SEEDLDA-COARSE(POST, LECTURE) → FINE-ASPECT(POST, LECTURE-LECTURER) SEEDLDA-SENTIMENT-COURSE(POST, NEGATIVE) ∧ SEEDLDA-SENTIMENT(POST, NEGATIVE) → SENTIMENT(POST, NEGATIVE) SEEDLDA-SENTIMENT-COURSE(POST, NEGATIVE) ∧ SEEDLDA-FINE(POST, QUIZ-GRADING) → FINE-ASPECT(POST, QUIZ-GRADING)</head><p>Encoding dependencies between aspect and sentiment SEEDLDA-FINE(POST, QUIZ-DEADLINES) ∧ SENTIMENT(POST, NEGATIVE) → FINE-ASPECT(POST, QUIZ-DEADLINES) SEEDLDA-FINE(POST, QUIZ-SUBMISSION) ∧ FINE-ASPECT(POST, QUIZ-SUBMISSION) → COARSE-ASPECT(POST, QUIZ)      <ref type="table" target="#tab_5">Tables 8 and 9</ref> give the results for the fine aspects under LECTURE and QUIZ. PSL-JOINT performs better than SEEDEDLDA in most cases, with- out suffering any statistically significant losses. Notable cases include the increase in scores for LECTURE-LECTURER, LECTURE-SUBTITLES, LECTURE-CONTENT, QUIZ-CONTENT, QUIZ- GRADING, and QUIZ-DEADLINES, for which the scores increase by a large margin over Seed- edLDA. We observe that for LECTURE-CONTENT and QUIZ-CONTENT, the increase in scores is more significant than others with SeededLDA per- forming very poorly. Since both lecture and quiz content have the same kind of words related to the course material, SeededLDA is not able to dis- tinguish between these two aspects. We found that in 63% of these missed predictions, Seed- edLDA predicts LECTURE-CONTENT, instead of QUIZ-CONTENT, and vice versa. In contrast, PSL- Joint uses both coarse and fine SeededLDA scores and captures the dependency between a coarse as- pect and its corresponding fine aspect. There- fore, PSL-Joint is able to distinguish between LECTURE-CONTENT and QUIZ-CONTENT. In the next section, we present some examples of posts that SEEDEDLDA misclassified but were predicted correctly by PSL-Joint. <ref type="table" target="#tab_7">Table 10</ref> presents results for the coarse-aspects. We observe that PSL-Joint performs better than SeededLDA for all classes. In particular for CER- TIFICATE and QUIZ, PSL-Joint exhibits a marked increase in scores when compared to SeededLDA. This is also true for sentiment, for which the scores for NEUTRAL and NEGATIVE sentiment show sig- nificant improvement <ref type="table" target="#tab_8">(Table 11)</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Correct Label</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>PSL</head><p>SeededLDA Post</p><formula xml:id="formula_4">QUIZ-CONTENT QUIZ-CONTENT LECTURE-CONTENT</formula><p>There is a typo or other mistake in the assignment instructions (e.g. es- sential information omitted) Type ID: programming-content Problem ID: programming-  As the second lecture video told me I started windows telnet and connected to the virtual device. Then I typed the same command for sending an sms that the lecture video told me to. The phone received a message all right and I was able to open it but the message itself seems to be written with some strange characters. <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Table 13</ref>: Example posts whose second-best prediction is correct <ref type="table" target="#tab_10">Table 12</ref> presents some examples of posts that PSL-Joint predicted correctly, and which Seed- edLDA misclassified. The first two examples illustrate that PSL can predict the subtle dif- ference between LECTURE-CONTENT and QUIZ- CONTENT. Particularly notable is the third ex- ample, which contains mention of both subtitles and audio, but the negative sentiment is associ- ated with audio rather than subtitles. PSL-Joint predicts the fine aspect as LECTURE-AUDIO, even though the underlying SeededLDA feature has a high score for LECTURE-SUBTITLES. This exam- ple illustrates the strength of the joint reasoning approach in PSL-Joint. Finally, in the last exam- ple, the post mentions starting a group to discuss videos. This is an ambiguous post containing the keyword video, while it is in reality a social post about starting a group. PSL-Joint is able to predict this because it uses both the sentiment scores as- sociated with the post and the SeededLDA scores for fine aspect, and infers that social posts are gen- erally positive. So, combining the feature values for social aspect and positive sentiment, it is able to predict the fine aspect as SOCIAL correctly. The continuous valued output predictions pro- duced by PSL-Joint allow us to rank the predicted variables by output prediction value. Analyzing the predictions for posts that PSL-Joint misclassi- fied, we observe that for four out of nine fine as- pects, more than 70% of the time the correct label is in the top three predictions. And, for all fine aspects, the correct label is found in the top 3 pre- dictions around 40% of the time. Thus, using the top three predictions made by PSL-Joint, we can understand the fine aspect of the post to a great extent. <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Table 13</ref> gives some examples of posts for which the second best prediction by PSL-Joint is the correct label. For these examples, we found that PSL-Joint misses the correct prediction by a small margin(&lt; 0.2). Since our evaluation scheme only considers the maximum value to determine the scores, these examples were treated as misclas- sified.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.3">Interpreting PSL-Joint Predictions</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.4">Understanding Instructor Intervention using PSL-Joint Predictions</head><p>In our 3275 annotated posts, the instructor replied to 787 posts. Of these, 699 posts contain a men- tion of some MOOC aspect. PSL-Joint predicts 97.8% from those as having an aspect and 46.9% as the correct aspect. This indicates that PSL-Joint is capable of identifying the most important posts, i.e. those that the instructor replied to, with high accuracy. PSL-Joint's MOOC aspect predictions can potentially be used by the instructor to select a subset of posts to address in order to cover the main reported issues. We found in our data that some fine aspects, such as CERTIFICATE, have a higher percentage of instructor replies than oth- ers, such as QUIZ-GRADING. Using our system, instructors can sample from multiple aspect cate-gories, thereby making sure that all categories of problems receive attention.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Conclusion</head><p>In this paper, we developed a weakly supervised joint probabilistic model (PSL-Joint) for predict- ing aspect-sentiment in online courses. Our model provides the ability to conveniently encode do- main information in the form of seed words, and weighted logical rules capturing the dependen- cies between aspects and sentiment. We validated our approach on an annotated dataset of MOOC posts sampled from twelve courses. We com- pared our PSL-Joint probabilistic model to a sim- pler SeededLDA approach, and demonstrated that PSL-Joint produced statistically significantly bet- ter results, exhibiting a 3-5 times improvement in F1 score in most cases over a system using only SeededLDA. As further shown by our qualitative results and instructor reply information, our sys- tem can potentially be used for understanding stu- dent requirements and issues, identifying posts for instructor intervention, increasing student reten- tion, and improving future iterations of the course.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" validated="true"><head>Table 3 : Seed words for coarse aspects</head><label>3</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>LECTURE-VIDEO: video, problem, download, play, player, watch, speed, length, long, fast, slow, render, qualiti 
LECTURE-AUDIO: volum, low, headphon, sound, audio, hear, maximum, troubl, qualiti, high, loud, heard 
LECTURE-LECTURER: professor, fast, speak, pace, follow, speed, slow, accent, absorb, quick, slowli 
LECTURE-SUBTITLES: transcript, subtitl, slide, note, lectur, difficult, pdf 
LECTURE-CONTENT: typo, error, mistak, wrong, right, incorrect, mistaken 
QUIZ-CONTENT: question, challeng, difficult, understand, typo, error, mistak, quiz, assignment 
QUIZ-SUBMISSION: submiss, submit, quiz, error, unabl, resubmit 
QUIZ-GRADING: answer, question, answer, grade, assignment, quiz, respons ,mark, wrong, score 
QUIZ-DEADLINE: due, deadlin, miss, extend, late 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" validated="false"><head>Table 4 :</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Seed words for fine aspects POSITIVE: interest, excit, thank, great, happi, glad, enjoy, forward, insight, opportun, clear, fantast, fascin, learn, hope, congratul NEGATIVE: problem, difficult, error, issu, unabl, misunderstand, terribl, bother, hate, bad, wrong, mistak, fear, troubl NEUTRAL: coursera, class, hello, everyon, greet, nam, meet, group, studi, request, join, introduct, question, thank</figDesc><table></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3" validated="false"><head>Table 5 :</head><label>5</label><figDesc>Seed words for sentiment DIFFICULTY: difficult, understand, ambigu, disappoint, hard, follow, mislead, difficulti, challeng, clear CONTENT: typo, error, mistak, wrong, right, incorrect, mistaken, score AVAILABILITY: avail, nowher, find, access, miss, view, download, broken, link, bad, access, deni, miss, permiss COURSE-1: develop, eclips, sdk, softwar, hardware, accuser, html, platform, environ, lab, ide, java, COURSE-2: protein, food, gene, vitamin, evolut, sequenc, chromosom, genet, speci, peopl, popul, evolv, mutat, ancestri COURSE-3: compani, product, industri, strategi, decision, disrupt, technolog, market</figDesc><table></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4" validated="false"><head>Table 7 : Representative rules from PSL-Joint model</head><label>7</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Model 

LECTURE-CONTENT 
LECTURE-VIDEO 
LECTURE-AUDIO 
LECTURE-LECTURER 
LECTURE-SUBTITLES 

Prec. 
Rec. 
F1 
Prec. 
Rec. 
F1 
Prec. 
Rec. 
F1 
Prec. 
Rec. 
F1 
Prec. 
Rec. 
F1 

SEEDEDLDA 
0.137 
0.057 
0.08 
0.156 
0.256 
0.240 
0.684 
0.684 
0.684 
0.037 
0.159 
0.06 
0.289 
0.631 
0.397 
PSL-JOINT 
0.407 
0.413 
0.410 
0.411 
0.591 
0.485 
0.635 
0.537 
0.582 
0.218 
0.623 
0.323 
0.407 
0.53 
0.461 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_5" validated="false"><head>Table 8 : Precision, recall and F1 scores for LECTURE fine aspects</head><label>8</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Model 

QUIZ-CONTENT 
QUIZ-SUBMISSION 
QUIZ-DEADLINES 
QUIZ-GRADING 

Prec 
Rec. 
F1 
Prec 
Rec. 
F1 
Prec. 
Rec. 
F1 
Prec. 
Rec. 
F1 

SEEDEDLDA 
0.042 
0.006 
0.011 
0.485 
0.398 
0.437 
0.444 
0.141 
0.214 
0.524 
0.508 
0.514 
PSL-JOINT 
0.324 
0.405 
0.36 
0.521 
0.347 
0.416 
0.667 
0.563 
0.611 
0.572 
0.531 
0.550 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_6" validated="false"><head>Table 9 : Precision, recall and F1 scores for QUIZ fine aspects</head><label>9</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Model 

LECTURE 
QUIZ 
CERTIFICATE 
SOCIAL 

Prec 
Rec. 
F1 
Prec. 
Rec. 
F1 
Prec. 
Rec. 
F1 
Prec. 
Rec. 
F1 

SEEDEDLDA 
0.597 
0.673 
0.632 
0.752 
0.583 
0.657 
0.315 
0.845 
0.459 
0.902 
0.513 
0.654 
PSL-JOINT 
0.563 
0.715 
0.630 
0.724 
0.688 
0.706 
0.552 
0.711 
0.621 
0.871 
0.530 
0.659 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_7" validated="false"><head>Table 10 : Precision, recall and F1 scores for coarse aspects</head><label>10</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Model 

POSITIVE 
NEGATIVE 
NEUTRAL 

Prec 
Rec. 
F1 
Prec. 
Rec. 
F1 
Prec. 
Rec. 
F1 

SEEDEDLDA 
0.104 
0.721 
0.182 
0.650 
0.429 
0.517 
0.483 
0.282 
0.356 
PSL-JOINT 
0.114 
0.544 
0.189 
0.571 
0.666 
0.615 
0.664 
0.322 
0.434 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_8" validated="false"><head>Table 11 :</head><label>11</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Precision, recall and F1 scores for sentiment 

5.2 PSL for Joint Aspect-Sentiment 
(PSL-Joint) 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_9" validated="false"><head>mistake Browser: Chrome 32 OS: Windows 7</head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><table>QUIZ-CONTENT 
QUIZ-CONTENT 
LECTURE-CONTENT 

There is a typo or other mistake on the page (e.g. factual error informa-
tion omitted) Week 4 Quiz Question 6: Question 6 When a user clicks 
on a View that has registered to show a Context Menu which one of the 
following methods will be called? 

LECTURE-AUDIO 
LECTURE-AUDIO 
LECTURE-SUBTITLES 

Thanks for the suggestion about downloading the video and referring to 
the subtitles. I will give that a try but I would also like to point out that 
what the others are saying is true for me too: The audio is just barely 
audible even when the volume on my computer is set to 100%. 

SOCIAL 
SOCIAL 
LECTURE-VIDEO 

Let's start a group for discussing the lecture videos. 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_10" validated="false"><head>Table 12 :</head><label>12</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Example posts that PSL-Joint predicted correctly, but were misclassified by SeededLDA 

Correct Label 
Predicted Label 
Second 
Post 
Prediction 

LECTURE-CONTENT 
QUIZ-CONTENT 
LECTURE-CONTENT 

I have a difference of opinion to the answer for Question 6 too. It differs from 
what is presented in lecture 1. 

SOCIAL 
LECTURE-SUBTITLES 
SOCIAL 

Hello guys!!! I am ... The course materials are extraordinary. The subtitles are 
really helpful! Thanks to instructors for giving us all a wonderful opportunity. 

LECTURE-CONTENT 
QUIZ-CONTENT 
LECTURE-CONTENT 

</table></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> http://www.crowdflower.com/</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Hinge-loss Markov random fields: Convex inference for structured prediction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Stephen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bert</forename><surname>Bach</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ben</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lise</forename><surname>London</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Getoor</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Conference on Uncertainty in Artificial Intelligence (UAI)</title>
		<meeting>the Conference on Uncertainty in Artificial Intelligence (UAI)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Bach</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Broecheler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Getoor</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:1505.04406</idno>
		<title level="m">Hinge-loss Markov random fields and probabilistic soft logic</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>cs.LG</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Latent Dirichlet allocation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Blei</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Andrew</forename><forename type="middle">Y</forename><surname>Ng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michael</forename><forename type="middle">I</forename><surname>Jordan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Machine Learning Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
			<publisher>JMLR</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">An unsupervised aspect-sentiment model for online reviews</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Samuel</forename><surname>Brody</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Noemie</forename><surname>Elhadad</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of Human Language Technologies: Conference of the North American Chapter</title>
		<meeting>Human Language Technologies: Conference of the North American Chapter</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>HLT</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Predicting instructor&apos;s intervention in mooc forums</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Snigdha</forename><surname>Chaturvedi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dan</forename><surname>Goldwasser</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hal</forename><surname>Daumé</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Iii</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL)</title>
		<meeting>the Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Jointly modeling aspects, ratings and sentiments for movie recommendation (JMARS)</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Qiming</forename><surname>Diao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Minghui</forename><surname>Qiu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chao-Yuan</forename><surname>Wu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alexander</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Smola</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jing</forename><surname>Jiang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chong</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the SIGKDD International Conference on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining (KDD)</title>
		<meeting>the SIGKDD International Conference on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining (KDD)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Old wine or warm beer: Target-specific sentiment analysis of adjectives</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Angela</forename><surname>Fahrni</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Manfred</forename><surname>Klenner</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Symposium on Affective Language in Human and Machine (AISB)</title>
		<meeting>the Symposium on Affective Language in Human and Machine (AISB)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Network-based drug-target interaction prediction with probabilistic soft logic</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Shobeir</forename><surname>Fakhraei</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bert</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Louiqa</forename><surname>Raschid</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lise</forename><surname>Getoor</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE/ACM Transactions on Computational Biology and Bioinformatics</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>TCBB</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A flexible framework for probabilistic models of social trust</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bert</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Angelika</forename><surname>Kimmig</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lise</forename><surname>Getoor</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jennifer</forename><surname>Golbeck</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the International Conference on Social Computing, Behavioral-Cultural Modeling, &amp; Prediction (SBP)</title>
		<meeting>the International Conference on Social Computing, Behavioral-Cultural Modeling, &amp; Prediction (SBP)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Incorporating lexical priors into topic models</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jagadeesh</forename><surname>Jagarlamudi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hal</forename><surname>Daumé</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Iii</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Raghavendra</forename><surname>Udupa</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the European Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics (EACL)</title>
		<meeting>the European Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics (EACL)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Aspect and sentiment unification model for online review analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Jo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Oh</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the International Conference on Web Search and Data Mining (WSDM)</title>
		<meeting>the International Conference on Web Search and Data Mining (WSDM)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A hierarchical aspect-sentiment model for online reviews</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Suin</forename><surname>Kim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jianwen</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Zheng</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alice</forename><surname>Oh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Shixia</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence (AAAI)</title>
		<meeting>the AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence (AAAI)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Annotating anaphoric shell nouns with their antecedents</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Varada</forename><surname>Kolhatkar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Heike</forename><surname>Zinsmeister</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Graeme</forename><surname>Hirst</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Linguistic Annotation Workshop and Interoperability with Discourse</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Joint sentiment/topic model for sentiment analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chenghua</forename><surname>Lin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yulan</forename><surname>He</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Conference on Information and Knowledge Management (CIKM)</title>
		<meeting>the Conference on Information and Knowledge Management (CIKM)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Weakly supervised joint sentiment-topic detection from text</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chenghua</forename><surname>Lin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yulan</forename><surname>He</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Everson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Ruger</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE Transactions on Knowledge and Data Engineering</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A survey of opinion mining and sentiment analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bing</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lei</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Mining Text Data</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">NLTK: The natural language toolkit</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Edward</forename><surname>Loper</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Steven</forename><surname>Bird</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the ACL Workshop on Effective Tools and Methodologies for Teaching Natural Language Processing and Computational Linguistics (ETMTNLP)</title>
		<meeting>the ACL Workshop on Effective Tools and Methodologies for Teaching Natural Language Processing and Computational Linguistics (ETMTNLP)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Multi-aspect sentiment analysis with topic models</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bin</forename><surname>Lu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Myle</forename><surname>Ott</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Claire</forename><surname>Cardie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Benjamin</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Tsou</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the International Conference on Data Mining Workshops (ICDMW)</title>
		<meeting>the International Conference on Data Mining Workshops (ICDMW)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Aspect extraction through semi-supervised modeling</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Arjun</forename><surname>Mukherjee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bing</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL)</title>
		<meeting>the Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Knowledge graph identification</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jay</forename><surname>Pujara</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hui</forename><surname>Miao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lise</forename><surname>Getoor</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">William</forename><surname>Cohen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">International Semantic Web Conference (ISWC)</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Learning latent engagement patterns of students in online courses</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Arti</forename><surname>Ramesh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dan</forename><surname>Goldwasser</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bert</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hal</forename><surname>Daume</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Iii</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lise</forename><surname>Getoor</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence (AAAI)</title>
		<meeting>the AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence (AAAI)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Understanding MOOC discussion forums using seeded lda</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Arti</forename><surname>Ramesh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dan</forename><surname>Goldwasser</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bert</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hal</forename><surname>Daumé</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Iii</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lise</forename><surname>Getoor</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ACL Workshop on Innovative Use of NLP for Building Educational Applications (BEA)</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Development of a framework to classify MOOC discussion forum posts: Methodology and challenges</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Glenda</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Stump</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jennifer</forename><surname>Deboer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jonathan</forename><surname>Whittinghill</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lori</forename><surname>Breslow</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">NIPS Workshop on Data Driven Education</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Modeling online reviews with multi-grain topic models</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ivan</forename><surname>Titov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ryan</forename><surname>Mcdonald</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the International Conference on World Wide Web</title>
		<meeting>the International Conference on World Wide Web</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>WWW</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Jointly modeling aspects and opinions with a maxEnt-LDA hybrid</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jing</forename><surname>Wayne Xin Zhao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hongfei</forename><surname>Jiang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xiaoming</forename><surname>Yan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</title>
		<meeting>the Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>EMNLP</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
