<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T10:14+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Learning to Mine Query Subtopics from Query Log</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date>July 26-31, 2015</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Zhenzhong</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Institute of Software</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Chinese Academy of Sciences</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Beijing</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Le</forename><surname>Sun</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Institute of Software</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Chinese Academy of Sciences</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Beijing</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xianpei</forename><surname>Han</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Institute of Software</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Chinese Academy of Sciences</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Beijing</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Learning to Mine Query Subtopics from Query Log</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 53rd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics and the 7th International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing</title>
						<meeting>the 53rd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics and the 7th International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing <address><addrLine>Beijing, China</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="341" to="345"/>
							<date type="published">July 26-31, 2015</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Many queries in web search are ambiguous or multifaceted. Identifying the major senses or facets of queries is very important for web search. In this paper, we represent the major senses or facets of queries as subtopics and refer to indentifying senses or facets of queries as query subtopic mining, where query subtop-ic are represented as a number of clusters of queries. Then the challenges of query subtopic mining are how to measure the similarity between queries and group them semantically. This paper proposes an approach for mining subtopics from query log, which jointly learns a similarity measure and groups queries by explicitly modeling the structure among them. Compared with previous approaches using manually defined similarity measures, our approach produces more desirable query subtop-ics by learning a similarity measure. Experimental results on real queries collected from a search engine log confirm the effectiveness of the proposed approach in mining query sub-topics.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Understanding the search intents of queries is essential for satisfying users' information needs and is very important for many search tasks such as personalized search, query suggestion, and search result presentation. However, it is not a trivial task because the underlying intents of the same query may be different for different users. Two well-known types of such queries are am- biguous queries and multifaceted queries. For example, the ambiguous query 'michael jordon' may refer to a basketball player or a professor of statistics in Berkeley. The multifaceted query 'harry potter' may refer to different search in- tents such as films, books, or games and so on.</p><p>Many approaches have been proposed to identi- fy the search intents of a query which are repre- sented by search goals, topics, or subtopics. For example, <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Broder (2002)</ref> classified query intents into three search goals: informational, naviga- tional, and transactional. <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Broder et al. (2007)</ref> and <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Li et al. (2005)</ref> represented query intents by top- ics. <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Clarke et al. (2009)</ref> represented query intents by subtopics which denote different senses or multiple facets of queries.</p><p>Previous work on query subtopic mining is mostly based on clustering framework by manu- ally defining a similarity measure with few fac- tors. <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Hu et al. (2012)</ref> employed an agglomerative clustering algorithm with a similarity measure combining string similarities, click similarities, and keyword similarities linearly. <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Wang et al. (2013)</ref> applied affinity propagation algorithm <ref type="bibr">(Frey and Dueck, 2009</ref>) with a sense-based simi- larity. <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Tsukuda et al. (2013)</ref> used a hierarchical clustering algorithm with the similarity measure based on search results.</p><p>In this paper, we argue that the similarity be- tween queries is affected by many different fac- tors and it could produce more desirable query subtopics by learning a similarity measure. To learn a similarity measure for query subtopic mining, a natural approach is to use a binary classifier, that is, the classifier targets pairs of queries and makes predictions about whether they belong to the same subtopic. However, be- cause such pairwise classifiers assume that pairs are independent, they might make inconsistent predictions: e.g., predicting queries qi and qj, qj and qk to belong to the same subtopic, but qi and qk to belong to different subtopics. For example, given three queries, 'luxury car', 'sport car' and 'XJ sport', for the query 'jaguar', a lexicon- similarity-based classifier is easy to learn that 'luxury car' and 'sport car', and 'sport car' and 'XJ sport' belong to the same subtopic; but diffi- cult to learn that 'luxury car' and 'XJ sport' be- long to the same subtopic. From this example, we can see that a learner should exploit these transitive dependencies among queries to learn a more effective similarity measure. Hence, in this paper, our first contribution is that we learn a similarity measure by explicitly modeling the dependencies among queries in the same subtop- ic. The second contribution is that we analyze the performance of the proposed approach with dif- ferent dependencies among queries. The third contribution is that we conduct experiments on real-world data and the experimental results con- firm the effectiveness of the proposed approach in mining query subtopics.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Learning to Mine Query Subtopics</head><p>In this section, we present our approach in details. First, we collect queries as subtopic candidates from query log using a heuristic method. Then, we learn a similarity measure to mine query sub- topics from these candidates.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">Collecting Subtopic Candidates from Query Log</head><p>In web search, users usually add additional words to clarify the underlying intents of a query ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Hu et al., 2012</ref>). For example, if the ambiguous query 'jaguar' does not satisfy a user's infor- mation need, he/she may submit 'jaguar sport car' as an expanded query to specify the subtopic. Therefore, for a given query q, we collect its re- formulations with additional words from query log as query subtopic candidates, e.g., we collect {'jaguar sports car', 'jaguar XJ sport', 'jaguar diet', …} for query 'jaguar'. We say query q ' is a subtopic candidate of q if (1) q ' is superset of q (e.g. q ' = 'jaguar sports car' and q = 'jaguar'), and (2) q ' occurred at least five times in query log. In this way, we collect a series of subtopic candi- dates for each query. Many subtopic candidates, however, belong to the same subtopic, e.g., 'jag- uar sports car' and 'jaguar XJ sport'. Thus, to obtain the subtopics of a query, we need to group its subtopic candidates into clusters, each of which corresponds to an individual subtopic.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">Mining Query Subtopics</head><p>As we described above, we need to group the subtopic candidates of a query into clusters to obtain its subtopics. The key to producing desir- able subtopics is how to measure the similarity between subtopic candidates. In this paper, we learn a similarity measure by exploiting the de- pendencies among subtopic candidates in the same subtopic. We represent each pair of subtopic candidates qi and qj as a feature vector ϕ(qi, qj), each dimen- sion of which describes a factor. The similarity measure Simw parameterized by w is defined as Simw(qi, qj) = w T •ϕ(qi, qj), which maps pairs of subtopic candidates to a real number indicating how similar the pair is: positive for similar and negative for dissimilar. As argued in the intro- duction, the dependencies among subtopic can- didates within the same subtopic are useful for learning an effective similarity measure. We de- note the dependencies among subtopic candi- dates as a graph h, whose vertices are subtopic candidates and edges connect two vertices be- longing to the same subtopic. In this paper, we employ two different graphs. The first one is the all-connection structure, where all subtopic can- didates belonging to the same subtopic associate with each other. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref> gives an example of the all-connection structure. The second one is the strong-connection structure, where each subtopic candidate only associates with its 'most similar' subtopic candidate within the same subtopic. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 2</ref> gives an example.  Formally, we denote the set of subtopic candi- dates for a given query q as S = {q1, q2, …, qN}. The label y is a partition of the N subtopic candi- dates into subtopic clusters. h is the correspond- ing graph that is consistent with y. h is consistent with a clustering y if every cluster in y is a con- nected component in h, and there are no edges in h that connect two distinct clusters in y. Given S, our approach makes predictions by maximizing the sum of similarities for subtopic candidate pairs that are adjacent in h, that is,</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">T w i j i j ( , ) ( , ) (i, j) (i,j) arg max ( , ) arg max w ( , ) y h Y H y h Y H h h Sim q q q q           </formula><p>where Y and H are the sets of possible y and h respectively. (i, j) ∈h denotes qi and qj are di- rectly connected in h.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>342</head><p>To predict a partition y with the all-connection structure, we use the algorithm in ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Bansal et al., 2002</ref>) with the objective function Eq (1). To pre- dict a partition y with the strong-connection structure, we run Kruskal's algorithm on h and each tree corresponds to a subtopic, as shown in Algorithm 1. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3">Solving the Proposed Approach</head><p>For a given set of subtopic candidates with anno- tated subtopics, {(Sn, yn)} (1≤n≤N), we need to estimate the optimal weight w. Empirically, the optimal weight w should minimize the error be- tween the predicted partition y ' and the true parti- tion y, and it should also have a good generaliza- tion capability. Therefore, it is learnt by solving the following optimization problem (Yu and Joa- chims, 2009):  </p><formula xml:id="formula_2">             </formula><p>where ∆(yn, y ' , h ' ) indicates a loss between a true partition yn and the predicted partition y ' speci- fied by h ' , ξn (1≤n≤N) is a set of slack variables to allow errors in the training data, and C con- trols the trade-off between empirical loss and model complexity. Intuitively, the loss function ∆(yn, y ' , h ' ) should satisfy that ∆(yn, y ' , h ' ) = 0 if yn = y ' , and rises as yn and y ' become more dissimilar. Because the all-connection structure is observable in the training data while the strong-connection struc- ture is hidden, we define different loss functions for them. For the all-connection structure, we define the loss function as, <ref type="bibr">'</ref>' n ( , , ) 10</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">D y y h T </formula><p>where T is the total number of pairs of subtopic candidates in the set partitioned by yn and y ' , and D is the total number of pairs where yn and y ' disagree about their cluster membership.</p><p>Since the strong-connection structure hn for yn is hidden in the training data, we cannot measure the loss between (yn, hn) and (y ' , h ' ). According to <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">(Yu and Joachims, 2009)</ref>, we define the loss function based on the inferred structure h ' as,</p><formula xml:id="formula_4">' '' n n n n (i, j) ( , , ) ( ) ( ) ( ,(i, j)) h y y h n y k y l y      </formula><p>where n(yn) and k(yn) are the number of subtopic candidates and the number of clusters in the cor- rect clustering yn. l(yn, (i, j) ) = 1 if qi and qj are in the same cluster in yn, otherwise l(yn, (i, j) ) = −1.</p><p>Then the optimization problem introduced in Eq.</p><p>(2) can be solved by the Concave-Convex Proce- dure (CCCP) <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">(Yuille and Rangarajan, 2003</ref>).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.4">Pairwise Similarity Features</head><p>The proposed approach requires a set of features to measure the similarity between two subtopic candidates. <ref type="table">Table 1</ref> lists the features employed in our approach. These features are categorized into two types: lexicon-based similarity and URL- based similarity. The lexicon-based similarity features are employed to measure the string simi- larity between two subtopic candidates. And the URL-based similarity features are used to meas- ure the semantic similarity between two subtopic candidates. The basic idea is that if two queries share many clicked URLs, they have similar search intent to each other ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Li et al., 2008</ref>). To</p><formula xml:id="formula_5">(2) (3)<label>(4)</label></formula><p>make the features comparable with each other, we normalize them into range of <ref type="bibr">[0,</ref><ref type="bibr">1]</ref> accord- ingly.</p><p>Feature Description COS cosine similarity between qi and qj EUC Euclidean distance between qi and qj JAC Jaccard coeff between qi and qj EDIT norm edit distance between qi and qj LEN |length(qi)-length(qj)| SUBSET whether one is a subset of the other UCOS cosine similarity between the clicked URL sets of qi and qj UJAC Jaccard coeff between the clicked URL sets of qi and qj <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>: pairwise similarity features employed in our approach</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Experiments</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Data Set</head><p>To illustrate the effectiveness of our approach, we use 100 ambiguous/multifaceted queries pro- vided by the NTCIR-9 intent task as original queries and collect their subtopic candidates from SogouQ dataset (http://www.sogou.com) using the method mentioned in section 2.1. For the 100 queries, we totally collect 2,280 query subtopic candidates. Three annotators manually label these candidates with their subtopics ac- cording to the content words of these candidates and their clicked web pages (if there are clicked URLs for the candidate in query log). A candi- date belongs to a specific subtopic if at least two annotators agree with it. At last we obtain 1,086 subtopics. We randomly split the original queries into two parts: half used for training and the rest for testing.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Evaluation Metrics and Baselines</head><p>To evaluate the performance of our approach, we employ the measures in ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Luo, 2005</ref>), which are computed as follows,</p><formula xml:id="formula_6">' ' ' ' '' ( , ( )) ( , ( )) , ( , )) ( , ) i i i i i i jj ii j i R g R R g R p r RR RR         </formula><p>where R ' is the predicted partition and R is the ground-truth partition; π(A, B) is a similarity measure between set A and B, which is Jaccard coefficient in this paper; and g(.) is the optimal mapping between R ' and R. Based on p and r, f- measure can be calculated as, The higher the f-measure score is, the better per- formance an approach achieves.</p><p>We used the following approaches as baselines:  K-means: we perform the standard k-means clustering algorithm with different manually defined similarity measures to mine query sub- topics. COS, JAC, EUC, EDIT refer to cosine similarity, Jaccard similarity, Euclidean dis- tance, and edit distance, respectively.  Binary Classification Cluster with the all- connection structure (BCC-AC): BCC-AC uses a SVM classifier to learn the weight w and clusters with correlation clustering method.  Binary Classification Cluster with the strong- connection structure (BCC-SC): BCC-SC uses a SVM classifier to learn the weight w and clusters with the method presented in Algo- rithm 1.</p><p>For the proposed methods, we denote the method with the all-connection structure as AC and the method with the strong-connection struc- ture as SC. The parameter C in Eq. <ref type="formula">(2)</ref> is picked from10 -2 to 10 4 using a 10-fold cross validation procedure. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3">Experimental Results</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Methods</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Table2</head><p>: the performance of all methods. "*" in- dicates significant difference at 0.05 level using a paired t-test. And AC achieves at least 11.28% precision improvement, 12.59% recall improvement, and 11.94% F-Measure improve- ment. These results confirm that the similarity between two subtopic candidates is affected by many factors and our methods can achieve more desirable query subtopics by learning a similarity measure.</p><p>Compared with BCC-AC and BCC-SC, SC achieves at least 8.07% precision improvement, 9.29% recall improvement, and 8.69% F- Measure improvement. And AC achieves at least 6.21% precision improvement, 6.53% recall im-provement, and 6.37% F-Measure improvement. These results confirm that the dependencies among the subtopic candidates within the same subtopic are useful for learning a similarity measure for query subtopic mining. Compared with AC, SC achieves 1.86% preci- sion improvement, 2.76% recall improvement, and 2.32% F-Measure improvement. These re- sults confirm that a subtopic candidate belonging to a given query subtopic does not need to simi- lar with all subtopic candidates within the given subtopic.</p><p>In order to understand which pairwise similari- ty feature is important for the problem of query subtopic mining, we list the features and their weights learned by SC, AC, and BCC (Binary Classification Cluster) in <ref type="table">Table 3</ref>  <ref type="table">Table 3</ref>: the features and their weights learned by the different methods.</p><p>As can be seen in <ref type="table">Table 3</ref>, JAC has the largest importance weight for mining query subtopics in the three methods. The URL-based features (UCOS and UJAC) have small importance weight. The reason is that clicked URLs are sparse in our query log and many long-tail sub- topic candidates in the same subtopic do not share any common URLs.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Conclusions</head><p>In this paper, we propose an approach for mining query subtopics from query log. Compared with previous approaches, our approach learns a simi- larity measure by explicitly modeling the de- pendencies among subtopic candidates within the same subtopic. Experimental results on real que- ries collected from a search engine log confirm our approach produces more desirable query sub- topics by using the learned similarity measure.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1. An example of the all-connection structure. The dashed circles denote the subtopics. The subtopic candidates (small solid circles) in the same dashed circle belong to the same subtopic. The weights indicate how similar the pair of two vertices is.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2. An example of the strong-connection structure.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Algorithm 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Mining Query Subtopic with Strong- connection Structure Input: the set of query subtopic candidates S = {q1, q2, …, qN}, feature vectors ϕ(qi, qj) (1≤i, j≤N, i≠j) and the weight w Output: the partition y //search for the strong-connection structure h, MST- KRUSKAL(G) denotes the Minimum Spanning Tree algorithm-Kruskal's algorithm for i = 1…N-1 do for j = i+1…N do sim = w T • ϕ(qi, qj); G(i, j)=−sim; end end h ' = MST-KRUSKAL(G); for i = 1…N-1 do for j = i+1…N do if h ' (i, j)&lt;0 then h(i, j) = 1; end end end // construct the partition y t = 0; y(1)=0; for i = 2…N do j = 1; while j ≤ i-1 do if h(j, i) = 1 then y(i)= y(j); break; end j = j+1; end if j ≥ i then t = t + 1; y(i) = t; end end return y</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>'</head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" validated="false"><head>Table 2 presents</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>the experimental results. Com-
pared with K-Means methods with different 
manually defined similarity measures, SC 
achieves at least 13.14% precision improvement, 
15.35% recall improvement, and 14.26% F-
Measure improvement. </table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3" validated="false"><head>.</head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><table>SC 
AC 
BCC 

COS 
0.08 
0.04 
0.19 
EUC 
−1.74 
−1.07 
−0.73 
JAC 
4.44 
4.73 
4.90 
EDIT 
−1.60 
−1.01 
−0.48 
LEN 
−1.34 
−0.91 
−1.07 
SUBSET 
0.21 
0.11 
−0.05 
UCOS 
0.01 
0.01 
0.04 
UJAC 
0.06 
0.07 
0.09 

</table></figure>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>The work is supported by the National Natural Science Foundation of China under Grants no. 61433015 and 61272324, and the National High Technology Development 863 Program of China under Grants no. 2015AA015405. Moreover, we sincerely thank the reviewers for their valuable comments.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Correlation clustering</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Bansal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Blum</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Chawla</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Machine Learning</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">56</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="89" to="113" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A taxonomy of web search</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">Z</forename><surname>Broder</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Sigir Forum</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">36</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3" to="10" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Robust classification of rare queries using web knowledge</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">Z</forename><surname>Broder</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Fontoura</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Gabrilovich</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Joshi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Josifovski</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">SIGIR</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="231" to="238" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Overview of the trec 2009 web track</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">L A</forename><surname>Clarke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Craswell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Soboroff</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">TREC&apos;09</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="9" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Ming query subtopics from search log data</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Hu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Qian</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Jiang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Pei</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Q</forename><surname>Zheng</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">SIGIR&apos;12</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="305" to="314" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Supervised clustering with support vector machines</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Finley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Joachims</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ICML</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="217" to="224" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Clustering by passing messages between data points</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Frey</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Dueck</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">science</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">315</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="972" to="976" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Kdd cup-2005 report: facing a great challenge</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Zheng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Dai</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">In SIGKDD Explor. Newsl</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="91" to="99" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Query-url bipartite based approach to personalized query recommendation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Kitsuregawa</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">AAAI&apos;08</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1189" to="1194" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">On Coreference resolution performance metrics</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Luo</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">HLT&amp;EMNLP</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="25" to="32" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Inferring Query Intent from Reformulations and Clicks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Radlinski</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Szummer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Craswell</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">WWW</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1171" to="1172" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Overview of the ntcir-9 intent task</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Song</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">NTCIR-9</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="82" to="105" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Microsoft research asia at the ntcir-10 intent task</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Tsukuda</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Dou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Sakai</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">NTCIR10</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="152" to="158" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Understanding the query: THCIB and THUIS at ntcir-10 intent task</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Tang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Xia</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Q</forename><surname>Hu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Na</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Q</forename><surname>Zhou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Zheng</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">NTCIR-10</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="132" to="139" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Learning Structural SVMs with Latent Variables</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Yu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Joachims</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ICML</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1169" to="1176" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The concaveconvex procedure</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Yuille</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Rangarajan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Neural Computation</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">915</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Method Feature</note>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
