<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T10:24+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Tracking unbounded Topic Streams</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
				<availability status="unknown"><p>Copyright Association for Computational Linguistics</p>
				</availability>
				<date>July 26-31, 2015. 2015</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dominik</forename><surname>Wurzer</surname></persName>
							<email>d.s.wurzer @sms.ed.ac.uk</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">School of Informatics</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">School of Informatics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">University of Edinburgh</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">University of Edinburgh vlavrenk</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Victor</forename><surname>Lavrenko</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">School of Informatics</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">School of Informatics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">University of Edinburgh</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">University of Edinburgh vlavrenk</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Miles</forename><surname>Osborne</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">School of Informatics</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">School of Informatics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">University of Edinburgh</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">University of Edinburgh vlavrenk</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bloomberg</forename><surname>London</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">School of Informatics</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">School of Informatics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">University of Edinburgh</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">University of Edinburgh vlavrenk</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Tracking unbounded Topic Streams</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 53rd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics and the 7th International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing</title>
						<meeting>the 53rd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics and the 7th International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing <address><addrLine>Beijing, China</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="1765" to="1773"/>
							<date type="published">July 26-31, 2015. 2015</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Tracking topics on social media streams is non-trivial as the number of topics mentioned grows without bound. This complexity is compounded when we want to track such topics against other fast moving streams. We go beyond traditional small scale topic tracking and consider a stream of topics against another document stream. We introduce two tracking approaches which are fully applicable to true streaming environments. When tracking 4.4 million topics against 52 million documents in constant time and space, we demonstrate that counter to expectations, simple single-pass clustering can outper-form locality sensitive hashing for nearest neighbour search on streams.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>The emergence of massive social media streams has sparked a growing need for systems able to process them. While previous research <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Hassan et al., 2009;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Becker et al., 2009;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Petrovic et al., 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Cataldi et al., (2010)</ref>; <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Weng et al., (2011)</ref>; Petrovic 2013) has focused on detecting new topics in unbounded textual streams, less attention was paid to following (tracking) the steadily growing set of topics. Standard topic tracking <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Allan, 2002</ref>) deals with helping human analysts follow and monitor ongoing events on massive data streams. By pairing topics with relevant documents, topic tracking splits a noisy stream of documents into sub-streams grouped by their target topics. This is a crucial task for financial and security analysts who are interested in pulling together relevant information from unstructured and noisy data streams. Other fields like summarization or topic modeling benefit from topic tracking as a mean to generate their data sources.</p><p>In todays data streams however, new topics emerge on a continual basis and we are interested in following all instead of just a small fraction of newly detected topics. Since its introduction <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Allan, 2002</ref>), standard topic tracking typically operates on a small scale and against a static set of predefined target topics. We go beyond such approaches and deal for the first time with massive, unbounded topic streams. Examples of unbounded topic streams include all events reported by news agencies each day across the world; popular examples of unbounded document streams include social media services such as Twitter. Tracking streams of topics allows re- search tasks like topic-modeling or summarization to be applied to millions of topics, a scale that is several orders of magnitude larger than those of current publications. We present two massive scale topic tracking systems capable of tracking unbounded topic streams. One is based on locality sensitive hashing (LSH) and the other on clus- tering. Since we operate on two unbounded data sources we are subject to the streaming model of computation <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">(Muthukrishnan, 2005)</ref>, which re- quires instant and single-pass decision making in constant time and space. Contrary to expectations, we find that nearest neighbour search on a stream based on clustering performs faster than LSH for the same level of accuracy. This is surprising as LSH is widely believed to be the fastest way of nearest neighbour search. Our experiments reveal how simple single-pass clustering outperforms LSH in terms of effectiveness and efficiency. Our results are general and apply to any setting where we have massive or infinite numbers of topics, matched against unboundedly large document streams.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Contributions</head><p>• For the first time we show how it is possi- ble to track an unbounded stream of topics in constant time and space, while maintain- ing a level of effectiveness that is statistically indistinguishable from an exact tracking sys- tem • We show how single-pass clustering can out- perform locality sensitive hashing in terms of effectiveness and efficiency for identifying nearest neighbours in a stream • We demonstrate that standard measures of similarity are sub-optimal when matching short documents against long documents</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Related Work</head><p>Topic or event tracking was first introduced in the Topic Detection and Tracking (TDT) program <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Allan, 2002</ref>). In TDT, topic tracking involves mon- itoring a stream of news documents with the in- tent to identify those documents relevant to a small predefined set of target topics. During the course of TDT, research focused extensively on the effec- tiveness of tracking systems, neglecting scale and efficiency. The three official data sets only range from 25k to 74k documents with a few hundred topics <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Allan, 2002</ref>).</p><p>More recently, the rise of publicly available real-time social media streams triggered new research on topic detection and tracking, in- tended to apply the technology to those high volume document streams. The novel data streams differ from the TDT data sets in their volume and level of noise. To provide real- time applications, traditional methods need to be overhauled to keep computation feasible. It became common practice to limit data sets to cope with the computational effort. Popular strate- gies involve reducing the number of tracked top- ics ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Lin et al., 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Nichols et al., 2012;</ref>) as well as sampling the document stream ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Ghosh et al., 2013</ref>). These approaches have proven to be efficient in cutting down workload but they also limit an application's performance. Furthermore, <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Sayyadi et al. (2009)</ref> discovered and tracked top- ics in social streams based on keyword graphs. They applied the sliding window principle to keep the computation feasible, although their data set only contained 18k documents. <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">Yang et al. 2012</ref> tracked topics in tweet streams using language models. To cope with the computational effort they assume a small set of topics of only a few dozen, which are defined in advance. <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">Tang et al. (2011)</ref> tracked a single topic on a few thousand blogs based on semantic graph topic models. <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">Pon et al. (2007)</ref> recommend news by tracking multi- ple topics for a user but their data sets only span several thousand documents and a few topics. Further related work includes the real-time filter- ing task, introduced as part of TREC's Microblog Track in 2012 ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Soboroff et al., 2012</ref>). <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Hong et al. (2013)</ref> explore topic tracking in tweet streams in relation to the TREC real-time filtering task by re- lying on a sliding window principle, while focus- ing on the cold start problem.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Topic Tracking</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Traditional Approach</head><p>Numerous approaches to topic tracking have emerged, spanning from probabilistic retrieval to statistical classification frameworks. While there is no single general approach, we define the tradi- tional approach to tracking from a high-level per- spective covering the basic principle of all previ- ous approaches. We do not make any assump- tions about the kind of topics, documents or dis- tance functions used. As defined by TDT <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Allan, 2002</ref>), we assume, we operate on an unbounded document stream with the goal of tracking a fixed set of target topics. Although topics are allowed to drift conceptually and evolve over time, new top- ics would always trigger the start of a new tracking system.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Algorithm 1 Traditional Tracking</head><p>INPUT:</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">TOPIC-SET {t T } DOCUMENT-STREAM {d D} OUTPUT: relevant topic-document pairs {t, d} while documents d in stream D do for all topics t in set T do similarity = computeSimilarity(d,t) if similarity &gt; threshold then emit relevant {t, d}</formula><p>As seen in Algorithm 1, documents arrive one at a time, requiring instant decision making through single pass processing. Each document is com- pared to all topics representations to identify the closest topic. The tracking decision is based on the similarity to the closest topic and usually defined by a thresholding strategy. Because incoming doc- uments can be relevant to more than one topic, we need to match it against all of them. Due to its sim- plicity, the traditional tracking approach is highly efficient when applied to a fairly low number of topics.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Shortcomings of the traditional approach</head><p>The traditional approach -though low in compu- tational effort -becomes challenging when scal- ing up the number of target topics. The compu- tational effort arises from the number of compar- isons made (the number of documents times top- ics). That explains, why researches following the traditional approach have either lowered the num- ber of documents or topics. Heuristics and index- ing methods increase the performance but offer no solution scalable to true streaming environments because they only allow for one-side scaling (ei- ther a large number of documents or topics). In- creasing either of the two components by a single document, increases the computational effort by the magnitude of the other one. For the extreme case of pushing to an infinite number of topics, tracking in constant space is a necessity.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Tracking at scale</head><p>Before directly turning to a full streaming set up in constant space, we approach tracking a topic stream on a document stream in unbounded space.</p><p>The key to scale up documents and topics, lies in reducing the number of necessary comparisons. Throughout the remainder of this paper we repre- sent documents and topics arriving from a steady high volume stream by term-weighted vectors in the vector space. In order to cut down the search space, we encap- sulate every topic vector by a hypothetical region marking its area of proximity. Those regions are intend to capture documents that are more likely to be relevant. Ideally, these regions form a hy- persphere centred around every topic vector with a radius equal to the maximum distance to rele- vant documents. The tracking procedure is then reduced to determining whether an incoming doc- ument is also enclosed by any of the hyperspheres.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">Approximated Tracking</head><p>Our first attempt to reach sub-linear execution time uses random segmentation of the vector space using hashing techniques. We frame the track- ing process as a nearest neighbour search prob- lem, as defined by <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Gionis et al. (1999)</ref>. Docu- ments arriving from a stream are seen as queries and the closest topics are the nearest neighbours to be identified. We explore locality sensitive hash- ing (LSH), as described by <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Indyk et al. (1998)</ref>, to approach high dimensional nearest neighbour search for topic tracking in sub-linear time. LSH, which has been used to speed up NLP applica- tions ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">Ravichandran et al., 2005</ref>), provides hash functions that guarantee that similar documents are more likely to be hashed to the same binary hash key than distant ones. Hash functions capture similarities between vectors in high dimensions and represent them on a low dimensional binary level. We apply the scheme by <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Charikar (2002)</ref>, which describes the probabilistic bounds for the cosine similarity between two vectors. Each bit in a hash key represents a documents position with respect to a randomly placed hyperplane. Those planes segment the vector space, forming high di- mensional polygon shaped buckets. Documents and topics are placed into a bucket by determin- ing on which side of each the hyperplanes they are positioned. We interpret these buckets as regions of proximity as the collision probability is directly proportional to the cosine similarity between two vectors.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Algorithm 2 LSH-based Tracking</head><p>INPUT:</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">TOPIC-STREAM {T } DOCUMENT-STREAM {D} OUTPUT: relevant topic-document pairs {t, d} while document d in T, D do if d T then hashKeys = hashLSH (d) store hashKeys in hashTables else if d D then candidateSet = lookupHashtables(hashLSH (d)) for all topics t in candidateSet do if similarity(d,t) &gt; threshold then emit relevant {t, d}</formula><p>Algorithm 2 outlines the pseudo code to LSH- based tracking. Whenever a topic arrives, it is hashed, placing it into a bucket. To increase col- lision probability with similar documents, we re- peat the hashing process with different hash func- tions, storing a topic and hash-key tuple in a hash table. On each arrival of a new document the same hash functions are applied and the key is matched against the hash tables, yielding a set of candidate topics. The probabilistic bounds of the hashing scheme guarantee that topics in the candidate set are on average more likely to be similar to the doc- ument than others. We then match each topic in the candidate set against the document to lower the false positive rate of LSH <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Gionis, et al., 1999</ref>). The number of exact comparisons necessary is reduced to the number of topics in the candidate set.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">Cluster based Tracking</head><p>LSH based tracking segments the vector-space randomly without consideration of the data's dis- tribution. In contrast, we now propose a data de- pendent approach through document clustering.</p><p>The main motivation for data dependent space segmentation is increased effectiveness resulting from taking the topic distribution within the vec- tor space into account when forming the regions of proximity. We construct these regions by group- ing similar topics to form clusters represented by a centroid. When tracking a document, it is matched against the centroids instead of all topics, yield- ing a set of candidate topics. This allows reducing the number of comparisons necessary to only the number of centroids plus the number of topics cap- tured by the closest cluster.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Algorithm 3 Cluster based Tracking</head><p>INPUT: INITIAL-CLUSTER-SET {c C} TOPIC-STREAM {T } DOCUMENT-STREAM {D} threshold for spawning a new cluster {thrspawn} threshold for adapting an existing cluster {thr adapt } OUTPUT: relevant topic-document pairs {t, d}</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">while document d in T, D do if d T then cmin = argminc{distances(d, c C)} if distance(d,cmin) &gt; thrspawn then spawnNewCluster(d → C) else if distance(d,cmin) &lt; thr adapt then contribute,assign(cmin,d) else assign(cmin,d) else if d D then cmin = argminc{distances(d,c C)} candidateSet = {t cmin} for all topics t in candidateSet do if similarity(d,t) &gt; threshold then emit relevant {t, d}</formula><p>While the literature provides a vast diversity of clustering methods for textual documents, our requirements regarding tracking streams of top- ics naturally reduce the selection to lightweight single-pass algorithms. <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">Yang et al. (2012)</ref> pro- vided evidence that in extreme settings simple ap- proaches work well in terms of balancing effec- tiveness, efficiency and scalability. We identified ArteCM by <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Carullo et al. (2008)</ref>, originally in- tended to cluster documents for the web, as suit- able. Algorithm 3 outlines our approach for clus- ter based tracking. Given an initial set of 4 ran- dom centroids, we compare each arriving topic to all centroids. We associate the new topic with the cluster whenever it is close enough. Particularly close documents contribute to a cluster, allowing it to drift towards topic dense regions. If the docu- ment is distant to all existing clusters, we spawn a new cluster based on the document. Documents arriving from the document stream are exactly matched against all centroids to determine the k-closest clusters. Topics associated with those clusters are subsequently exhaustively compared with the document, yielding topic-document pairs considered to be relevant. Probing more than one cluster increases the probability of finding similar topics. This does not correlate with soft-clustering methods as multiple probing happens at querying time while topics are assigned under a hard clus- tering paradigm.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3">Algorithm Comparison</head><p>Both the LSH-and the cluster-based tracking al- gorithm provide two parameters that are conceptu- ally directly comparable to each other. The num- ber of bits per hash key and the threshold for spawning new clusters directly determine the size of the candidate set by either varying the bucket size or the cluster radius. The size of the candi- date set trades a gain in efficiency against a loss in effectiveness. Fewer topics in the candidate set heavily reduce the search space for the tracking process but increase the chance of missing a rele- vant topic. Bigger sets are more likely to cover rel- evant topics but require more computational effort during the exact comparison step. The proposed algorithms allow continuously adjusting the can- didate set size between two extremes of having all topics in a single set and having a separate set for each topic. The second parameter both algorithms have in common, is the number of probes to increase the probability of identifying similar topics. While LSH-based tracking offers the number of hash ta- bles, cluster-based tracking provides the number of clusters probed. We again encounter a trade-off between gains in efficiency at the cost of effective-ness. Each additionally probed cluster or looked up table increases the chance of finding relevant topics as well as the computational effort.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Tracking Streams in Constant Space</head><p>Operation in constant space is crucial when track- ing topic streams. We ensure this by placing an upper limit on the number of concurrently tracked topics. Whenever the limit is reached, an active topic is deleted and subsequently not considered any longer. The strategy for selecting deletion candidates is heavily application dependant. To handle topic streams, LSH-based tracking replaces the entries of an active topic in its hash-tables by the values of the new topic, whenever the maxi- mum number of topics is reached. Cluster-based tracking requires more adaptation because we al- low clusters to drift conceptually. Whenever the maximum number of topics is reached, the con- tribution of the deletion candidate to its cluster is reverted and it is removed, freeing space for a new topic.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Experiments</head><p>We evaluate the three algorithms in terms of effectiveness and efficiency. Starting out with tracking a small set of topics using the traditional approach, we evaluate various sim- ilarity metrics to ensure high effectiveness.</p><p>We then conduct scaling experiments on mas- sive streams in bounded and unbounded space.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Corpora</head><p>Traditional tracking datasets are unsuitable to approach tracking at scale as they consist of only a few thousand documents and several hundred topics <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Allan, 2002</ref> </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Relevance Judgements</head><p>The topics we picked range from natural disasters, political and financial events to news about celebrities, as seen in table 3. We adopted the search-guided-annotation process used by NIST ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Fiscus et al., 2002</ref>) and followed NIST's TDT annotation guidelines. According to the definition of TDT, a document is relevant to a topic if it speaks about it <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Allan, 2002</ref>). In total we identified 14,436 tweets as relevant to one of 30 topics.</p><p>total number of topics 4.4 mio annotated topics 30 total number of documents 52 mio documents relevant to one of the 30 annotated topics 14.5k </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Baseline</head><p>We use an exact tracking system as a baseline.</p><p>To speed up runtime, we implement an inverted index in conjunction with term-at-a-time query execution. Additionally, we provide a trade off between effectiveness and efficiency by ran- domly down sampling the Twitter stream. Note that this closely resembles previous approaches to scale topic tracking ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Ghosh et al., 2013</ref>).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Evaluation Metrics</head><p>We evaluate effectiveness by recall and precision and combine them using F1 scores. Efficiency is evaluated using two different metrics. We provide a theoretical upper bound by computing the number of dot products required for tracking ( <ref type="bibr">Equations 1-4)</ref>.   <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">William and Kate arrive in Canada  1021  Floods in Seoul  Floods and landslides in North and South Korea  432  Flight 4896  Flight 4896 crashed  11  Bangladesh-India border  Bangladesh and India sign a border pact  4  Goran Hadzic</ref> War criminal Goran Hadzic got arrested 2 They therefore indicate performance without system-or implementation-dependent distortions. Equations 2 and 3 represent the cost to identify the candidate set for the LSH-and cluster-based al- gorithm plus the cost resulting from exhaustively comparing the candidate sets with the documents (Equation 4). Because we compute the dot products for a worst case scenario, we also provide the runtime in sec- onds. All run-times are averaged over 5 runs, mea- sured on the same idle machine. To ensure fair comparison, all algorithms are implemented in C using the same libraries, compiler, compiler opti- mizations and run as a single process using 4 GB of memory. Because the runtime of the traditional approach (∼171 days) exceeds our limits, we esti- mate it based on extrapolating 50 runs using up to 25,000 topics. Note that this extrapolation favours the efficiency of the baseline system as it ignores hardware dependent slowdowns when scaling up the number of topics.</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">DP traditional = n D * n T (1) DP LSH−based = (n D +n T ) * (k * L)+DP cs (2) DP cluster−based = (n D + n T ) * c + DP cs (3) DP cs = n D * n C<label>(4)</label></formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.1">Exact tracking</head><p>In our first experiment we track 30 annotated topics on 52 million tweets using the traditional approach. We compare various similarity mea- sures <ref type="table" target="#tab_5">(Table 4)</ref> and use the best-performing one in all following experiments. Our data set dif- fers from the TREC and TDT corpora, which used news-wire articles. <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Allan et al. (2000)</ref> report that the cosine similarity constantly performed as the best distance function for TDT. The use of Wikipedia and Twitter causes a different set of similarity measures to perform best. This results from the imbalance in average document length between Wikipedia articles (590 terms) and tweets (11 terms). The term weights in short tweets (many only containing a single term) are inflated by the cosine's length normalization. Those short tweets are however not uniquely linkable to target topics and consequently regarded as non-relevant by annotators, which explains the drop in per- formance. The similarity function chosen for all subsequent experiments is a BM25 weighted dot product, which we found to perform best.  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.2">Tracking at scale, using Wikipedia and Twitter</head><p>Previously, we conducted small scale experi- ments, now we are looking to scale them up, by tracking 4.4 million Wikipedia articles on 52 million tweets without limiting the number of topics tracked. The resulting trade-off between effectiveness and efficiency is shown in <ref type="figure">Figure  1</ref> and 2. The right-most point corresponds to exhaustive comparison of every document against every topic -this results in highest possible ef- fectiveness (F1 score) and highest computational cost. All runs use optimal tracking thresholds de- termined by sweeping them while optimizing on F1 score as an objective function. We also show the performance resulting from the traditional approach when randomly down-sampling the doc- ument (Twitter) stream, which resembles previous attempts to scale tracking ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Ghosh et al., 2013)</ref>. Every point on the LSH-based tracking curve in <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref> and 2 represents a different number of bits per hash key (varying between 4 and 20) and tables (ranging from 6 to 200). The points on the cluster-based tracking curves result from varying the number of clusters (ranging from 1 to 100,000) and probes. The resulting bucket sizes span from a few dozen to over a million topics. As expected, the graphs in <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref> closely resembles those in <ref type="figure">Figure 2</ref>. The two figures also show that the performance of all three algorithms is continuously adjustable. Unsurprisingly, LSH- and cluster-based tracking clearly outperform random document sampling for the traditional ap- proach, based on their more effective search space reduction strategies. More surprisingly, we also observe that cluster-based tracking outperforms tracking based on LSH in terms of efficiency for F1 scores between 10% and 20%. To understand why tracking based on clustering is faster than randomized tracking, we further investigate their abilities in cutting down the search space. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 3</ref> presents the candidate set size nec- essary to find a certain ratio of relevant topics. The graph also illustrates the impact of probing multiple clusters. When focusing on a recall up to 60%, LSH-based tracking requires a signif- icantly larger candidate set size in comparison with tracking through clustering. For example, LSH-based tracking needs to examine 30% of all topics to reach a recall of 50%, while the cluster based approach only needs to look at 9%. This effect diminishes for higher recall values. Fur- thermore, we observe an impressive performance gain in recall from 20% to 60%, resulting from additionally probing the k-closest clusters instead of just the closest one. While data dependent segmentation is expected to outperform LSH in terms of effectiveness, we were surprised by the magnitude of its impact on efficiency.</p><p>The lack in effectiveness of LSH has a direct negative implication on its efficiency for tracking. In order to make up for its suboptimal space seg- mentation, it requires substantially bigger candi- date sets to reach the same level of recall as the cluster-based approach. The size of the candi- date set is critical because we assume a subsequent exact comparison phase to lower the false posi- tive rate. The overhead of both algorithms is out- weighed by the cost of exact comparison for the candidate set. <ref type="table" target="#tab_6">Table 5</ref>, which compares the performance of the three algorithms, reveals a drastic reduction in run- time of up to 80%, at the cost of only a minor decrease in F1 score. The differences of 6% and 10% percent in F1 score are statistically not sig- nificant according to a sign test (p&lt;=0.362 and p&lt;=0.2). Consequently, both algorithms achieve substantial runtime reduction, while maintaining a level of effectiveness that is statistically indistin- guishable from the traditional (exact) approach.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.3">Tracking Wikipedia on Twitter in constant space</head><p>Tracking a stream of topics in bounded space is highly application specific due to the deletion pro- cedure. We know from previous studies <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">(Nichols et al., 2012</ref>) that a topic's popularity within Twit- ter fades away over time. We are interested in keeping currently active topics and delete those that attract the least number of recent documents. This set-up has the interesting aspect that the doc-Algorithm F1 score Dot Products Runtime (sec) traditional approach 0.217 2.3 * 10 14 1.5 * 10 7 LSH-based tracking 0.196 (-10%) 1.4 * 10 14 (-39%) 8.0 * 10 6 (-46%) cluster-based tracking 0.204 (-6%) 3.1 * 10 13 (-86%) 2.5 * 10 6 (-83%) cluster-based tracking unbounded 0.204 3.1 * 10 13 2.5 * 10 6 bounded 0.189 (-7%) 1.8 * 10 11 (-99%) 3.3 * 10 4 (-98%) <ref type="table">Table 6</ref>: Effectiveness and efficiency for tracking in bounded and unbounded space ument stream dictates the lifespan of each topic in the topic stream. <ref type="table">Table 6</ref> contains the results of cluster-and LSH-based tracking and compares them to their bounded versions using the same set up. Note that the hit in performance is solely defined by the amount of memory provided and therefore continuously adjustable. For this particular experiment, we chose an upper bound of 25k concurrent topics. The table repre- sents a substantial drop in runtime, following the reduced search space, at a fairly low expense in effectiveness. Based on our observations, we hy- pothesise that significant topics are more likely to be discussed during random Twitter chatter than the average Wikipedia topic. It is interesting to notice that the runtime also indicates a lower over- head for LSH-based tracking in comparison with the cluster-based approach. This difference was hidden in the unbounded tracking experiments but carries now more weight.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7">Conclusion</head><p>We extended traditional topic tracking by demon- strating that it is possible to track an unbounded stream of topics in constant space and time. We also presented two approaches to tracking, based on LSH and clustering that efficiently scale to a high number of topics and documents while main- taining a level of effectiveness that is statistically indistinguishable from an exact tracking system. While they trade gains in efficiency against a loss in effectiveness, we showed that cluster based tracking does so more efficiently due to more ef- fective space segmentation, which allows a higher reduction of the search space. Contrary to com- mon believes this showed how nearest neighbour search in data streams based on clustering per- forms faster than LSH, for the same level of accu- racy. Furthermore, we showed that standard mea- sures of similarity (cosine) are sub-optimal when tracking Wikipedia against Twitter.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 1 :Figure 2 :</head><label>12</label><figDesc>Figure 1: Trade-off between efficiency and dot-products for LSH-and cluster-based tracking as well as a random downsampling approach for traditional tracking</figDesc><graphic url="image-1.png" coords="7,72.00,62.81,215.25,120.23" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Figure 3: Comparing the candidate set size with the Recall of LSH-with cluster-based tracking without the exact evaluation phase; The magnitude of the candidate set size represents the ratio between the number of candidate topics and the total number of topics;</figDesc><graphic url="image-3.png" coords="7,307.28,62.81,217.88,119.18" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" validated="false"><head>Table 1 : Data set statistics</head><label>1</label><figDesc></figDesc><table></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3" validated="false"><head>Table 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Definition of variables for equation 1-4 </table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4" validated="false"><head>Table 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Showing 6 example topics plus a short summary of relevant tweets, as well as the number of relevant tweets per topic 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_5" validated="false"><head>Table 4 :</head><label>4</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Comparing the effectiveness of similarity mea-
sures when matching 30 Wikipedia articles against 52 million 
tweets 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_6" validated="false"><head>Table 5 : Effectiveness and efficiency of LSH-and cluster-based tracking to the traditional approach</head><label>5</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Algorithm 
Space 
F1 score 
dot products 
runtime (sec) 

LSH-based tracking 
unbounded 0.196 
1.4  *  10 14 
8.0  *  10 6 
bounded 
0.173 (-12%) 5.1  *  10 11 (-99%) 4.1  *  10 4 (-99%) 

</table></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> http://stream.twitter.com 2 http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikipedia database</note>

			<note place="foot">Eichmann, D. and P. Sirivasan. 1999. &quot;Filters, Webs and Answers: The University of Iowa TREC-8 Results&quot; Eighth Conference on Text Retrieval, NIST, USA.</note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Detections, bounds, and timelines: Umass and tdt-3</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">James</forename><surname>Allan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Victor</forename><surname>Lavrenko</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Daniella</forename><surname>Malin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Russell</forename><surname>Swan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of Topic Detection and Tracking Workshop</title>
		<meeting>Topic Detection and Tracking Workshop</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="167" to="174" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">On-line new event detection and tracking</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">James</forename><surname>Allan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ron</forename><surname>Papka</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Victor</forename><surname>Lavrenko</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 21st annual international ACM SIGIR conference on Research and development in information retrieval (SIGIR &apos;98</title>
		<meeting>the 21st annual international ACM SIGIR conference on Research and development in information retrieval (SIGIR &apos;98<address><addrLine>New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Topic Detection and Tracking: Event-Based Information Organization</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">James</forename><surname>Allan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
			<publisher>Kluwer Academic Publishers</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Norwell, MA, USA</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Emerging topic detection on Twitter based on temporal and social terms evaluation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mario</forename><surname>Cataldi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Luigi</forename><forename type="middle">Di</forename><surname>Caro</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Claudio</forename><surname>Schifanella</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Tenth International Workshop on Multimedia Data Mining</title>
		<meeting>the Tenth International Workshop on Multimedia Data Mining</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="10" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Event Identification in Social Media</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Becker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Naaman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Gravano</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">12th International Workshop on the Web and Databases (WebDB&apos;09)</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Providence, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Clustering of short commercial documents for the web</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Moreno</forename><surname>Carullo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Elisabetta</forename><surname>Binaghi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ignazio</forename><surname>Gallo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nicola</forename><surname>Lamberti</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Paper presented at the meeting of the ICPR</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Similarity estimation techniques from rounding algorithms</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Moses</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Charikar</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the thirty-fourth annual ACM symposium on Theory of computing (STOC &apos;02)</title>
		<meeting>the thirty-fourth annual ACM symposium on Theory of computing (STOC &apos;02)<address><addrLine>New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Topic detection and tracking evaluation overview. Topic detection and tracking: event-based information organization</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Fiscus</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Doddington</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="17" to="31" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">On sampling the wisdom of crowds: random vs. expert sampling of the twitter stream</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Saptarshi</forename><surname>Ghosh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Muhammad</forename><forename type="middle">Bilal</forename><surname>Zafar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Parantapa</forename><surname>Bhattacharya</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Naveen</forename><surname>Sharma</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Niloy</forename><surname>Ganguly</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Krishna</forename><surname>Gummadi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 22nd ACM international conference on Conference on information &amp; knowledge management (CIKM-13)</title>
		<meeting>the 22nd ACM international conference on Conference on information &amp; knowledge management (CIKM-13)<address><addrLine>New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Aristides</forename><surname>Gionis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Piotr</forename><surname>Indyk</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rajeev</forename><surname>Motwani</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Similarity Search in High Dimensions via Hashing. InProceedings of the 25th International Conference on Very Large Data Bases (VLDB &apos;99)</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>San Francisco, CA, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Event Detection and Tracking in Social Streams</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sayyadi</forename><surname>Hassan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hurst</forename><surname>Matthew</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Maykov</forename><surname>Alexey</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the ICWSM</title>
		<meeting>the ICWSM<address><addrLine>CA, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Exploiting topic tracking in real-time tweet streams</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yihong</forename><surname>Hong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yue</forename><surname>Fei</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jianwu</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2013 international workshop on Mining unstructured big data using natural language processing</title>
		<meeting>the 2013 international workshop on Mining unstructured big data using natural language processing<address><addrLine>New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Approximate nearest neighbours: towards removing the curse of dimensionality</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Piotr</forename><surname>Indyk</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rajeev</forename><surname>Motwani</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the thirtieth annual ACM symposium on Theory of computing (STOC &apos;98)</title>
		<meeting>the thirtieth annual ACM symposium on Theory of computing (STOC &apos;98)<address><addrLine>New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Smoothing techniques for adaptive online language models: topic tracking in tweet streams</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jimmy</forename><surname>Lin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rion</forename><surname>Snow</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">William</forename><surname>Morgan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 17th ACM SIGKDD international conference on Knowledge discovery and data mining</title>
		<meeting>the 17th ACM SIGKDD international conference on Knowledge discovery and data mining<address><addrLine>New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="422" to="429" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Data streams: Algorithms and applications</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Muthukrishnan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
			<publisher>Now Publishers Inc</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Summarizing sporting events using twitter</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jeffrey</forename><surname>Nichols</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mahmud</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Clemens</forename><surname>Drews</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2012 ACM international conference on Intelligent User Interfaces (IUI &apos;12)</title>
		<meeting>the 2012 ACM international conference on Intelligent User Interfaces (IUI &apos;12)<address><addrLine>New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Streaming first story detection with application to Twitter</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sasa</forename><surname>Petrovic</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Miles</forename><surname>Osborne</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Victor</forename><surname>Lavrenko</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Human Language Technologies: The 2010 Annual Conference of the North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics (HLT &apos;10)</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Stroudsburg, PA, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Real-time event detection in massive streams</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sasa</forename><surname>Petrovic</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>School of Informatics, University of Edinburgh</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
<note type="report_type">Ph.D. thesis</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Randomized Algorithms and NLP: Using Locality Sensitive Hash Functions for High Speed Noun Clustering</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Deepak</forename><surname>Ravichandran</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Patrick</forename><surname>Pantel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Eduard</forename><surname>Hovy</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of ACL</title>
		<meeting>ACL</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Tracking multiple topics for finding interesting articles</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Raymond</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Pon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alfonso</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Cardenas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Buttler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Terence</forename><surname>Critchlow</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 13th ACM SIGKDD international conference on Knowledge discovery and data mining (KDD &apos;07)</title>
		<meeting>the 13th ACM SIGKDD international conference on Knowledge discovery and data mining (KDD &apos;07)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Overview of the trec-2012 microblog track</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Soboroff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Ounis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Lin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of TREC</title>
		<meeting>TREC</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A Wikipedia based semantic graph model for topic tracking in blogosphere</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jintao</forename><surname>Tang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ting</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Qin</forename><surname>Lu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ji</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wenjie</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Twenty-Second international joint conference on Artificial Intelligence-Volume Three (IJCAI&apos;11). TDT by NIST</title>
		<meeting>the Twenty-Second international joint conference on Artificial Intelligence-Volume Three (IJCAI&apos;11). TDT by NIST</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Event Detection in Twitter</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jianshu</forename><surname>Weng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Erwin</forename><surname>Leonardi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Francis</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceeding of ICWSM</title>
		<meeting>eeding of ICWSM</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>AAAI Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A framework for summarizing and analysing twitter feeds</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xintian</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Amol</forename><surname>Ghoting</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yiye</forename><surname>Ruan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Srinivasan</forename><surname>Parthasarathy</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 18th ACM SIGKDD international conference on Knowledge discovery and data mining</title>
		<meeting>the 18th ACM SIGKDD international conference on Knowledge discovery and data mining</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
