<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T12:08+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main"></title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract/>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Introduction</head><p>This volume contains the abstracts of the ACL-IJCNLP 2015 tutorials. This year we had a joint call- for-tutorials, coordinated with the NAACL and EMNLP co-chairs (6 co-chairs in total). We received 32 high-quality proposals, and it was a difficult task to make a final selection. The six co-chairs applied the following criteria for evaluation: relevance to ACL community, quality of instructor, quality of proposal, own estimate of attendance, newly emerging area, and being an introductions into related fields. The tutorials were then assigned to venues, trying to respect proposers' preferences and to balance topics across venues. In the end we accepted eight tutorials for ACL-IJCNLP. All eight of these are organized as half-day tutorials.</p><p>We are very grateful to Yang Liu and Thamar Solorio (NAACL tutorial chairs), Maggie Li and Khalil Sima'an (EMNLP tutorial chairs), Le Sun and Yang Liu (local chairs), Wanxiang Che and Guodong Zhou (publication chairs), Yuji Matsumoto (general chair), and of course Priscilla Rasmussen, for various kinds of help, advice and assistance offered during the process of putting the tutorial programme and materials together. Most importantly, we would like to thank the tutorial presenters for the time and effort in preparing and presenting the tutorials.</p><p>We hope you will enjoy the tutorials! ACL-IJCNLP 2015 Tutorial Chairs Eneko Agirre, University of the Basque Country Kevin Duh, Nara Institute of Science and Technology</p></div>		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl/>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
