<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T12:30+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Detecting Deceptive Groups Using Conversations and Network Analysis</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
				<availability status="unknown"><p>Copyright Association for Computational Linguistics</p>
				</availability>
				<date>July 26-31, 2015. 2015</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dian</forename><surname>Yu</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Computer Science Department</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yulia</forename><surname>Tyshchuk</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Industrial and Systems Engineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute 1</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Heng</forename><surname>Ji</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Computer Science Department</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">William</forename><surname>Wallace</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Industrial and Systems Engineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute 1</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Detecting Deceptive Groups Using Conversations and Network Analysis</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 53rd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics and the 7th International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing</title>
						<meeting>the 53rd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics and the 7th International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing <address><addrLine>Beijing, China</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="857" to="866"/>
							<date type="published">July 26-31, 2015. 2015</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Deception detection has been formulated as a supervised binary classification problem on single documents. However, in daily life, millions of fraud cases involve detailed conversations between deceivers and victims. Deceivers may dynamically adjust their deceptive statements according to the reactions of victims. In addition, people may form groups and collaborate to deceive others. In this paper, we seek to identify deceptive groups from their conversations. We propose a novel subgroup detection method that combines linguistic signals and signed network analysis for dynamic clustering. A social-elimination game called Killer Game is introduced as a case study 1. Experimental results demonstrate that our approach significantly out-performs human voting and state-of-the-art subgroup detection methods at dynamically differentiating the deceptive groups from truth-tellers.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Deception generally entails messages and infor- mation intentionally transmitted to create a false conclusion <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Buller et al., 1994)</ref>. Deception detec- tion is an important task for a wide range of ap- plications including law enforcement, intelligence gathering, and financial fraud. Most of the previ- ous work (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">(Ott et al., 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Feng et al., 2012)</ref>) focused on content analysis of a single document in isolation (e.g., a product review). The promot- ers of a product may post fake complimentary re- views, while their competitors may hire people to write fake negative reviews <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">(Ott et al., 2011</ref>).</p><p>However, when we want to detect deception from text or voice conversations, the deception be- havior may be affected by the following factors be- yond textual statements.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.">Dynamic. Recent research in social science</head><p>suggests that deception communication is dy- namic and involves interactions among peo- ple (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(Buller and Burgoon, 1996)</ref>). Addi- tionally, the research postulates that human's capacity to learn by observation enables him to acquire large, integrated units of behav- ior by example <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Bandura, 1971)</ref>. Therefore, a person's behavior concerning deception or truth-telling can change constantly, while he learns from others' statements during conver- sations. 2. Global. People may form groups for purpose of deception. Research in social psychology has shown that an individual's object-related behavior may be affected by the attitudes of other people due to group dynamics <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(Friedkin, 2010</ref>).</p><p>Recent studies typically have been conducted over "static" written or oral deceptive statements. There is no obligatory requirement for communi- cation between the author and the readers of these statements <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">(Yancheva and Rudzicz, 2013)</ref>. As a result, a victim of deception tends to trust the sto- ry mainly based on the statement he reads <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">(Ott et al., 2011</ref>). However, in daily life, millions of fraud cases involve detailed conversations between de- ceivers and victims. A deceiver may make a state- ment, which is partially true in order to deceive or mislead victims and adjust his deceptive strate- gies based on the reactions of victims ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">Zhou et al., 2004</ref>). Therefore, it is more challenging to identity a deceiver in an interactive process of deception.</p><p>Most deception detection research addressed in- dividual deceivers, but deceivers often act in pairs or larger groups ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">Vrij et al., 2010</ref>). The interac- tions within a deceptive group have been ignored. For example, a product review from a deceiver may be supported by his teammates so that his deceptive comments can be read by more poten- tial buyers. In this case, we can identify a decep- tive group based on their collaborations and com- mon characteristics, which is more promising than the typical methods of classifying individual state- ments as deceptive or trustworthy.</p><p>In order to identify deceptive groups by analyz- ing the evolution of a person's deception strategy during his interactions with victims and the inter- actions within the deceptive group from conver- sations, we use a social-elimination game called Killer Game which contains the ground-truth of subgroups.</p><p>The killer game has many variants that involve different roles and skills. We choose a classical version played by three roles/teams: detectives, c- itizens, and killers. The role of each player (game participant) is randomly assigned by a third-party game judge. Every killer/detective is given the i- dentities of his teammates. There are two alter- nating phases of the game: "night", when killer- s may covertly "murder" a player and detectives may learn one player's role; and "day", when sur- viving players are informed of who was killed last "night" and then asked to speculate about the roles of other surviving players. Before a "day" ends, every surviving player should vote for a suspect. The candidate with the most votes is eliminated. A player's identity is not exposed after his "death". The game continues until all killers have been e- liminated or all detectives have been killed. The killers are treated as deceivers, and citizens and detectives as truth-tellers.</p><p>In this paper, we present an unsupervised ap- proach for differentiating the deceptive groups from truth-tellers in a game. During each round, we use Natural Language Processing (NLP) tech- niques to identify a player's attitude toward other players (Section 2), which are used to construc- t a vector of attitudes for each surviving player (Section 3.1) and a signed social network repre- sentation (Section 3.2) for the discussions. Then we use a clustering algorithm to cluster the atti- tude vector space and obtain results for each round (Section 3.1). We also implement a greedy op- timization algorithm to partition the singed net- work based on the attitude clustering result (Sec- tion 3.2). Finally, we apply a pairwise-similarity approach that makes use of the predicted co- occurrence relations between players to combine all results from each round (Section 3.3). <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref> provides an overview of our system pipeline.</p><p>The major novel contributions of this paper are as follows.</p><p>• This is the first study to investigate conversa- tions and deceptive groups for computerized deception detection.</p><p>• The proposed clustering technique is shown to be successful in separating deceptive groups from truth-tellers.</p><p>• The method can be applied to dynamically detect subgroups in a network with discus- sants who tend to change their opinions.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Attitude Identification</head><p>In this section, we describe how we take a player's statement in a single round as input to extract his attitudes toward other players and represent them by an attitude 3-tuple (speaker, target, polarity) list. For this work, the polarity of attitudes ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Balahur et al., 2009</ref>) can be positive (1), negative (-1) or neutral (0). A game log from a single round will be used as our illustrative example, as shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 2</ref>. don't think 2 is a killer. I doubt 7's intention. Please vote for 7. 14(D): 10, 13, 16 are good. I don't think 7 must be a killer. 2 is obviously bad. I'm a citizen. System: 16, 11, 14, 7, 1, 3, 8, 12, 4 vote for 2 · · · 10, 13, 5, 2 vote for 7 · · · 9, 6 vote for 11 · · · 2 is out. statement in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 2</ref>, its attitude tuple list is: <ref type="bibr">[(16, 1</ref> Each player has a game ID, assigned by the online game system based on when s/he entered the game room. e.g., http://www.3j3f.com/how/ <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 2</ref>: Killer game sample log (1st round). 6(C): Why do you want to attack 2? I don't understand. 14 is suspicious. 7(K): It's hard to define 6's identity. 4 may be a citizen. I will vote for 2. 6 sounds very weird and I found 6 very suspicious. I will follow the detective 5 to vote for 2. 8(C): We should calm down. 7 seems to be a bad person. 9(C): 1 and 7 seem to be killers. There is no evidence to support 2 as a detective. 3 is a citizen. 4 is possibly a detective. 6 is also good. 10(D): I agree with you. 7 must be a killer. 2 and 7 should debate. 11(C): I don't know 2 but I think 2 is good. 3 is good. There should be one or two killers among 1, 4 and 7. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">Target and Attitude Word Identification</head><p>We start by identifying targets and attitude words from conversations. In the killer game, a target is tences that include at least one attitude word from a player's statement during each round.</p><p>We develop a rule-based approach for attitude- target pairing: if there is at least one ID in the sen- tence, we associate all attitude words in that sen- tence with it. Otherwise, if "I" is the only subject or there are no subjects at all, we associate atti- tude words with the ID of the speaker. We reverse the polarity of an attitude word if it appears in a negation context.</p><p>Previous methods pair a target and an atti- tude word if they satisfy at least one dependency rules (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">(Somasundaran and Wiebe, 2009)</ref>). We check the POS tag sequence between them. For each attitude-target pair, if there exists an attitude word, a belief-oriented verb such as "think", "be- lieve", "feel", or more than two verbs in the se- quence, we will discard this pair. The assumption is that POS tag sequences can be used to summa- rize dependency rules when statements are rela- tively short.</p><p>For those targets, the speaker didn't mention or there is no positive/negative attitude word used when they are mentioned, the attitude polarity s- core is set to 0. For instance, given Player 16's s- tatement in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 2</ref></p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>, its attitude tuple list is: [(16, 16, +1), (16, 11, -1), (16, 2, -1), (16, 1, 0), (16, 3, 0), . . . , (16, 15, 0)].</head><p>1 Each player has a game ID, assigned by the online game system based on when s/he entered the game room. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">Target and Attitude Word Identification</head><p>We start by identifying targets and attitude word- s from conversations. In the killer game, a target is represented by his unique ID 2 and game terms are regarded as attitude words. We collected 41 terms in total from the game's website 3 and re- lated discussion forum posts. ICTCLAS ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">Zhang et al., 2003</ref>) is used for word segmentation and part-of-speech (POS) tagging. There are two kind- s of game terms: positive and negative. Posi- tive terms include "citizen", "good person", "good person certified by the detectives" and "detective". Negative terms include "killer", "killer verified by the detectives" and "a killer who claimed him- self/herself to be a detective". We assign the po- larity score +1, -1 to positive and negative terms respectively.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">Attitude-Target Pairing</head><p>Then we associate each attitude word with it- s corresponding target. We remove interrogative and exclamatory sentences and only keep the sen- tences that include at least one attitude word from a player's statement during each round.</p><p>We develop a rule-based approach for attitude- target pairing: if there is at least one ID in the sen- tence, we associate all attitude words in that sen- tence with it. Otherwise, if "I" is the only subject or there are no subjects at all, we associate atti- tude words with the ID of the speaker. We reverse the polarity of an attitude word if it appears in a negation context.</p><p>Previous methods pair a target and an attitude word if they satisfy at least one dependency rule (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">(Somasundaran and Wiebe, 2009)</ref>). We check the POS tag sequence between them. For each attitude-target pair, if there exists an attitude word, a belief-oriented verb such as "think", "be- lieve", "feel", or more than two verbs in the se- quence, we will discard this pair. The assumption is that POS tag sequences can be used to summa- rize dependency rules when statements are rela- tively short.</p><p>For those targets, the speaker didn't mention or there is no positive/negative attitude word used when they are mentioned, the attitude polarity s- core is set to 0. For instance, given Player 16's s- tatement in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 2</ref>, its attitude tuple list is: <ref type="bibr">[(16, 16, +1</ref>), (16, 11, -1), (16, 2, -1), (16, 1, 0), (16, 3, 0), . . . , <ref type="bibr">(16,</ref><ref type="bibr">15,</ref><ref type="bibr">0)</ref>].</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Clustering</head><p>Since the statements in conversations are relatively short and concise, it is difficult to identify which one is deceptive, even using deep linguistic fea- tures such as the language style.</p><p>In this section, we introduce a method to con- struct an attitude profile for each player and a signed network based on the attitude tuple list in Section 2, and combine them to analyze a dynam- ic network with discussants telling lies and truths.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Clustering based on Attitude Profile</head><p>We use a vector containing numerical values to represent each player's attitude toward identified targets in each round. The values correspond to the polarity scores in a player's attitude tuple list. For example, the polarity score of player 16's atti- tude toward target 11 is −1 as shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 2</ref>.</p><p>We call this vector as the discussant attitude pro- file (DAP) following (Abu-Jbara et al., 2012a).</p><p>Suppose there are n players who participate in a single game. Since a player's identity is not ex- posed to the public after his death <ref type="bibr">4</ref> , people can still analyze the identity of a "dead" player. Therefore,</p><note type="other">the number of possibly mentioned targets in each round equals to n. Given all the statements from m surviving players in a single round, each play- er's DAP has n + 1 dimensions including his vote and thus we can have a m × (n + 1) attitude ma- trix A where A ij represents the attitude polarity of i toward j we got from Section 2. A i(n+1) repre- sents i's vote. In a certain round, given a set of m surviving players X = {x 1 , x 2 , · · · , x m } to be clustered and their respective DAPs, we can modify the Eu- clidean metric to compute the differences in atti- tudes and get an m × m distance matrix M :</note><formula xml:id="formula_0">Mij = n k=1 (A ik − A jk ) 2 + (2 − 2δA i(n+1) ,A j(n+1) ) 2 (1)</formula><p>The Kronecker delta function δ is:</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">δij = 1 i = j 0 i = j<label>(2)</label></formula><p>We use this function to compare the votes of t- wo players separately because a player's vote can be inconsistent with his previous statements. We assume that there is a larger distance between two players when they vote for different suspects.</p><p>A common assumption in previous research was that a member is more likely to show a positive attitude toward other members in the same group, and a negative attitude toward the opposing group- s (Abu-Jbara et al., 2012a). However, a deceiver may pretend to be innocent by supporting those truth-tellers and attacking his teammates, whose i- dentities have already been exposed. Therefore, it is not enough to judge the relationship between two players by simply measuring the distance be- tween their DAPs.</p><p>In addition to comparing DAPs between player- s i and j, we also consider the attitudes of other players toward i and j, as well as their attitudes toward each other. We modify M ij as follows and show it in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">Figure 3</ref>:</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">M ij = Mij + m k=1 (A ki − A kj ) 2 + (h(Aij) + h(Aji)) 2 (3)</formula><p>where the function h detects the negative atti- tudes. h(x) = 0 if x ≥ 0 and h(x) = −1 other- wise.</p><p>We perform hierarchical clustering on the con- densed distance matrix of M and use the complete linkage method to compute the distance between two clusters <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">(Voorhees, 1986)</ref>. We set the num- ber of clusters as 3 since there are three natural groups in the game. We focus on separating de- ceivers (killers) from truth-tellers (citizens and de- tectives).  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Signed Network Partition</head><p>When we computed the distance between two players in Section 3.1, we did not consider the net- work structure among all the players. For exam- ple, if A supports C, B supports D and C and D dislike each other, A and B may belong to differ- ent groups. Thus, we propose to capture the in- teractions in the social network to further improve the attitude-profile-based clustering result. We can easily convert the attitude matrix A into a signed network by adding a directed edge i → j between i and j if A ij = 0. We denote a directed graph corresponding to a signed network as G = (V, S, N, W ), where V is the set of nodes, S is the set of positive edges, N is the set of negative edges and W : (V × V ) → {−1, 1} is a function that maps every directed edge to a value, W (i, j) = A ij .</p><p>We use a greedy optimization algorithm <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Doreian and Mrvar, 1996</ref>) to find partitions. A criteri- on function for an optimal partitioning procedure is constructed such that positive links are dense within groups and negative links are dense be- tween groups. For any potential partition C, we seek to minimize the following error function:</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">E(C) = C∈C [(1 − γ) i∈C j / ∈C W (i, j)Si,j − γ i,j∈C W (i, j)Ni,j]<label>(4)</label></formula><p>where γ ∈ [0, 1] controls the balance of the penalty difference between putting a positive edge across and a negative edge within a group. We re- gard these two types of errors as equally important and set γ = 0.5 for our experiments.</p><p>Initially, we use the clustering result in Sec- tion 3.1 to partition nodes into three differen- t groups and an error function, E, is evaluated for that cluster. Every cluster has a set of neighbor clusters in the cluster space. A neighbor cluster is obtained by moving a node from one group to another, or exchanging two nodes in two different groups. E is evaluated for all the neighbor clusters of the current cluster and the one with the lowest value is set as the new cluster. The algorithm is repeated until it finds a minimal solution 5 . We set the upper limit for the number of subgroups to 3.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3">Cluster Ensembles</head><p>The relationships between players are dynamic throughout the game. For example, a killer tends to hide his identity and pretends to be friendly to others at later stages in order to survive. Thus, it is insufficient to rely on a single round's discus- sion to cluster players. In addition, for each single round, we also need to combine the clustering re- sults from the attitude profiles of the players and the signed network.</p><p>In a game with information gathered from up to r rounds, let P = {P 1 , P 2 , · · · , P r } be the set of r clusterings (partitionings) based on attitude profiles and P = {P 1 , P 2 , · · · , P r } be the set of r clusterings based on the signed network.</p><p>Using the co-occurrence relations between players, we can generate a n × n pairwise simi- larity matrix T based on the information of all r rounds:</p><formula xml:id="formula_4">T r ij = λ · vote ij + (1 − λ) · vote ij r ij<label>(5)</label></formula><p>5 Since our graphs are small, we search through all parti- tions. We repeated 1000 times in our experiment.</p><p>where vote ij , vote ij are the number of times that player i and j are assigned to the same cluster in P and P respectively. r ij denotes the number of rounds when both of them survived (r ij ≤ r). T r ij ∈ <ref type="bibr">[0,</ref><ref type="bibr">1]</ref>. We assign a higher weight to the re- sult of P 1 and set λ = 2/3 in our experiments.</p><p>Given the input in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 2</ref>, x 3 and x 4 are as- signed to the same cluster in P 1 (vote 34 = 1) and in P   <ref type="figure">Figure 4</ref>: Example of cluster ensemble for a single round.</p><p>We apply hierarchical clustering <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">(Voorhees, 1986)</ref> to the similarity matrix above to obtain the final global clustering results.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Experiments</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">Dataset Construction</head><p>We recorded 10 games from 3J3F 6 , one of the most popular Chinese online killer game web- sites <ref type="bibr">7</ref> . A screenshot of the game system inter- face is shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_9">Figure 5</ref>. There are 16 partic- ipating players per game: 4 detectives, 4 killer- s and 8 citizens. Each player occupies a posi- tion in 1 . All the surviving players can express their attitudes via a voice channel using 2 , while detectives and killers can also communicate with teammates in their respective private team chan- nels 3 via texts. The system provides real-time updates on the game progress, voting results, and so on using the public channel 4 . We manually transcribed speech and stored the text information in the public channel, which contains the voting and death information. The average game length   is about 76.3 minutes and there are on average 5 rounds and 411 sentences per game. Note that our method is language-independent and could easily be adapted to other languages. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">Evaluation Metrics</head><p>We use two metrics to evaluate the clustering ac- curacy: Purity and Entropy. Purity ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">Manning et al., 2008</ref>) is a metric in which each cluster is as- signed to the class with the majority vote in the cluster, and then the accuracy of this assignmen- t is measured by dividing the number of correctly assigned instances by the total number of instances N . More formally:</p><formula xml:id="formula_5">purity(Ω, C) = 1 N k max j |w k ∩ c j |<label>(6)</label></formula><p>where Ω = {w 1 , w 2 , · · · , w k } is the set of clusters and C = {c 1 , c 2 , · · · , c j } is the set of classes. w k is interpreted as the set of instances in w k and c j is the set of instances in c j . The purity increases as the quality of clustering improves. Entropy ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Steinbach et al., 2000</ref>) measures the uniformity of a cluster. The entropy for all clusters is defined by the weighted sum of the entropy of each cluster:</p><formula xml:id="formula_6">Entropy = − j n j n i P (i, j) × log 2 P (i, j)<label>(7)</label></formula><p>where P (i, j) is the probability of finding an el- ement from the category i in the cluster j, n j is the number of items in cluster j and n is the total number of items in the distribution. The entropy decreases as the quality of clustering improves.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3">Overall Performance</head><p>We compare our approach with two state-of-the- art subgroup detection methods and human perfor- mance as follows:</p><p>1. DAPC: In Section 3.1, we introduced our im- plementation of the discussant attitude profile clustering (DAPC) method proposed in (Abu- Jbara et al., 2012a). In the original DAPC method, for each opinion target, there are 3 dimensions in the feature vector, correspond- ing to (1) the number of positive expression- s, (2) negative expressions toward the tar- get from the online posts and (3) the num- ber of times the discussant mentioned the tar- get. For our experiment, we only keep one dimension representing the discussant's atti- tude (positive, negative, neutral) toward the target since a discussant attitude remains the same in his statement within a single round. 2. Network: We also implemented the signed network partition method for subgroup detec- tion proposed by ). To determine the number of subgroups t, we set an upper limit of t = 3 in order to minimize the optimization function.</p><p>3. Human Voting: We also compare our meth- ods with human voting results. There are two subgroups based on the voting results. The players with the highest votes each round be- long to one subgroup and the rest of the play- ers are in the other subgroup. <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">Table 1</ref> shows the overall performance of vari- ous methods on subgroup detection and <ref type="figure" target="#fig_10">Figure 6</ref> depicts the average performance. We can see that our method significantly outperforms two baseline methods and human voting. The human perfor- mance is not satisfying, which indicates it's very challenging even for a human to identify a deceiv- er whose deceptive statement is mixed with plenty of truthful opinions (Xu and Zhao, 2012). By extending the DAPC method (EDPAC), we can estimate the distance between two players more accurately by considering the attitudes of other players toward them and their attitudes to- ward each other. Given the log in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 2</ref> as in- put, players 5 (detective) and 7 (killer) are clus- tered into one group when DAPC is applied s- ince they don't have conflicting views on the i- dentities of other players. However, 5 voted for 7 and is supported by more players compared with 7, which indicates that they are less likely to be teammates. We can successfully separate them af- ter re-computing the distance between them.</p><p>Adding network information provided 5.7% further gain in Purity. In some cases, the perfor- mance remains the same when EDAPC clustering result is already optimal with the minimum value of the criterion function.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.4">Dynamic Subgroup Detection</head><p>As shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_11">Figure 7</ref>, the performance of our approach improves as the game proceeds. Play- ers seldom maintain their opinions throughout a game. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 2</ref> shows that most killers <ref type="bibr">(16,</ref><ref type="bibr">1,</ref><ref type="bibr">12)</ref> insisted that citizen 11 should be a killer except 7. As a response to the group pressure <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Asch, 1951)</ref>, 7 changed his opinion and stated that 11 could be a killer in the following round.</p><p>In reality, a discussant who participates in an online discussion tends to change his opinion- s about a target as he learns more information, which shows both the necessity and importance of the dynamic detection of subgroups. Our method can be applied to detect subgroups dynamically by grouping posts into multiple discussion "rounds" based on their timestamps. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Related Work</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.1">Opinion Analysis</head><p>Our work on mining a player's attitude toward oth- er players is related to opinion mining. Attitudes and opinions are related and can be regarded as the same in our task. Compared with the previ- ous work (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">(Qiu et al., 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Kim and Hovy, 2006</ref>)), the opinion words and targets in our task are relatively easier to recognize due to the sim- plicity of statements. Some recent work (e.g., (So- masundaran and Wiebe, 2009; Abu-Jbara et al., 2012a)) developed syntactic rules to pair an opin- ion word and a target if they satisfy at least one specific dependency rule. We use POS tag se- quences to efficiently help us filter out irrelevant pairs.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.2">Deception Detection</head><p>Most of the previous computational work for deception detection used supervised/semi- supervised classification methods ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">Li et al., 2013b)</ref>. Besides lexical and syntactical fea- tures <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">(Ott et al., 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Feng et al., 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b30">Yancheva and Rudzicz, 2013)</ref>, <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Feng and Hirst (2013)</ref> pro- posed using profile compatibility to distinguish fake and genuine reviews. <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">Xu and Zhao (2012)</ref> used deep linguistic features such as text genre to detect deceptive opinion spams. <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Banerjee et al. (2014)</ref> used extended linguistic signals such as keystroke patterns. <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Li et al. (2013a)</ref> used topic models to detect the difference between deceptive and truthful topic-word distribution. Researchers have began to realize the importance of analyzing computer-mediated communication in deception detection. <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">Zhou and Sung (2008)</ref> conducted an empirical study on deception cues using the killer game as a task scenario and obtained many interesting findings (e.g., deceivers send fewer messages than truth-tellers).</p><p>Our work is most related to the work of Chit- taranjan and Hung (2010) on detecting deceptive roles in the Werewolf Game which is another vari- ant of the killer game. They created a Werewolf data set by audio-visual recording 8 games played by 2 groups of people face-to-face and extract- ed audio features and interaction features for their experiments. However, we should note that non face-to-face deception detection emphasizes ver- bal and linguistic cues over less controllable non- verbal communication cues <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">(Walther, 1996)</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.3">Subgroup Detection</head><p>In online discussions, people usually split into subgroups based on various topics. The member of a subgroup is more likely to show positive at- titude to the members of the same subgroup, and negative attitude to the members of opposing sub- groups ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Abu-Jbara et al., 2012a</ref>). Previous work also studied subgroup detection in social media sites. Abu-Jbara et al. (2012a) constructed a dis- cussant attitude profile (DAP) for each discussant and then used clustering techniques to cluster their attitudes. <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">2012b;</ref> pro- posed various methods to automatically construct a signed social network representation of discus- sions and then identify subgroups by partitioning their signed networks. <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Qiu et al. (2013)</ref> applied collaborative filtering through Probabilistic Matrix Factorization (PMF) to generalize and improve ex- tracted opinion matrices.</p><p>An underlying assumption of the previous work was that a participant will not tell lies nor hide his own stance. Moreover, their work did not take in- to account that a person's attitude or stance will change as he learns more by reading the com- ments from others and acquiring more background knowledge <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Bandura, 1971)</ref>. Our contribution is that we extend the DAP method and combine it with the signed network partition in order to clus- ter the hidden group members. We also develop a novel cluster ensemble approach in order to ana- lyze the dynamic network.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Conclusions and Future Work</head><p>Using the killer game as a case study, we present an effective clustering method to detect subgroups from dynamic conversations with lies and truth- s. This is the first work to utilize the dynam- ics of group conversations for deception detec- tion. Experiments demonstrated that truth-tellers and deceptive groups are separable and the pro- posed method significantly outperforms baseline approaches and human voting.</p><p>Our work builds a pathway to future work in deception detection in content-rich dynamic envi- ronments such as electronic commerce and repeat- ed interrogation which will require sophisticated content and network analysis. In real-life suspects may be interrogated about particular events on nu- merous occasions. Our method can potentially be modified to find criminals who act in groups based on their statements. Other applications of this re- search include law enforcement, financial fraud, fraudulent ad campaigns and social engineering.</p><p>This study focuses on analyzing the verbal con- tent in conversations. It will be interesting to study non-verbal features such as blink rate, gaze aver- sion and pauses ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Granhag and Strömwall, 2002</ref>) when people play this game face-to-face and com- bine the non-verbal and verbal features for decep- tion detection. In addition, it is worth exploring the impact of cross-cultural analysis in detecting deception. When attempting to detect deceit in people of other ethnic origin than themselves, peo- ple perform even worse in terms of lie detection accuracy than when judging people of their own ethnic origin <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">(Vrij, 2000</ref>). For the future work, we aim to use automatic prediction of deceivers to help truth-tellers win games more easily.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>864</head></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: Deceptive group detection for a single round.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>2</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>System: 15 was killed last night. 15, please leave your last words. 15(C): I'm a citizen. Over. 16(K): I'm a good person. 11 and 2 are suspicious. 1(K): I'm a good person. It has been a long time since I played as a killer. I'm a citizen. 11 is suspicious and I don't want to comment on 16's statement. 2(C): I'm a detective. 6 was proved as a killer last night. Over. 3(C): I don't know 2's identity. It's hard to judge 16's statement. 1 seems to be a good person. I'm a citizen. 4(C): Citizen. I cannot find a killer. I trust 2 since 2 sounds a good person. 16 is suspicious. I regard 16 as a killer. I'm 2's teammate. 5(D): I'm a detective. I verify 2's identity and 2 is a killer. 13 is good.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>12(K): 11 sounds like a killer. 2 is a killer. I'm a citizen. Vote for 2. 13(D): 15 is a citizen. 16 is logically good. I think 1, 8, 9, 10 are OK. I don't think 2 is a killer. I doubt 7's intention. Please vote for 7. 14(D): 10, 13, 16 are good. I don't think 7 must be a killer. 2 is obviously bad. I'm a citizen. System: 16, 11, 14, 7, 1, 3, 8, 12, 4 vote for 2 · · · 10, 13, 5, 2 vote for 7 · · · 9, 6 vote for 11 · · · 2 is out.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head>Figure 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2: Killer game sample log (the 1st round).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_6"><head>Figure 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Figure 3: Computation of the distance between player i and j based on the attitude matrix.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_7"><head>1</head><label></label><figDesc>(vote 34 = 1) respectively as shown in Fig- ure 4. x 3 and x 4 co-occurred in the first round (r 34 = 1). T 1 34 = (2/3 × 1 + 1/3 × 1)/1 = 1.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_8"><head>Game</head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_9"><head>Figure 5 :</head><label>5</label><figDesc>Figure 5: Screenshot of the online killer game interface.</figDesc><graphic url="image-1178.png" coords="6,75.66,313.07,210.98,125.72" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_10"><head>Figure 6 :</head><label>6</label><figDesc>Figure 6: An overview of the average performance of all the methods.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_11"><head>Figure 7 :</head><label>7</label><figDesc>Figure 7: Average performance based on different rounds.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" validated="false"><head>Table 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Results on subgroup detection. D refers to DAPC, N refers to Network, H refers to Human Voting, and eD 

refers to extended DAPC. 

</table></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> The data set is publicly available for research purposes at: http://nlp.cs.rpi.edu/data/killer.zip</note>

			<note place="foot" n="2"> Each player has a game ID, assigned by the online game system based on when he entered the game room. 3 e.g., http://www.3j3f.com/how/</note>

			<note place="foot" n="4"> Each round, the player killed by killers and the player with the most votes are out.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="6"> http://www.3j3f.com 7 All data sets and resources will be made available for research purposes upon the acceptance of the paper.</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgement</head><p>This work was supported by the U.S. DARPA DEFT Program No. FA8750-13-2-0041, ARL NS-CTA No. W911NF-09-2-0053, NSF Award-s IIS-0953149 and IIS-1523198, AFRL DREAM project, gift awards from IBM, Google, Disney and Bosch. The views and conclusions contained in this document are those of the authors and should not be interpreted as representing the of-ficial policies, either expressed or implied, of the U.S. Government. The U.S. Government is autho-rized to reproduce and distribute reprints for Gov-ernment purposes notwithstanding any copyright notation here on.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Subgroup detection in ideological discussions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Abu-Jbara</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Diab</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Dasigi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Radev</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Attitudeminer: mining attitude from online discussions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Abu-Jbara</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Hassan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Radev</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics-Human Language Technologies (NAACL HLT</title>
		<meeting>North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics-Human Language Technologies (NAACL HLT</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Identifying opinion subgroups in arabic online discussions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Abu-Jbara</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>King</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Diab</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Radev</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>Association for Computational Linguistics</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Effects of group pressure upon the modification and distortion of judgments. Groups, leadership, and men</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Asch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1951" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Opinion mining on newspaper quotations</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Balahur</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Steinberger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Goot</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Pouliquen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Kabadjov</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">IEEE/WIC/ACM International Joint Conferences on Web Intelligence and Intelligent Agent Technologies</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Social Learning Theory. General Learning Corporation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Bandura</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1971" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Keystroke patterns as prosody in digital writings: A case study with deceptive reviews and essays</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Banerjee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Feng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Kang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Choi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. Empirical Methods on Natural Language Processing</title>
		<meeting>Empirical Methods on Natural Language essing</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>EMNLP</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Interpersonal deception theory</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Buller</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Burgoon</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Communication theory</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Deception: Strategic and nonstrategic communication</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>David B Buller</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Judee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Burgoon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Daly</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Wiemann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1994" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Strategic interpersonal communication</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Are you awerewolf? detecting deceptive roles and outcomes in a conversational role-playing game</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Chittaranjan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Hung</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">IEEE International Conference on Acoustics Speech and Signal Processing</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">A partitioning approach to structural balance</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Doreian</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Mrvar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Social networks</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Detecting deceptive opinions with profile compatibility</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Feng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Hirst</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing</title>
		<meeting>International Joint Conference on Natural Language essing</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>IJCNLP 2013</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Syntactic stylometry for deception detection</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Feng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Banerjee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Choi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL</title>
		<meeting>Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The attitude-behavior linkage in behavioral cascades</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Friedkin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Social Psychology Quarterly</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Repeated interrogations: verbal and non-verbal cues to deception</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Granhag</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Strömwall</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Applied Cognitive Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Detecting subgroups in online discussions by modeling positive and negative relations among participants</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Hassan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Abu-Jbara</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Radev</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing and Computational Natural Language Learning</title>
		<meeting>Empirical Methods in Natural Language essing and Computational Natural Language Learning</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>EMNLP-CoNLL</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Extracting opinions, opinion holders, and topics expressed in online news media text</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Kim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Hovy</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. ACL-COLING 2006 Workshop on Sentiment and Subjectivity in Text</title>
		<meeting>ACL-COLING 2006 Workshop on Sentiment and Subjectivity in Text</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Topicspam: a topic-model based approach for spam detection</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Cardie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>Association for Computational Linguistics</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Identifying manipulated offerings on review portals</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Ott</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Cardie</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. Empirical Methods on Natural Language Processing</title>
		<meeting>Empirical Methods on Natural Language essing</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Introduction to information retrieval</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Manning</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Raghavan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Schütze</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
			<publisher>Cambridge university press Cambridge</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Finding deceptive opinion spam by any stretch of the imagination</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Ott</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Choi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Cardie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Hancock</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL</title>
		<meeting>Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Opinion word expansion and target extraction through double propagation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Qiu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Bu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Computational linguistics</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Mining user relations from online discussions using sentiment analysis and probabilistic matrix factorization</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Qiu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Jiang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics-Human Language Technologies (NAACL HLT</title>
		<meeting>North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics-Human Language Technologies (NAACL HLT</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Recognizing stances in online debates</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Somasundaran</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Wiebe</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. Joint Conference of the Annual Meeting of the ACL and the 4th International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing of the AFNLP</title>
		<meeting>Joint Conference of the Annual Meeting of the ACL and the 4th International Joint Conference on Natural Language essing of the AFNLP</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A comparison of document clustering techniques</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Steinbach</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Karypis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Kumar</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. KDD 2000 workshop on text mining</title>
		<meeting>KDD 2000 workshop on text mining</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Implementing agglomerative hierarchic clustering algorithms for use in document retrieval. Information Processing &amp; Management</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Voorhees</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1986" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Pitfalls and opportunities in nonverbal and verbal lie detection</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Vrij</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Granhag</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Porter</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Science in the Public Interest</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Detecting lies and deceit: The psychology of lying and implications for professional practice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Vrij</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
			<publisher>Wiley</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Computer-mediated communication impersonal, interpersonal, and hyperpersonal interaction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Walther</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Communication research</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Using deep linguistic features for finding deceptive opinion spam</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Q</forename><surname>Xu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Zhao</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. International Conference on Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>International Conference on Computational Linguistics</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Automatic detection of deception in child-produced speech using syntactic complexity features</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Yancheva</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Rudzicz</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>Association for Computational Linguistics</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Hhmmbased chinese lexical analyzer ictclas</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Yu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Xiong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Q</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. SIGHAN 2003 workshop on Chinese language processing</title>
		<meeting>SIGHAN 2003 workshop on Chinese language processing</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Cues to deception in online chinese groups</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Zhou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Sung</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. Hawaii International Conference on System Sciences</title>
		<meeting>Hawaii International Conference on System Sciences</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Automating linguistics-based cues for detecting deception in text-based asynchronous computermediated communications. Group decision and negotiation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Zhou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Burgoon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Nunamaker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Twitchell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
