<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T11:06+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Bring you to the past: Automatic Generation of Topically Relevant Event Chronicles</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
				<availability status="unknown"><p>Copyright Association for Computational Linguistics</p>
				</availability>
				<date>July 26-31, 2015. 2015</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tao</forename><surname>Ge</surname></persName>
							<email>getao@pku.edu.cn, wenzhepei@pku.edu.cn, jih@rpi.edu,</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Ministry of Education</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">School of EECS</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">Key Laboratory of Computational Linguistics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Peking University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>100871</postCode>
									<settlement>Beijing</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Collaborative Innovation Center for Language Ability</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>221009</postCode>
									<settlement>Xuzhou, Jiangsu</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wenzhe</forename><surname>Pei</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Ministry of Education</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">School of EECS</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">Key Laboratory of Computational Linguistics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Peking University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>100871</postCode>
									<settlement>Beijing</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Heng</forename><surname>Ji</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="department">Computer Science Department</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>12180</postCode>
									<settlement>Troy</settlement>
									<region>NY</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sujian</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
							<email>lisujian@pku.edu.cn, chbb@pku.edu.cn, szf@pku.edu.cn</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Ministry of Education</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">School of EECS</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">Key Laboratory of Computational Linguistics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Peking University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>100871</postCode>
									<settlement>Beijing</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Collaborative Innovation Center for Language Ability</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>221009</postCode>
									<settlement>Xuzhou, Jiangsu</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Baobao</forename><surname>Chang</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Ministry of Education</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">School of EECS</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">Key Laboratory of Computational Linguistics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Peking University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>100871</postCode>
									<settlement>Beijing</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Collaborative Innovation Center for Language Ability</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>221009</postCode>
									<settlement>Xuzhou, Jiangsu</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Zhifang</forename><surname>Sui</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Ministry of Education</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">School of EECS</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">Key Laboratory of Computational Linguistics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Peking University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>100871</postCode>
									<settlement>Beijing</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Collaborative Innovation Center for Language Ability</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>221009</postCode>
									<settlement>Xuzhou, Jiangsu</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Bring you to the past: Automatic Generation of Topically Relevant Event Chronicles</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 53rd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics and the 7th International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing</title>
						<meeting>the 53rd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics and the 7th International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing <address><addrLine>Beijing, China</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="575" to="585"/>
							<date type="published">July 26-31, 2015. 2015</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>An event chronicle provides people with an easy and fast access to learn the past. In this paper, we propose the first novel approach to automatically generate a topically relevant event chronicle during a certain period given a reference chronicle during another period. Our approach consists of two core components-a time-aware hierarchical Bayesian model for event detection, and a learning-to-rank model to select the salient events to construct the final chronicle. Experimental results demonstrate our approach is promising to tackle this new problem.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Human civilization has developed for thousands of years. During the long period, history witnessed the changes of societies and dynasties, the revo- lution of science and technology, as well as the emergency of celebrities, which are great wealth for later generations. Even nowadays, people usu- ally look back through history either for their work or interests. Among various ways to learn history, many people prefer reading an event chronicle summarizing important events in the past, which saves much time and efforts.</p><p>The left part of <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref> shows a disaster event chronicle from Infoplease 1 , by which people can easily learn important disaster events in 2009. Un- fortunately, almost all the available event chron- icles are created and edited manually, which re- quires editors to learn everything that happened in the past. Even if an editor tries her best to gener- ate an event chronicle, she still cannot guarantee that all the important events are included. More- over, when new events happen in the future, she <ref type="bibr">1</ref> http://www.infoplease.com/world/disasters/2009.html needs to update the chronicle in time, which is laborious. For example, the event chronicle of 2010 in Wikipedia 2 has been edited 8,488 times by 3,211 distinct editors since this page was cre- ated. In addition, event chronicles can vary ac- cording to topic preferences. Some event chroni- cles are mainly about disasters while others may focus more on sports. For people interested in sports, the event chronicle in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref> is unde- sirable. Due to the diversity of event chronicles, it is common that an event chronicle regarding a specific topic for some certain period is unavail- able. If editing an event chronicle can be done by computers, people can have an overview of any pe- riod according to their interests and do not have to wait for human editing, which will largely speed up knowledge acquisition and popularization.</p><p>Based on this motivation, we propose a new task of automatic event chronicle generation, whose goal is to generate a topically relevant event chron- icle for some period based on a reference chroni- cle of another period. For example, if an disaster event chronicle during 2009 is available, we can use it to generate a disaster chronicle during 2010 from a news collection, as shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref>.</p><p>To achieve this goal, we need to know what events happened during the target period, whether these events are topically relevant to the chron- icle, and whether they are important enough to be included, since an event chronicle has only a limited number of entries. To tackle these chal- lenges, we propose an approach consisting of two core components -an event detection component based on a novel time-aware hierarchical Bayesian model and a learning-to-rank component to select the salient events to construct the final chronicle. Our event detection model can not only learn topic preferences of the reference chronicle and mea- sure topical relevance of an event to the chronicle but also can effectively distinguish similar events by taking into account time information and event- specific details. Experimental results show our ap- proach significantly outperforms baseline methods and that is promising to tackle this new problem.</p><p>The major novel contributions of this paper are:</p><p>• We propose a new task automatic generation of a topically relevant event chronicle, which is meaningful and has never been studied to the best of our knowledge.</p><p>• We design a general approach to tackle this new problem, which is language- independent, domain-independent and scal- able to any arbitrary topics.</p><p>• We design a novel event detection model. It outperforms the state-of-the-art event detec- tion model for generating topically relevant event chronicles.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Terminology and Task Overview</head><p>Figure 2: An example of relevance-topic-event hi- erarchical structure for a disaster event chronicle.</p><p>As shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref>, an event (entry) in an event chronicle corresponds to a specific occur- rence in the real world, whose granularity depends on the chronicle. For a sports chronicle, an event entry may be a match in 2010 World Cup, while for a comprehensive chronicle, the World Cup is regarded as one event. In general, an event can be represented by a cluster of documents related to it. The topic of an event can be considered as the event class. For example, we can call the topic of MH17 crash as air crash (fine-grained) or disaster (coarse-grained). The relation between topic and event is shown through the example in <ref type="figure">Figure 2</ref>.</p><p>An event chronicle is a set of important events occurring in the past. Event chronicles vary ac- cording to topic preferences. For the disaster chronicle shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref>, earthquakes and air crashes are relevant topics while election is not. Hence, we can use a hierarchical structure to orga- nize documents in a corpus, as <ref type="figure">Figure 2</ref> shows.</p><p>Formally, we define an event chronicle E = {e 1 , e 2 , ..., e n } where e i is an event entry in E and it can be represented by a tuple e i = D e i , t e i , z e i . D e i denotes the set of documents about e i , t e i is e i 's time and z e i is e i 's topic. Spe- cially, we use Λ to denote the time period (inter- val) covered by E, and θ to denote the topic distri- bution of E, which reflects E's topic preferences.</p><p>As shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref>, the goal of our task is to generate an (target) event chronicle E T during Λ T based on a reference chronicle E R during Λ R . The topic distributions of E T and E R (i.e., θ T and θ R ) should be consistent.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Event Detection</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Challenges of Event Detection</head><p>Figure 3: Documents that are lexically similar but refer to different events. The underlined words are event-specific words.</p><p>For our task, the first step is to detect topically relevant events from a corpus. A good event de- tection model should be able to (1) measure the topical relevance of a detected event to the reference chronicle.</p><p>(2) consider document time information.</p><p>(3) look into a document's event-specific details.</p><p>The first requirement is to identify topically rele- vant events since we want to generate a topically relevant chronicle. The second and third require- ments are for effectively distinguishing events, es- pecially similar events like the example in <ref type="figure">Figure  3</ref>. To distinguish the similar events, we must con- sider document time information (for distinguish- ing events in d 1 and d 2 ) and look into the docu- ment's event-specific details (the underlined words in <ref type="figure">Figure 3</ref>) (for distinguishing events in d 1 and d 3 ).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">TaHBM: A Time-aware Hierarchical Bayesian Model</head><p>To tackle all the above challenges mentioned in Section 3.1, which cannot be tackled by conven- tional detection methods (e.g., agglomerative clus- tering), we propose a Time-aware Hierarchical Bayesian Model (TaHBM) for detecting events. The plate diagram and generative story of TaHBM are depicted in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 4</ref> and <ref type="figure">Figure 5</ref> respectively. For a corpus with M documents, TaHBM assumes each document has three labels - s, z, and e. s is a binary variable indicating a doc- ument's topical relevance to the reference event chronicle, whose distribution is a Bernoulli dis- tribution π s drawn from a Beta distribution with</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Model Overview</head><formula xml:id="formula_0">Draw π s ∼ Beta(γ s ) For each s ∈ {0, 1}: draw θ (s) ∼ Dir(α) For each z = 1, 2, 3, ..., K: draw φ (z) ∼ Dir(ε), ψ (z) z ∼ Dir(β z ) For each e = 1, 2, 3, ..., E: draw ψ (e) e ∼ Dir(β e ) For each document m = 1, 2, 3, ..., M : Draw s ∼ Bernoulli(π s ) Draw z ∼ M ulti(θ (s) ) Draw e ∼ M ulti(φ (z) ) Draw t ∼ Gaussian(µ e , σ e ), t ← t Draw π x ∼ Beta(γ x )</formula><p>For each word w in document m:</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">Draw x ∼ Bernoulli(π x ) If x = 0: draw w ∼ ψ (z) z Else: draw w ∼ ψ (e) e</formula><p>Figure 5: The generative story of TaHBM symmetric hyperparameter γ s . s=1 indicates the document is topically relevant to the chronicle while s=0 means not. z is a document's topic label drawn from a K-dimensional multinomial distri- bution θ, and e is a document's event label drawn from an E-dimensional multinomial distribution φ. θ and φ are drawn from Dirichlet distributions with symmetric hyperparameter α and ε respec- tively. For an event e , it can be represented by a set of documents whose event label is e . In TaHBM, the relations among s, z and e are similar to the hierarchical structure in <ref type="figure">Figure 2</ref>. Based on the dependencies among s, z and e, we can compute the topical relevance of an event to the reference chronicle by Eq (1) where P (e|z), P (e), P (s) and P (z|s) can be estimated using Bayesian inference (some details of estimation of P (s) and P (s|z) will be discussed in Section 3.3) and thus we solve the first challenge in Section 3.1 (i.e., topical relevance measure problem).</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">P (s|e) = P (s) × P (z|s) × P (e|z) P (e)<label>(1)</label></formula><p>Now, we introduce how to tackle the second challenge -how to take into account a document's time information for distinguishing events. In TaHBM, we introduce t, document timestamps. We assume t = t where t is drawn from a Gaussian distribution with mean µ and variance σ 2 . Each event e corresponds to a specific Gaus- sian distribution which serves as a temporal con-straint for e. A Gaussian distribution has only one peak around where the probability is concentrated. Its value trends to zero if a point lies far away from the mean. For this reason, a Gaussian dis- tribution is suitable to describe an event's tempo- ral distribution whose probability usually concen- trates around the event's burst time and it will be close to zero if time lies far from the burst time. <ref type="figure">Figure 6</ref> shows the temporal distribution of the July 2009 Urumqi riots 3 . The probability of this event concentrates around the 7th day. If we use a Gaussian distribution (the dashed curve in <ref type="figure">Figure  6</ref>) to constrain this event's time scope, the doc- uments whose timestamps are beyond this scope are unlikely to be grouped into this event's cluster.</p><p>Now that the problems of topical relevance measure and temporal constraints have been solved, we discuss how to identify event-specific details of a document for distinguishing events. By analyzing the documents shown in <ref type="figure">Figure 3</ref>, we find that general words (e.g., earthquake, kill, injury, devastate) indicate the document's topic while words about event-specific details (e.g.,</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Napa, California, 3.4-magnitude) are helpful to determine what events the document talks about. Assuming a person is asked to analyze what event a document discusses, it would be a natural way</head><p>to first determine topic of the document based its general words, and then determine what event it talks about given its topic, timestamp and event- specific details, which is exactly the way our TaHBM works.</p><p>For simplicity, we call the general words as topic words and call the words describing event- specific information as event words. Inspired by the idea of <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Chemudugunta et al. (2007)</ref>, given the different roles these two kinds of words play, we assume words in a document are generated by two distributions: topic words are generated by a topic word distribution ψ z while event words are gen- erated by an event word distribution ψ e . ψ z and ψ e are |V |-dimensional multinomial distributions drawn from Dirichlet distributions with symmetric hyperparameter β z and β e respectively, where |V | denotes the size of vocabulary V . A binary indica- tor x, which is generated by a Bernoulli distribu- tion π x drawn from a Beta distribution with sym- metric hyperparameter γ x , determines whether a word is generated by ψ z or ψ e . Specifically, if x = 0, a word is drawn from ψ z ; otherwise the 3 http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/July 2009 Urumqi riots <ref type="figure">Figure 6</ref>: The temporal distribution of documents about the Urumqi riots, which can be described by a Gaussian distribution (the dashed curve). The horizontal axis is time (day) and the vertical axis is the number of documents about this event.</p><p>word is drawn from ψ e . Since ψ z is shared by all events of one topic, it can be seen as a background word distribution which captures general aspects. In contrast, ψ e tends to describe the event-specific aspects. In this way, we can model a document's general and specific aspects and use the informa- tion to better distinguish similar events 4 .</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Model Inference</head><p>Like most Bayesian models, we use collapsed Gibbs sampling for model inference in TaHBM. For a document m, we present the conditional probability of its latent variables s, z and x for sampling:</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">P (sm| s¬m, z, γs, α) = cs + γs s (cs + γs) × cs,z m + α z (cs,z + α)<label>(2)</label></formula><p>P (zm| z¬m, e, s, wm, xm, α, ε, βz)</p><formula xml:id="formula_4">= cs m ,z + α z (cs m,z + α) × cz,e m + ε e (cz,e + ε) × Nm n=1 ( cz,w m,n + n−1 i=1 1(wm,i = wm,n) + βz w∈V (cz,w + βz) + n − 1 ) (1−xm,n) (3) P (xm,n|</formula><p>wm, x¬m,n, zm, em, γx)</p><formula xml:id="formula_5">= cm,x + γx Nm + 2γx × ( cz m,wm,n + βz w∈V (cz m,w + βz) ) (1−x) × ( ce m,wm,n + βe w∈V (ce m,w + βe) ) x (4)</formula><p>where V denotes the vocabulary, w m,n is the n th word in a document m, c s is the count of docu- ments with topic relevance label s, c s,z is the count of documents with topic relevance label s and topic label z, c z,w is the count of word w whose document's topic label is z, c m,x is the count of words with binary indicator label x in m and 1(·) is an indicator function. Specially, for variable e which is dependent on the Gaussian distribution, its conditional probabil- ity for sampling is computed as Eq <ref type="formula" target="#formula_7">(5)</ref>:</p><formula xml:id="formula_6">P (em| e¬m, z,</formula><p>wm, xm, tm, ε, βe, µe, σe)</p><formula xml:id="formula_7">= cz m ,e + ε e (cz m,e + ε) × tm+1 tm pG(tm; µe, σ e ) × Nm n=1 ( ce,w m,n + n−1 i=1 1(wm,i = wm,n) + βe w∈V (ce,w + βe) + n − 1 ) xm,n<label>(5)</label></formula><p>where p G (x; µ, σ) is a Gaussian probability mass function with parameter µ and σ.</p><p>The function p G (·) can be seen as the temporal distribution of an event, as discussed before. In this sense, the temporal distribution of the whole corpus can be considered as a mixture of Gaussian distributions of events. As a natural way to esti- mate parameters of mixture of Gaussians, we use EM algorithm <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Bilmes, 1998)</ref>. In fact, Eq (5) can be seen as the E-step. The M-step of EM updates µ and σ as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_8">µ e = d∈De t d |D e | , σ e = d∈De (t d − µ e ) 2 |D e |<label>(6)</label></formula><p>where t d is document d's timestamp and D e is the set of documents with event label e. Specially, for sampling e we use σ e defined as σ e = σ e + τ (τ is a small number for smoothing 5 ) because when σ is very small (e.g., σ = 0), an event's temporal scope will be strictly constrained. Using σ e can help the model overcome this "trap" for better parameter estimation.</p><p>Above all, the model inference and parameter estimation procedure can be summarized by algo- rithm 1.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3">Learn Topic Preferences of the Event Chronicle</head><p>A prerequisite to use Eq (1) to compute an event's topical relevance to an event chronicle is that we know P (s) and P (z|s) which reflects topic preferences of the event chronicle. Nonetheless, P (s) and P (z|s) vary according to different event chronicles. Hence, we cannot directly estimate 5 τ is set to 0.5 in our experiments. for each event e do 12:</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Algorithm 1 Model inference for TaHBM</head><p>update µ e , σ e according to <ref type="bibr">Eq (6)</ref> 13:</p><p>end for 14: end for them in an unsupervised manner; instead, we pro- vide TaHBM some "supervision". As we men- tioned in section 3.2, the variable s indicates a document's topical relevance to the event chron- icle. For some documents, s label can be easily derived with high accuracy so that we can exploit the information to learn the topic preferences.</p><p>To obtain the labeled data, we use the descrip- tion of each event entry in the reference chroni- cle E R during period Λ R as a query to retrieve relevant documents in the corpus using Lucene <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">(Jakarta, 2004</ref>) which is an information retrieval software library. We define R as the set of doc- uments in hits of any event entry in the reference chronicle returned by Lucene:</p><formula xml:id="formula_9">R = ∪ e∈E R Hit(e)</formula><p>where Hit(e) is the complete hit list of event e re- turned by Lucene. For document d with timestamp t d , if d / ∈ R and t d ∈ Λ R , then d is considered ir- relevant to the event chronicle and thus it would be labeled as a negative example.</p><p>To generate positive examples, we use a strict criterion since we cannot guarantee that all the documents in R are actually relevant. To pre- cisely generate positive examples, a document d is labeled as positive only if it satisfies the positive condition which is defined as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_10">∃ e∈E R 0 ≤ t d − t e ≤ 10 ∧ sim(d, e) ≥ 0.4</formula><p>where t e is time <ref type="bibr">6</ref> of event e, provided by the ref- erence chronicle. sim(d, e) is Lucene's score of d given query e. According to the positive con- dition, a positive document example must be lexi-cally similar to some event in the reference chron- icle and its timestamp is close to the event's time.</p><p>As a result, we can use the labeled data to learn topic preferences of the event chronicle. For the labeled documents, s is fixed during model infer- ence. In contrast, for documents that are not la- beled, s is sampled by <ref type="bibr">Eq (2)</ref>. In this manner, TaHBM can learn topic preferences (i.e., P (z|s)) without any manually labeled data and thus can measure the topical relevance between an event and the reference chronicle.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Event Ranking</head><p>Generating an event chronicle is beyond event de- tection because we cannot use all detected events to generate the chronicle with a limited number of entries. We propose to use learning-to-rank tech- niques to select the most salient events to generate the final chronicle since we believe the reference event chronicle can teach us the principles of se- lecting salient events. Specifically, we use SVM- Rank <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">(Joachims, 2006</ref>).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">Training and Test Set Generation</head><p>The event detection component returns many doc- ument clusters, each of which represents an event. As Section 3.2 shows, each event has a Gaussian distribution whose mean indicates its burst time in TaHBM. We use the events whose burst time is during the reference chronicle's period as training examples and treat those during the target chroni- cle's period as test examples. Formally, the train- ing set and test set are defined as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_11">T rain = {e|µ e ∈ Λ R }, T est = {e|µ e ∈ Λ T }</formula><p>In the training set, events containing at least one positive document (i.e. relevant to the event chron- icle) in Section 3.3 are labeled as high rank pri- ority while those without positive documents are labeled as low priority.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">Features</head><p>We use the following features to train the ranking model, all of which can be provided by TaHBM.</p><p>• P (s = 1|e): the probability that an event e is topically relevant to the reference chronicle.</p><p>• P (e|z): the probability reflects an event's im- pact given its topic.</p><p>• σ e : the parameter of an event e's Gaussian distribution. It determines the 'bandwidth' of the Gaussian distribution and thus can be considered as the time span of e.</p><p>• |D e |: the number of documents related to event e, reflecting the impact of e.</p><p>• |De| σe : For an event with a long time span (e.g., Premier League), the number of relevant doc- uments is large but its impact may not be pro- found. Hence, we use |De| σe to normalize |D e |, which may better reflect the impact of e.  <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Graff et al., 2003</ref>) and remove documents whose titles and first paragraphs do not include any burst words. We detect burst words us- ing Kleinberg algorithm <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">(Kleinberg, 2003)</ref>, which is a 2-state finite automaton model and widely used to detect bursts. In total, there are 140,557 documents in the corpus. Preprocessing: We remove stopwords and use Stanford CoreNLP ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">Manning et al., 2014</ref>) to do lemmatization. Parameter setting: For TaHBM, we empirically set α = 0.05, β z = 0.005, β e = 0.0001, γ s = 0.05, γ x = 0.5, ε = 0.01, the number of topics K = 50, and the number of events E = 5000. We run Gibbs sampler for 2000 iterations with burn-in period of 500 for inference. For event ranking, we set regularization parameter of SVMRank c = 0.1. Chronicle display: We use a heuristic way to generate the description of each event. Since the first paragraph of a news article is usually a good summary of the article and the earliest document in a cluster usually explicitly describes the event, for an event represented by a document cluster, we choose the first paragraph of the earliest doc- ument written in 2010 in the cluster to generate the event's description. The earliest document's timestamp is considered as the event's time.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Experiments</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.2">Evaluation Methods and Baselines</head><p>Since there is no existing evaluation metric for the new task, we design a method for evaluation.</p><p>Although there are manually edited event chronicles on the web, which may serve as ref- erences for evaluation, they are often incomplete. For example, the 2010 politics event chronicle on Wikipedia has only two event entries. Hence, we first pool all event entries of existing chronicles on the web and chronicles generated by approaches evaluated in this paper and then have 3 human assessors judge each event entry for generating a ground truth based on its topical relevance, impact and description according to the standard of the reference chronicles. An event entry will be in- cluded in the ground-truth only if it is selected as a candidate by at least two human judges. On aver- age, the existing event chronicles on the web cover 50.3% of event entries in the ground-truth.</p><p>Given the ground truth, we can use Precision@k to evaluate an event chronicle's quality.</p><formula xml:id="formula_12">P recision@k = |E G ∩ E topk |/k</formula><p>where E G and E topk are ground-truth chronicle and the chronicle with top k entries generated by an approach respectively. If there are multiple event entries corresponding to one event in the ground-truth, only one is counted.</p><p>For comparison, we choose several baseline ap- proaches. Note that event detection models except TaHBM do not provide features used in learning- to-rank model. For these detection models, we use a criterion that considers both relevance and im- portance to rank events:</p><formula xml:id="formula_13">rankscore basic (e) = d∈De max e ∈E R sim(d, e )</formula><p>where E R is the reference chronicle and sim(d, e ) is Lucene's score of document d given query e . We call this ranking criterion as basic criterion.</p><p>• Random: We randomly select k documents to generate the chronicle.</p><p>• NB+basic: Since TaHBM is essentially an extension of NB, we use Naive Bayes (NB) to detect events and basic ranking criterion to rank events.</p><p>• B-HAC+basic: We use hierarchical agglom- erative clustering (HAC) based on BurstVSM schema ( <ref type="bibr">Zhao et al., 2012)</ref> to detect events, which is the state-of-the-art event detection method for general domains.</p><p>• TaHBM+basic: we use this baseline to verify the effectiveness of learning-to-rank.</p><p>As TaHBM, the number of clusters in NB is set to 5000 for comparison. For B-HAC, we adopt the same setting with (Zhao et al., 2012).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.3">Experiment Results</head><p>Using the evaluation method introduced above, we can conduct a quantitative evaluation for event chronicle generation approaches <ref type="bibr">9</ref> . <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">Table 1</ref> shows the overall performance. Our approach outperforms the baselines for all chron- icles. TaHBM beats other detection models for chronicle generation owing to its ability of incor- porating the temporal information and identifica- tion of event-specific details of a document. More- over, learning-to-ranking is proven more effective to rank events than the basic ranking criterion.</p><p>Among these 5 chronicles, almost all ap- proaches perform best on disaster event chronicle while worst on sports event chronicle. We ana- lyzed the results and found that many event entries in the sports event chronicle are about the open- ing match, or the first-round match of a tourna- ment due to the display method described in Sec- tion 5.1. According to the reference sport event chronicle, however, only matches after quarterfi- nals in a tournament are qualified to be event en- tries. In other words, a sports chronicle should provide information about the results of semi-final and final, and the champion of the tournament in- stead of the first-round match's result, which ac- counts for the poor performance. In contrast, the earliest document about a disaster event always di- rectly describes the disaster event while the fol- lowing reports usually concern responses to the event such as humanitarian aids and condolence from the world leaders. The patterns of reporting war events are similar to those of disasters, thus the quality of war chronicle is also good. Pol- itics is somewhat complex because some politi- cal events (e.g., election) are arranged in advance while others (e.g., government shutdown) are un- expected. It is notable that for generating com- prehensive event chronicles, learning-to-rank does sports politics disaster war comprehensive P@50 P@100 P@50 P@100 P@50 P@100 P@50 P@100 P@50 P@100    We analyze the errors of the disaster, sports and comprehensive event chronicle since they are rep- resentative, as shown in <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">Table 2</ref>.</p><p>Topical irrelevance is a major error source for both disaster and sports event chronicles. This problem mainly arises from incorrect identifica- tion of topically relevant events during detection. Moreover, disaster and sports chronicles have their own more serious problems. Disaster event chron- icles suffer from the indirect description problem since there are many responses (e.g., humanitar- ian aids) to a disaster. These responses are top- ically relevant and contain many documents, and thus appear in the top list. One possible solution might be to increase the event granularity by ad- justing parameters of the detection model so that the documents describing a major event and those discussing in response to this event can be grouped into one cluster (i.e., one event). In contrast, the sports event chronicle's biggest problem is on mi- nor events, as mentioned before. Like the sports chronicle, the comprehensive event chronicle also has many minor event entries but its main prob- lem results from its strict criterion. Since com- prehensive chronicles can include events of any topic, only extremely important events can be in- cluded. For example, "Netherlands beat Uruguay to reach final in the World Cup 2010" may be a correct event entry in sports chronicles but it is not a good entry in comprehensive chronicles. Com- pared with comprehensive event chronicles, events in other chronicles tend to describe more details. For example, a sports chronicle may regard each match in the World Cup as an event while compre- hensive chronicles consider the World Cup as one event, which requires us to adapt event granularity for different chronicles.</p><p>Also, we evaluate the time of event entries in these five event chronicles because event's hap- pening time is not always equal to the timestamp of the document creation time <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">(UzZaman et al., 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Ge et al., 2013</ref>). We collect existing man- ually edited 2010 chronicles on the web and use their event time as gold standard. We define a metric to evaluate if the event entry's time in our chronicle is accurate:</p><formula xml:id="formula_14">diff = e∈E∩E * |(t e − t * e )|/|E ∩ E * |</formula><p>where E and E * are our chronicle and the manu- ally edited event chronicle respectively. t e is e's time labeled by our method and t * e is e's correct time. Note that for multiple entries referring the same event in event chronicles, the earliest entry's time is used as the event's time to compute diff.  <ref type="table">Table 3</ref>: Difference between an event's actual time and the time in our chronicles. Time unit is a day. <ref type="table">Table 3</ref> shows the performance of our approach in labeling event time. For disaster, sports and war, the accuracy is desirable since important events about these topics are usually reported in time. In contrast, the accuracy of political event time is the lowest. The reason is that some political events may be confidential and thus they are not reported as soon as they happen; on the other hand, some political events (e.g., a summit) are reported several days before the events happen. The com- prehensive event chronicle includes many political events, which results in a lower accuracy.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Related Work</head><p>To the best of our knowledge, there was no previ- ous end-to-end topically relevant event chronicle generation work but there are some related tasks.</p><p>Event detection, sometimes called topic detec- tion <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Allan, 2002)</ref>, is an important part of our ap- proach. <ref type="bibr">Yang et al. (1998)</ref> used clustering tech- niques for event detection on news. <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">He et al. (2007)</ref> and <ref type="bibr">Zhao et al. (2012)</ref> designed burst fea- ture representations for detecting bursty events. Compared with our TaHBM, these methods lack the ability of distinguishing similar events.</p><p>Similar to event detection, event extraction fo- cuses on finding events from documents. Most work regarding event extraction ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Grishman et al., 2005;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Ahn, 2006;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b18">Ji and Grishman, 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b26">Liao and Grishman, 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Hong et al., 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Chen and Ng, 2012;</ref>) was developed under Automatic Content Extraction (ACE) program. The task only defines 33 event types and events are in much finer grain than those in our task. Moreover, there was work ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">Verhagen et al., 2005;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Chambers and Jurafsky, 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Bethard, 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Chambers, 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Chambers et al., 2014</ref>) about temporal event extraction and tracking. Like ACE, the granularity of events in this task is too fine to be suitable for our task.</p><p>Also, timeline generation is related to our work. Most previous work focused on generating a time- line for a document ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Do et al., 2012</ref>), a centroid entity ( ) or one major event <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(Hu et al., 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b32">Yan et al., 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b27">Lin et al., 2012;</ref>. In addition, <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Li and Cardie (2014)</ref> gen- erated timelines for users in microblogs. The most related work to ours is <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">Swan and Allan (2000)</ref>. They used a timeline to show bursty events along the time, which can be seen as an early form of event chronicles. Different from their work, we generate a topically relevant event chronicle based on a reference event chronicle.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7">Conclusions and Future Work</head><p>In this paper, we propose a novel task -automatic generation of topically relevant event chronicles. It can serve as a new framework to combine the merits of Information Retrieval, Information Ex- traction and Summarization techniques, to rapidly extract and rank salient events. This framework is also able to rapidly and accurately capture a user's interest and needs based on the reference chronicle (instead of keywords as in Information Retrieval or event templates as in Guided Summarization) which can reflect diverse levels of granularity.</p><p>As a preliminary study of this new challenge, this paper focuses on event detection and rank- ing. There are still many challenges for gener- ating high-quality event chronicles. In the fu- ture, we plan to investigate automatically adapt- ing an event's granularity and learn the principle of summarizing the event according to the refer- ence event chronicle. Moreover, we plan to study the generation of entity-driven event chronicles, leveraging more fine-grained entity and event ex- traction approaches. <ref type="bibr">Yiming Yang, Tom Pierce, and Jaime Carbonell. 1998.</ref> A study of retrospective and on-line event detection. In SIGIR.</p><p>Wayne Xin Zhao, Rishan Chen, Kai Fan, Hongfei Yan, and Xiaoming Li. 2012. A novel burst-based text representation model for scalable event detection. In ACL.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: Example for automatic generation of a topically relevant event chronicle.</figDesc><graphic url="image-1.png" coords="2,72.00,62.81,456.38,128.00" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 4 :</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Figure 4: The plate diagram of TaHBM. The shaded nodes are observable nodes.</figDesc><graphic url="image-4.png" coords="3,81.92,478.55,198.43,127.56" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Topically irrelevant: the topic of an event entry is irrelevant to the event chronicle. Minor events: the event is not important enough to be included. For example, "20100828: Lebanon beat Canada 81-71 in the opening round of the basketball world championships" is a minor event in the sports chronicle because it is about an opening-round match and not important enough. Indirect description: the entry does not describe a major event directly. For instance, "20100114: Turkey expressed sorrow over the Haiti earth- quake" is an incorrect entry in the disaster chroni- cle though it mentions the Haiti earthquake. Redundant entries: multiple event entries de- scribe the same event.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" validated="false"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>5.1 Experiment Setting Data: We use various event chronicles during 2009 as references to generate their counterparts during 2010. Specifically, we collected disaster, sports, war, politics and comprehensive chroni- cles during 2009 from mapreport 7 , infoplease and Wikipedia 8 . To generate chronicles during 2010, we use 2009-2010 APW and Xinhua news in En- glish Gigaword (</figDesc><table></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3" validated="false"><head>Table 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Performance of event chronicle generation. 

Topically Irrelevant Trivial Events Indirect Description Redundant Entries 
disaster 
31.91% 
17.02% 
44.68% 
6.38% 
sports 
38.82% 
55.29% 
3.52% 
2.35% 
comp 
-
67.16% 
31.34% 
1.49% 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4" validated="false"><head>Table 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Proportion of errors in disaster, sports and comprehensive event chronicles. 

not show significant improvement. A possible rea-
son is that a comprehensive event chronicle does 
not care the topical relevance of a event. In other 
words, its ranking problem is simpler so that the 
learning-to-rank does not improve the basic rank-
ing criterion much. 
Moreover, we analyze the incorrect entries in 
the chronicles generated by our approaches. In 
general, there are four types of errors. 
</table></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="2"> http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2010</note>

			<note place="foot" n="4"> TaHBM is language-independent, which can identify event words without name tagging. But if name tagging results are available, we can also exploit them (e.g., we can fix x of a named entity specific to an event to 1 during inference.).</note>

			<note place="foot" n="6"> The time unit of t d and te is one day.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="7"> http://www.mapreport.com 8 http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2009</note>

			<note place="foot" n="9"> Due to the space limitation, we display chronicles generated by our approach in the supplementary notes.</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>We thank the anonymous reviewers for their thought-provoking comments. This work is sup-ported by National Key Basic Research Pro-gram of China 2014CB340504, NSFC project 61375074, China Scholarship Council <ref type="bibr">(CSC, No. 201406010174)</ref> and USA ARL NS-CTA No. W911NF-09-2-0053. The contact author of this paper is Zhifang Sui.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The stages of event extraction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Ahn</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Workshop on Annotating and Reasoning about Time and Events</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Topic detection and tracking: event-based information organization</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">James</forename><surname>Allan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
			<publisher>Springer Science &amp; Business Media</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Cleartk-timeml: A minimalist approach to tempeval 2013</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Steven</forename><surname>Bethard</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Second Joint Conference on Lexical and Computational Semantics</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">A gentle tutorial of the em algorithm and its application to parameter estimation for gaussian mixture and hidden markov models</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Jeff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Bilmes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">126</biblScope>
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>International Computer Science Institute</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Jointly combining implicit constraints improves temporal ordering</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nathanael</forename><surname>Chambers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dan</forename><surname>Jurafsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">EMNLP</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dense event ordering with a multi-pass architecture</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nathanael</forename><surname>Chambers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Taylor</forename><surname>Cassidy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bill</forename><surname>Mcdowell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Steven</forename><surname>Bethard</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">TACL</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="273" to="284" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Navytime: Event and time ordering from raw text</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nathanael</forename><surname>Chambers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<publisher>DTIC Document</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
<note type="report_type">Technical report</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Modeling general and specific aspects of documents with a probabilistic topic model</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chaitanya</forename><surname>Chemudugunta</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Padhraic Smyth Mark</forename><surname>Steyvers</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">NIPS</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Language specific issue and feature exploration in chinese event extraction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Zheng</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Heng</forename><surname>Ji</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">NAACL</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Joint modeling for chinese event extraction with rich linguistic features</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chen</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Vincent</forename><surname>Ng</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">COLING</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Joint inference for event timeline construction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wei</forename><surname>Quang Xuan Do</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dan</forename><surname>Lu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Roth</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">EMNLP</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Event-based time label propagation for automatic dating of news articles</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tao</forename><surname>Ge</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Baobao</forename><surname>Chang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sujian</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Zhifang</forename><surname>Sui</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">EMNLP</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Graff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Junbo</forename><surname>Kong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ke</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kazuaki</forename><surname>Maeda</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
			<publisher>English gigaword. Linguistic Data Consortium</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Philadelphia</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Nyu&apos;s english ace 2005 system description</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ralph</forename><surname>Grishman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Westbrook</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Adam</forename><surname>Meyers</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ACE 2005 Evaluation Workshop</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Using burstiness to improve clustering of topics in news streams</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Qi</forename><surname>He</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kuiyu</forename><surname>Chang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ee-Peng</forename><surname>Lim</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ICDM</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Using cross-entity inference to improve event extraction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yu</forename><surname>Hong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jianfeng</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bin</forename><surname>Ma</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jian-Min</forename><surname>Yao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Guodong</forename><surname>Zhou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Qiaoming</forename><surname>Zhu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ACL</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Generating breakpoint-based timeline overview for news topic retrospection</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Po</forename><surname>Hu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Minlie</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Peng</forename><surname>Xu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Weichang</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Adam</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Usadi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xiaoyan</forename><surname>Zhu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ICDM</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Apache lucene-a highperformance, full-featured text search engine library</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Apache</forename><surname>Jakarta</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Refining event extraction through cross-document inference</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Heng</forename><surname>Ji</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ralph</forename><surname>Grishman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ACL</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Cross-document event extraction and tracking: Task, evaluation, techniques and challenges</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Heng</forename><surname>Ji</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ralph</forename><surname>Grishman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Zheng</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Prashant</forename><surname>Gupta</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">RANLP</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Training linear svms in linear time</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Thorsten</forename><forename type="middle">Joachims</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">SIGKDD</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Bursty and hierarchical structure in streams</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jon</forename><surname>Kleinberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Data Mining and Knowledge Discovery</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="373" to="397" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Timeline generation: Tracking individuals on twitter</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jiwei</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Claire</forename><surname>Cardie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<publisher>WWW</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Evolutionary hierarchical dirichlet process for timeline summarization</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jiwei</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sujian</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ACL</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Employing compositional semantics and discourse consistency in chinese event extraction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Peifeng</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Guodong</forename><surname>Zhou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Qiaoming</forename><surname>Zhu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Libin</forename><surname>Hou</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">EMNLP</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Joint event extraction via structured prediction with global features</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Qi</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ji</forename><surname>Heng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Liang</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ACL</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Using document level cross-event inference to improve event extraction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Shasha</forename><surname>Liao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ralph</forename><surname>Grishman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ACL</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Generating event storylines from microblogs</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chen</forename><surname>Lin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chun</forename><surname>Lin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jingxuan</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dingding</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yang</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tao</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">CIKM</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The stanford corenlp natural language processing toolkit</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mihai</forename><surname>Christopher D Manning</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">John</forename><surname>Surdeanu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jenny</forename><surname>Bauer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Finkel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Steven</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Bethard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Mcclosky</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ACL System Demonstrations</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Automatic generation of overview timelines</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Russell</forename><surname>Swan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">James</forename><surname>Allan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">SIGIR</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Naushad</forename><surname>Uzzaman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hector</forename><surname>Llorens</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">James</forename><surname>Allen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Leon</forename><surname>Derczynski</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marc</forename><surname>Verhagen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">James</forename><surname>Pustejovsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:1206.5333</idno>
		<title level="m">Tempeval-3: Evaluating events, time expressions, and temporal relations</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
<note type="report_type">arXiv preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Automating temporal annotation with tarsqi</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marc</forename><surname>Verhagen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Inderjeet</forename><surname>Mani</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Roser</forename><surname>Sauri</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Robert</forename><surname>Knippen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jessica</forename><surname>Seok Bae Jang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Anna</forename><surname>Littman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">John</forename><surname>Rumshisky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">James</forename><surname>Phillips</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Pustejovsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ACL demo</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Evolutionary timeline summarization: a balanced optimization framework via iterative substitution</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rui</forename><surname>Yan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xiaojun</forename><surname>Wan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jahna</forename><surname>Otterbacher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Liang</forename><surname>Kong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xiaoming</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yan</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">SIGIR</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
