<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T12:32+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Joint Models of Disagreement and Stance in Online Debate</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
				<availability status="unknown"><p>Copyright Association for Computational Linguistics</p>
				</availability>
				<date>July 26-31, 2015. 2015</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dhanya</forename><surname>Sridhar</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">James</forename><surname>Foulds</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bert</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
							<email>bhuang@vt.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science</orgName>
								<address>
									<region>Virginia Tech</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lise</forename><surname>Getoor</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marilyn</forename><surname>Walker</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of California Santa Cruz</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Joint Models of Disagreement and Stance in Online Debate</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 53rd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics and the 7th International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing</title>
						<meeting>the 53rd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics and the 7th International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing <address><addrLine>Beijing, China</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="116" to="125"/>
							<date type="published">July 26-31, 2015. 2015</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Online debate forums present a valuable opportunity for the understanding and modeling of dialogue. To understand these debates, a key challenge is inferring the stances of the participants, all of which are interrelated and dependent. While collectively modeling users&apos; stances has been shown to be effective (Walker et al., 2012c; Hasan and Ng, 2013), there are many modeling decisions whose ramifications are not well understood. To investigate these choices and their effects, we introduce a scalable unified probabilis-tic modeling framework for stance classification models that 1) are collective, 2) reason about disagreement, and 3) can model stance at either the author level or at the post level. We comprehensively evaluate the possible modeling choices on eight topics across two online debate corpora , finding accuracy improvements of up to 11.5 percentage points over a local classifier. Our results highlight the importance of making the correct modeling choices for online dialogues, and having a unified probabilistic modeling framework that makes this possible.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Understanding stance and opinion in dialogues can provide critical insight into the theoretical un- derpinnings of discourse, argumentation, and sen- timent. Systems for predicting the stances of indi- viduals can potentially have positive social impact and are of practical interest to non-profits, govern- mental organizations, and companies. For exam-</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Dialogue Turns Stance</head><p>User 1: 18. That's the smoking age thats the shooting age. Why do you think they call it ATF? ANTI User 2: Shooting age? I know 7 year old shooters. 18 should be the gun purchasing age, but there is really no "shooting" age.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>ANTI</head><p>User 1: I know. I was just pointing out that the logic used to propose a 21 year "shooting age" was inconsistent.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>ANTI</head><p>User 2: I see. I dont think its really fair that you can join the army at 18 and use handguns and military weapons, but you cant purchase a handgun until 21. <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref>: Example of a debate dialogue turn be- tween two users on the gun control topic, from 4FORUMS.COM.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>ANTI</head><p>ple, stance predictions may be used to target pub- lic awareness and advocacy campaigns, direct po- litical fundraising and get-out-the vote efforts, and improve personalized recommendations. Online debate websites are a particularly rich source of argumentative dialogic data <ref type="figure">(Fig. 1</ref>). On these websites, users debate and share their opin- ions on a variety of social and political issues. Previous work <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">(Somasundaran and Wiebe, 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b23">Walker et al., 2012c</ref>) has shown that stance clas- sification in online debates is a challenging prob- lem. While collective approaches that jointly pre- dict user stance seem promising ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">Walker et al., 2012c;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Hasan and Ng, 2013)</ref>, the rich structure of online debate forums necessitates many modeling choices. For example, users publish opinions and reply and respond to each others' posts. In so do- ing, they may agree or disagree with either all or a portion of another user's post, suggesting that collective classifiers for stance may benefit from text-based disagreement modeling. Furthermore, one can model stance either at the author level- assuming that an author's stance is based on all of their posts on a topic <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(Burfoot et al., 2011</ref>)-or at the post level-assuming that an author's stance is post-specific and may vary across posts <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(Hasan and Ng, 2013)</ref>. These decisions can drastically change the nature of stance models, so understand- ing their implications is critical.</p><p>In this paper, we develop a flexible modeling framework for stance classification using proba- bilistic soft logic (PSL) ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Bach et al., 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Bach et al., 2015)</ref>, a recently introduced probabilis- tic modeling framework. 1 PSL is a probabilis- tic programming system that allows models to be specified using a declarative, rule-like language. The resulting models are a special form of con- ditional random field, called a hinge-loss Markov random field, which admits highly scalable exact inference ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Bach et al., 2013)</ref>. Modeling stance in large, richly connected online debate forums requires a careful exploration of many modeling choices. This complex domain especially benefits from PSL's flexibility and scalability. PSL makes it easy to develop model variations and extensions, as one can readily incorporate new factors captur- ing additional intuitions about dependencies in a domain.</p><p>We evaluate our models on data from two debate sites, 4FORUMS and CREATEDEBATE ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Walker et al., 2012b;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Hasan and Ng, 2013)</ref>, which we describe in detail in Section 2. Our experi- mental results show that there are important rami- fications of several modeling decisions, including whether to use collective or non-collective mod- els, to represent stance at the post level or the au- thor level, and how to model disagreement. We find that with appropriate modeling choices, our approach leads to improvements of up to 11.5 per- centage points of accuracy over simple classifica- tion approaches.</p><p>Our contributions include (1) a flexible, unified framework for modeling online debates, (2) ex- tensive experimental study of many possible mod- els on eight forum datasets, collected across two different debate websites, and (3) general model- ing recommendations resulting from our empirical studies.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Online Debate Forums</head><p>Online debate forums represent richly structured argumentative dialogues. On these forums, users debate with each other in discussion threads on a variety of topics or issues, such as gun control, gay marriage, and marijuana legalization. Each dis- cussion consists of a number of posts, which are short text documents authored by users of the fo- rum. A post is either a reply to a previous post, or it is the start (root) of a thread. As users en- gage with each other, a thread branches out into a tree of argumentative interactions between the users. Forum users often post numerous times and across multiple discussions and topics, which creates a richly structured interaction graph. On- line debates present different challenges than more controlled dialogic settings such as congressional debates. Posts are short and informal, there is lim- ited external information about authors, and de- bate topics admit many modes of argumentation ranging from serious, to tangential, to sarcastic. The reply graph in online debates also has sub- stantially different semantics to networks in other debate settings, such as the graph of speaker men- tions in congressional debates. To illustrate this setting, <ref type="figure">Fig. 1</ref> shows an example dialogue between two users who are debating their opinions on the topic of gun control.</p><p>In the context of online debate forums, stance classification ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Thomas et al., 2006;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Somasundaran and Wiebe, 2009</ref>) is the task of assigning stance labels with respect to a discussion topic, either at the level of the user or the level of the post. Stance is typically treated as a binary classification prob- lem, with labels PRO and ANTI. In <ref type="figure">Fig. 1</ref>, both users' stances toward gun control are ANTI.</p><p>Previous work on stance in online debates has shown that contextual information given by reply links is important for stance classification ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">Walker et al., 2012a)</ref>, and that collective classification of- ten outperforms methods which treat each post independently. <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Hasan and Ng (2013)</ref> use condi- tional random fields (CRFs) to encourage opposite stances between sequences of posts, and <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">Walker et al. (2012c)</ref> use MaxCut over explicitly given re- buttal links between posts to separate them into PRO and ANTI clusters. <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">Sridhar et al. (2014)</ref> use hinge-loss Markov random fields (HL-MRFs) to encourage consistency between post level stance labels and observed post-level textual agreements and disagreements.</p><p>While the first two approaches leverage rebuttal or reply links, they model reply links as being in- dicative of opposite stances. However, as shown in <ref type="figure">Fig. 1</ref>, responses-even rebuttals-can occur be-tween users with the same stance, which suggests the benefit of a more nuanced treatment of reply links. The approach of <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">Sridhar et al. (2014)</ref> con- siders text-based agreement annotations between posts, though it requires that reply links are la- beled. Accurate reply polarity labels are likely to be as expensive to obtain as the stance labels that we aim to predict. Noisy or sparse reply labels are cheaper, though likely to reduce performance. In this work, we show how to reason over uncertain reply label predictions to improve stance classifi- cation.</p><p>Also in the online debate setting, <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Hasan and Ng (2014)</ref> show the benefits of joint modeling to clas- sify post-level stance and the authors' reasons for their stances. In contrast, in this work we focus on the dependencies between stance and polarity of replies.</p><p>In the context of opinion subgroup discov- ery, Abu-Jbara and <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Radev (2013)</ref> demonstrate the effectiveness of clustering users by opinion- target similarity. In contrast, <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Murakami and Raymond (2010)</ref> use simple recurring patterns such as "that's a good idea" to categorize reply links as agree, disagree or neutral, prior to using Max- Cut for subgroup clustering of comment streams on government websites. This approach improves over a MaxCut approach that casts all reply links as disagreements. Building on this work, <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Lu et al. (2012)</ref> model unsupervised discovery of support- ing and opposing groups of users for topics in on- line military forums. They improve upon a Max- Cut baseline by formulating a linear program (LP) to combine multiple textual and reply-link signals, suggesting the benefits of jointly modeling textual and reply-link features.</p><p>In a different line of work, while Somasundaran and Wiebe (2010) do not use relational informa- tion between users or posts, their approach shows the benefit of modeling opinions and their targets at a fine-grained level using relational sentiment analysis techniques. Similarly, <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Wang and Cardie (2014)</ref> demonstrate the effectiveness of using sen- timent analysis to identify disputes on Wikipedia Talk pages. Boltuži´Boltuži´c andŠnajderandˇandŠnajder (2014) and <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Ghosh et al. (2014)</ref> study various linguistic fea- tures to model stance and agreement interactions respectively.</p><p>In the congressional debate setting, approaches using CRFs and similar collective techniques such as minimum-cut have also leveraged reply link  polarity for improvements in stance classification ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Thomas et al., 2006;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Bansal et al., 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Balahur et al., 2009;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Burfoot et al., 2011</ref>). How- ever, these methods rely heavily on features spe- cific to the congressional setting in order to pre- dict link polarity, and make little use of textual features. In contrast, Abbott et al. (2011) use a range of linguistic features from the text of posts and their parents to classify agreement or disagree- ment between posts on the online debate website 4FORUMS.COM, without the goal of classifying stance.</p><p>In this work, we study datasets from two on- line debate websites: 4FORUMS.COM, from the Internet Argument Corpus ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Walker et al., 2012b)</ref>, and CREATEDEBATE.COM <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(Hasan and Ng, 2013)</ref>. <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Table 1</ref> shows statistics about these datasets in- cluding the average number of users per dis- cussion topic and average number of posts au- thored. The best stance classification accuracy to date for online debate forums ranges from 70.1% on CONVINCEME.NET to 75.4% on CREATEDE- BATE.COM ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">Walker et al., 2012c;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Hasan and Ng, 2013</ref>). The web interface for CONVINCEME.NET enforces opposite stances for reply posts, making this dataset inapplicable for text-based disagree- ment modeling, and so we do not consider it in our experiments. In the more typical online debate forum corpora that we study, the presence of a re- ply, or even a textual disagreement between posts, does not necessarily indicate opposite stance (e.g. in gun control debates on 4Forums, 23% of dis- agreements correspond with same stance).</p><p>For our unified framework, we specify a hinge- loss Markov random field to reason jointly about stance and reply-link polarity labels. A closely related line of work focuses on improving struc-tured prediction with domain knowledge modeled as constraints in the objective function <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Chang et al., 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Ganchev et al., 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Mann and McCallum, 2010)</ref>. Though more often used in semi- supervised settings, constraint-based learning can be especially appropriate for supervised learning when commonly used feature functions for linear models do not capture the richness of the data. Our HL-MRF formulation admits highly expres- sive features while maintaining a convex objec- tive, thereby enjoying both tractability and a fully probabilistic interpretation.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Modeling Choices</head><p>We face multiple modeling decisions that may impact predictive performance when classifying stance in online debates. A key contribution of this work is the exploration of the ramifications of these choices. We consider the following varia- tions on modeling: collective (C) versus local (L) classifiers, whether to explicitly model disagree- ment (D), and author-level (A) versus post-level (P) models.</p><p>Collective versus Local. Both collective and non-collective methods for stance prediction re- quire a strong local text classifier. The methods proposed in this paper build upon the state-of-the- art local classification approach of <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">Walker et al. (2012a)</ref>, which trains a supervised classifier us- ing features including n-grams, lexical category counts, and text lengths. We use logistic regres- sion for the local classifier. These models will be referred to as local (L). In collective (C) classifi- cation approaches for stance prediction, the stance labels are all predicted jointly, leveraging relation- ships along the graph of replies. The simplest way to make use of reply links is to encode that the stance of posts (or authors) that reply to each other is likely to be opposite ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">Walker et al., 2012c;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Hasan and Ng, 2013)</ref>. Collective approaches at- tempt to find the most likely joint stance labeling that is consistent with both the local classifier's predictions and the alternation of stance along re- sponse threads. The alternating stance assumption is not necessarily a hard constraint, and may po- tentially be overridden by the local predictions. C and L models can be constructed with A or P-level granularity as described below, resulting in four modeling combinations.</p><p>Modeling Disagreement. As seen in <ref type="figure">Fig. 1</ref> and <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Table 1</ref>, the assumption that reply links corre- spond to opposite stance is not always correct. This suggests the potential benefit of more nu- anced models of agreement and disagreement. A natural disagreement modeling approach is to pre- dict the polarity of reply links jointly with stance.</p><p>There are two variants of reply link polarity to consider. In textual disagreement, replying posts are coded as expressing agreement or disagree- ment with the text of the parent post. This may not correspond to a disagreement in stance rela- tive to the thread topic. Some forum interfaces support user self-labeling of post reply links as re- buttals or agreements, thereby explicitly provid- ing textual disagreement labels for posts. Alter- natively, in the stance disagreement variant, reply links denote either same or opposite stance be- tween users (posts). In <ref type="figure">Fig. 1</ref>, User 1 and User 2 disagree in text but have the same stance. For collective modeling of stance and disagreement, it is useful to consider the stance disagreement vari- ant which identifies opposite and same-stance re- ply links, and jointly encourage stance predictions to be consistent with the disagreement predictions.</p><p>As with the local classification of stance, we can construct local classifiers for stance disagreement. In this work, for each reply link instance, we use a copy of the local stance classification features for each author/post at the ends of the reply link. The linguistic features further include discourse mark- ers such as "actually" and "because" from the dis- agreement classifier of <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Abbott et al. (2011)</ref>. Addi- tionally, we use textual disagreement as a feature for stance disagreementwhen available. When re- ply links are not explicitly labeled as rebuttals or agreements, or only rebuttals are known, we in- stead predict textual disagreement using the fea- tures given above, trained on a separate data set with textual-disagreement labels.</p><p>Finally, with a stance disagreement classifier in hand, we can build collective models that predict stance based on predicted stance disagreement po- larity. We denote these models as disagreement (D). When applied at one of A or P-level model- ing, this yields two more possible modeling con- figurations. These models are certainly more com- plex than others we consider, but their design is consistent with intuition about the nature of dis- course, so the added complexity may yield better accuracy.</p><note type="other">All models: Collective models only: Disagreement models only:</note><formula xml:id="formula_0">localPro(X1) → pro(X1) disagree(X1, X2) ∧ pro(X1) → ¬ pro(X2) localDisagree(X1, X2) → disagree(X1, X2) ¬ localPro(X1) → ¬ pro(X1) disagree(X1, X2) ∧ ¬ pro(X1) → pro(X2) ¬ localDisagree(X1, X2) → ¬ disagree(X1, X2) ¬ disagree(X1, X2) ∧ pro(X1) → pro(X2) pro(X1) ∧ ¬ pro(X2) → disagree(X1, X2) ¬ disagree(X1, X2) ∧ ¬ pro(X1) → ¬ pro(X2) pro(X1) ∧ pro(X2) → ¬ disagree(X1, X2) disagree(X1, X2) = 1 ¬ pro(X1) ∧ ¬ pro(X2) → ¬ disagree(X1, X2)</formula><p>Figure 2: PSL rules to define the collective classification models, both for post-level and author-level models. Each X is an author or a post, depending on the level of granularity that the model is applied at. The disagree(X 1 , X 2 ) predicates apply to post reply links, and to pairs of authors connected by reply links.</p><p>Author-Level versus Post-Level. When model- ing debates, stance classifiers can predict either the stance of a debate participant (i.e. an author Nevertheless, given a prediction target, either author or post, it may be beneficial to consider modeling at a different level of granularity. For example, <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Hasan and Ng (2013)</ref> find that post-level prediction accuracy can be improved by "clamp- ing" all posts by a given author to the same stance in order to smooth their labels. Alterna- tively, author-level predictions may potentially be improved by first treating each post separately, thereby effectively giving a classifier more train- ing examples, i.e. the number of posts instead of the number of authors. With this procedure, a fi- nal author-level prediction can be obtained by av- eraging the predictions over the posts for the au- thor, trading the noisiness of post-level instances against the smoothing afforded by the final ag- gregation. When designing a stance classifier, the modeler must decide the level of granularity for the prediction target and find the best model therein.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">A Collective Classification Framework</head><p>To study these choices, we build a flexible stance classification framework that implements the above variations using probabilistic soft logic (PSL) ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Bach et al., 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Bach et al., 2013</ref>), a re- cently introduced probabilistic programming sys- tem. Like other probabilistic modeling frame- works, notably Markov logic ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Richardson and Domingos, 2006</ref>), PSL uses a logic-like language for defining the potential functions for a condi- tional random field. However, unlike Markov logic, PSL makes inference tractable, even in the loopy author-level networks and the very large post-level networks of online debates.</p><p>PSL's tractability arises from the use of a special class of conditional random field models referred to as hinge-loss MRFs (HL-MRFs), which admit efficient, scalable and exact maximum a posteriori (MAP) inference ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Bach et al., 2013</ref>). These mod- els are defined over continuous random variables, and MAP inference is a convex optimization prob- lem over these variables. Formally, a hinge-loss MRF defines a probability density function of the form</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">P (Y|X) = 1 Z exp − M r=1 λ r φ r (Y, X) ,<label>(1)</label></formula><p>where the entries of Y and X are in <ref type="bibr">[0,</ref><ref type="bibr">1]</ref>, λ is a vector of weight parameters, Z is a normalization constant, and</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">φ r (Y, X) = (max{l r (Y, X), 0}) ρr (2)</formula><p>is a hinge-loss potential specified by a linear func- tion l r and optional exponent ρ r ∈ {1, 2}. Given a collection of first-order PSL rules, each instan- tiation of the rules maps to a hinge-loss poten- tial function as in Equation 2, and the potential functions define an HL-MRF model. For exam- ple, a ⇒ b max(a − b, 0), where a and b are ground variables, and max(a − b, 0) is a convex relaxation of logical implication, and which can be understood as its distance to satisfaction. For a full description of PSL, see ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Bach et al., 2015</ref>).</p><p>The models we introduce are specified by the PSL rules in <ref type="figure">Fig. 2</ref>, with both post-level and author-level models following the same design. We denote the different modeling choices with the letters defined in Section 3. First, local logistic regression classifiers output stance probabilities based on textual features of posts or authors. All of the models begin with these real-valued stance predictions, encoded by the observed predicate lo- calPro(X i ). The rules listed for all models en- courage the inferred global predictions pro(X i ) to match these local predictions.</p><p>This defines the local classification models L, which are HL-MRFs with node potentials and no edge potentials, and which are equivalent to the local classifiers. The collective models extend the L models by adding edge potentials which en- courage the stance labels to respect disagreement relationships along reply links. Specifically, ev- ery reply link between authors (for author-level models) or between posts (for post-level mod- els) x 1 and x 2 is associated with a latent vari- able disagree(x 1 , x 2 ). The rules encourage the global stance variables to respect the polarity of the disagreement variables (same stance, or op- posite stance) and while also trying to match the stance classifiers. For the models that do not ex- plicitly model disagreement, it is assumed that ev- ery reply edge constitutes a disagreement, i.e. dis- agree(x 1 , x 2 ) = 1. These models are denoted C.</p><p>Otherwise, the disagreement variables are en- couraged to match binary-valued predictions from the local disagreement classifiers. We binarize the predictions of the disagreement classifiers to encourage propagation. The disagreement vari- ables are modeled jointly with the stance variables, and label information propagates in both direc- tions between stance and disagreement variables. The full joint stance/disagreement collective mod- els are denoted D. In the following, the models are denoted by pairs of letters according to their col- lectivity level and modeling granularity. For ex- ample, AC denotes collective classification per- formed at the author level, without joint model- ing of disagreement. To train these models and use them for prediction, weight learning and MAP inference are performed using the structured per- ceptron algorithm and ADMM algorithm of <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Bach et al. (2013)</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Experimental Evaluation</head><p>The goals of our experiments were to validate the proposed collective modeling framework, and to make substantive conclusions about the merits of the different possible modeling options described in Section 3. To this end, we evaluated the mod- els on eight topics from 4FORUMS.COM ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Walker et al., 2012b</ref>) and CREATEDEBATE.COM <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(Hasan and Ng, 2013)</ref>, for classification tasks at both the author level and the post level. With comparison to <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Hasan and Ng (2013)</ref>, our collective models (C) are essentially equivalent to their CRF, up to the form of the CRF potential function, which is not explicitly specified in the paper. A further goal of our experiments was to determine whether the modeling options in our more general CRF could improve performance over models with this struc- ture.</p><p>On average, each topic-wise data set contains hundreds of authors and thousands of posts. The 4FORUMS data sets are annotated for stance at the author level, while CREATEDEBATE has stance la- bels at the post level. To perform post-level evalu- ations on 4FORUMS we apply author labels to the posts of each author, and on CREATEDEBATE we computed author labels by selecting the majority label of their posts. For 4FORUMS, since post- level stance labels correspond directly to author- level stance labels, we use averages of post-level predictions as the local classifier output for au- thors. Section 2 includes an overview of these de- bate forum data sets.</p><p>In the experiments, classification accuracy was estimated via five repeats of 5-fold cross- validation. In each fold, we ran logistic regres- sion using the scikit-learn software package, 2 us- ing the default settings, except for the L1 regu- larization trade-off parameter C which was tuned on a within-fold hold-out set consisting of 20% of the discussions within the fold. For the collec- tive models, weight learning was performed on the same in-fold tuning sets. We trained via 700 itera- tions of structured perceptron, and ran the ADMM MAP inference algorithm to convergence at test time. On average, weight learning and inference took around 1 minute per fold.</p><p>The full results for author-level and post-level predictions are given in <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">Table 2 and Table 3</ref>, re- spectively. In the tables, entries in bold identify statistically significant differences from the local classifier baseline under a paired t-test with sig- nificance level α = 0.05. These results are sum- marized in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Fig. 3</ref>, which shows box plots for the six possible models, computed over the final cross- validated accuracy scores of each of the four data  A closer analysis reveals some subtleties. When comparing D models with C models in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Fig. 3</ref>, dis- agreement modeling makes a much bigger differ- ence at the author level than at the post level. This is likely impacted by the level of class imbalance for disagreement classification in the different lev- els of modeling. Disagreement, rather than agree- ment, between authors prompts many responses. Thus, reply links are more likely disagreements when measured at the post level, as seen in <ref type="table">Ta-4FORUMS   CREATEDEBATE   Models Abortion  Evolution  Gay  Gun  Abortion  Gay  Marijuana  Obama  Marriage</ref> Control Rights PL 61.9 ± 4.3 76.6 ± 3.9 72.0 ± 3.6 66.4 ± 4.6 66.4 ± 5.2 70.2 ± 5.0 74.1 ± 6.5 63.8 ± 8.7 PC 63.4 ± 5.9 74.6 ± 4.1 73.7 ± 4.3 68.3 ± 5.5 68.7 ± 5.7 72.6 ± 5.6 75.4 ± 7.4 66.1 ± 8.5 PD 63.0 ± 5.4 76.7 ± 4.2 73.7 ± 4.6 67.9 ± 5.0 69.5 ± 5.7 73.2 ± 5.9 74.7 ± 7.0 66.1 ± 8.5 AL 64.9 ± 4.2 77.3 ± 2.9 74.5 ± 2.9 67.1 ± 4.5 65.2 ± 6.5 69.5 ± 4.4 74.0 ± 6.6 59.0 ± 7.5 AC 66.0 ± 5.0 74.4 ± 4.2 75.7 ± 5.1 61.5 ± 5.6 65.8 ± 7.0 73.6 ± 3.5 73.9 ± 7.6 62.5 ± 8.3 AD 65.8 ± 4.4 78.7 ± 3.3 77.1 ± 4.4 67.1 ± 5.4 67.4 ± 7.5 74.0 ± 5.3 74.8 ± 7.5 63.0 ± 8.3  On the other hand, the assumption that re- ply edges constitute disagreement is less accurate when modeling at the author level (see <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Table 1</ref>). In this case, the full joint disagreement model is necessary to obtain good performance. In an ex- treme example, the two datasets with the lowest disagreement rates at the author level are evolution (44.4%) and gun control (50.7%) from 4FORUMS. The AC classifier performed very poorly for these data sets, dropping to 46.9% accuracy in one in- stance, as the "opposite stance" assumption did not hold <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">(Tables 2 and 3</ref>). The full joint disagree- ment model AD performed much better, in fact achieving an outstanding accuracy rates of 80.3% and 80.5% for posts on evolution and gay marriage respectively. To illustrate the benefits of author- level disagreement modeling, <ref type="figure">Fig. 4</ref> shows a post for an author whose stance towards gun control is correctly predicted by AD but not the AC model,</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Text Stance</head><p>Post: I agree with everything except the last part. Safe gun storage is very important, and sensible storage requirements have two important factors.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>ANTI</head><p>Reply: I can agree with this. And in case it seemed otherwise, I know full well how to store guns safely, and why it's nec- essary. My point was that I don't like the idea of such a law, especially when you consider the problem of enforcement. <ref type="figure">Figure 4</ref>: A post-reply pair by 4FORUMS.COM au- thors whose gun control stance is correctly pre- dicted by AD, but not by AC.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>ANTI</head><p>along with a subsequent reply. The authors largely agree with each other's views, which the joint dis- agreement model leverages, while the simpler col- lective model encourages opposite stance due to the presence of reply links between them. To summarize our conclusions from these ex- periments, the results suggest that author-level modeling is the preferred strategy, regardless of the prediction task. In this scenario, it is essen- tial to explicitly model disagreement in the collec- tive classifier. Our top performing AD model sta- tistically significantly outperforms the respective prediction task baseline on 6 out of 8 topics for both tasks with p-values less than 0.001. Based on our experimental results, we recommend the full author-disagreement model AD as the classifier of choice.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Discussion and Future Work</head><p>The prediction of user stance in online debate fo- rums is a valuable task, and modeling debate di- alogue is complex and requires many decisions such collective or non-collective reasoning, nu- anced or naive use of disagreement information, and post versus author-level modeling granularity. We systematically explore each choice, and in do- ing so build a unified joint framework that incor- porates each salient decision. Our method uses a hinge-loss Markov random field to encourage con- sistency between local classifier predictions for stance and disagreement information. We find that modeling at the author level gives better predic- tive performance regardless of the granularity of the prediction task, and that nuanced disagreement modeling is of particular importance for author- level collective modeling. The resulting collective classifier gives improved predictive performance over both the simple non-collective and standard collective approaches, with a running time over- head of only a few minutes, thanks to the efficient nature of hinge-loss MRFs.</p><p>There are many directions for future work. Our results have found that collective reasoning can also be beneficial at the post level, as previously reported by <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Hasan and Ng (2013)</ref>. It is likely that a multi-level model for a combination of post-and author-level collective modeling of both stance and disagreement could bring further improve- ments in performance. It would also be informa- tive to explore dynamic models which elucidate trends of opinions over time. Another direction is to model influence between users in online debate forums, and to identify the most influential users who are able to convince other users to change their opinions. Finally, we note that stance and disagreement classification are both challenging and important problems, and going forward, there is likely to be much room for improvement in these prediction tasks.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>(A)) (Burfoot et al., 2011), or the stance expressed by a specific dialogue act (i.e. a post (P)) (Hasan and Ng, 2013). The choice of prediction target may depend on the downstream goal, such as user modeling or the study of the dialogic expression of disagreement. From a philosophical perspec- tive, authors are individuals who hold opinions, while posts are not. A post is simply a piece of text which may or may not express the opinions of its author.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Figure 3: Overall accuracies per model for the author stance prediction task, computed over the final results for each of the four data sets per forum. Note that we expect significant variation in these plots, as the data sets are of varying degrees of difficulty.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" validated="false"><head>Table 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Structural statistics averages for 4FO-
RUMS and CREATEDEBATE. 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" validated="false"><head>Table 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Author stance classification accuracy and standard deviation for 4FORUMS (left) and CREAT-
EDEBATE (right), estimated via 5 repeats of 5-fold cross-validation. Bolded figures indicate statistically 
significant (α = 0.05) improvement over AL, the baseline model for the author stance classification task. 

4FORUMS 
CREATEDEBATE 

Models Abortion 
Evolution 
Gay 
Gun 
Abortion 
Gay 
Marijuana 
Obama 
Marriage 
Control 
Rights </table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3" validated="false"><head>Table 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Post stance classification accuracy and standard deviations for 4FORUMS (left) and CREAT-
EDEBATE (right), estimated via 5 repeats of 5-fold cross-validation. Bolded figures indicate statistically 
significant (α = 0.05) improvement over PL, the baseline model for the post stance classification task. 

ble 1. Therefore, enforcing disagreement may be 
a better assumption at the post level, and the nu-
anced disagreement model is not necessary in this 
case. The overall improvements in accuracy from 
disagreement modeling for post-level models were 
small. 

</table></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> PSL is an open-source Java toolkit, available here: http://psl.cs.umd.edu.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="2"> Available at http://scikit-learn.org/.</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>This work was supported by NSF grant IIS1218488, and IARPA via DoI/NBC contract number D12PC00337. The U.S. Government is authorized to reproduce and distribute reprints for governmental purposes notwithstanding any copyright annotation thereon. Disclaimer: The views and conclusions contained herein are those of the authors and should not be interpreted as necessarily representing the official policies or endorsements, either expressed or implied, of IARPA, DoI/NBC, or the U.S. Government.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">How can you say such things?!?: Recognizing disagreement in informal political argument</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marilyn</forename><surname>References Rob Abbott</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jean</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Walker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Pranav</forename><surname>Fox Tree</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Robeson</forename><surname>Anand</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Joseph</forename><surname>Bowmani</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>King</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ACL Workshop on Language and Social Media</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Identifying opinion subgroups in Arabic online discussions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Amjad</forename><surname>Abu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">-Jbara</forename><surname>Dragomir R Radev</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ACL</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Hinge-loss Markov random fields: Convex inference for structured prediction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Stephen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bert</forename><surname>Bach</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ben</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lise</forename><surname>London</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Getoor</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Uncertainty in Artificial Intelligence (UAI)</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Bach</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Broecheler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Getoor</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:1505.04406</idno>
		<title level="m">Hinge-loss Markov random fields and probabilistic soft logic</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>cs.LG</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Determining the polarity and source of opinions expressed in political debates</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alexandra</forename><surname>Balahur</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Zornitsa</forename><surname>Kozareva</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Andres</forename><surname>Montoyo</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Computational Linguistics and Intelligent Text Processing</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The power of negative thinking: Exploiting label disagreement in the min-cut classification framework</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mohit</forename><surname>Bansal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Claire</forename><surname>Cardie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lillian</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
			<publisher>COLING</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Back up your stance: recognizing arguments in online discussions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Filip</forename><surname>Boltuži´boltuži´c</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jaň</forename><surname>Snajder</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ACL Workshop on Argumentation Mining</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Collective classification of congressional floor-debate transcripts</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Clinton</forename><surname>Burfoot</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Steven</forename><surname>Bird</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Timothy</forename><surname>Baldwin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ACL</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Structured learning with constrained conditional models</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ming-Wei</forename><surname>Chang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lev</forename><surname>Ratinov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dan</forename><surname>Roth</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Machine learning</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">88</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="399" to="431" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Posterior regularization for structured latent variable models</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kuzman</forename><surname>Ganchev</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Joao</forename><surname>Graça</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jennifer</forename><surname>Gillenwater</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ben</forename><surname>Taskar</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Machine Learning</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2001" to="2049" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Analyzing argumentative discourse units in online interactions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Debanjan</forename><surname>Ghosh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Smaranda</forename><surname>Muresan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nina</forename><surname>Wacholder</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mark</forename><surname>Aakhus</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Matthew</forename><surname>Mitsui</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ACL Workshop on Argumentation Mining</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Stance classification of ideological debates: Data, models, features, and constraints</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Saidul</forename><surname>Kazi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Vincent</forename><surname>Hasan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Ng</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Why are you taking this stance? Identifying and classifying reasons in ideological debates</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Saidul</forename><surname>Kazi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Vincent</forename><surname>Hasan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Ng</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">EMNLP</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Unsupervised discovery of opposing opinion networks from forum discussions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Lu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Zhai</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Roth</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">CIKM</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Generalized expectation criteria for semi-supervised learning with weakly labeled data</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Gideon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Andrew</forename><surname>Mann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Mccallum</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Machine Learning</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="955" to="984" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Support or Oppose? Classifying positions in online debates from reply activities and opinion expressions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Akiko</forename><surname>Murakami</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rudy</forename><surname>Raymond</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ACL</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Markov logic networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Matthew</forename><surname>Richardson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Pedro</forename><surname>Domingos</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Machine learning</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">62</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="2" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Recognizing stances in online debates</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Swapna</forename><surname>Somasundaran</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Janyce</forename><surname>Wiebe</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ACL and AFNLP</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Recognizing stances in ideological on-line debates</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Swapna</forename><surname>Somasundaran</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Janyce</forename><surname>Wiebe</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">NAACL HLT 2010 Workshop on Computational Approaches to Analysis and Generation of Emotion in Text</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Collective stance classification of posts in online debate forums</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dhanya</forename><surname>Sridhar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lise</forename><surname>Getoor</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marilyn</forename><surname>Walker</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ACL Joint Workshop on Social Dynamics and Personal Attributes in Social Media</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Get out the vote: Determining support or opposition from Congressional floor-debate transcripts</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Matt</forename><surname>Thomas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bo</forename><surname>Pang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lillian</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">EMNLP</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">That&apos;s your evidence?: Classifying stance in online political debate</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marilyn</forename><surname>Walker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Pranav</forename><surname>Anand</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rob</forename><surname>Abbott</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jean</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Fox Tree</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Craig</forename><surname>Martell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Joseph</forename><surname>King</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Support Sciences</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A corpus for research on deliberation and debate</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marilyn</forename><surname>Walker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Pranav</forename><surname>Anand</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Robert</forename><surname>Abbott</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jean</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Fox Tree</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">LREC</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Stance classification using dialogic properties of persuasion</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marilyn</forename><surname>Walker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Pranav</forename><surname>Anand</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Robert</forename><surname>Abbott</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Richard</forename><surname>Grant</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">NAACL</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A piece of my mind: A sentiment analysis approach for online dispute detection</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lu</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Claire</forename><surname>Cardie</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ACL</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
