<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T12:42+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">On the Importance of Ezafe Construction in Persian Parsing</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
				<availability status="unknown"><p>Copyright Association for Computational Linguistics</p>
				</availability>
				<date>July 26-31, 2015. 2015</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alireza</forename><surname>Nourian</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mohammad</forename><forename type="middle">Sadegh</forename><surname>Rasooli</surname></persName>
							<email>rasooli@cs.columbia.edu</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mohsen</forename><surname>Imany</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Heshaam</forename><surname>Faili</surname></persName>
							<email>hfaili@ut.ac.ir</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Department of Computer Engineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Department of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Iran University of Science and Technlogy</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Tehran</settlement>
									<country key="IR">Iran</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">School of Electrical and Computer Engineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Columbia University</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>New York</settlement>
									<region>NY</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="institution">University of Tehran</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Tehran</settlement>
									<country key="IR">Iran</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">On the Importance of Ezafe Construction in Persian Parsing</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 53rd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics and the 7th International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing</title>
						<meeting>the 53rd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics and the 7th International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing <address><addrLine>Beijing, China</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="877" to="882"/>
							<date type="published">July 26-31, 2015. 2015</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Ezafe construction is an idiosyncratic phenomenon in the Persian language. It is a good indicator for phrase boundaries and dependency relations but mostly does not appear in the text. In this paper, we show that adding information about Ezafe construction can give 4.6% relative improvement in dependency parsing and 9% relative improvement in shallow parsing. For evaluation purposes, Ezafe tags are manually annotated in the Persian dependency treebank. Furthermore, to be able to conduct experiments on shallow parsing, we develop a dependency to shallow phrase structure convertor based on the Persian dependencies.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>There have been many studies on improving syn- tactic parsing methods for natural languages. Al- though most of the parsing methods are language- independent, we may still require some language specific knowledge for improving performance. Besides many studies on parsing morphologically rich languages ( <ref type="bibr">Seddah et al., 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr">Seeker and Kuhn, 2013)</ref>, syntactic parsing for the Persian lan- guage is not yet noticeably explored. Concretely speaking, there are some recent work on depen- dency parsing for Persian ( <ref type="bibr">Seraji et al., 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Ghayoomi, 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Khallash et al., 2013</ref>) and very few studies on shallow parsing ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Kian et al., 2009</ref>).</p><p>The main focus of this paper is on the usefulness of Ezafe construction in Persian syntactic process- ing. Ezafe is an unstressed vowel -e that occurs at the end of some words (-ye in some specific occa- sions) that links together elements belonging to a single constituent <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(Ghomeshi, 1997)</ref>. It often ap- proximately corresponds in usage to the English preposition "of" <ref type="bibr">(Abrahams, 2004</ref>). In the follow- ing example, the first word has an Ezafe vowel:</p><p>montazer e Ab waiting Ezaf e water waiting f or water This is an idiosyncratic construction that ap- pears in the Persian language with Perso-Arabic script. This construction is similar to Idafa con- struction in Arabic and construct state in Hebrew <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Habash, 2010)</ref>. It is mostly used for showing a possessive marker, adjective of a noun or connect- ing parts of a name (i.e. first and last name) or ti- tle. As a general statement, Ezafe occurs between any two items that have some sort of connection <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(Ghomeshi, 1997)</ref>. Ezafe vowel is attached to the head noun and to the modifiers that follow it: attributive nouns, adjectival and prepositional phrases <ref type="bibr">(Samvelian, 2006</ref>). As depicted in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure  1</ref>, this construction is very useful for disambiguat- ing syntactic structures. The main issue here is that Ezafe rarely appears in the written text. This relies on the fact that Persian is written in Perso- Arabic script and vowels are mostly not written.</p><p>There are few studies <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">(Noferesti and Shamsfard, 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Asghari et al., 2014</ref>) on automatically find- ing Ezafe construction. In this work, we modify the part of speech tagset for the Persian words. This is done by adding an indicator of Ezafe to each part of speech (POS) tag and then train a su- pervised tagger on the modified tags. We show that having this modified tagset can both improve dependency parsing and shallow parsing (chunk- ing). We achieve 12.8% and 4.6% relative error re- duction in dependency parsing with gold and auto- 877 root .</p><p>is black table+Ezafe on+Ezafe book    matic POS tags. We also achieve 31% and 9% rel- ative error reduction in shallow parsing with gold and automatic POS tags.</p><p>Our work is not only restricted to the effect of Ezafe in parsing, but as a byproduct, we create an open-source rule-based dependency to chunk con- verter for the Persian language. We have also man- ually tagged all words in the Persian dependency treebank ( <ref type="bibr">Rasooli et al., 2013</ref>) with 99.6% anno- tator agreement. This dataset is available for re- search purposes. <ref type="bibr">1</ref> The main contributions of this paper are: 1) showing the usefulness of Ezafe construction on dependency parsing and chunking, 2) developing a statistical chunker for the Persian language, 3) enriching the Persian treebank with manual Ezafe tags. The remainder of this paper is organized as the following: we describe our approach and data preparation in §2 and then conduct experiments in §3. Error analysis and conclusion are made in §4 and §5.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Data Preparation</head><p>We define a simple procedure to include the in- formation about Ezafe construction in our data. Concretely, we attach the Ezafe indicator to the tags and train a POS tagger on the new tagset. This idea is very similar to that of ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Asghari et al., 2014</ref> </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">Chunking Data Preparation</head><p>Unfortunately there is no standard chunking data for the Persian language. To compensate for this, we define the following rules to convert a depen- dency tree (based on Dadegan treebank dependen- cies ( <ref type="bibr">Rasooli et al., 2013)</ref>) to a shallow phrase structure:</p><p>-We initialize every node (word) as a separate chunk; e.g. verb creates a VP.</p><p>-If a node has a head or dependent belonging to a chunk (without any gap), attach that node to the same chunk.</p><p>-If a node is a preposition/postposition, attach it to its next/previous dependent and create a PP.</p><p>-A node with a dependency relation "non- verbal element", "verb particle", or "enclitic non-verbal element" belongs to the same VP as its head.</p><p>-If a node is a particle, subordinating clause, coordinating conjunction, or punctuation, we should not create an independent chunk for it.</p><p>-If a node is a "noun post modifier" or "Ezafe dependent", attach it to its parent chunk.</p><p>-If a node is a "conjunction of a noun" or "conjunction of an adjective" and has a sib- ling with either "Ezafe dependent" or "noun post-modifier" dependency relation, it should have the same chunk as its parent.</p><p>-If a node with pseudo-sentence POS has an adverbial dependency with its parent, it cre- ates an ADVP and otherwise a VP. Implementation of the above rules is available in the Hazm toolkit. <ref type="bibr">2</ref> There are some minor excep- tions in the above rules that are handled manually in the toolkit.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Experiments</head><p>In this section we describe our experiments on Ezafe tagging, parsing and also adding manual Ezafe tags to the Persian dependency treebank.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Automatic Ezafe Tagging</head><p>As mentioned in §2, we attach Ezafe feature in- dicator to the tags and train a POS tagger on the new tagset. We use Wapiti tagger ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Lavergne et al., 2010</ref>) to train a standard trigram CRF sequence tagger model with standard transition features and the following emission features: word form of the current, previous and next word, combination of the current word and next word, combination of the current word and previous word, prefixes and suffixes up to length 3, indicator of punctuation and number (digit) for the current, previous and next word. The tagger has an accuracy of 98.71% with the original tagset and 97.33% with the mod- ified tagset.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Gold Standard Ezafe Tags</head><p>The Persian dependency treebank does not provide gold Ezafe tags. In order to evaluate the effect of gold Ezafe tags, we try to manually annotate Ezafe in the treebank. This is done by six annotators where all of them are native speakers and linguists. The inter-annotator agreement of a small portion of the data (one thousand sentences) is 99.6%. Our manual investigation shows that almost half of the disagreements was because of the mistakes and not because of the complicated structure. <ref type="table">Table  1</ref> shows the statistics about the presence of Ezafe tag for each specific POS.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3">Chunking</head><p>We use Wapiti tagger ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Lavergne et al., 2010</ref>) to train a standard CRF tagger with IOB tags for phrase chunking. The features include third or- der transition features and emission features of word form and POS for the current word, previ- ous word and the word before it, the next word and the word after it. As shown in <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">Table 2</ref>    <ref type="table">Table 3</ref>: Chunking results on the Persian depen- dency treebank test data with automatic POS tags.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.4">Dependency Parsing</head><p>Similar to the chunking experiments, we provide two sets of experiments to validate our hypothesis about the importance of Ezafe construction. We <ref type="table">Tagset   MaltParser  YaraParser  TurboParser  LAS  UAS  LAS  UAS  LAS  UAS  POS</ref> 88.13% 90.69% 88.60% 91.17% 89.88% 92.25% FPOS 88.46% 91.01% 89.02% 91.56% 89.98% 92.30% POSe 89.12% 91.64% 89.91% 92.42% 90.85% 93.24%   <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Covington, 1990</ref>) after optimizing it with Malt opti- mizer ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Ballesteros and Nivre, 2012)</ref>, Yara with the default settings (64 beam) and 10 training epochs and Turbo with its default settings. The main rea- son for picking these three parsers is that we want to see the effect of Ezafe construction on a greedy parser (Malt), beam parser (Yara), and a graph- based parser (Turbo). As shown in <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">Table 4</ref> and 5, the parsing accuracy is improved across all dif- ferent parsers by using the Ezafe tagset.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Error Analysis</head><p>In this section we provide some error analysis for showing the effectiveness of our approach.</p><p>Effect on the common POS tags Our investiga- tion on the development data shows that the depen- dency attachment accuracy is improved by 6.5% for adjectives and 6.2% for nouns. This is consis- tent with our intuition because Ezafe construction mostly occurs in nouns and adjectives. It is worth noting that for some tags such as determiners the Ezafe construction does not help.</p><p>Ezafe indicator as a feature We try to use Ezafe as an independent feature in Malt parser. This is done by adding the indicator in the fea- ture column in CoNLL dependency format. We then use Malt optimizer ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Ballesteros and Nivre, 2012)</ref> to find the optimized feature setting. We see that adding this feature gives us the same accuracy improvement as having the modified tagset. This shows that we do not really need to have a parser that uses extra features to add Ezafe information.</p><p>Manual data investigation We randomly picked some sentences from the development data and observed the same effect as we could expect from adding Ezafe to the tagset: the main gain is on those sentences where the presence/absence of Ezafe construction is crucial for making correct decisions by the parser. For example, in the following sub-sentence, the word means "China" but the dependency parser without knowing Ezafe tag, confused it with the other meaning: "ruffle" and created a "non-verbal element" (light verb) dependency with the verb, instead of making it an Ezafe dependent to the previous word ( ). Effect on the training data size For investigat- ing the benefit of Ezafe construction, we train Malt parser on different data sizes starting from 50% of the original size. This trend is depicted in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Figure 2</ref>. The interesting fact is that we can leverage Ezafe construction and use only 70% of the training data while reaching the accuracy of the original part of speech tagset trained on the whole data. 50% 60% 70% 80% 90% 100% 86% </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Conclusion</head><p>In this paper we showed the effectiveness of Ezafe construction as a robust feature for syntactic pars- ing in Persian. One interesting direction for fur- ther research would be to show the effect of this feature in other natural language processing tasks.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>punc root mos sbj posdep npostmod (a) First reading: The book is on the black</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Second reading: The book on the table is black.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: This figure shows two different readings for the same sentence with different Ezafe constructions. As shown in the trees, Ezafe affects both phrase boundaries and dependency relations.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>Figure 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2: Trend on the data size and accuracy. As shown by the horizontal dashed line, Ezafe tags can improve over standard tags while having approximately 70% of the data.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" validated="false"><head>table . root</head><label>.</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>. 
is black table on+Ezafe book+Ezafe 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" validated="false"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>and 3, our intuition holds for both gold and automatic tags. We observe that using Ezafe on gold tags, gives 2 https://github.com/sobhe/hazm</figDesc><table>Tag 
Freq. Relative Freq. Ezafe % 
N 
190048 
39.24% 
34.22% 
PREP 
56376 
11.64% 
12.04% 
ADJ 
35902 
7.41% 
17.45% 
PRENUM 6018 
1.24% 
1.21% 
IDEN 
835 
0.17% 
5.03% 
POSNUM 560 
0.12% 
30.71% 
other 
194572 
40.18% 
00.10% 

Table 1: Statistics about Ezafe for each POS tag in 
the Persian dependency treebank. 

us better performance compared to using coarse-
grained POS tags and also fine-grained POS tags 
(FPOS) provided by the dependency treebank an-
notators. The tagset in Peykare corpus is very dif-
ferent from the treebank. Because of this incon-
sistency, we could not reproduce the results with 
automatic FPOS tags trained on Peykare corpus. 
Our experiments on training solely on the tree-
bank FPOS tags do not give us a reliable FPOS 
tagger and this leads to very low parsing accuracy. 
Therefore we do not conduct experiments with au-
tomatic FPOS tags. Table 3 shows the results with 
automatic tags. As shown in the table, using the 
the Ezafe tagset improves the chunking accuracy. 

Tagset Precision 
Recall 
F-Measure 
POS 
91.98% 
90.37% 
91.17% 
FPOS 
92.37% 
90.92% 
91.64% 
POSe 
93.88% 93.97% 
93.92% 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3" validated="false"><head>Table 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Chunking results on the Persian de-
pendency treebank test data with gold POS tags. 
FPOS refers to the fine-grained POS tags in the 
Persian dependency treebank and POSe is the 
modified Ezafe-enriched tagset. 

Tagset Tag Acc. Precision Recall F-Measure 
POS 
98.71% 89.44% 88.02% 88.72% 
POSe 97.33% 90.42% 89.13% 89.77% 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4" validated="true"><head>Table 4 :</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Dependency Parsing results on the test data with different gold standard tagsets. UAS is the unlabeled attachment score and LAS is the labeled attachment score.</figDesc><table>Tagset 
Tag acc. 
MaltParser 
YaraParser 
TurboParser 
LAS 
UAS 
LAS 
UAS 
LAS 
UAS 
POS tagger 
98.71% 85.34% 88.80% 85.90% 89.43% 87.28% 90.59% 
POSe tagger 97.33% 85.74% 89.24% 86.35% 89.86% 87.73% 91.02% 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_5" validated="true"><head>Table 5 : Dependency Parsing results on the test data with different automatic tagsets.</head><label>5</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>use three different off-the-shelf parsers: 1) Malt 
parser v1.8 (Nivre et al., 2007), 2) Yara parser 
v0.2 (Rasooli and Tetreault, 2015), and 3) Turbo 
parser v2.2 (Martins et al., 2013). We train Malt 
with Covington non-projective algorithm </table></figure>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgement</head><p>We thank Computer Research Center of Is-lamic Sciences (CRCIS) for supporting us on corpus annotation. We thank Parinaz Dadras, Saeedeh Ghadrdoost-Nakhchi, Manouchehr Kouhestani, Mostafa Mahdavi, Azadeh Mirzaei, Neda Poormorteza-Khameneh, Morteza Rezaei-Sharifabadi and Salimeh Zamani for helping us on annotation and the three anonymous reviewers for their helpful comments.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Modern Persian: a coursebook</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Simin Abrahams. Routledge</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A probabilistic approach to persian ezafe recognition</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Habibollah</forename><surname>Asghari</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jalal</forename><surname>Maleki</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Heshaam</forename><surname>Faili</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 14th Conference of the European Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the 14th Conference of the European Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics<address><addrLine>Gothenburg, Sweden</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014-04" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="138" to="142" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Association for Computational Linguistics</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Maltoptimizer: A system for maltparser optimization</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Miguel</forename><surname>Ballesteros</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Joakim</forename><surname>Nivre</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
				<title level="m">Proceedings of the Eighth International Conference on Language Resources and Evaluation</title>
		<meeting>the Eighth International Conference on Language Resources and Evaluation<address><addrLine>Istanbul, Turkey, May</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2757" to="2763" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>European Language Resources Association (ELRA</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Lessons from building a Persian written corpus: Peykare. Language Resources and Evaluation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mahmood</forename><surname>Bijankhan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Javad</forename><surname>Sheykhzadegan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mohammad</forename><surname>Bahrani</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Masood</forename><surname>Ghayoomi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">45</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="143" to="164" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Parsing discontinuous constituents in dependency grammar</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Michael A Covington</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Computational Linguistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">16</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="234" to="236" />
			<date type="published" when="1990" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Word clustering for Persian statistical parsing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Masood</forename><surname>Ghayoomi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Advances in Natural Language Processing</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="126" to="137" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Non-projecting nouns and the ezafe: Construction in Persian</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jila</forename><surname>Ghomeshi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Natural Language &amp; Linguistic Theory</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="729" to="788" />
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Introduction to Arabic natural language processing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Nizar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Habash</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Synthesis Lectures on Human Language Technologies</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="187" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">An empirical study on the effect of morphological and lexical features in Persian dependency parsing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mojtaba</forename><surname>Khallash</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ali</forename><surname>Hadian</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Behrouz</forename><surname>Minaeibidgoli</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Fourth Workshop on Statistical Parsing of MorphologicallyRich Languages</title>
		<meeting>the Fourth Workshop on Statistical Parsing of MorphologicallyRich Languages<address><addrLine>Seattle, Washington, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2013-10" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="97" to="107" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Developing a Persian chunker using a hybrid approach</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tara</forename><surname>Soheila Kian</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mehrnoush</forename><surname>Akhavan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Shamsfard</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">International Multiconference on Computer Science and Information Technology, 2009. IMCSIT&apos;09</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>IEEE</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="227" to="234" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Practical very large scale CRFs</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Thomas</forename><surname>Lavergne</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Olivier</forename><surname>Cappé</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">François</forename><surname>Yvon</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings the 48th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL)</title>
		<meeting>the 48th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2010-07" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="504" to="513" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Turning on the turbo: Fast third-order non-projective turbo parsers</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>André</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Miguel</forename><surname>Martins</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Noah</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Almeida</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Smith</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="617" to="622" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Maltparser: A language-independent system for data-driven dependency parsing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Joakim</forename><surname>Nivre</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Johan</forename><surname>Hall</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jens</forename><surname>Nilsson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Atanas</forename><surname>Chanev</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gülsen</forename><surname>Eryigit</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sandra</forename><surname>Kübler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Svetoslav</forename><surname>Marinov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Erwin</forename><surname>Marsi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Natural Language Engineering</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">02</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="95" to="135" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A hybrid algorithm for recognizing the position of ezafe constructions in Persian texts</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Samira</forename><surname>Noferesti</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mehrnoush</forename><surname>Shamsfard</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">International Journal of Interactive Multimedia and Artificial Intelligence</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="17" to="25" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
