<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T10:18+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Corpus Pattern for Semantic Processing</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
				<availability status="unknown"><p>Copyright Association for Computational Linguistics</p>
				</availability>
				<date>July 26-31, 2015. 2015</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Patrick</forename><surname>Hanks</surname></persName>
							<email>patrick.w.hanks@gmail.com</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Elisabetta</forename><surname>Jezek</surname></persName>
							<email>jezek@unipv.it</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Daisuke</forename><surname>Kawahara</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Octavian</forename><surname>Popescu</surname></persName>
							<email>o.popescu@us.ibm.com</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">University of Wolverhampton</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="GB">UK</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">University of Pavia</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">Kyoto University</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit3">IBM Research</orgName>
								<address>
									<region>IT, JP, US</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="department">Introduction</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Corpus Pattern for Semantic Processing</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the Tutorials of the 53rd Annual Meeting of the ACL and the 7th IJCNLP</title>
						<meeting>the Tutorials of the 53rd Annual Meeting of the ACL and the 7th IJCNLP <address><addrLine>Beijing, China</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="12" to="15"/>
							<date type="published">July 26-31, 2015. 2015</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract/>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>This tutorial presents a corpus-driven, pat- tern-based empirical approach to meaning representation and computation. Patterns in text are everywhere, but techniques for iden- tifying and processing them are still rudi- mentary. Patterns are not merely syntactic but syntagmatic: each pattern identifies a lexico-semantic clause structure consisting of a predicator (verb or predicative adjective) together with open-ended lexical sets of col- locates in different clause roles (subject, ob- ject, prepositional argument, etc.). If NLP is to make progress in identifying and pro- cessing text meaning, pattern recognition and collocational analysis will play an essential role, because:</p><p>Many, if not most meanings, require the presence of more than one word for their normal realization. ... Pat- terns of co-selection among words, which are much stronger than any description has yet allowed for, have a direct connection with mean- ing. (J. M. <ref type="bibr">Sinclair, 1998</ref>).</p><p>The tutorial presents methods for building patterns on the basis of corpus evidence, us- ing machine learning methods. It discusses some possible applications of pattern inven- tories and invites discussion of others. It is intended for an audience with heterogeneous competences but with a common interest in corpus linguistics and computational models for meaning-related tasks in NLP. We report on the methodologies for building resources for semantic processing and their contribu- tion to NLP tasks. The goal is to provide the audience with an operative understanding of the methodology used to acquire corpus pat- terns and of their utility in NLP applications.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Overview</head><p>Natural language sentences make use of lex- ical, syntactic, semantic and pragmatic in- formation in order to fulfill their role of con- veying meaning. Previous research on com- puting the meaning of linguistic expressions -from approaches which consider overt dis- tributional information on words to deep se- mantic ones, based on first order and lambda calculus representations -has highlighted two major issues: (1) the appropriate level of formalization for meaning representation cannot be founded only on premises derived from prior experience, (2) the lack of large- scale annotated corpora which combine dif- ferent levels of semantic annotation hinders the development of machine-learning appli- cations. In particular, in the framework of big data analytics for semantically pro- cessing large corpora, these two issues must be addressed.</p><p>The regular structure of normal clauses can be used as a basis in order to learn the rules that lie behind recurrent meaningful con- structs in natural language. It has been shown <ref type="bibr">(Hanks&amp;Pustejovsky 2004</ref><ref type="bibr">, Pustejovsky&amp;Jezek 2008</ref><ref type="bibr">, Popescu&amp;Magnini 2007</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b12">, Popescu 2013</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b7">, Kawahara et al. 2014</ref> that it is possible to identify and to learn cor- pus patterns that encode the information that accounts for the senses of the verb and its arguments in the context. These patterns link the syntactic structure of clauses and the se- mantic types of argument fillers via the role that each of these play in the disambiguation of the clause as a whole. With regard to ir- regularities, there are quite a few clauses in a corpus where these patterns do not seem to match the text, because of the apparent in- compatibility between the actual and the ex- pected semantic types of the arguments (Jez- ek&amp;Hanks 2010, Hanks 2012). However, it is possible to build statistical models that simultaneously generate both the regular and the innovative representation of a clause. Available solutions developed up to now range from supervised to totally unsuper- vised approaches. The patterns obtained en- code the necessary information for handling the meaning of each word individually as well as that of the clause as a whole. As such they are instrumental in building better lan- guage models <ref type="bibr">(Dligach&amp;Palmer 2011</ref>). In the contexts matched by such patterns, any word is unequivocally disambiguated. The semantic types used in pattern representation play a discriminative role, therefore the pat- terns are sense discriminative and as such they can be used in word sense disambigua- tion and other meaning-related tasks (see among others <ref type="bibr">, Cumby&amp;Roth 2003</ref><ref type="bibr">, Popescu&amp;Magnini 2007</ref><ref type="bibr">, Pustejovsky et al. 2010</ref>). Also, the meaning of a pattern as a whole is expressed as a set of basic implicatures. The implicatures are instrumental in textual en- tailment, semantic similarity and paraphras- ing generation ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Popescu et al. 2011</ref><ref type="bibr">, Nicolae&amp;Popescu 2013</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b17">, Vo et. al 2014</ref>. Depend- ing on the proposed application, the implica- tures associated with a pattern may be ex- pressed in any of a wide variety of other ways, e.g. as a translation into another lan- guage or as a synonym set. The automatic aligning of the set of patterns of two lan- guages via their shared semantic types is used in meaning-preserving translation tasks <ref type="bibr">(Popescu&amp;Jezek 2013</ref>).</p><p>The relatively recent research on corpus data has shown that intermediate text representa- tions (ITRs), built in a bottom-up manner from corpus examples towards a complex representation of clauses, play an important role in dealing with the meaning disambigua- tion problem. ITRs offer an important degree of freedom in finding the right cut between various levels of semantic information. Large-scale corpus-driven lexical analysis leads to two apparently contradictory con- clusions. On the one hand, the regularities of word use (valencies, collocations) are more regular than what most pre-corpus linguists would have predicted. On the other hand, the irregularities are more irregular. In particu- lar, verb usage in language displays a con- tinuous blend between regular constructs with clearly distinct senses and new and in- novative usages. The Theory of Norms and Exploitations (Hanks 2013) maintains that language exhibits mainly a rule-governed behavior, but argues that there is not just one monolithic system of rules. Instead, there are two interactive sets of rules: 1) Norms: a set of rules for using words normally and idio- matically: these are the rules of grammar; they account for 70%-90% of all utterances - depending on the type of the verb, the topic, and the domain. However, they do not ac- count for linguistic creativity, nor for chang- es in word meaning; 2) Exploitation rules, which account for creativity and innovative usage (about 10%-30% of corpus examples). Exploitation rules also account for phenom- ena such as meaning shift. Pattern Dictionar- ies are resources based on Corpus Pattern Analysis (CPA). They contains examples for each category for a large number of English and Italian verbs and are available at http://pdev.org.uk/ (Hanks 2004), and at http://tpas.fbk.eu/resource ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Jezek et al. 2014</ref>).</p><p>The corpus-pattern methodology is designed to offer a viable solution to meaning repre- sentation. The techniques we present are widely applicable in NLP and they deal effi- ciently with data sparseness and open do- main expression of semantic relationships.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>The tutorial is divided into three main parts, which are strongly interconnected: (A) Building Corpus Patterns via the Theory of Norms and Exploitations, (B) Inducing Se- mantic Types and Semantic Task Oriented Ontologies, and (C) Machine Learning and</head><p>Applications of Corpus Patterns.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Outline</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Corpus, Language Usage and Computa- ble Semantic Properties of Verb Phrases section</head><p>Basic Computational Semantic Con- cepts His current work is focused on automatic induction of semantic frames and semantic parsing, verb polysemic classes, verb sense disambiguation, and automatic induction of semantic frames.</p><p>Octavian Popescu is a researcher at IBM T. J. Watson Research Center, working on computational semantics with focus on cor- pus patterns for question answering, textual entailment and paraphrasing. He taught vari- ous NLP graduate courses in computational semantics at Trento University (IT), Colora- do University at Boulder (US) and Universi- ty of Bucharest (RO).</p></div>		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">On Kernel Methods for Relational Learning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Cumby</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Roth</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of ICML 2003</title>
		<meeting>ICML 2003<address><addrLine>Washington</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Good Seed Makes a Good Crop: Accelerating Active Learning Using Language Modeling</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Dligach</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Palmer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of ACL</title>
		<meeting>ACL<address><addrLine>Oregon</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Corpus Pattern Analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Hanks</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the XI Euralex International Congress</title>
		<editor>Williams G. and S. Vessier</editor>
		<meeting>the XI Euralex International Congress<address><addrLine>Lorient, Université de Bretagne-Sud</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Common Sense About Word Meaning:Sense in Context</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Hanks</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Pustejovsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the TSD</title>
		<meeting>the TSD</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">3206</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">How People use words to make Meanings. Semantic Types meet Valencies</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Hanks</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Input, Process and Product: Developments in Teaching and Language Corpora</title>
		<editor>A. Bulton and J. Thomas</editor>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Masaryk University Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Lexical Analysis: Norms and Exploitations</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Hanks</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<publisher>MITPress</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">T-PAS; A resource of Typed Predicate Argument Structures for linguistic analysis and semantic processing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Jezek</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Hanks</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">;</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Jezek</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Magnini</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Feltracco</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Bianchini</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Popescu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of LREC</title>
		<meeting>LREC<address><addrLine>Reykjavik</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="7" to="22" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>What lexical sets tell us about conceptual categories</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Inducing Example-based Semantic Frames from a Massive Amount of Verb Uses</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Kawahara</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Pederson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Popescu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Palmer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the EACL</title>
		<meeting>the EACL<address><addrLine>Gothenburg</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Determining is-a relationships for Textual Entailment</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Niculae</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Popescu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Prceedings of JSSP</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Trento</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Sense Discriminative Patterns for Word Sense Disambiguation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Popescu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Magnini</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of Semantic Content Acquisition and Representation</title>
		<meeting>Semantic Content Acquisition and Representation<address><addrLine>NODALIDA, Tartu</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Magnini Journal Proceedings of the IJCAI Workshop Learning by Reasoning and its Applications in Intelligent Question-Answering</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Popescu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Cabrio</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<pubPlace>Barcelona</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Pattern Based Translation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Popescu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Jezek</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of Tralogy-II</title>
		<meeting>Tralogy-II<address><addrLine>Paris</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Learning Corpus Pattern with Finite State Automata</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Popescu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of IWSC</title>
		<meeting>IWSC<address><addrLine>Berlin</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Mapping CPA onto Ontonotes Senses</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Popescu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Hanks</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Palmer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of LREC</title>
		<meeting>LREC<address><addrLine>Reykjavik</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Sense in Context</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Pustejovsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Hanks</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Rumshisky</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of COLING</title>
		<meeting>COLING<address><addrLine>Geneva</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Semantic Coercion in Language: Beyond Distributional Analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Pustejovsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Jezek</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Italian Journal of Linguistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="181" to="214" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Lexical Item</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Sinclair</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Contrastive Lexical Semantics. Benjamins</title>
		<editor>E. WEigand</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">FBK-TR: SVM for Semantic Relatedness and Corpus Patterns for RTE</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Vo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Popescu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Caselli</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings SemEval</title>
		<meeting>SemEval<address><addrLine>Dublin</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
