<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T10:12+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">End-to-end Argument Generation System in Debating</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date>July 26-31, 2015. c 2015</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Misa</forename><surname>Sato</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Hitachi Ltd. Research</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Development Group 1-280, Higashi-koigakubo, Kokubunji-shi</addrLine>
									<postCode>185-8601</postCode>
									<settlement>Tokyo</settlement>
									<country key="JP">Japan</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kohsuke</forename><surname>Yanai</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Hitachi Ltd. Research</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Development Group 1-280, Higashi-koigakubo, Kokubunji-shi</addrLine>
									<postCode>185-8601</postCode>
									<settlement>Tokyo</settlement>
									<country key="JP">Japan</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Toshihiko</forename><surname>Yanase</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Hitachi Ltd. Research</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Development Group 1-280, Higashi-koigakubo, Kokubunji-shi</addrLine>
									<postCode>185-8601</postCode>
									<settlement>Tokyo</settlement>
									<country key="JP">Japan</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Toshinori</forename><surname>Miyoshi</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Hitachi Ltd. Research</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Development Group 1-280, Higashi-koigakubo, Kokubunji-shi</addrLine>
									<postCode>185-8601</postCode>
									<settlement>Tokyo</settlement>
									<country key="JP">Japan</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Makoto</forename><surname>Iwayama</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Hitachi Ltd. Research</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Development Group 1-280, Higashi-koigakubo, Kokubunji-shi</addrLine>
									<postCode>185-8601</postCode>
									<settlement>Tokyo</settlement>
									<country key="JP">Japan</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Qinghua</forename><surname>Sun</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Hitachi Ltd. Research</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Development Group 1-280, Higashi-koigakubo, Kokubunji-shi</addrLine>
									<postCode>185-8601</postCode>
									<settlement>Tokyo</settlement>
									<country key="JP">Japan</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yoshiki</forename><surname>Niwa</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Hitachi Ltd. Research</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Development Group 1-280, Higashi-koigakubo, Kokubunji-shi</addrLine>
									<postCode>185-8601</postCode>
									<settlement>Tokyo</settlement>
									<country key="JP">Japan</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">End-to-end Argument Generation System in Debating</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of ACL-IJCNLP 2015 System Demonstrations</title>
						<meeting>ACL-IJCNLP 2015 System Demonstrations <address><addrLine>Beijing, China</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="109" to="114"/>
							<date type="published">July 26-31, 2015. c 2015</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>We introduce an argument generation system in debating, one that is based on sentence retrieval. Users can specify a motion such as This house should ban gambling, and a stance on whether the system agrees or disagrees with the motion. Then the system outputs three argument paragraphs based on &quot;values&quot; automatically decided by the system. The &quot;value&quot; indicates a topic that is considered as a positive or negative for people or communities, such as health and education. Each paragraph is related to one value and composed of about seven sentences. An evaluation over 50 motions from a popular debate web-site showed that the generated arguments are understandable in 64 paragraphs out of 150.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>This paper describes our end-to-end argument generation system, developed to participate in En- glish debating games as an AI debater. When users give a "motion" like This house should ban gam- bling and a "stance" on whether the system should agree or disagree with the motion, the system gen- erates argument scripts in the first constructive round of a debate.</p><p>Among NLP communities, interest is growing in argumentation, such as argumentation mining and claim detection ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Levy et al., 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Mizuno et al., 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Park et al., 2014</ref>). However, argument generation is still as hard a task as other text gener- ation tasks; no standard methods or systems exist, as far as we know.</p><p>We assume that argument generation systems are helpful in a variety of decision-making situ- ations such as business, law, politics and medical care. This is because people usually investigate existing arguments on the Internet, newspapers, or research papers before reaching conclusions. In this research, we focus on debating game style because there is similarity in argument construc- tion between debating games and actual decision- making.</p><p>The difficulty in argument generation is that ar- gument scripts have to be persuasive. We ex- plain this need by comparing argument generation with multi-document summarization. In the two tasks, one practical approach is combining partial texts retrieved from multiple documents. Gener- ated scripts in both tasks should be natural and have sufficient content. Because the summariza- tion task is to generate summary scripts of multi- ple documents, the essential basis of its evaluation is coverage, that is, how much content in the origi- nal documents is included in the generated scripts. However, as the role of argument scripts is to per- suade people, persuasiveness is more important than coverage.</p><p>We believe that the following three points are required to generate persuasive argument scripts:</p><p>1. Consistency with a given stance 2. Cause and effect relationships 3. Relevance to people's values For example, when debaters focus on an agree stance with a motion of This house should ban gambling, one persuasive argument would discuss the negative effects of gambling. To reach a dis- cussion about the negative effects under this con- dition, we need to consider the three points.</p><p>1. Consistency means that the stance of argu- ment scripts must be equal to the given stance and consistent in the overall arguments. For example, because the gambling motion implies the claim that gambling is negative, the generated argument should include only negative aspects of gambling.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>2.</head><p>Causality makes argumentation persua- sive. To capture causality, we focus on pro- moting/suppressing relationships. Hashimoto et 3. Values There are topics obviously considered to be positive or negative and highly relevant to people's values. For instance, health, education and natural environment are considered to be pos- itive values, while crime, pollution and high cost are considered to be negative. It is possible to gen- erate scripts about negative effects by collecting partial texts describing negative values linked to gambling, such as crime.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Overview</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">Demo Description</head><p>Visitors will have the opportunity to select a mo- tion and a stance and to run the system to generate argument scripts automatically.</p><p>Each argument script generated by the system consists of three topics corresponding to values, such as health, education and revenue. This ap- proach comes from our observations that persua- sive arguments would be related to multiple val- ues. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref> shows the interface of the system and an example of generated argument scripts. First, users give text scripts about the "motion" and se- lect the "stance" whether agree or disagree. In the figure, the given motion is This house should ban smoking in public spaces, and the given stance is an agree side. When users click the start but- ton, the system begins processing. Users can see how many sentences or documents are processed and how many sentences belong to each value in the graphs in the upper right corner. Finally, the system provides three generated paragraphs with their value titles such as poverty, pollution, and disease while the generated argument scripts are read aloud by our text-to-speech system. <ref type="figure">Figure 2</ref> shows the overview of the system.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">System Overview</head><p>As discussed above, the key of constructing ar- guments is to find positive/negative effects of a tar- get in the motion. In this paper, we call the target "a motion keyphrase".</p><p>Positive/negative effects appear in the form of affect relationships like something affects some- thing. Main elements of arguments are sentences that contain affect relationships whose subject is a motion keyphrase and whose object represents a value.</p><p>We have two types of affect predicates: affect+ and affect−. Affect+ means a promoting predi- cate such as create, enhance, expand, improve, in- crease. On the other hand, affect− means a sup- <ref type="figure">Figure 2</ref>: System Overview pressing predicate such as decrease, discourage, eliminate, limit, threaten. The system stored the affect relationships in text data as automatically added annotations described in Section 4.</p><p>Though the system consists of 21 algorithms, we describe four main components in this paper:</p><p>(1) A motion analysis component decides a motion keyphrase and a polarity of arguments to be generated. (2) A value selection component decides mul- tiple values relevant to the given motion by retrieving sentences that contain affect rela- tionships. (3) A sentence retrieval component retrieves sentences relevant to each value from the stored text data. (4) A sentence ordering and rephrasing component combines and arranges the re- trieved sentences to construct natural argu- ment scripts.</p><p>They are processed in a pipeline and some of the algorithms are processed in parallel on a cluster of 10 machines. We describe key functions of the components in Section 3.</p><p>The system uses large text data from Gigaword corpus ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Napoles et al., 2012)</ref> and the annotations to the text data. The annotations are added auto- matically in a preprocessing step. Section 4 de- scribes what kinds of annotations exploited in the system. The text and annotation data are stored us- ing Cassandra 1 , which is an open-source database management system designed for handling large amounts of data across commodity servers. They are indexed into Solr 2 , open source enterprise search platform, that enables full-text search.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3">Evaluation</head><p>We evaluated the generated argument scripts on the basis of subjective evaluations. We used 50 motions from a popular debate web- site Debatabase 3 as inputs to the system. The system outputs three paragraphs per motion, and each paragraph is composed of seven sentences, totaling 150 paragraphs for 50 motions. The para- graphs are rated by authors on a five point scale ranging from 0 to 4. Each evaluator judges 30 paragraphs in 10 motions. The paragraphs that do not include any claims or supporting evidence re- lated to the motion, are given a rating of 0 points. A 1 point rating is given when the argument is un- derstood by the evaluator, despite a number of ir- relevant sentences. If more than four of the seven sentences in the paragraph are relevant to the given motion and consistent to the stance, it is given a 2 point rating. If the evaluator feels it is persuasive, it is given a 3 point rating. When it satisfies the above conditions and is presented as a natural ar- gument, it is given a 4 point rating. <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table 1</ref> shows the results. We found that the ar- gumentations are understandable in 64 paragraphs (= 38+16+10+0) out of 150.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Pipeline Components</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Motion Analysis Component</head><p>In the beginning of processing, the system an- alyzes the given motion text, and extracts a keyphrase, a motion polarity, a predicate, an at- titude, and contexts. A predicate is a phrase which gives positive/negative sign to a keyphrase, and an   attitude is a predicate of this house. <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Table 2</ref> shows results of motion analysis.</p><p>To analyze a motion, the system has 22 rules with their priority. <ref type="table">Table 3</ref> shows a part of the rules. The rules are applied in the order by their priority, until a motion keyphrase is extracted.</p><p>Suppose that the given motion is This house be- lieves that casino is harmful for the city and the given stance is agree(+1) (corresponding to the first line of <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Table 2</ref>). The first rule "K be modify- ed for C" in <ref type="table">Table 3</ref> matches the motion. As harmful is a modifying predicate, casinos is K and the city is C. An attitude of this house is believe. A motion polarity is −1 because of the negative predicate harmful(−1). In the same way, from the second to the fourth rules in <ref type="table">Table 3</ref> can analyze the other three motion examples in <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Table 2</ref>.</p><p>The system calculates an argument polarity by multiplying the sign of the given stance and the motion polarity. The system constructs arguments that discuss the motion keyphrase, in accordance with the argument polarity. For example, if the given stance is agree(+1) and the motion polarity is negative(−1), then the system decides an argu- ment polarity is −1 and constructs arguments that claim "the motion keyphrase is negative(−1)".</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Value Selection Component</head><p>The value selection component decides multiple values relevant to the given motion by using a value dictionary. The value dictionary formulates a set of values that represents what is important in human's life, what is harmful in communities, etc. Each value is regarded as a viewpoint of the generated argument. <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">Table 4</ref> describes an example of the value dic- tionary. As shown in <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">Table 4</ref>, each value (e.g., dis- ease, investment) belongs to a field (e.g., health, economy, respectively), and has three attributes: a value polarity, representative phrases, and context phrases. The value polarity +1(−1) means that the value is something good(bad). The represen- tative phrases are linguistic expressions of the val- ues, and the numbers are their weights calculated by IDF in Gigaword corpus. The context phrases are phrases that are likely to appear in neighbor of the value in text documents. They are used to solve ambiguity of the linguistic expressions. The value dictionary of the current system contains 16 fields and 61 values.</p><p>The procedure of the value selection is below:</p><p>Step 1 Retrieves sentences that contain affect re- lationships between the motion keyphrase and one of representative phrases in the value dictionary. For instance, it retrieves Gam- bling increases the number of crimes.</p><p>Step 2 Calculates a polarity to the keyphrase in each sentence, and filters out the sentences where the polarity is not equivalent to the ar- gument polarity. For instance, the polarity for Gambling increases the number of crimes is −1 by multiplying +1 (increase in the affect dictionary) and −1 (crime in the value dictio- nary), which equals to the argument polarity.</p><p>Step 3 Sums weights of found values and selects the top five values.</p><p>The value dictionary was created manually. First, fields of the dictionary were determined by the authors in reference to the roles of govern- ment agencies, and then value entries related to each field were chosen manually from Debatabase. Second, a rule-based extractor that extracts values discussed in a document was constructed using the dictionary, and the extractor applied to each docu- ment in Debatabase. Third, we manually added new entries to the dictionary. If a value is ex- tracted from a document, we extracted represen- tative/context phrases corresponding to the value from the document. If no value is extracted, we extracted new values that were contained in the document. We continued these steps of classify- ing documents and adding entries to the dictionary like a Bootstrapping method.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3">Sentence Retrieval Component</head><p>This component retrieves sentences relevant to each value from the stored text data. It first retrieves documents using a query com- posed of weighted phrases. The retrieved docu- ments should contain both the motion keyphrase and more than one representative phrases of the decided values. While the motion keyphrases can be replaced with their synonyms or hy- ponyms, their weights are smaller than the orig- inal keyphrases; those of synonyms are 0.75 and those of hyponyms are 0.5. The synonyms and hy- ponyms are acquired by WordNet <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Miller, 1995)</ref>. Because short documents don't usually contains informative scripts, the length of retrieved docu- ments are limited to more than 200 words.</p><p>For example, when the motion keyphrase is gambling, a search query for a health value is (gambling#49.53 OR gaming#22.87) AND (health#27.48 OR disease#36.60 OR addiction#52.39 OR hospital#29.76) AND (length: <ref type="bibr">[200 TO * ]</ref>).</p><p>The real numbers following sharp signs are weights of the former phrases, calculated by mul- tiplying the IDF of the phrase and a synonym or hyponym reduction rate.</p><p>The retrieval step prefers sentences that contain promote/suppress relationships. The polarities of the retrieved sentences must be equal to the argu- ment polarity. The polarity of each sentence is calculated by the product of the signs of related phrases, such as the predicate of the keyphrase, the promote/suppress verb, and the representative value phrase. In the example of gambling ban(−1) decrease(−1) the number of crimes(−1), the po- larity of the sentence is −1.</p><p>The system uses about 10,000,000 newswire documents and retrieves 500 per value in this step.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.4">Sentence Ordering and Rephrasing Component</head><p>This component processes the sentence set of each value separately. The sentence ordering step orders the retrieved sentences in the natural order in debating by the method reported in ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Yanase et al., 2015</ref>). The method employs an assumpsion that a constructive speech item in debating consists of a claim sen- tence and one or more supporting sentences, and that the claim sentence lies in the first position of the paragraph. The assumption is implemented as two machine learning problems: claim sentence selection and supporting sentence ordering. The claim sentence selection problem is formulated as a binary-classification problem where a given sen- tence is a claim or not. In the supporting sentence ordering problem, the method orders the other sen- tences on the basis of connectivity of pairs of sen- tences. This problem is formulated as a ranking problem, similarly to ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Tan et al., 2013)</ref>. Features for machine learning models in both problems are extracted not only from the sentences to be ordered but also from the motion text.</p><p>Finally, the rephrasing step trims or replaces surplus phrases referring to too many details for argument scripts, such as dates and people's names. Several simple rules are used.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Data Preprocessing: Annotations</head><p>The system adds annotations automatically in pre- processing into the stored text data by using dic- tionaries and syntax information by Stanford Core NLP ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Manning et al., 2014</ref>). In the current system, about 250 million annotations are stored. Users can add the annotations manually. A list of main semantic annotations is below: affect: promoting/suppressing relationships. For example, it adds an annotation of "affect+: casino → the number of crimes" into a text casino increases the number of crimes. The affect dictionary, which is manually created, contains 608 positive phrases and 371 negative phrases. modify: phrases which gives positive/negative sign to words governed by them. For example, it adds an annotation of "modify−: environment" into a text harmful environment. The modification dictionary contains 79 positive phrases and 134 negative phrases. believe: relationships which represents attitudes of a subject to its object. For example, it adds an annotation of "believe−: smoking" into a text The government bans smoking in public spaces be- cause of a negative believe phrase ban. The be- lieve dictionary contains 30 positive phrases, 47 negative phrases and 15 neutral phrases.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Error Analysis</head><p>We describe three major problems of the system here: (1) identification errors, (2) polarity errors, (3) motion format limitation.</p><p>(1) Identification errors occur on recognizing a motion keyphrase in text data on sentence re- trieval step. The system can incorrectly retrieve sentences including mentions whose expressions are the same as or similar to the motion keyphrase but different in their meanings. In the screenshot of <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref>, for example, although "smoking" in the motion refers to "tobacco smoking," the first sentence in the pollution paragraph argues about "smoking caused by a fire."</p><p>The identification problem is especially obvi- ous in the case a motion keyphrase forms a com- pound noun. For instance, on the motion of This House should ban cosmetic surgery, it is not clear if surgery in some text is equal to cosmetic surgery or not. The errors would show requirements of more precise word sense disambiguation or coref- erence resolution among multiple documents.</p><p>(2) Polarity errors are not so rare. Regarding the disease paragraph in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref>, the second sentence would contain an argument on the opposite stance in error.</p><p>(3) Motion format limitation is that the system can process only motions in formats which ask people if its motion keyphrase should be banned or permitted. Representative examples of unaccept- able motions are comparison like This house be- lieves that capitalism is better than socialism and questions of an adequate degree like This House should lower the drinking age.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Conclusion</head><p>We described a demonstration of our argument generation system. Our system can generate un- derstandable arguments on a given motion for a given stance. Our next work is to generate coun- terarguments, which argue against the opponents.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: Screenshot and Sample Input &amp; Output Script</figDesc><graphic url="image-1.png" coords="2,94.68,62.69,408.19,254.75" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Motion Analysis Rules. K = motion keyphrase, C = contexts. priority rule predicate instances 1 K be modify-ed for C modify: good(+1), honor(+1), popular(+1), harmful(−1), negative(−1), weak(−1) 2 affect K affect: create(+1), enhance(+1), increase(+1), cut(−1), discourage(−1), eliminate(−1) 3 believe K believe: allow(+1), legalize(+1), permit(+1), support(+1), ban(−1), oppose(−1) 4 K be believe-ed believe: allow(+1), legalize(+1), permit(+1), support(+1), ban(−1), oppose(−</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" validated="false"><head>Table 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Evaluation Results 
Evaluation Score Num of paragraphs 
0: make-no-sense 
86 
1: understandable 
38 
2: +clear 
16 
3: +persuasive 
10 
4: +natural 
0 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" validated="false"><head>Table 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Motion Analysis Results 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" validated="false"><head>Table</head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><table></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3" validated="true"><head>Table 4 : Value Dictionary</head><label>4</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>field 
value 
polarity representative phrases 
context phrases 
economy investment 
+1 
investment:27.8, development aid:48.2 asset, bank, capital, fund, profit, stock, ... 
finance 
cost 
−1 
expense:35.9, expenditure:55.7 
budget, dollar, fuel, lower, price, share, ... 
finance 
income 
+1 
revenue:35.4, wage:39.8 
budget, company, earnings, higher, gain, ... 
health 
disease 
−1 
disease:36.6, complication:40.1 
AIDS, Alzheimer, blood, cancer, death, ... 
safety 
crime 
−1 
crime:31.5, prostitution:56.2 
arrest, gun, jail, kidnapping, victim, ... 
... 
... 
... 
... 
... 

</table></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> Cassandra: http://cassandra.apache.org 2 Apache Solr: http://lucene.apache.org/solr</note>

			<note place="foot" n="3"> Debatabase: http://idebate.org/debatabase</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>We would like to thank Prof. Kentaro Inui from Tohoku University for valuable discussion.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Excitatory or Inhibitory: A New Semantic Orientation Extracts Contradiction and Causality from the Web</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chikara</forename><surname>Hashimoto</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kentaro</forename><surname>Torisawa</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Stijn De</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Saeger</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of EMNLPCoNLL 2012</title>
		<meeting>EMNLPCoNLL 2012</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="619" to="630" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Stanford CoreNLP Natural Language Processing Toolkit</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christopher</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Manning</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mihai</forename><surname>Surdeanu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">John</forename><surname>Bauer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jenny</forename><surname>Finkel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Steven</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Bethard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Mcclosky</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of ACL 2014 System Demonstrations</title>
		<meeting>ACL 2014 System Demonstrations</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="55" to="60" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">WordNet: A Lexical Database for English</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">George</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Miller</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Communications of the ACM</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">38</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="39" to="41" />
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Identifying Appropriate Support for Propositions in Online User Comments</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Joonsuk</forename><surname>Park</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Claire</forename><surname>Cardie</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the First Workshop on Argumentation Mining</title>
		<meeting>the First Workshop on Argumentation Mining</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="29" to="38" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Organizing Information on the Web through Agreement-Conflict Relation Classification</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Junta</forename><surname>Mizuno</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Eric</forename><surname>Nichols</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yotaro</forename><surname>Watanabe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kentaro</forename><surname>Inui</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Eighth Asia Information Retrieval Societies Conference</title>
		<meeting>the Eighth Asia Information Retrieval Societies Conference</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="126" to="137" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Courtney</forename><surname>Napoles</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Matthew</forename><surname>Gormley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Benjamin</forename><surname>Van Durme</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<publisher>Linguistic Data Consortium</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Philadelphia</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Annotated English Gigaword LDC2012T21. Web Download</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Context Dependent Claim Detection</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ran</forename><surname>Levy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yonatan</forename><surname>Bilu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Daniel</forename><surname>Hershcovich</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ehud</forename><surname>Aharoni</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Noam</forename><surname>Slonim</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of COLING 2014: Technical Papers</title>
		<meeting>COLING 2014: Technical Papers</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1489" to="1500" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Learning to order natural language texts</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jiwei</forename><surname>Tan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jianguo</forename><surname>Xiaojunwan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Xiao</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 51st Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the 51st Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="87" to="91" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Learning Sentence Ordering for Opinion Generation of Debate</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Toshihiko</forename><surname>Yanase</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Toshinori</forename><surname>Miyoshi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kohsuke</forename><surname>Yanai</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Misa</forename><surname>Sato</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Makoto</forename><surname>Iwayama</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yoshiki</forename><surname>Niwa</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Paul</forename><surname>Reisert</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kentaro</forename><surname>Inui</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2nd Workshop on Argumentation Mining</title>
		<meeting>the 2nd Workshop on Argumentation Mining</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="94" to="103" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
