<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T11:51+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Rhetoric Map of an Answer to Compound Queries</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date>July 26-31, 2015</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Boris</forename><surname>Galitsky</surname></persName>
							<email>bgalitsky@hotmail.com</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory">Dmitry Ilvovsky National Research Universi-ty Higher School of Eco-nomics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Knowledge Trail Inc. San-Francisco</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Moscow</settlement>
									<country>USA, Russia</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sergey</forename><forename type="middle">O</forename><surname>Kuznetsov</surname></persName>
							<email>skuznetsov@hse.ru</email>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="laboratory">National Research Universi-ty Higher School of Eco-nomics</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Moscow</settlement>
									<country key="RU">Russia</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Rhetoric Map of an Answer to Compound Queries</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 53rd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics and the 7th International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing</title>
						<meeting>the 53rd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics and the 7th International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing <address><addrLine>Beijing, China</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="681" to="686"/>
							<date type="published">July 26-31, 2015</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Given a discourse tree for a text as a candidate answer to a compound query, we propose a rule system for valid and invalid occurrence of the query keywords in this tree. To be a valid answer to a query, its keywords need to occur in a chain of elementary discourse unit of this answer so that these units are fully ordered and connected by nucleus-satellite relations. An answer might be invalid if the que-ries&apos; keywords occur in the answer&apos;s satellite discourse units only. We build the rhetoric map of an answer to prevent it from firing by queries whose keywords occur in non-adjacent areas of the Answer Map. We evaluate the improvement of search relevance by filtering out search results not satisfying the proposed rule system, demonstrating a 4% increase of accuracy with respect to the nearest neighbor learning approach which does not use the discourse tree structure.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Answering compound queries, where its key- words are distributed through text of a candidate answer, is a sophisticated problem requiring deep linguistic analysis. If the query keywords occur in an answer text in a linguistically connected manner, this answer is most likely relevant. This is usually true when all these keywords occur in the same sentence: they should be connected syntactically. For the inter-sentence connections, these keywords need to be connected via anapho- ra, refer to the same entity or sub-entity, or be linked via rhetoric discourse.</p><p>If the query keywords occur in different sen- tences, there should be linguistic cues for some sort of connections between these occurrences. If there is no connection, then different constraints for an object expressed by a query might be ap- plied to different objects in the answer text, therefore, this answer is perhaps irrelevant. There are following possibilities of such connec- tions.</p><p>Anaphora. If two areas of keyword occurrenc- es are connected with anaphoric relation, the an- swer is most likely relevant.</p><p>Communicative actions. If the text contains a dialogue, and some question keywords are in a request and other are in the reply to this request, then these keywords are connected and the an- swer is relevant. To identify such situation, one needs to find a pair of communicative actions and to confirm that this pair is of request-reply kind.</p><p>Rhetoric relations. They indicate the coher- ence structure of a text <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Mann and Thompson, 1988)</ref>. Rhetoric relations for text can be repre- sented by a Discourse tree (DT) which is a la- beled tree. The leaves of this tree correspond to contiguous units for clauses (elementary dis- course units, EDU). Adjacent EDUs as well as higher-level (larger) discourse units are orga- nized in a hierarchy by rhetoric relation (e.g., background, attribution). Anti-symmetric rela- tion takes a pair of EDUs: nuclei, which are core parts of the relation, and satellites, the supportive parts of the rhetoric relation.</p><p>The most important class of connections we focus in this study is rhetoric. Once an answer text is split into EDUs, and rhetoric relations are established between them, it is possible to estab- lish rules for whether query keywords occurring in text are connected by rhetoric relations (and therefore, this answer is likely relevant) or not connected (and this answer is most likely irrele- vant). Hence we use the DT as a base for an An- swer Map of a text: certain sets of nodes in DT correspond to queries so that this text is a valid answer, and certain sets of nodes correspond to an invalid answer. Our definition of the Answer Map follows the methodology of inverse index for search: instead of taking queries and consid- ering all valid answers for it from a set of text, we take a text (answer) and consider the totality of valid and invalid queries consisting of the keywords from this text.</p><p>Usually, the main clause of a compound query includes the main entity and some of its con- straints, and the supplementary clause includes the other constraint. In the most straightforward way, the main clause of a query is mapped into a nucleus and the supplementary clause is mapped into a satellite of RST relation such as elabora- tion. Connection by other RST relation, where a satellite introduces additional constraints for a nucleus, has the same meaning for answer validi- ty. This validity still holds when two EDUs are connected with a symmetric relation such as joint. However, when the images of the main and supplementary clause of the query are satellites of different nucleus, it most likely means that they express constraints for different entities, and therefore constitute an irrelevant answer for this query.</p><p>There is a number of recent studies employing RST features for passage re-ranking under ques- tion answering <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Joty and Moschitti, 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Surdeanu et al., 2014</ref>). In the former study, the feature space of subtrees of parse trees includes the RST relations to improve question answer accuracy. In the latter project, RST features con- tributed to the totality of features learned to re- rank the answers. In ( <ref type="bibr">Galitsky et al., 2014</ref>) rheto- ric structure, in particular, was used to broaden the set of parse trees to enrich the feature space by taking into account overall discourse structure of candidate answers. Statistical learning in these studies demonstrated that rhetoric relation can be leveraged for better search relevance. In the cur- rent study, we formulate the explicit rules for how a query can be mapped into the answer DT and the relevance of this map can be verified.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Example of an Answer Map</head><p>Ex. 1. DT including 6 nodes {e1...e6} is shown in   Ex. 2.</p><p>I went to watch a movie because I had nothing else to do. I en- joyed the movie which was about animals finding food in a de- sert. To feed in a desert envi- ronment, zebras run hundreds of miles in search of sources of water.</p><p>This answer is valid for the following queries (phrases) since their keywords form v-set:</p><p>-enjoy movie watched when nothing else to do -I went to watch a movie about feeding in desert en- vironment -I went to watch a movie about zebras run hundreds of miles 682 -I went to watch a movie about searching sources of water And this text is not a correct answer for the following queries (phrases), since their keywords form i-sets:</p><p>-animals find food in desert when have nothing else to do -I had nothing else except finding food in a desert -I had nothing else to do but run hundreds of miles in search of water -finding food in a desert -a good thing to do</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Definition and Construction Algo- rithm</head><p>Discourse tree includes directed arcs for anti- symmetric rhetoric relation and undirected arcs for symmetric rhetoric relations such as joint, time sequence, and others. For two nodes of DT we define its directed common ancestor as a common ancestor node which is connected with these nodes via directed arcs. The valid set of EDUs which is a result of mapping of a query is closed under common di- rected ancestor relation: it should contain the set of all directed common ancestor for all EDUs. Hence this constraint is applied for antisymmet- ric RST relations; query terms can occur in symmetric EDU nodes in an arbitrary way.</p><p>To construct an Answer Map from DT, firstly, we need to map keywords and phrases of a query into EDUs of an answer. For each noun phrase for a query, we find one or more EDUs which include noun phrases with the same head noun. Not each keyword has to be mapped, but there should be not more than a single EDU each key- word is mapped under a given mapping. For ex- ample, noun phrase from the query family do- ing its taxes is mapped into the EDU in- cluding how individuals and families file their taxes since they have the same head noun tax. If a multiple mapping exists for a query, we need to find at least one valid occur- rence to conclude that this query is a valid one for the given map.</p><p>For a query Q, if its keywords occur in candi- date answer A and the set of EDUs í µí± í µí±í µí±í µí±¢ , then commonAncestorsDT(A)(í µí± í µí±í µí±í µí±¢ )  í µí± í µí±í µí±í µí±¢ .</p><p>For a real-word search system, the enforce- ment of RST rules occurs at indexing time, since RST parsing is rather slow.</p><p>For answer text A, we produce a sequence of texts í µí°´íµí°´í µí± &lt; {A directed common ancestor I} for all pairs of EDU nodes connected with their par- ents by directed arcs. Then the match of the set of keyword occurs with the extended index in the regular manner: there is no element í µí°´íµí°´í µí± for inva- lid mapping í µí± to í µí± í µí±í µí±í µí±¢ .</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Approach Scalability</head><p>In terms of search engineering, enforcing of the condition of the Rhetoric Map of an answer re- quires additional part of the index besides the inverse one. Building this additional index re- quires enumeration of all maximal sequences of keywords from Rhetoric Map for every docu- ment (potential answer A). Once A is determined to be fired by query Q using the regular search index, there should be an entry in Rhetoric Map which is fired by a query formed as a conjunc- tion of terms in Q.</p><p>Since application of Rhetoric Map rules oc- curs via an inverse index, the search time is con- stant with respect to the size of the overall RM index and size of a given document. The index- ing time is significantly higher due to rhetoric parsing, and the size of index is increased ap- proximately by the number of average maximal paths in a DT graph, which is 3-5. Hence alt- hough the performance of search will not signifi- cantly change, the amount of infrastructure ef- forts associated with RM technology is substan- tial.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Evaluation</head><p>We used the TREC evaluation dataset as a list of topics: http://trec.nist.gov/data/qa/. Given a short factoid question for entity, person, organization, event, etc. such as #EVENT Pakistan earth- quakes of October 2005# we ran a web search and automatically (using shallow parsing provided by Stanford NLP) extracted compound sentences from search expressions, such as A massive earthquake struck Pakistan and parts of India and Afghanistan on Saturday morning <ref type="bibr">October 8, 2005</ref>. This was the strongest earthquake in the area during the last hundred years.</p><p>Ten to twenty such queries were derived for a topic. Those portions of text were selected with obvious rhetoric relation between the clauses. We then fed Bing Search Engine API such que- ries and built the Answer Map for each candidate answer. We then ran the Answer Map -based filter. Finally, we manually verify that these fil- tered answers are relevant to the initial questions and to the queries.</p><p>We evaluated improvement of search rele- vance for compound queries by applying the DT rules. These rules provide Boolean decisions for candidate answers, but we compare them with score-based answer re-ranking based on ML of baseline SVM tree kernel <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Moschitti, 2006</ref>), dis- course-based SVM <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Ilvovsky, 2014)</ref> and nearest- neighbor Parse Thicket-based approach ( .</p><p>The approach based on SVM tree kernel takes question-answer pairs (also from TREC dataset) and forms the positive set from the correct pairs and negative set from the incorrect pairs. The tree kernel learning ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Duffy and Collins, 2002</ref>) for the pairs of extended parse trees produces multi- ple parse trees for each sentence, linking them by discourse relations of anaphora, communicative actions, "same entity" relation and rhetoric rela- tions ( <ref type="bibr">Galitsky et al., 2014</ref>).</p><p>In the Nearest Neighbor approach to question -answer classification one takes the same data of parse trees connected by discourse relations and instead of applying SVM learning to pairs, compare these data for question and answer di- rectly, finding the highest similarity.</p><p>To compare the score-based answer re-ranking approaches with the rule-based answer filtering one, we took first 20 Bing answers and classified them as valid (top 10) and invalid (bottom 10) under the former set of approaches and selected up to 10 acceptable (using the original ranking) under the latter approach. Hence the order of these selected set of 10 answers is irrelevant for our evaluation and we measured the percentage of valid answers among them (the focus of eval- uation is search precision, not recall).</p><p>Answer validity was assessed by Amazon Me- chanical Turk. The assessors were asked to choose relevant answers from the randomly sort- ed list of candidate answers. <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table 1</ref> shows the evaluation results. The top two rows show the answer filtering methods and sources of discourse information. Bottom rows show evaluation results for queries with various rhetoric relations between clauses.</p><p>One can observe just a 1.5% improvement by using SVM tree kernel without discourse, further 3.5% improvement by using discourse-enabled SVM tree kernel, and further improvement of 2.8% by using nearest neighbor learning. The latter is still 4% lower than the Answer Map ap- proach, which is the focus of this study. We ob- serve that the baseline search improvement, SVM tree kernel approach has a limited capabil- ity of filtering out irrelevant search results in our evaluation settings. Also, the role of discourse information in improving search results for que- ries with symmetric rhetoric relation between clauses is lower than that of the anti-symmetric relations.</p><p>Code and examples are available at code.google.com/p/relevance-based-on-parse- trees/ (package opennlp.tools.parse_thicket.external_rst).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Discussion and Conclusion</head><p>Overall, our evaluation settings are focused on compound queries where most answers correctly belong to the topic of interest in a query and there is usually sufficient number of keywords to assure this. However, in the selected search do- main irrelevant answers are those based on for- eign entities or mismatched attributes of these entities. Hence augmenting keyword statistics with the structured information of parse trees is not critical to search accuracy improvement. At the same time, discourse information for candi- date answers is essential to properly form and interpret the constraints expressed in queries.</p><p>Although there has been a substantial ad- vancement in document-level RST parsing, in- cluding the rich linguistic features-based of <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Feng and Hirst, 2012)</ref> and powerful parsing models ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Joty et al., 2013)</ref>, document level dis- course analysis has not found a broad range of applications such as search. The most valuable information from DT includes global discourse features and long range structural dependencies between DT constituents. Despite other studies ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Surdeanu et al., 2014</ref>) showed that discourse information is beneficial for search via learning, we believe this is the first study demonstrating how Answer Map affects search directly. To be a valid answer for a ques- tion, its keywords need to occur in adjacent EDU chain of this answer so that these EDUs are fully ordered and connected by nucleus -satellite rela- tions. Note the difference between the proximity in text as a sequence of words and proximity in DT ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Croft et al., 2009</ref>). An answer is expected to be invalid if the questions' keywords occur in the answer's satellite EDUs and not in their nucleus EDUs. The purpose of the rhetoric map of an answer is to prevent it from being fired by ques- tions whose keywords occur in non-adjacent are- as of this map.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Fig 1 (</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Joty and Moschitti, 2014). Text is split into six EDUs: [what's more,]e1 [he be- lieves]e2 [seasonal swings in the auto industry this year aren't occurring at the same time in the past,]e3 [because of production and pricing dif- ferences]e4 [that are curbing the accuracy of seasonal ad- justments]e5 ] [built into the employment data.]e6</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Fig. 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Fig.1. Discourse tree for the Example 1 Horizontal lines indicate text segments; satellites are connected to their nuclei by curved arrows. One can see that this text is a relevant answer to the query Are seasonal swings in the auto industry due to pricing differences? but is an irrelevant answer to the query Are pricing differences built into employment data?</figDesc><graphic url="image-1.png" coords="2,306.13,70.82,148.80,102.54" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Fig. 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Fig. 2. An Answer Map and its areas for valid and invalid answers A valid set of nodes of an Answer Map is defined as the one closed under common ancestor relations in a DT. For example, the i-nodes on the bottom-left of DT in Fig. 2 constitute the invalid set, and the v-nodes on the right of DT constitute the valid set. Ex. 2.</figDesc><graphic url="image-2.png" coords="2,338.00,334.90,154.32,85.65" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" validated="true"><head>Table 1 . Evaluation results</head><label>1</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Filtering method 
Baseline 
Bing search, 
% 

SVM TK 
learning of QA 
pairs (baseline 
improvement), 
% 

SVM TK 
learning for 
the pairs for 
extended parse 
trees, % 

Nearest 
neighbor for 
question -
answer, % 

Answer 
Map, % 

Sources / 
Query 
types 

Source of 
discourse 
information 

-
-
Anaphora, same entity, selected 
discourse relations 

Discourse 
Tree 

Clauses connected with 
elaboration 

68.3 
69.4 
73.9 
74.6 
79.2 

Clauses connected with 
attribution 

67.5 
70.1 
72.7 
75.1 
78.8 

Clauses connected with 
summary 

64.9 
66.3 
70.2 
74.0 
78.0 

Clauses in 
joint/sequence relation 

64.1 
65.2 
68.1 
72.3 
76.3 

Average 
66.2 
67.8 
71.2 
74.0 
78.0 

</table></figure>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Discriminative Reranking of Discourse Parses Using Tree Kernels</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Joty</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Moschitti</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2014 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP)</title>
		<meeting>the 2014 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP)<address><addrLine>Doha, Qatar</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014-10-25" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2049" to="2060" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Text-level discourse parsing with rich linguistic features</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wei</forename><surname>Feng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Hirst</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 50th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL-2012)</title>
		<meeting>the 50th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL-2012)<address><addrLine>Jeju, Korea</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="60" to="68" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Discourse Complements Lexical Semantics for Nonfactoid Answer Reranking</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Jansen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Surdeanu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Clark</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 52nd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL)</title>
		<meeting>the 52nd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A Novel Discriminative Framework for Sentence-Level Discourse Analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Joty</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Carenini</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Ng</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2012</title>
		<meeting>the 2012</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
			</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Natural Language Processing and Computational Natural Language Learning</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Jeju Island</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="904" to="915" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>EMNLP-CoNLL</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Rhetorical Structure Theory: Toward a Functional Theory of Text Organization</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Mann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Thompson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Text</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="243" to="281" />
			<date type="published" when="1988" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Combining Intra-and Multi-sentential Rhetorical Parsing for Document-level Discourse Analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Joty</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Carenini</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Ng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Mehdad</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 51st Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the 51st Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics<address><addrLine>Sofia, Bulgaria</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Matching sets of parse trees for answering multi-sentence questions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Galitsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Ilvovsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">O</forename><surname>Kuznetsov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Strok</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Recent Advances in Natural Language Processing (RANLP)</title>
		<meeting>the Recent Advances in Natural Language Processing (RANLP)<address><addrLine>Shoumen, Bulgaria</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="285" to="294" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Going beyond sentences when applying tree kernels</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Ilvovsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Student Research Workshop ACL</title>
		<meeting>the Student Research Workshop ACL</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="56" to="63" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Parse Thicket Representations for Answering Multisentence questions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Galitsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Usikov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">O</forename><surname>Kuznetsov</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">20th International Conference on Conceptual Structures</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Learning communicative actions of conflicting human agents</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Galitsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">O</forename><surname>Kuznetsov</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Exp. Theor. Artif. Intell</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="277" to="317" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Machine Learning of Syntactic Parse Trees for Search and Classification of Text. Engineering Application of AI</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Galitsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Efficient Convolution Kernels for Dependency and Constituent Syntactic Trees</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Moschitti</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 17th European Conference on Machine Learning</title>
		<meeting>the 17th European Conference on Machine Learning<address><addrLine>Berlin, Germany</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Structural relationships for large-scale learning of answer re-ranking</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Severyn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Moschitti</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">SIGIR</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2012</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="741" to="750" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Fast Support Vector Machines for Convolution Tree Kernels</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Severyn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Moschitti</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Data Mining Knowledge Discovery</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">25</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="325" to="357" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Convolution kernels for natural language</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Collins</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Duffy</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of NIPS</title>
		<meeting>NIPS</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="625" to="632" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Deterministic coreference resolution based on entity-centric, precision-ranked rules</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Chang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Peirsman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Chambers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mihai</forename><surname>Surdeanu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dan</forename><surname>Jurafsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Computational Linguistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">39</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Search Engines-Information Retrieval in Practice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Croft</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Metzler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Strohman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<publisher>Pearson Education. North America</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The Nature of Statistical Learning Theory</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Vapnik</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
			<publisher>Springer-Verlag</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
