<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T12:33+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">NiuParser: A Chinese Syntactic and Semantic Parsing Toolkit</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date>July 26-31, 2015. c 2015</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jingbo</forename><surname>Zhu</surname></persName>
							<email>zhujingbo@mail.neu.edu.cn</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory">Natural Language Processing Lab. Northeastern University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Muhua</forename><surname>Zhu</surname></persName>
							<email>zhumuhua@gmail.com</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory">Natural Language Processing Lab. Northeastern University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Qiang</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
							<email>wangqiangneu@gmail.com</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory">Natural Language Processing Lab. Northeastern University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tong</forename><surname>Xiao</surname></persName>
							<email>xiaotong@mail.neu.edu.cn</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory">Natural Language Processing Lab. Northeastern University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">NiuParser: A Chinese Syntactic and Semantic Parsing Toolkit</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of ACL-IJCNLP 2015 System Demonstrations</title>
						<meeting>ACL-IJCNLP 2015 System Demonstrations <address><addrLine>Beijing, China</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="145" to="150"/>
							<date type="published">July 26-31, 2015. c 2015</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>We present a new toolkit-NiuParser-for Chinese syntactic and semantic analysis. It can handle a wide range of Natural Language Processing (NLP) tasks in Chi-nese, including word segmentation, part-of-speech tagging, named entity recognition , chunking, constituent parsing, dependency parsing, and semantic role labeling. The NiuParser system runs fast and shows state-of-the-art performance on several benchmarks. Moreover, it is very easy to use for both research and industrial purposes. Advanced features include the Software Development Kit (SDK) interfaces and a multi-thread implementation for system speed-up.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Chinese has been one of the most popular world languages for years. Due to its complexity and diverse underlying structures, processing this lan- guage is a challenging issue and has been clearly an important part of Natural Language Processing (NLP). Many tasks are proposed to analyze and understand Chinese, ranging from word segmen- tation to syntactic and/or semantic parsing, which can benefit a wide range of natural language ap- plications. To date, several systems have been developed for Chinese word segmentation, part- of-speech tagging and syntactic parsing (exam- ples include Stanford CoreNLP 1 , FudanNLP 2 , LT- P <ref type="bibr">3</ref> and etc.) though some of them are not opti- mized for Chinese.</p><p>In this paper we present a new toolkit for Chinese syntactic and semantic analysis (cal- l it NiuParser 4 ). Unlike previous systems, the NiuParser toolkit can handle most of Chinese parsing-related tasks, including word segmenta- tion, part-of-speech tagging, named entity recog- nition, chunking, constituent parsing, dependency parsing, and semantic role labeling. To the best of our knowledge we are the first to report that all seven of these functions are supported in a single NLP package.</p><p>All subsystems in NiuParser are based on sta- tistical models and are learned automatically from data. Also, we optimize these systems for Chinese in several ways, including handcrafted rules used in pre/post-processing, heuristics used in various algorithms, and a number of tuned features. The systems are implemented with C++ and run fast. On several benchmarks, we demonstrate state-of- the-art performance in both accuracy/F1 score and speed.</p><p>In addition, NiuParser can be fit into large-scale tasks which are common in both research-oriented experiments and industrial applications. Several useful utilities are distributed with NiuParser, such as the Software Development Kit (SDK) inter- faces and a multi-thread implementation for sys- tem speed-up.</p><p>The rest of the demonstration is organized as follows. Section 2 describes the implementation details of each subsystem, including statistical ap- proaches and some enhancements with handcraft- ed rules and dictionaries. Section 3 represents the ways to use the toolkit. We also show the perfor- mance of the system in Section 4 and finally we conclude the demonstration and point out the fu- ture work of NiuParser in Section 5.  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Word</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">The NiuParser System</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">What is NiuParser</head><p>The NiuParser system is a sentence-level syntactic and semantic parsing toolkit developed by Natu- ral Language Processing Laboratory in Northeast- ern University of China. The system is designed specifically to process the Chinese language. Sub- systems of NiuParser include word segmentation, POS tagging, named entity recognition, shallow syntactic parsing (chunking), constituent parsing, dependency parsing, and constituent parse-based semantic role labeling. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref> shows the archi- tecture of the NiuParser system. As we can see from the figure, subsystems in NiuParser are orga- nized in a pipeline structure. A given sentence is first segmented into a word sequence, each word in which is assigned a POS tag by the POS tag- ging subsystem. Based on the POS tagging result, we can choose to do named entity recognition or syntactic parsing. Finally, shallow semantic struc- tures are generated by semantic role labeling on the base of constituent parsing.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">Statistical Approaches to Subsystems</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2.1">Sequence Labeling</head><p>The subsystems of word segmentation, POS tag- ging, named entity recognition, and chunking in NiuParser are based on statistical sequence label- ing models. Specifically, we adopt linear-chain Conditional Random Fields (CRF) ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Lafferty et al., 2001</ref>) as the method for sequence labeling. Given an input sample X = x 1 , x 2 , . . . , x L and its cor- responding sequence Y = y 1 , y 2 , . . . , y L , Condi- tional Random Fields are defined as follows.</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">Pw(Y |X) = 1 Zw(X) exp(W T Φ(X, Y )))<label>(1)</label></formula><p>where Z w (X) denotes the normalization constant and Φ(X, Y ) are manually defined feature func- tions. In the testing phase, the Viterbi algorithm is applied to find an optimal label sequence or a k-best list for a testing instance.</p><p>With Conditional Random Fields, Chinese word segmentation is regarded as a character- based sequence labeling problem. We adopt the scheme of six tags (B, B2, B3, I, E, O) to translate between a segmented sentence and its correspond- ing label sequence ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Zhao et al., 2005</ref>). Specifical- ly, B, B2, B3 denotes the first, the second, and the third character in a word, respectively. I means that the character is inside in a word, and E means that the character is at the end of a word. Finally, O denotes a single-character word. Features in- clude the characters (and their combinations) in a sliding window.</p><p>As mentioned above, the NiuParser system uti- lizes the pipeline method to integrate all the sub- systems. That is, POS tagging, named enti- ty recognition, and chunking take the output of the preceding subsystem as input. For POS tag- ging, we obtain training data from Penn Chinese Treebank (CTB) ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Xue et al., 2005</ref>), which has 32 POS tags. The named entity recognition subsys- tem takes the guideline of OntoNotes ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Pradhan et al., 2007)</ref>. Named entities annotated in OntoNotes have 18 entity types in total, including person names, organization names, and events, etc. Ta- ble 1 presents a complete list of the entity types in OntoNotes. Chunking uses training data derived from constituent parse trees in CTB. In NiuParser, we consider phrase types including noun phrase (NP), verbal phrase (VP), quantifier phrase (QP), prepositional phrase (PP), adjective phrase (AD- JP), and classifier phrase (CLP), etc. Features for the three subsystems are words (and their combi- nations) in a sliding window. Prefix and suffix of words are also used as features for better system generalization.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2.2">Transition-based Parsing</head><p>Syntactic parsers can be grouped into two cate- gories according to decoding algorithms: dynam- ic programming-based and transition-based. For the purpose of efficiency, we implement the con- stituent and two versions of dependency parsers in the NiuParser system with transition-based meth- ods ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Zhu et al., 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Zhang and Nivre, 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Chen and Manning, 2014</ref>). Specifically, parser- s are variants of shift-reduce parsers, which start from an initial state and reach a final state by per- forming an action in each stage transition. One version of the dependency parsers follows the work in <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Chen and Manning, 2014</ref>), regarding the state transition process as a sequence of clas- sification decisions. In each transition, a best ac- tion is chosen by a Neural Network classifier. The other parses (the constituent parser and the other version of dependency parser) utilize exactly the same framework, where both training and decod- ing phases are formalized as a beam search pro- cess. In the decoding phase, the candidate parse with the highest score in the beam will be picked as the parsing result once the beam search process terminates. In the training phase, a beam search- based global online training method is adopted. The training process iterates through the whole training data by decoding the sentences sequent- ly. On each sentence, parameters will be updated immediately once the gold parse is pruned off the beam. In the NiuParser system, we utilize aver- aged perceptron to learn parameters.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2.3">Two-Stage Classification</head><p>Researchers in semantic role labeling have ex- plored diverse syntactic structures (chunks, con- stituent parses, and dependency parses) as input. The semantic role labeling subsystem in NiuPars- er considers constituent parse trees as input. The subsystem can recognize constituents in a parse tree as arguments with respect to a specified pred- icate (See <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Figure 4)</ref>. Here, semantic role labeling is formalized as a two-stage classification prob- lem. The first stage (called identification) conduct- s a binary classification to decide whether a con- stituent in a parse tree is an argument. After the first stage, a set of constituents is fed to the sec- ond stage (called classification) classifier which is a multi-class classifier, used for assigning each ar- gument an appropriate semantic label.</p><p>The statistical model used in the semantic role labeling subsystem is Maximum Entropy <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Berger et al., 1996)</ref>, which provides classification de- cisions with corresponding probabilities. With such probabilities, the identification stage applies the algorithm of enforcing non-overlapping argu- ments ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Jiang and Ng, 2006</ref>) to maximize the log- probability of the entire labeled parse tree. In the classification stage, the classifier assigns labels to arguments independently.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3">Improvements and Advanced Features</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3.1">Word Segmentation</head><p>In Chinese sentences, words like dates, email addresses, and web page URLs are pervasive but training data for statistical methods is limited in size to cover enough such words. A purely statistical approach often fails to recognize such words once the words do not appear in the training  <ref type="table">, including fictional  NORP  nationalities or religious or political groups  FACILITY  building, airports, highways, etc. ORGANIZATION companies, agencies, etc.  GPE  countries, cities, states  LOCATION  non-GPE, mountain ranges, bodies of water  PRODUCT  vehicles, weapons, foods, etc.  EVENT  named hurricanes, battles, wars, sports events  WORD OF ART titles or books, songs, etc.  LAW  named documents made into laws  LANGUAGE  named language  DATE  absolute or relative dates or periods  TIME  times smaller than a day  PERCENT  percentage *including "%"  MONEY  monetary values, including unit  QUANTITY  measurements, as of weight or distances  ORDINAL</ref> "first", "second" CARDINAL numerals that do not fall under another type <ref type="table">Table 1</ref> data. Fortunately, such words generally have some regular patterns and can be recognized by regular expressions. The NiuParser system provides a regular expression engine to do preprocessing for the CRF-based segmenter.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Post-processing:</head><p>Besides the word types handled in the preprocessing step, a CRF-based segmenter has a low accuracy in recogniz- ing out-of-vocabulary words. The NiuParser system implements a double-array trie for post- processing. Users can add entries (each entry is a string of characters and its corresponding segments) into a dictionary. String of characters in the dictionary will be assured to be segmented according to its corresponding segments.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3.2">Named Entity Recognition</head><p>In academics, named entity recognition often suf- fers from limited training data. In contrast, practi- tioners generally seek to mine a large-vocabulary entity dictionary from the Web, and then use the entity dictionary to recognize entities as a maxi- mum matching problem. This approach, howev- er, fails to resolve ambiguities. The improvement here is to combine dictionary-based methods and statistical methods.</p><p>We first use the forward maximum matching ap- proach to recognize entities in an input sentence by using an entity dictionary. The recognition re- sult is then sent to a CRF-based recognizer. Here each word is assigned a label (start of an entity, in- side an entity, or end of an entity) according to the maximum matching result. The labels are used as additional features in the CRF-based recognizer. This approach is similar to the stacking method.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3.3">System Speed-up</head><p>In addition to fast algorithms (e.g., shift-reduce parsing), NiuParser also supports a multithread- ing mode to make full advantage of computers with more than one CPU or core. In general, the speed can be improved when multiple threads are involved. However, it does not run faster when too many threads are used (e.g., run with more than 8 threads) due to the increased cost of scheduling.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.4">Usage</head><p>The NiuParser system supports three ways to use the functionalities in the toolkit.</p><p>First, users can use the toolkit as an executable file in the command lines. Model files and config- uration of the system are specified in a configura- tion file. Input-output files and the functionality to be used are specified as command line arguments. Second, all the functionalities in NiuParser can be integrated into users' own applications or busi- ness process by using the toolkit's SDK interfaces. The SDK supports both Windows and Linux plat- forms. In contrast to web services, SDK is more suitable to be deployed in the server side.</p><p>Third, a demo web page is provided for users to view the analysis results intuitively. <ref type="bibr">5</ref> All the analysis results are presented graphically.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Experiments</head><p>We ran our system on several benchmarks. Specif- ically, we trained and tested word segmentation, POS tagging, chunking, and constituent parsing on CTB5.1: articles 001-270 and 440-1151 were used for training and articles 271-300 were used for testing. The performance of named entity recog- nition was reported on OntoNotes, where 49,011 sentences were used for training and 1,340 sen- tences were used for testing. For semantic role labeling, we adopted the same data set and split- ting as in <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Xue, 2008)</ref>. Finally, the data set and splitting in ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Zhang and Clark, 2011</ref>) were used to evaluate the performance of dependency parsing.</p><p>All results were reported on a machine with a 800MHz CPU and 4GB memory. See <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">Table 2</ref> for results of acurracy/F1 scores, memory use, mod- el sizes and speed. Note that we evaluated the speed with a single thread and the accuracies were achieved with statistical models only.</p><p>From the results we can see that most of the sub- systems achieve state-of-the-art performance, (the chunking subsystem is an exception, whose accu- racy still have some room left for further improve- ments.). In addition, the memory use of dependen- cy parsing is extremely heavy. We will optimize the implementation of dependency parsing in our future work.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Conclusions and Future Work</head><p>We have presented the NiuParser Chinese syntac- tic and semantic analysis toolkit. It can handle several parsing tasks for Chinese, including word segmentation, part-of-speech tagging, named enti- ty recognition, chunking, constituent parsing, de- pendency parsing, and constituent parser-based se- mantic role labeling. The NiuParser system is fast and shows state-of-the-art performance on sever- al benchmarks. Moreover, it supports several ad- vanced features, such as the Software Develop- ment Kit (SDK) interfaces and the multi-thread implementation for system speed-up.</p><p>In our future work, we will add more function-  alities to NiuParser. First of all, we will integrate a new subsystem which conducts dependency-based semantic role labeling. In addition, we will de- velop a faster constituent parsers by using Recur- rent Neural Network. According to the previous work <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Chen and Manning, 2014</ref>) (and its clone in the NiuParser system), this method reduces the cost of feature extraction and thus shows the ad- vantage in speed. We expect the same approach can be adapted to constituent parsing.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: The system architecture of NiuParser.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Fig- ure 2 and Figure 3 present an example parse of the two parsers, respectively.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>Figure 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2: Example of constituent parsing in NiuParser.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head>Figure 4 :</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Figure 3: Example of dependency parsing in NiuParser. IP</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" validated="false"><head>Table 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Evaluation of NiuParser on various tasks.  † beam search-based global training method. 
 ‡ classification-based method with Neural Networks. characters per second.  *  predicates per second. 

</table></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="4"> http://www.niuparser.com/index.en. html</note>

			<note place="foot" n="5"> http://demo.niuparser.com/index.en. html</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledges</head><p>This work was supported in part by the National Science Foundation of China (Grants 61272376, 61300097, and 61432013).</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A maximum entropy approach to natural language processing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Adam</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Berger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Stephen</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Della Pietra</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Vincent</forename><forename type="middle">J Dealla</forename><surname>Pietra</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Computational Linguics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="39" to="71" />
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A fast and accurate dependency parser using neural networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Danqi</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christopher</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Manning</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of EMNLP</title>
		<meeting>of EMNLP</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="740" to="750" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Semantic role labeling of nombank: a maximum entropy approach</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ping</forename><surname>Zheng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hwee Tou</forename><surname>Jiang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Ng</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of EMNLP</title>
		<meeting>of EMNLP</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="138" to="145" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Conditional random fields: Probabilistic models for segmenting and labeling sequence data</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">John</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Lafferty</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Andrew</forename><surname>Mccallum</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Fernando</forename><forename type="middle">C N</forename><surname>Pereira</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of ICML</title>
		<meeting>of ICML</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Ontonotes: A unified relational semantic representation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Sameer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hovy</forename><surname>Pradhan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mitch</forename><surname>Eduard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Martha</forename><surname>Marcus</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lance</forename><surname>Palmer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ralph</forename><surname>Ramshaw</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Weischedel</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of ICSC</title>
		<meeting>of ICSC</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The penn chinese treebank: Phrase structure annotation of a large corpus</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nianwen</forename><surname>Xue</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Fei</forename><surname>Xia</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chiou</forename><surname>Fu-Dong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Palmer</forename><surname>Martha</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Natural Language Engineering</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="207" to="238" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Labeling chinese predicates with semantic roles</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nianwen</forename><surname>Xue</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Computational Linguistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">32</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="225" to="255" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Syntactic processing using the generalized perceptron and beam search</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yue</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Stephen</forename><surname>Clark</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Computational Linguistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">37</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="105" to="151" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Transitionbased dependency parsing with rich non-local features</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yue</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Joakim</forename><surname>Nivre</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of ACL 2011</title>
		<meeting>of ACL 2011</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="188" to="193" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">An improved chinese word segmentation system with conditional randome fileds</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Hai</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chang-Ning</forename><surname>Zhao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mu</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of SIGHAN</title>
		<meeting>of SIGHAN</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="162" to="165" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A fast and accurate constituent parsing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Muhua</forename><surname>Zhu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yue</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wenliang</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Min</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jingbo</forename><surname>Zhu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of ACL</title>
		<meeting>of ACL</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
