<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T10:36+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Automatic Identification of Age-Appropriate Ratings of Song Lyrics</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
				<availability status="unknown"><p>Copyright Association for Computational Linguistics</p>
				</availability>
				<date>July 26-31, 2015. 2015</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Anggi</forename><surname>Maulidyani</surname></persName>
							<email>anggi.maulidyani@ui.ac.id, maruli@cs.ui.ac.id</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Faculty of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Universitas Indonesia Depok 16424</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>West Java</settlement>
									<country key="ID">Indonesia</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ruli</forename><surname>Manurung</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Faculty of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Universitas Indonesia Depok 16424</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>West Java</settlement>
									<country key="ID">Indonesia</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Automatic Identification of Age-Appropriate Ratings of Song Lyrics</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 53rd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics and the 7th International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing</title>
						<meeting>the 53rd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics and the 7th International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing <address><addrLine>Beijing, China</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="583" to="587"/>
							<date type="published">July 26-31, 2015. 2015</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>This paper presents a novel task, namely the automatic identification of age-appropriate ratings of a musical track, or album, based on its lyrics. Details are provided regarding the construction of a dataset of lyrics from 12,242 tracks across 1,798 albums along with age-appropriate ratings obtained from various web resources , along with results from various text classification experiments. The best accuracy of 71.02% for classifying albums by age groups is achieved by combining vector space model and psycholinguistic features.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Media age-appropriateness can be defined as the suitability of the consumption of a media item, e.g. a song, book, film, videogame, etc., by a child of a given age based on norms that are gen- erally agreed upon within a society. Such norms may include behavioral, sociological, psycholog- ical, and other factors. Whilst we acknowledge that this is largely a subjective judgment, and that there may be wide variance between very small circles that could be considered demographically homogenous, nevertheless, parents, educators, and policymakers may find such judgments valuable in the process of guiding and supervising the media consumption of children.</p><p>This topic is closely related to well-known con- tent rating schemes such as the MPAA film rating system 1 , but whereas such schemes are focused more on whether a film contains adult material or not, age-appropriatness can be thought of as being more nuanced, and takes into consideration more factors such as educational value.</p><p>One popular resource for such ratings is Com- mon Sense Media 2 , a website that provides re- views for various media, with a focus on age ap- propriateness and learning potential for children.</p><p>Whilst acknowledging that such ratings are of interest to many people, the position of this re- search is neutral towards the efficacy and utility of such ratings: we only seek to ask the question of whether it is possible to automate the identifi- cation of these age-appropriateness ratings.</p><p>This work focuses on song lyrics. There are many aspects that can contribute to the age- appropriateness of a song, but we believe that by far the most dominant factor is its lyrics. Thus, the approach that is taken to automating the identifi- cation of age-appropriatness ratings is to treat it as a supervised text classification task: first, a corpus of song lyrics along with age-appropriateness rat- ings is constructed, and subsequently this corpus is used to train a model based on various textual features.</p><p>To give the reader an idea of this task, <ref type="figure">Fig- ures 1 to 3</ref> show a sampler of snippets of lyrics 3 from songs along with their age-appropriate rat- ings according to Common Sense Media. Our goal is to be able to automatically predict the age- appropriate rating given the lyrics of a song in such cases.</p><p>Oh, I'm Sammy the snake And I look like the letter "S"ssss. Oh, yes. I'm all wiggly and curvy, And I look like the letter "S"ssss. I confess.</p><p>(age-appropriate rating: 2)</p><p>Figure 1: Snippet of "Sammy the Snake", from Sesame Street Halloween Collection Do you want to build a snowman? Come on, let's go and play I never see you anymore Come out the door It's like you've gone away (age-appropriate rating: 5) In Section 2 we discuss related work, before presenting our work on constructing the corpus (Section 3) and carrying out text classification ex- periments (Section 4). Finally, we present a tenta- tive summary in Section 5.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Related Work</head><p>To our knowledge, there is no previous work that has attempted what is described in this pa- per. There is some thematically related work, such as automatic filtering of pornographic con- tent ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Polpinij et al., 2006;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Sood et al., 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Xiang et al., 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Su et al., 2004</ref>), but we believe the na- ture of the task is significantly different such that a different approach is required.</p><p>However, text or document classification, the general technique employed in this paper, is a very common task ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Manning et al., 2008)</ref>. In text clas- sification, given a document d, the task is to assign it a class, or label, c, from a fixed, human-defined set of possible classes C = {c 1 , c 2 , . . . , c n }. In or- der to achieve this, a training set of labelled doc- uments d, c is given to a learning algorithm to learn a classifier that maps documents to classes.</p><p>Documents are typically represented as a vec- tor in a high-dimensional space, such as term- document matrices, or results of dimensional- ity reduction techniques such as Latent Semantic Analysis ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Landauer et al., 1998)</ref>, or more recently, using vector representations of words produced by neural networks <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Pennington et al., 2014)</ref>.</p><p>Text classification has many applications, among others spam filtering ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Androutsopoulos et al., 2000</ref>) and sentiment analysis <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Pang and Lee, 2008)</ref>.</p><p>One particular application that could be deemed of relevance with respect to our work is that of readability assessment <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(Pitler and Nenkova, 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Feng et al., 2010)</ref>, i.e. determining the ease with which a written text can be understood by a reader, since age is certainly a dimension along which readability varies. However, our literature re- view of this area suggested that the aspects be- ing considered in readability assessment are suf- ficiently different from the dimensions that seem to be most relevant for media age appropriatness ratings. Following <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Manurung et al. (2008)</ref>, we hy- pothesize that utilizing resources such as the MRC Psycholinguistic Database <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Coltheart, 1981)</ref> could be valuable in determining age appropriateness, in particular various features such as familiarity, im- ageability, age-of-acquisition, and concreteness.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Corpus Construction</head><p>There are three steps in obtaining the data required for our corpus: obtaining album details and age- appropriateness ratings, searching for the track- listing of each album, and obtaining the lyrics for each song. Each step is carried out by querying a different website. To achieve this, a Java applica- tion that utilizes the jsoup library 4 was developed.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Obtaining album details and age-appropriateness ratings</head><p>The Common Sense Media website provides re- views for various music albums. The reviews con- sist of a textual review, the age-appropriate rating for the album, which consists of an integer in the interval <ref type="bibr">[2,</ref><ref type="bibr">17]</ref> or the label 'Not For Kids', and metadata about the album such as title, artist, and genre. Aside from that, there are also other an- notations such as a quality rating (1-5 stars), and specific aspectual ratings such as positive mes- sages, role models, violence, sex, language, con- sumerism, drinking, drugs &amp; smoking. The web- site also allows visitors to contribute user ratings and reviews. In our experiments we only utilize the album metadata and integer indicating the age- appropriate rating.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Tracklist searching</head><p>A tracklist is a list of all the songs, or tracks, con- tained within an album. From the information pre- viously obtained from Common Sense Media, the next step is to obtain the tracklist of each album. For this we query the MusicBrainz website <ref type="bibr">5</ref> , an open music encyclopedia that makes music meta- data available to the public. To obtain the tracklists we employed the advanced query search mode that allows the use of boolean operators. We tried sev- eral combinations of queries involving album ti- tle, singer, and label information, and it turned out that queries consisting of album title and singer produced the highest recall. When MusicBrainz returns multiple results for a given query, we sim- ply select the first result. For special cases where the tracks on an album are performed by vari- ous artists, e.g. a compilation album, or a sound- track album, it is during this stage that we also ex- tract information regarding the track-specific artist name. Finally, we assume that if the album title contains the string 'CD Single' then it only con- tains one track and we skip forward to the next step.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3">Lyrics searching</head><p>For this step, we consulted two websites as the source reference for song lyrics, songlyrics.com and lyricsmode.com. The former is first consulted, and only if it fails to yield any results is the latter consulted. If a track is not found on both websites, we discard it from our data set. Similar to the pre- vious step, we perform a query to obtain results, however during this step the query consists of the song title and singer. Once again, given multiple results we simply choose the first result. In to- tal, we were able to retrieve lyrics from 12,242 songs across 1,798 albums. Once the dataset is complete, classifiers were trained and used to carry out experiment scenarios that vary along several factors. For the class labels, two scenarios are considered: one where each age rating from 2 to 17 and 'Not For Kids' is a sepa- rate class, and another where the data is clustered together based on some conventional developmen- tal age groupings 6 , i.e. toddlers (ages 2 &amp; 3), pre- schoolers (ages 4 &amp; 5), middle-childhood 1 (ages 6 to 8), middle-childhood 2 (ages 9 to 11), young- teens (ages 12 to 14), and teenagers (ages 15 to 17), with an additional category for ages beyond 17 using the 'Not For Kids' labelled data.</p><p>For the instance data, two scenarios are also considered: one where classification is done on a per-track basis, and one on a per-album basis (i.e. where lyrics from all its constituent tracks are con- catenated).</p><p>As for the feature representation, three primary variations are considered:</p><p>Vector Space Model. This is a baseline method where each word appearing in the dataset becomes a feature, and a vector representing an instance consists of the tf.idf values of all words. Addi- tionally, stemming is first performed on the words, and information gain-based attribute selection is applied.</p><p>MRC Psycholinguistic data. For this feature representation, given each distinct word appear- ing in the lyrics of a track (or album), a lookup is performed on the MRC psycholinguistic database, and if appropriate values exist, they are added to the tally for the familiarity, imageability, age-of- acquisition, and concreteness scores. Thus, an in- stance is represented by a vector with four real val- ues. The vectors are normalized with respect to the number of words contributing to the values.</p><p>GloVe vectors. GloVe 7 is a tool that produces vector representations of words trained on very large corpora ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Pennington et al., 2014</ref>). It is sim- ilar to dimensionality reduction approaches such as latent semantic analysis. For this experiment, the 50-dimensional pre-trained vectors trained on Wikipedia and Gigaword corpora were used.</p><p>When combining feature representations, we simply concatenate their vectors.</p><p>Finally, for the classification itself, the Weka toolkit is used. Given the ordinal nature of the class labels, classification is carried out via regres- sion ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Frank et al., 1998</ref>), using the M5P-based classifier ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Wang and Witten, 1997</ref>). The experi- ments were run using 4-fold cross validation.</p><p>For the initial experiment, only the baseline VSM feature representation was used, and the treatment of class labels and instance granularity was varied. The results can be seen in <ref type="table">Table 2</ref>, which shows the average accuracy, i.e. the per- centage of test instances that were correctly la- belled, across 4 folds.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Age group</head><p>Year Per-track 69.77% 58.58% Per-album 70.60% 57.15% <ref type="table">Table 2</ref>: Initial experiment varying class and in- stance granularity</p><p>For the follow-up experiment, we focus on the task of classifying at the per-album level of gran- ularity, as ultimately this is the level at which the original annotations are obtained. For the class labels, both age groups and separate ages are used. The feature representation was varied rang- ing from VSM, VSM + MRC, VSM + GloVe, and VSM + GloVe + MRC. The results can be seen in </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Features</head><p>Age group Year VSM 70.60% 57.15% VSM + MRC 71.02% 56.80% VSM + GloVe 70.58% 57.68% VSM + GloVe + MRC 70.47% 57.85% <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Table 3</ref>: Results varying feature representations</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Discussion &amp; Summary</head><p>From the initial experiment, it appears that distin- guishing tracks at the level of granularity of spe- cific year/age (e.g. "is this song more appropriate for a 4 or 5 year old?") is very difficult, as indi- cated by an accuracy of only 57% to 58%. Bear in mind, however, that this is a seventeen-way clas- sification task. Shifting the level of granularity to that of age groups transforms the task into a more feasible one, with an accuracy around the 70% mark. It is surprising to note that the per-track performance is better than the per-album perfor- mance when tracks are distinguished by specific age/year rather than age groups. We had initially hypothesized that classifying albums would be a more consistent task given the increased context and evidence available. As for the various feature representations, we note that the addition of the MRC psycholinguis- tic features of familiarity, imageability, concrete- ness, and age-of-acquisition does provide a small accuracy increase in certain cases, as evidenced by the highest accuracy of 71.02% when classifying albums by age group using the VSM + MRC fea- tures. The use of the GloVe vectors gives a slight contribution in the case of classifying albums by specific age/year, where the highest accuracy of 57.85% is obtained when combining VSM with both the MRC and GloVe features.</p><p>There are many other features and contexts that can also be utilized. For instance, given the meta- data of artist, album, and genre, additional infor- mation may be extracted from the web, e.g. the artist's biography, general-purpose album reviews, genre tendencies, etc., all of which may contribute to discerning age-appropriateness. Another set of features that can be utilized are readability met- rics, as they are often correlated with the age of the reader.</p><p>To summarize, this paper has introduced a novel task with clear practical applications in the form of automatically identifying age-appropriate ratings of songs and albums based on lyrics. The work reported is still in its very early stages, neverthe- less we believe the findings are of interest to NLP researchers.</p><p>Another question that needs to be addressed is what sort of competence and agreement hu- mans achieve on this task. To that end, we plan to conduct a manual annotation experiment in- volving several human subjects, themselves varied across different age groups, and to measure inter- annotator reliability ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Passonneau et al., 2006</ref>).</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 2 :Figure 3 :</head><label>23</label><figDesc>Figure 2: Snippet of "Do you want to build a snowman?", from Frozen Original Motion Picture Soundtrack You can take everything I have You can break everything I am Like I'm made of glass Like I'm made of paper Go on and try to tear me down I will be rising from the ground Like a skyscraper Like a skyscraper (age-appropriate rating: 9) Figure 3: Snippet of "Skyscraper", from Unbroken-Demi Lovato</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" validated="true"><head>Table 1 provides</head><label>1</label><figDesc>an overview of the number of tracks and albums ob- tained per age rating.</figDesc><table>Group 
Age #Tracks #Albums 

Toddler 
2 
696 
119 
3 
130 
23 

Pre-schooler 
4 
251 
46 
5 
204 
31 

Middle childhood 1 
6 
281 
41 
7 
358 
71 
8 
654 
118 

Middle childhood 2 
9 
237 
50 
10 
1,590 
253 
11 
580 
105 

Young teen 
12 
1,849 
253 
13 
1,767 
242 
14 
1,453 
177 

Teenager 
15 
653 
116 
16 
521 
64 
17 
180 
16 
Adult 
&gt;17 
838 
73 
Total 
12,242 
1,798 

Table 1: Statistics of the dataset 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" validated="false"><head>Table 3 .</head><label>3</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>7 http://nlp.stanford.edu/projects/glove/ 

</table></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> http://www.mpaa.org/film-ratings</note>

			<note place="foot" n="2"> http://www.commonsensemedia.org 3 All works are copyrighted to their respective owners.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="4"> http://www.jsoup.org</note>

			<note place="foot" n="4"> Experimentation Since the constructed data set is imbalanced, we use the SMOTE oversampling technique to overcome this problem (Chawla et al., 2002). This results in a balanced dataset with the same number of samples in each class. 5 http://www.musicbrainz.org</note>

			<note place="foot" n="6"> http://www.cdc.gov/ncbddd/childdevelopment/positiveparenting/</note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">An evaluation of na¨ıvena¨ıve Bayesian anti-spam filtering</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ion</forename><surname>Androutsopoulos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">John</forename><surname>Koutsias</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Konstantinos</forename><surname>Chandrinos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Georgios</forename><surname>Paliouras</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Constantine</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Spyropoulos</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the workshop on Machine Learning in the New Information Age, 11th European Conference on Machine Learning</title>
		<meeting>the workshop on Machine Learning in the New Information Age, 11th European Conference on Machine Learning<address><addrLine>Barcelona, Spain</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="9" to="17" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Smote: Synthetic minority over-sampling technique</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Nitesh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kevin</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Chawla</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lawrence</forename><forename type="middle">O</forename><surname>Bowyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">Philip</forename><surname>Hall</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Kegelmeyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Artif. Int. Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">16</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="321" to="357" />
			<date type="published" when="2002-06" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The MRC psycholinguistic database</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Max</forename><surname>Coltheart</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The Quarterly Journal of Experimental Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">33</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="497" to="505" />
			<date type="published" when="1981" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A comparison of features for automatic readability assessment</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lijun</forename><surname>Feng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Martin</forename><surname>Jansche</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Matt</forename><surname>Huenerfauth</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Noémie</forename><surname>Elhadad</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 23rd International Conference on Computational Linguistics: Posters, COLING &apos;10</title>
		<meeting>the 23rd International Conference on Computational Linguistics: Posters, COLING &apos;10<address><addrLine>Stroudsburg, PA, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="276" to="284" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Using model trees for classification. Machine Learning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Frank</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Inglis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Holmes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">32</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="63" to="76" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Witten</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">An introduction to latent semantic analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Thomas</forename><surname>Landauer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Peter</forename><surname>Foltz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Darrell</forename><surname>Laham</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Discourse Processes</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">25</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="259" to="284" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Introduction to Information Retrieval</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christopher</forename><surname>Manning</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Prabhakar</forename><surname>Raghavan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hinrich</forename><surname>Schutze</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
			<publisher>Cambridge University Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The construction of a pun generator for language skills development</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ruli</forename><surname>Manurung</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Graeme</forename><surname>Ritchie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Helen</forename><surname>Pain</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Annalu</forename><surname>Waller</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dave</forename><forename type="middle">O</forename><surname>Mara</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rolf</forename><surname>Black</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Applied Artificial Intelligence</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="841" to="869" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Opinion mining and sentiment analysis. Foundations and trends in information retrieval</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bo</forename><surname>Pang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lillian</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="135" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Inter-annotator agreement on a multilingual semantic annotation task</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rebecca</forename><surname>Passonneau</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nizar</forename><surname>Habash</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Owen</forename><surname>Rambow</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Fifth International Conference on Language Resources and Evaluation</title>
		<meeting>the Fifth International Conference on Language Resources and Evaluation<address><addrLine>Genoa, Italy</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006-05" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">GloVe: Global vectors for word representation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jeffrey</forename><surname>Pennington</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Richard</forename><surname>Socher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christopher</forename><surname>Manning</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2014 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP)</title>
		<meeting>the 2014 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1532" to="1543" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Association for Computational Linguistics</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Revisiting readability: A unified framework for predicting text quality</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Emily</forename><surname>Pitler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ani</forename><surname>Nenkova</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing, EMNLP &apos;08</title>
		<meeting>the Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing, EMNLP &apos;08<address><addrLine>Stroudsburg, PA, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="186" to="195" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Contentbased text classifiers for pornographic web filtering</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Polpinij</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Chotthanom</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Sibunruang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Chamchong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Puangpronpitag</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Systems, Man and Cybernetics, 2006. SMC &apos;06. IEEE International Conference on</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006-10" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1481" to="1485" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Using crowdsourcing to improve profanity detection</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sara</forename><forename type="middle">Owsley</forename><surname>Sood</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Judd</forename><surname>Antin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Elizabeth F</forename><surname>Churchill</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">AAAI Spring Symposium: Wisdom of the Crowd</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Improving the precision of the keyword-matching pornographic text filtering method using a hybrid model</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gui-Yang</forename><surname>Su</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jian-Hua</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ying-Hua</forename><surname>Ma</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Shenghong</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Zhejiang University Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1106" to="1113" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Induction of model trees for predicting continuous classes</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Witten</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Poster papers of the 9th European Conference on Machine Learning</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Detecting offensive tweets via topical feature discovery over a large scale twitter corpus</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Guang</forename><surname>Xiang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bin</forename><surname>Fan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ling</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jason</forename><surname>Hong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Carolyn</forename><surname>Rose</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 21st ACM International Conference on Information and Knowledge Management, CIKM &apos;12</title>
		<meeting>the 21st ACM International Conference on Information and Knowledge Management, CIKM &apos;12<address><addrLine>New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1980" to="1984" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
