<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T12:34+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Temporal Anchoring of Events for the TimeBank Corpus</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date>August 7-12, 2016</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nils</forename><surname>Reimers</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">Iryna Gurevych † ‡ †Ubiquitous Knowledge Processing Lab (UKP-TUDA</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Technische Universität Darmstadt ‡ Research Training Group AIPHES Technische Universität Darmstadt</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nazanin</forename><surname>Dehghani</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">Iryna Gurevych † ‡ †Ubiquitous Knowledge Processing Lab (UKP-TUDA</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Technische Universität Darmstadt ‡ Research Training Group AIPHES Technische Universität Darmstadt</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Temporal Anchoring of Events for the TimeBank Corpus</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 54th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
						<meeting>the 54th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics <address><addrLine>Berlin, Germany</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="2195" to="2204"/>
							<date type="published">August 7-12, 2016</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Today&apos;s extraction of temporal information for events heavily depends on annotated temporal links. These so called TLINKs capture the relation between pairs of event mentions and time expressions. One problem is that the number of possible TLINKs grows quadratic with the number of event mentions, therefore most annotation studies concentrate on links for mentions in the same or in adjacent sentences. However, as our annotation study shows, this restriction results for 58% of the event mentions in a less precise information when the event took place.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>In automatic text analysis, it is often important to precisely know when an event occurred. A user * Guest researcher from the School of Electrical and Computer Engineering, University of Tehran.</p><p>1 https://www.ukp.tu-darmstadt.de/data /timeline-generation/temporal-anchoring -of-events/ might be interested in retrieving news articles that discuss certain events which happened in a given time period, for example articles discussing car bombings in the 1990s. The user might not only be interested in articles from that time period, but also in more recent articles that cover events from that period. Knowing when an event happened is also essential for time aware summarization, au- tomated timeline generation as well as automatic knowledge base creation. In many cases, time plays a crucial role for facts stored in a knowledge base, for example for the facts when a person was born or died. Also, some facts are only true for a certain time period, like being the president of a country. Event extraction can be used to automat- ically infer many facts for knowledge bases, how- ever, to be useful, it is crucial that the date when the event happened can precisely be extracted.</p><p>The TimeBank Corpus ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Pustejovsky et al., 2003</ref>) is a widely used corpus using the TimeML specifications <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Saurí et al., 2004</ref>) for the anno- tations of event mentions and temporal expres- sions. In order to anchor events in time, the Time- Bank Corpus uses the concept of temporal links (TLINKs) that were introduced by <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Setzer (2001)</ref>. A TLINK states the temporal relation between two events or an event and a time expression. For ex- ample, an event could happen before, simultane- ous, or after a certain expression of time. The TimeBank Corpus served as dataset for the shared tasks TempEval-1, 2 and 3 ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Verhagen et al., 2007;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Verhagen et al., 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b13">UzZaman et al., 2013)</ref>.</p><p>In this paper we describe a new approach to an- chor every event in time. Instead of using tem- poral links between events and temporal expres- sions, we consider the event time as an argument of the event mention. The annotators are asked to write down the date when an event happened in a normalized format for every event mention. The annotation effort is for this reason identical to the number of event mentions, i.e. for a doc- ument with 200 event mentions, the annotators must perform 200 annotations. When annotating the event mentions, the annotators are asked to take the complete document into account. Section 3 presents our annotation scheme, and section 4 gives details about the conducted annotation study.</p><p>The number of possible TLINKs scales quadratic with the number of events and temporal expressions. Some documents of the TimeBank Corpus contain more than 200 events and tem- poral expressions, resulting in more than 20.000 possible TLINKs. Hand-labeling all links is extremely time-consuming and even when using transitive closures and computational support, it is not feasible to annotate all possible TLINKs for a larger set of documents. Therefore, all annotation studies limited the number of TLINKs to annotate. For example, in the original TimeBank Corpus, only links that are salient were annotated. Which TLINKs are salient is fairly vague and results in a comparably low reported inter-annotator agree- ment. Furthermore, around 62% of all events do not have any attached TLINK, i.e. for most of the events in the original TimeBank Corpus, no temporal statement can be made.</p><p>In contrast to the sparse annotation of TLINKs used in the TimeBank Corpus, the TimeBank- Dense Corpus ( ) used a dense annotation and all temporal links for events and time expressions in the same sentence and in di- rectly succeeding sentences were annotated. For a subset of 36 documents with 1729 events and 289 time expressions, they annotated 12,715 temporal links, which is around 6.3 links per event and time expression. Besides the large effort needed for a dense annotation, a major downside is the limita- tion that events and time expressions must be in the same or in adjacent sentences. Our annota- tion study showed that in 58.72% of the cases the most informative temporal expression is more than one sentence apart from the event mention. For around 25% of the events, the most informative temporal expression is even five or more sentences away. Limiting the TLINKs to pairs that are at most one sentence apart poses the risk that impor- tant TLINKs are not annotated and consequently cannot be learned by automated systems.</p><p>A further drawback of TLINKs is that it can be difficult or even impossible to encode tempo- ral information that originates from different parts in the text. Given the sentence: December 30th, 2015 -During New Year's Eve, it is traditionally very busy in the center of Brussels and people gather for the fireworks display. But the upcoming [display] Event was canceled today due to terror alerts.</p><p>For a human it is simple to infer the date for the event display. But it is not possible to encode this knowledge using TLINKs, as the date is not ex- plicitly mentioned in the text.</p><p>To make our annotations comparable to the dense TLINK annotation scheme of the TimeBank-Dense Corpus ( ), we annotated the same documents and compare the results in section 5. For 385 out of 872 events (44.14%), our annotation scheme results in a more precise value on which date an event happened.</p><p>Section 6 presents a baseline system to extract event times. For a subset of events, it achieves an F 1 -score of 49.01% while human agreement for these events is 80.50%.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Previous Annotation Work</head><p>The majority of corpora on events uses sparse temporal links (TLINKs) to enable anchoring of events in time. <ref type="bibr">The original TimeBank (Pustejovsky et al., 2003</ref>) only annotated salient tem- poral relations. The subsequent TempEval com- petitions ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Verhagen et al., 2007;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Verhagen et al., 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b13">UzZaman et al., 2013</ref>) are based on the original TimeBank annotations, but tried to im- prove the coverage and added some further tem- poral links for mentions in the same sentence. The MEANtime corpus <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">(van Erp et al., 2015</ref>) applied a sparse annotation and only temporal links be- tween events and temporal expressions in the same and in succeeding sentences were annotated. The MEANtime corpus distinguishes between main event mentions and subordinated event mentions, and the focus for TLINKs was on main events.</p><p>More dense annotations were applied by Bram- A drawback of the previous annotation works is the limitation that only links between expres- sions in the same or in succeeding sentences are annotated. In case the important temporal expres- sion, that defines when the event occurred, is more than one sentence away, the TLINK will not be an- notated. Consequently, retrieving the information when the event occurred is not possible. Increas- ing this window size would result in a significantly increased annotation effort as the number of links grows quadratic with the number of expressions.</p><p>Our annotation is the first for the TimeBank Corpus that does not try to annotate the quadratic growing number of temporal links. Instead, we consider the event time as an argument of the indi- vidual event mention and it is annotated directly by the annotators. This reduces the annotation effort by 85% in comparison to the TimeBank- Dense Corpus. This allows an annotator to anno- tate significant more documents in the same time. Also, all temporal information, independent where it is mentioned in the document, can be taken into account resulting in a much more precise anchor- ing of events in time, as section 5 shows.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Event Time Annotation Scheme</head><p>The annotation guidelines for the TimeBank Cor- pus ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Saurí et al., 2004</ref>) define an event as a cover term for situations that happen or occur. Events can be punctual or last for a period of time. They also consider as events those predicates describing states or circumstances in which something holds true. For the TimeBank Corpus, the smallest ex- tent of text (usually a single word) that expresses the occurrence of an event is annotated.</p><p>The aspectual type of the annotated events in the TimeBank Corpus can be distinguished into achievement events, accomplishment events, and states <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Pustejovsky, 1991</ref>). An achievement is an event that results into an instantaneous change of some sort. Examples of achievement events are to find, to be born, or to die. Accomplishment events also result into a change of some sort, however, the change spans over a longer time period. Ex- amples are to build something or to walk some- where. States on the other hand do not describe a change of some sort, but that something holds true for some time, for example, being sick or to love someone. The aspectual type of an event does not only depend on the event itself, but also on the context in which the event is expressed.</p><p>Our annotation scheme was created with the goal of being able to create a knowledge base from the extracted events in combination with their event times. Punctual events are a single dot on the time axis while events that last for a pe- riod of time have a begin and an end point. It can be difficult to distinguish between punctual events and events with a short duration. Furthermore, the documents typically do not report precise starting and ending times for events, hence we decided to distinguish between events that happened at a Sin- gle Day and Multi-Day Events that span over mul- tiple days. We used days as the smallest granu- larity for the annotation as none of the annotated articles contained any information on the hour, the minute or the second when the event happened. In case a corpus contains this information, the anno- tation scheme could be extended to include this in- formation as well.</p><p>For Single Day Events, the event time is writ- ten in the format YYYY-MM-DD. For Multi-Day Events, the annotator annotates the begin point and the end point of the event. In case no statement can be made on when an event happened, the event will be annotated with the label not applicable. This applies only to 0.67% of the annotated events in the TimeBank Corpus which is mainly due to annotation errors in the TimeBank Corpus.</p><p>He was sent into space on <ref type="bibr">May 26, 1980</ref>. He spent six days aboard the Salyut 6 spacecraft.</p><p>The first event in this text, sent, will be anno- tated with the event time 1980-05-26. The second event, spent, is a Multi-Day Event and is anno- tated with the event time beginPoint=1980-05-26 and endPoint=1980-06-01.</p><p>In case the exact event time is not stated in the document, the annotators are asked to narrow down the possible event time as precisely as possi- ble. For this purpose, they can annotate the event time with after YYYY-MM-DD and before YYYY- MM-DD.</p><p>In 1996 he was appointed military at- tache at the Hungarian embassy in Washington.</p><p>[...] McBride was part of a seven-member crew aboard the Orbiter Challenger in October 1984</p><p>The event appointed is annotated after 1996-01- 01 before 1996-12-31 as the event must have hap- pened sometime in 1996. The Multi-Day Event part is annotated <ref type="bibr">with beginPoint=after 1984</ref><ref type="bibr">-1001 before 1984</ref><ref type="bibr">-10-31 and endPoint=after 1984</ref><ref type="bibr">- 10-01 before 1984</ref>.</p><p>To speed up the annotation process, annota- tors were allowed to write YYYY-MM-xx to ex- press that something happened sometime within the specified month and YYYY-xx-xx to express that the event happened sometime during the specified year. Annotators were also allowed to annotate events that happened at the Document Creation Time with the label DCT.</p><p>The proposed annotation scheme requires that event mentions are already annotated. For our an- notation study we used the event mentions that were already defined in the TimeBank Corpus. In contrast to the annotation of TLINKs, temporal expressions must not be annotated in the corpus.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Annotation Study</head><p>The annotation study was performed on the same subset of documents as used by the TimeBank- Dense Corpus ( ) with the event mentions that are present in the TempEval-3 dataset ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">UzZaman et al., 2013</ref>). Cassidy et al. se- lected 36 random documents from the TimeBank Corpus ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Pustejovsky et al., 2003</ref>). These 36 doc- uments include a total of 1498 annotated events. This allows to compare our annotations to those of the TimeBank-Dense Corpus (see section 5).</p><p>Each document has been independently anno- tated by two annotators according to the annota- tion scheme introduced above. We used the freely available WebAnno ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Yimam et al., 2013)</ref>. To speed up the annotation process, the existent tem- poral expressions that are defined in the TimeBank Corpus were highlighted. These temporal expres- sions are in principle not required to perform our annotations, but the highlighting of them helps to determine the event time. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 1</ref> depicts a sam- ple annotation made by WebAnno. The two anno- tators were trained on 15 documents distinct from the 36 documents annotated for the study. Dur- ing the training stage, the annotators discussed the decisions they have made with each other.</p><p>After both annotators completed the annotation task, the two annotations were curated by one per- son to derive one final annotation. The curator ex- amined the events where the annotators disagreed and decided on the final annotation. The final an- notation might be a merge of the two provided an- notations. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">Inter-Annotator-Agreement</head><p>We use Krippendorff's α <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Krippendorff, 2004</ref>) with the nominal metric to compute the Inter- Annotator-Agreement (IAA). The nominal metric considers all distinct labels equally distant from one another, i.e. partial agreement is not measured. The annotators must therefore completely agree.</p><p>Using this metric, the Krippendorff's α for the 36 annotated documents is α = 0.617.  reported a Kappa agreement between 0.56 − 0.64 for their annotation of TLINKs. Com- paring these numbers is difficult, as the annota- tion tasks were different. According to <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Landis and Koch (1977)</ref>, these numbers lie on the border of a moderate and a substantial level of agreement.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">Disagreement Analysis</head><p>In 648 out of 1498 annotated events, the anno- tators disagreed on the event time. In 42.3% of the disagreements, the annotators disagreed on whether the event mention is a Single Day Event or a Multi-Day Event. Such disagreement occurs when it is unclear from the text whether the event lasted for one or for several days. For example, an article reported on a meeting and due to a lack of precise temporal information in the document, one annotator assumed that the meeting lasted for one day, the other that it lasted for several days. A different source for the disagreement has been the annotation of states. They can either be anno- tated with the date where the text gives evidence that they hold true, or they can be annotated as a Multi-Day Event that begins before that date and ends after that date.</p><p>Different annotations for Multi-Day Events ac- count for 231 out of the 648 disagreements (35.6%). In this category, the annotators disagreed on the begin point in 110 cases (47.6%), on the end point in 57 cases (24.7%) and on the begin as well as on the end point in 64 cases (27.7%). The Krippendorff's α for all begin point annotations is 0.629 and for all end point annotations it is 0.737.</p><p>A disagreement on Single Day Events was ob- served for 143 event mentions and accounts for 22.1% of the disagreements. The observed agree- ment for Single Day Events is 80.5% or α = 0.799. Most disagreements for Single Day Events were whether the event occurred on the same date as the document was written or if it occurred be- fore the document was written.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3">Measuring Partial Agreement</head><p>One issue of the strict nominal metric is that it does not take partial agreement into account. In several cases, the two annotators agreed in prin- ciple on the event time, but might have labeled it slightly differently. One annotator might have taken more clues from the text into account to nar- row down when an event has happened. One an- notator for example, has annotated an event with the label after 1998-08-01 before 1998-08-31. The second annotator has taken an additional textual clue into account, which was that the event must have happened in the first half of August 1998 and annotated it as after 1998-08-01 before 1998-08- 15. Even though both annotators agree in princi- ple, when using the nominal metric it would be considered as a distinct annotation.</p><p>To measure this effect, we created a relaxed metric to measure mutual exclusivity:</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">d M E (a, b) =</formula><p>1 if a and b are mutual exclusive 0 else</p><p>The metric measures whether two annotations can be satisfied at the same time. Given the event happened on August 5th, 1998, then the two an- notations after 1998-08-01 before 1998-08-31 and after 1998-08-01 before 1998-08-15 would both be satisfied. In contrast, the two annotations after 1998-02-01 and before 1997-12-31 can never be satisfied at the same time and are therefore mutual exclusive.</p><p>Out of the 648 disagreements, 71 annotations were mutually exclusive. Computing the Krippen- dorff's α with the above metric yields a value of α M E = 0.912. <ref type="table">Table 1</ref> gives an overview of the assigned labels. Around 58.21% of the events are either instanta- neous events or their duration is at most one day. 41.12% of the events are Multi-Day Events that take place over multiple days. While for Single Day Events there is a precise date for 55.73% of the events, the fraction is much lower for Multi- Day Events. In this category, only in 19.81% of the cases the begin point is precisely mentioned in the article and only in 15.75% of the cases, the end point is precisely mentioned.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.4">Annotation Statistics</head><p>The most prominent label for Single Day Events is the Document Creation Time (DCT). 48.28% of Single Day Events happened on the day the arti- cle was created, 33.49% of these events happened at least one day before the DCT and 17.43% of the mentions refer to future events. This distribu- tion shows, that the news articles and TV broad- cast transcripts from the TimeBank Corpus mainly report on events that happened on the same day.</p><p>For Multi-Day Events, the distribution looks different. In 76.46% of the cases, the event started in the past, and in 65.10% of the cases, it is still ongoing.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.5">Most Informative Temporal Expression</head><p>Not all temporal expressions in a text are of the same relevance for an event. In fact, in many cases only a single temporal expression is of im- portance, which is the expression stating when the event occurred. Our annotations allow us to de- termine most informative temporal expression for an event. We define the most informative tem- poral expression as the expression that has been used by the annotator to determine the event time. We checked for all annotations whether the event date can be found as a temporal expression in the document and computed the distance to the closest one with a matching value. The distance is mea- sured as the number of sentences. 421 out of 1498 events happened on the Document Creation Time and were excluded from this computation. The Document Creation Time is provided as additional metadata in the TimeBank Corpus, and it is often not explicitly mentioned in the document text. <ref type="figure">Figure 2</ref> shows the distance between the most informative temporal expression and the event mention. In 23.68% of the cases, the time ex- pression is in the same sentence, and in 17.59% of the cases, the time expression is either in the next or in the previous sentence. It follows that in 58.72%, of the cases the most informative time ex- pression cannot be found in the same or in the pre- ceding or succeeding sentence. This is important to note, as previous shared tasks like TempEval- 1,-2, and -3 ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Verhagen et al., 2007;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Verhagen et al., 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b13">UzZaman et al., 2013</ref>) and previous an- notation studies like the TimeBank-Dense Corpus ( ) only considered the relation between event mentions and temporal expressions in the same and in adjacent sentences. However, for the majority of events, the most informative temporal expression is not in the same or in the preceding / succeeding sentence.</p><p>For 7.31% of the annotated events, no matching temporal expression was found in the document. Those were mainly events where the event time was inferred by the annotators from multiple tem- poral expressions in the document. An example is that the year of the event was mentioned in the beginning of the document and the month of the event was mentioned in a later part of the docu- ment.</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">≤ −5 −4 −3 −2 −1 0 1 2 3 4 ≥ 5 MS 0 0.1 0.2 0.3</formula><p>Distance (# sentences)</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Distribution of Distances</head><p>Figure 2: Distribution of distances in sentences between the event mention and the most infor- mative temporal expression. For 58.72% of the event mentions, the most informative time expres- sion is not in the same or in the previous/next sen- tence. For 7.3% of the mentions, the time expres- sion originates from multiple sources (MS).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Comparison of Annotation Schemes</head><p>Depending on the application scenario and the text domain, the use of TLINKs or the proposed an- notation scheme may be advantageous. TLINKs have the capability to capture the temporal order of events, even when temporal expressions are com- pletely absent in a document, which is often the case for novels. The proposed annotation scheme has the advantage that temporal information, inde- pendent where and in which form it is mentioned in the document, can be taken into account. How- ever, the proposed scheme requires that the events can be anchored on a time axis, which is easy for news articles and encyclopedic text but hard for novels and narratives. In this section, we evaluate the application sce- nario of temporal knowledge base population and time-aware information retrieval. For temporal knowledge base population, it is important to de- rive the date for facts and events as precisely as possible <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Surdeanu, 2013)</ref>. Those facts can ei- ther be instantaneous, e.g. a person died, or they can last for a longer time like a military conflict. Similar requirements are given for time-aware in- formation retrieval, where it can be important to know at which point in time something occurred <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Kanhabua and Nørvåg, 2012</ref>).</p><p>We use the TimeBank-Dense Corpus ( ) with its TLINKs annotations and compare those to our event time annotations. The TimeBank-Dense Corpus annotated all TLINKs between Event-Event, Event-Time, and Time- Time pairs in the same sentence and between succeeding sentences as well as all Event-DCT and Time-DCT pairs. Six different link types were defined: BEFORE, AFTER, INCLUDES, IS INCLUDED, SIMULTANOUS, and VAGUE, where VAGUE encodes that the annotators where not able to make a statement on the temporal rela- tion of the pair.</p><p>We studied how well the event time is captured by the dense TLINK annotation. We used transi- tive closure rules as described by  to deduct also TLINKs for pairs that were not annotated. For example, when event 1 hap- pened before event 2 and event 2 happened before date 1 , we can infer that event 1 happened before date 1 . Using this transitivity allows to infer re- lations for pairs that are more than one sentence apart. For all annotated events, we evaluated all TLINKs, including the TLINKs inferred from the transitivity rules, and derived the event time as pre- cisely as possible. We then computed how precise the inferred event times are in comparison to our annotations. Preciseness is measured in the num- ber of days. An event that is annotated with 1998- 02-13 has the preciseness of 1 day. If the inferred event time from the TLINKs is after 1998-02-01 and before 1998-02-15, then the preciseness is 15 days. A more precise anchoring is preferred.</p><p>The TimeBank-Dense Corpus does not have a link type to mark that an event has started or ended at a certain time point. This makes the TLINK annotation impractical for the durative events that span over multiple days. According to our annota- tion study, 41.12% of the events in the TimeBank Corpus last for longer time periods. For these 41.12%, it cannot be inferred from when to when the events lasted.</p><p>In 487 out of the 872 Single Day Events (55.85%), the TLINKs give a result with the same precision as our annotations. For 198 events (22.71%), our annotation is more precise, i.e. the time window where the event might have hap- pened is smaller. For 187 events (21.44%), no event time could be inferred from the TLINKs. This is due to the fact that there was no link to any temporal expression even when transitivity was taken into account.</p><p>For the 487 events where the TLINKs resulted in an event time as precise as our annotation, the vast majority of them were events that happened at the Document Creation Time. As depicted in <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>, 421 events happened at DCT. For those events the precise date can directly be derived from the annotated link between each event men- tion and the DCT. For all other events that did not happen at the Document Creation Time, the TLINKs result for the most cases in a less precise anchoring in time and for around a fifth of these cases in no temporal anchoring at all while we do anchor them.</p><p>We can conclude, that even a dense TLINK an- notation gives suboptimal information on when events have happened, and due to the restriction that TLINKs are only annotated in the same and in adjacent sentences, a lot of relevant temporal information gets lost.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Automated Event Time Extraction</head><p>In this section, we present a baseline system for automatic event time extraction. The system uses temporal relations in which the event is involved and anchors the event to the most precise time. For this purpose, we have defined a two-step process to determine the events' time. Given a set of docu- ments in which the events and time expressions are already annotated, the system first obtains a set of possible times for each of the events. Second, the most precise time is selected or generated for each event.</p><p>For the first step, we use the multi-pass ar- chitecture introduced by  that was trained and evaluated on the TimeBank- Dense Corpus ( ). Cham- bers et al. describe multiple rules and machine learning based classifiers to extract relations be- tween events and temporal expressions. This ar- chitecture extracts temporal relations of the type BEFORE, AFTER, INCLUDES, IS INCLUDED, and SIMULTANOUS. The classifiers are combined into a precision-ranked cascade of sieves. The ar- chitecture presented by Chambers et al. does not produce temporal information that an event has started or ended at a certain time point and can therefore only be used for Single Day Events.</p><p>We use these sieves to add the value of the tem- poral expression and the corresponding relation to a set of possible times for each event. In fact, for each event we generate a set of &lt;relation, time&gt; tuples in which the event is involved.</p><p>Police confirmed Friday that the body found along a highway</p><p>For example, the one sieve adds [IS INCLUDED, F riday 1998−02−13 ] and a second sieve adds <ref type="bibr">[BEFORE, DCT 1998−02−14 ]</ref> to the set of possible event times for the confirmed event.</p><p>Applying the sequence of the sieves will ob- tain all various temporal links for each event.</p><p>In the next step, if the event has a relation of type SIMULTANEOUS, IS INCLUDED or INCLUDES, the system sets the event time to the value of the time expression. If the event has a relation of type BEFORE and/or AFTER, the sys- tem narrows down the event time as precisely as possible. If the sieve determines the relation type as VAGUE, the set of possible event times remains unchanged.</p><p>Algorithm 1 demonstrates how the event time is selected or generated from a set of possible times.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Algorithm 1 Automatic Event Time Extraction</head><p>1: function EVENTTIME(times) 2:</p><p>if times is empty then 3:</p><p>return Applying the proposed method on the TimeBank-Dense Corpus, we obtained some value for the event time for 593 of 872 (68%) Sin- gle Day Events. For 359 events (41%), the system generates the event time with the same precision as our annotations. <ref type="table">Table 2</ref> gives statistics of the automatically obtained event times.</p><p>To evaluate the output of the proposed system, we evaluated how precise the automatically ob- tained event times are in comparison with our an- notations. <ref type="table">Table 3</ref> shows for 41% of events, the proposed system generates the same event time</p><p>Single <ref type="table">Day Events  # Events  %  with precise date  260  29.82%  after + before  16  1.84%  after  99  11.35%  before  218  25%  not available  279</ref> 31.99% <ref type="table">Table 2</ref>: Statistics on the automatically obtained event times for events happened on a single day. The obtained event time can either be precise or the system used before and after to narrow down the event time. For 279 events, the system cannot infer any event time.</p><p>as our annotations. For 21% events our annota- tion is more precise, i.e. the time window where the event might have happened is smaller. For 47 events (5.38%), the system infers an event time that is in conflict with the human annotation, for example a disagreement if an event happened be- fore or after DCT. Considering event times that have the same preciseness as our annotations as true positives, the precision of the proposed sys- tem is 60.54% and the recall is 41.17% for Single Day Events. As presented in section 4, human an- notators agree in 80.50% of the cases on the label for Single Day Events. The less precise and non- inferred event times are mainly due to the fact that temporal expressions, that are more than one sen- tence apart, are not taken into account by the sieve architecture.  <ref type="table">Table 3</ref>: Evaluation results of proposed system in comparison with our annotations.</p><p>In this work we focused on the automated an- choring of Single Day Events and presented a baseline system that relies on the work of . The F 1 -score with 49.01% is in comparison to the human score of 80.50% comparatively low. However, only in 5.38% of the cases, the automatically inferred event time is plain wrong. In the most cases, no event time could be inferred (31.99%) or it was less precise than the human annotation (21.44%).</p><p>Extending the described approach to Multi- Day-Events is not straight forward. The TimeBank-Dense Corpus and consequently the system by Chambers et al. does not include a TLINK type to note that an event has started or ended at a certain date, hence, extracting the begin point and end point for Multi-Day-Events is not possible. A fundamental adaption of the system by Chambers et al. would be required.</p><p>In contrast to Single Day Events, extracting the event time for Multi-Day Events requires more ad- vanced logic. The start date of the event must be before the end date of the event. The relation to events that are included in the Multi-Day Events must be checked to avoid inconsistencies. The de- velopment of an automated system for Multi-Day Events is subject of our ongoing work.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7">Conclusion</head><p>We presented a new annotation scheme for anchor- ing events in time and annotated a subset of the TimeBank Corpus ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Pustejovsky et al., 2003</ref>) using this annotation scheme. The annotation guidelines as well as the annotated corpus are publicly avail- able. <ref type="bibr">2</ref> In the performed annotation study, the Krip- pendorff's α inter-annotator agreement was con- siderably high at α = 0.617. The largest disagree- ment resulted from events in which it was not ex- plicitly mentioned when the event happened. Us- ing a more relaxed measure for Krippendorff's α which only assigns a distance to mutual exclusive annotations, the agreement changed to α M E = 0.912. We can conclude that after little training, annotators are able to perform the annotation with a high agreement.</p><p>The effort for annotating TLINKs on the other hand scales quadratic with the number of events and temporal expressions. This imposes the often used restriction that only temporal links between events and temporal expressions in the same or in succeeding sentences are annotated. Even with this restriction, the annotation effort is quite sig- nificant, as on average 6.3 links per mention must be annotated. As <ref type="figure">Figure 2</ref> depicts, in more than 58.72% of the cases the most informative temporal expression is more than one sentence apart from the event mention. As a consequence, inferring from TLINKs when an event happened is less pre- cise as temporal information that is more than one sentence away can often not be taken into account.</p><p>For the 872 Single Day Events, the correct event time could be inferred from the TLINKs only in 487 cases. For 187 Single Day Events, no event time at all could be inferred, as no temporal ex- pression was within the one sentence window of that event.</p><p>A drawback of the proposed scheme is the lack of temporal ordering of events beyond the small- est unit of granularity, which was in our case one day. The scheme is suitable to note that several events occurred at the same date, but their order on that date cannot be encoded. In case the tem- poral ordering is important for the application sce- nario, the annotation scheme could be extended and TLINKs could be annotated for events that fall on the same date. Another option is to increase the granularity, but this requires that the informa- tion in the documents also allow this more precise anchoring.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>sen et al. (2006), Kolomiyets et al. (2012), Do et al. (2012) and by Cassidy et al. (2014). While Bramsen et al., Kolomiyets et al., and Do et al. only annotated some temporal links, Cassidy et al. annotated all Event-Event, Event-Time, and Time- Time pairs in the same sentence as well as in di- rectly succeeding sentences leading to the densest annotation for the TimeBank Corpus.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: Sample Annotation made with WebAnno. The violet annotations are existing annotations of temporal expressions from the TimeBank Corpus. The span for the beige annotations, the event mentions, come also from the TimeBank Corpus. Our annotators added the value for the event time for those beige annotations.</figDesc><graphic url="image-1.png" coords="4,314.36,62.81,204.10,65.20" type="bitmap" /></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="2"> https://www.ukp.tu-darmstadt.de/data /timeline-generation/temporal-anchoring-of-events/</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgement</head><p>This work has been supported by the German Re-search </p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Inducing Temporal Graphs</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Philip</forename><surname>Bramsen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Pawan</forename><surname>Deshpande</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yoong Keok</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Regina</forename><surname>Barzilay</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2006 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing, EMNLP &apos;06</title>
		<meeting>the 2006 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing, EMNLP &apos;06<address><addrLine>Stroudsburg, PA, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="189" to="198" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">An Annotation Framework for Dense Event Ordering</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Taylor</forename><surname>Cassidy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bill</forename><surname>Mcdowell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nathanael</forename><surname>Chambers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Steven</forename><surname>Bethard</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 52nd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the 52nd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics<address><addrLine>Baltimore, Maryland, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="501" to="506" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Short Papers)</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dense Event Ordering with a Multi-Pass Architecture</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nathanael</forename><surname>Chambers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Taylor</forename><surname>Cassidy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bill</forename><surname>Mcdowell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Steven</forename><surname>Bethard</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Transactions of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="273" to="284" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Joint Inference for Event Timeline Construction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wei</forename><surname>Quang Xuan Do</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dan</forename><surname>Lu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Roth</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2012 Joint Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing and Computational Natural Language Learning</title>
		<meeting>the 2012 Joint Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing and Computational Natural Language Learning<address><addrLine>Stroudsburg, PA, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="677" to="687" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Learning to Rank Search Results for Time-sensitive Queries</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nattiya</forename><surname>Kanhabua</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kjetil</forename><surname>Nørvåg</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 21st ACM International Conference on Information and Knowledge Management, CIKM &apos;12</title>
		<meeting>the 21st ACM International Conference on Information and Knowledge Management, CIKM &apos;12<address><addrLine>New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2463" to="2466" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Extracting Narrative Timelines As Temporal Dependency Structures</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Oleksandr</forename><surname>Kolomiyets</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Steven</forename><surname>Bethard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mariefrancine</forename><surname>Moens</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 50th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics: Long Papers</title>
		<meeting>the 50th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics: Long Papers<address><addrLine>Stroudsburg, PA, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="88" to="97" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Klaus</forename><surname>Krippendorff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Content Analysis: An Introduction to Its Methodology</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Sage Publications</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>second edition</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Measurement of Observer Agreement for Categorical Data</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Richard</forename><surname>Landis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gary</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Koch</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Biometrics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">33</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="159" to="174" />
			<date type="published" when="1977" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The TIMEBANK Corpus</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">James</forename><surname>Pustejovsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Patrick</forename><surname>Hanks</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Roser</forename><surname>Sauri</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>See</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Robert</forename><surname>Gaizauskas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Andrea</forename><surname>Setzer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dragomir</forename><surname>Radev</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Beth</forename><surname>Sundheim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Day</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lisa</forename><surname>Ferro</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marcia</forename><surname>Lazo</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of Corpus Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>Corpus Linguistics<address><addrLine>Lancaster, UK</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="647" to="656" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Syntax of Event Structure</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">James</forename><surname>Pustejovsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">41</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="47" to="81" />
			<date type="published" when="1991" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Andrea Setzer, and James Pustejovsky</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Roser</forename><surname>Saurí</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jessica</forename><surname>Littman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Robert</forename><surname>Gaizauskas</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">TimeML Annotation Guidelines</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Version 1.2.1</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Temporal Information in Newswire Articles: An Annotation Scheme and Corpus Study</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Andrea</forename><surname>Setzer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
			<pubPlace>Sheffield, UK</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>University of Sheffield</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
<note type="report_type">Ph.D. thesis</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Overview of the TAC 2013 Knowledge Base Population Evaluation: English Slot Filling and Temporal Slot Filling</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mihai</forename><surname>Surdeanu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the TAC-KBP 2013 Workshop</title>
		<meeting>the TAC-KBP 2013 Workshop<address><addrLine>Gaithersburg, Maryland, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">SemEval-2013 Task 1: TempEval-3: Evaluating Time Expressions, Events, and Temporal Relations</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Naushad</forename><surname>Uzzaman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hector</forename><surname>Llorens</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Leon</forename><surname>Derczynski</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marc</forename><surname>Verhagen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">James</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Allen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">James</forename><surname>Pustejovsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 7th International Workshop on Semantic Evaluation</title>
		<meeting>the 7th International Workshop on Semantic Evaluation<address><addrLine>Atlanta, Gerogia, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="9" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Annotated Data, version 2</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Piek</forename><surname>Marieke Van Erp</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rodrigo</forename><surname>Vossen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Annelyse</forename><surname>Agerri</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Manuela</forename><surname>Minard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ruben</forename><surname>Speranza</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Egoitz</forename><surname>Urizar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Itziar</forename><surname>Laparra</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">German</forename><surname>Aldabe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Rigau</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
			<pubPlace>Amsterdam, Netherlands</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
<note type="report_type">Technical report</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">SemEval-2007 Task 15: TempEval Temporal Relation Identification</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marc</forename><surname>Verhagen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Robert</forename><surname>Gaizauskas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Frank</forename><surname>Schilder</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mark</forename><surname>Hepple</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Graham</forename><surname>Katz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">James</forename><surname>Pustejovsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 4th International Workshop on Semantic Evaluations, SemEval &apos;07</title>
		<meeting>the 4th International Workshop on Semantic Evaluations, SemEval &apos;07<address><addrLine>Stroudsburg, PA, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="75" to="80" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Association for Computational Linguistics</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">SemEval-2010 Task 13: TempEval-2</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marc</forename><surname>Verhagen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Roser</forename><surname>Saurí</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tommaso</forename><surname>Caselli</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">James</forename><surname>Pustejovsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 5th International Workshop on Semantic Evaluation, SemEval &apos;10</title>
		<meeting>the 5th International Workshop on Semantic Evaluation, SemEval &apos;10<address><addrLine>Stroudsburg, PA, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="57" to="62" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Association for Computational Linguistics</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">WebAnno: A Flexible, Web-based and Visually Supported System for Distributed Annotations</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Iryna</forename><surname>Seid Muhie Yimam</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Richard</forename><surname>Gurevych</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chris</forename><surname>Eckart De Castilho</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Biemann</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 51st Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics: System Demonstrations</title>
		<meeting>the 51st Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics: System Demonstrations<address><addrLine>Sofia, Bulgaria</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2013-08" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="6" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
