<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T12:29+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">The Social Impact of Natural Language Processing</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date>August 7-12, 2016</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dirk</forename><surname>Hovy</surname></persName>
							<email>dirk.hovy@hum.ku.dk</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Center for Language Technology</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Ethics &amp; Philosophy of Technology Delft University of Technology Delft</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Copenhagen Copenhagen</orgName>
								<address>
									<country>Denmark, The Netherlands</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Shannon</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Spruit</surname></persName>
							<email>s.l.spruit@tudelft.nl</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Center for Language Technology</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Ethics &amp; Philosophy of Technology Delft University of Technology Delft</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Copenhagen Copenhagen</orgName>
								<address>
									<country>Denmark, The Netherlands</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">The Social Impact of Natural Language Processing</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 54th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
						<meeting>the 54th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics <address><addrLine>Berlin, Germany</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="591" to="598"/>
							<date type="published">August 7-12, 2016</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Medical sciences have long since established an ethics code for experiments, to minimize the risk of harm to subjects. Natural language processing (NLP) used to involve mostly anonymous corpora, with the goal of enriching linguistic analysis, and was therefore unlikely to raise ethical concerns. As NLP becomes increasingly widespread and uses more data from social media, however, the situation has changed: the outcome of NLP experiments and applications can now have a direct effect on individual users&apos; lives. Until now, the discourse on this topic in the field has not followed the technological development , while public discourse was often focused on exaggerated dangers. This position paper tries to take back the initiative and start a discussion. We identify a number of social implications of NLP and discuss their ethical significance, as well as ways to address them.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>After the Nuremberg trials revealed the atrocities conducted in medical research by the Nazis, medi- cal sciences established a set of rules to determine whether an experiment is ethical. This involved incorporating the principles of biomedical ethics as a lingua franca of medical ethics <ref type="bibr">(Beauchamp and Childress, 2001</ref>).</p><p>These guidelines were designed to balance the potential value of conducting an experiment while preventing the exploitation of human subjects. Today, any responsible research institution uses these-or comparable-criteria to approve or re- ject experiments before any research can be con- ducted. The administrative body governing these decisions is the Institutional Review Board (IRB).</p><p>IRBs mostly pertain to experiments that directly involve human subjects, though, and so NLP and other data sciences have not employed such guide- lines. Work on existing corpora is unlikely to raise any flags that would require an IRB approval. <ref type="bibr">1</ref> Data sciences have therefore traditionally been less engaged in ethical debates of their subject, even though this seems to be shifting, see for instance <ref type="bibr">Wallach (2014)</ref>, <ref type="bibr">Galaz et al. (2015)</ref>, or O'Neil (2016). The public outcry over the "emotional contagion" experiment on Facebook ( <ref type="bibr">Kramer et al., 2014</ref>) further suggests that data sci- ences now affect human subjects in real time, and that we might have to reconsider the application of ethical considerations to our research ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Puschmann and Bozdag, 2014</ref>). NLP research not only in- volves similar data sets, but also works with their content, so it is time to start a discussion of the ethical issues specific to our field.</p><p>Much of the ethical discussion in data sciences to date, however, has centered around privacy con- cerns ( <ref type="bibr">Tse et al., 2015</ref>). We do not deny the reality and importance of those concerns, but they involve aspects of digital rights management/access con- trol, policy making, and security, which are not specific to NLP, but need to be addressed in the data sciences community as a whole. Steps to- wards this have been taken by <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Russell et al. (2015)</ref>.</p><p>Instead, we want to move beyond privacy in our ethical analysis and look at the wider social impact NLP may have. In particular, we want to explore the impact of NLP on social justice, i.e., equal opportunities for individuals and groups (such as minorities) within society to access re- sources, get their voice heard, and be represented in society.</p><p>Our contributions We believe ethical discus- sions are more constructive if led by practition- ers, since the public discussion of ethical aspects of IT and data sciences is often loaded with fear of the unknown and unrealistic expectations. For example, in the public discourse about AI <ref type="bibr">(Hsu, 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr">Eadicicco, 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr">Khatchadourian, 2015)</ref>, people either dismiss the entire approach, or ex- aggerate the potential dangers (see <ref type="bibr">Etzioni (2014)</ref> for a practioner's view point). This paper is an at- tempt to take back the initiative for NLP.</p><p>At the same time, we believe that the field of ethics can contribute a more general framework, and so this paper is an interdisciplinary collabora- tion between NLP and ethics researchers.</p><p>To facilitate the discussion, we also provide some of the relevant terminology from the liter- ature on ethics of technology, namely the concepts of exclusion, overgeneralization, bias confirma- tion, topic under-and overexposure, and dual use.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Does NLP need an ethics discussion?</head><p>As discussed above, the makeup of most NLP ex- periments so far has not obviated a need for ethi- cal considerations, and so, while we are aware of individual discussions <ref type="bibr">(Strube, 2015)</ref>, there is lit- tle discourse in the community yet. A search for "ethic*" in the ACL anthology only yields three results. One of the papers <ref type="bibr">(McEnery, 2002</ref>) turns out to be a panel discussion, another is a book re- view, leaving only <ref type="bibr">Couillault et al. (2014)</ref>, who devote most of the discussion to legal and quality issues of data sets. We know social implications have been addressed in some NLP curricula, 2 but until now, no discipline-wide discussion seems to take place.</p><p>The most likely reason is that NLP research has not directly involved human subjects. <ref type="bibr">3</ref> His- torically, most NLP applications focused on fur- ther enriching existing text which was not strongly linked to any particular author (newswire), was usually published publicly, and often with some temporal distance (novels). All these factors cre- ated a distance between text and author, which pre- vented the research from directly affecting the au- thors' situation. This situation has changed lately due to the in- creased use of social media data, where authors are current individuals, who can be directly affected by the results of NLP applications. <ref type="bibr">Couillault et al. (2014)</ref> touch upon these issues under "traceabil- ity" (i.e., whether individuals can be identified): this is undesirable for experimental subjects, but might be useful in the case of annotators.</p><p>Most importantly, though: the subject of NLP- language-is a proxy for human behavior, and a strong signal of individual characteristics. Peo- ple use this signal consciously, to portray them- selves in a certain way, but can also be identified as members of specific groups by their use of subcon- scious traits <ref type="bibr">(Silverstein, 2003;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Agha, 2005;</ref><ref type="bibr">Johannsen et al., 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr">Hovy and Johannsen, 2016)</ref>.</p><p>Language is always situated ( <ref type="bibr">Bamman et al., 2014</ref>), i.e., it is uttered in a specific situation at a particular place and time, and by an individual speaker with all the characteristics outlined above. All of these factors can therefore leave an imprint on the utterance, i.e., the texts we use in NLP carry latent information about the author and situation, albeit to varying degrees. This information can be used to predict author characteristics from text ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Rosenthal and McKeown, 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr">Nguyen et al., 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Alowibdi et al., 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr">Ciot et al., 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr">Liu and Ruths, 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr">Volkova et al., 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr">Volkova et al., 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Plank and Hovy, 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Preotiuc-Pietro et al., 2015a;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Preot¸iucPreot¸iuc-Pietro et al., 2015b)</ref>, and the character- istics in turn can be detected by and influence the performance of our models ( <ref type="bibr">Mandel et al., 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr">Volkova et al., 2013;</ref>.</p><p>As more and more language-based technologies are becoming available, the ethical implications of NLP research become more important. What re- search is carried out, and its quality, directly affect the functionality and impact of those technologies.</p><p>The following is meant to start a discussion ad- dressing ethical issues that can emerge in (and from) NLP research.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">The social impact of NLP research</head><p>We have outlined the relation between language and individual traits above. Language is also a political instrument, though, and an instrument of power. This influence stretches into politics and everyday competition, for example for turn- taking <ref type="bibr">(Laskowski, 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr">Bracewell and Tomlinson, 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Prabhakaran and Rambow, 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr">Prab-hakaran et al., 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr">Tsur et al., 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr">Khouzami et al., 2015</ref>, inter alia), .</p><p>The mutual relationships between language, so- ciety, and the individual are also the source for the societal impact factors of NLP: failing to rec- ognize group membership (Section 3.1), implying the wrong group membership (see Section 3.2), and overexposure (Section 3.3). In the following, we discuss sources of these problems in the data, modeling, and research design, and suggest possi- ble solutions to address them.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Exclusion</head><p>As a result of the situatedness of language, any data set carries a demographic bias, i.e., latent information about the demographics in it. Over- fitting to these factors can have have severe ef- fects on the applicability of findings. In psychol- ogy, where most studies are based on western, educated, industrialized, rich, and democratic re- search participants (so-called WEIRD, <ref type="bibr">Henrich et al. (2010)</ref>), the tacit assumption that human nature is so universal that findings on this group would translate to other demographics has led to a heav- ily biased corpus of psychological data. In NLP, overfitting to the demographic bias in the training data is due to the i.i.d. assumption. I.e., models implicitly assume all language to be identical to the training sample. They therefore perform worse or even fail on data from other demographics.</p><p>Potential consequences are exclusion or demo- graphic misrepresentation. This in itself already represents an ethical problem for research pur- poses, threatening the universality and objectiv- ity of scientific knowledge <ref type="bibr">(Merton, 1973</ref>). These problems exacerbate, though, once they are ap- plied to products. For instance, standard language technology may be easier to use for white males from California (as these are taken into account while developing it) rather than women or citi- zens of Latino or Arabic descent. This will re- inforce already existing demographic differences, and makes technology less user friendly for such groups, cf. authors like <ref type="bibr">Bourdieu and Passeron (1990)</ref> have shown how restricted language, like class specific language or scientific jargon, can hinder the expression of outsiders' voices from certain practices. A lack of awareness or de- creased attention for demographic differences in research stages can therefore lead to issues of ex- clusion of people along the way.</p><p>Concretely, the consequences of exclusion for NLP research have recently been pointed out by <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Hovy and Søgaard (2015)</ref> and <ref type="bibr">Jørgensen et al. (2015)</ref>: current state-of-the-art NLP models score a significantly lower accuracy for young people and ethnic minorities vis-` a-vis the modeled demo- graphics.</p><p>Better awareness of these mechanism in NLP research and development can help prevent prob- lems further on. Potential counter-measures to de- mographic bias can be as simple as downsampling the over-represented group in the training data to even out the distribution. The work by <ref type="bibr">Mohammady and Culotta (2014)</ref> shows another approach, by using existing demographic statistics as super- vision. In general, measures to address overfitting or imbalanced data can be used to correct for de- mographic bias in data.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Overgeneralization</head><p>Exclusion is a side-effect of the data. Overgener- alization is a modeling side-effect.</p><p>As an example, we consider automatic infer- ence of user attributes, a common and interest- ing NLP task, whose solution also holds promise for many useful applications, such as recommen- dation engines and fraud or deception detection ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Badaskar et al., 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr">Fornaciari and Poesio, 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Ott et al., 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr">Banerjee et al., 2014</ref>).</p><p>The cost of false positives seems low: we might be puzzled or amused when receiving an email ad- dressing us with the wrong gender, or congratulat- ing us to our retirement on our 30th birthday.</p><p>In practice, though, relying on models that pro- duce false positives may lead to bias confirmation and overgeneralization. Would we accept the same error rates if the system was used to predict sexual orientation or religious views, rather than age or gender? Given the right training data, this is just a matter of changing the target variable.</p><p>To address overgeneralization, the guiding question should be "would a false answer be worse than no answer?" We can use dummy variables, rather than take a tertium non datur approach to classification, and employ measures such as er- ror weighting and model regularization, as well as confidence thresholds. In research, we can observe this effect in waves of research topics that receive increased main- stream attention, often to fall out of fashion or become more specialized, cf. ACL papers with "grammars" vs. "neural" in the title <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">(Figure 1</ref>).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3">The problem of exposure</head><p>Such topic overexposure may lead to a psycho- logical effect called availability heuristic <ref type="bibr">(Tversky and Kahneman, 1973)</ref>: if people can recall a certain event, or have knowledge about specific things, they infer it must be more important. For instance, people estimate the size of cities they recognize to be larger than that of unknown cities <ref type="bibr">(Goldstein and Gigerenzer, 2002</ref>).</p><p>However, the same holds for individu- als/groups/characteristics we research. The heuristics become ethically charged when char- acteristics such as violence or negative emotions are more strongly associated with certain groups or ethnicities ( <ref type="bibr">Slovic et al., 2007)</ref>. If research repeatedly found that the language of a certain demographic group was harder to process, it could create a situation where this group was perceived to be difficult, or abnormal, especially in the presence of existing biases. The confirmation of biases through the gendered use of language, for example, has also been at the core of second and third wave feminism (Mills, 2012).</p><p>Overexposure thus creates biases which can lead to discrimination. To some extent, the fran- tic public discussion on the dangers of AI can be seen as a result of overexposure <ref type="bibr">(Sunstein, 2004</ref>).</p><p>There are no easy solutions to this problem, which might only become apparent in hindsight. It can help to assess whether the research direction of a project feeds into existing biases, or whether it overexposes certain groups.</p><p>Underexposure can negatively impact evalua- tion. Similar to the WEIRD-situation in psy- chology, NLP tends to focus on Indo-European data/text sources, rather than small languages from other language groups, for example in Asia or Africa. This focus creates an imbalance in the available amounts of labeled data. Most of the exisitng labeled data covers only a small set of languages. When analyzing a random sample of Twitter data from 2013, we found that there were no treebanks for 11 of the 31 most frequent lan- guages, and even fewer semantically annotated resources (the ACE corpus covers only English, Arabic, Chinese, and Spanish). <ref type="bibr">4</ref> Even if there is a potential wealth of data available from other languages, most NLP tools are geared towards English <ref type="bibr">(Schnoebelen, 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr">Munro, 2013)</ref></p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>. The prevalence of resources for English has created an underexposure to typolog- ical variety: both morphology and syntax of En- glish are global outliers. Would we have focused on n-gram models to the same extent if English was as morhpologically complex as, say, Finnish?</head><p>While there are many approaches to develop multi-lingual and cross-lingual NLP tools for lin- guistic outliers <ref type="bibr">(Yarowsky and Ngai, 2001;</ref><ref type="bibr">Das and Petrov, 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr">Søgaard, 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Søgaard et al., 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Agi´cAgi´c et al., 2015)</ref>, there simply are more commercial incentives to overexpose En- glish, rather than other languages. Even if other languages are equally (or more) interesting from a linguistic and cultural point of view, English is one of the most widely spoken language and therefore opens up the biggest market for NLP tools. This focus on English may be self-reinforcing: the ex- istence of off-the-shelf tools for English makes it easy to try new ideas, while to start exploring other languages requires a higher startup cost in terms of basic models, so researchers are less likely to work on them.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Dual-use problems</head><p>Even if we address all of the above concerns and do not intend any harm in our experiments, they can still have unintended consequences that nega- tively affect people's lives <ref type="bibr">(Jonas, 1984)</ref>.</p><p>Advanced analysis techniques can vastly improve search and educational applications <ref type="bibr">(Tetreault et al., 2015)</ref>, but can re-enforce pre- scriptive linguistic norms when degrading on non-standard language.</p><p>Stylometric analysis can shed light on the provenance of historic texts <ref type="bibr">(Mosteller and Wallace, 1963)</ref>, but also endanger the anonymity of political dissenters. Text classification approaches help decode slang and hidden messages <ref type="bibr">(Huang et al., 2013</ref>), but have the potential to be used for censorship. At the same time, NLP can also help uncovering such restrictions ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Bamman et al., 2012</ref>). As recently shown by <ref type="bibr">Hovy (2016)</ref>, NLP techniques can be used to detect fake reviews, but also to generate them in the first place.</p><p>All these examples indicate that we should be- come more aware of the way other people ap- propriate NLP technology for their own purposes. The unprecedented scale and availability can make the consequences of NLP technologies hard to gauge.</p><p>The unintended consequences of research are also linked to the incentives associated with fund- ing sources. The topic of government and mili- tary involvement in the field deserves special at- tention in this respect. On the one hand, <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Anderson et al. (2012)</ref> show how a series of DARPA-funded workshops have been formative for ACL as a field in the 1990s. On the other hand, there are schol- ars who refuse military-related funding for moral reasons. <ref type="bibr">5</ref> While this decision is up to the individual re- searcher, the examples show that moral consider- ations go beyond the immediate research projects. We may not directly be held responsible for the unintended consequences of our research, but we can acknowledge the ways in which NLP can enable morally questionable/sensitive practices, raise awareness, and lead the discourse on it in an informed manner. The role of the researcher in such ethical discussions has recently been pointed out by <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Rogaway (2015)</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Conclusion</head><p>In this position paper, we outlined the potential so- cial impact of NLP, and discussed ways for the practitioner to address this. We also introduced exclusion, overgeneralization, bias confirmation, topic overexposure, and dual use. Countermea- sures for exclusion include bias control techniques like downsampling or priors; for overgeneraliza- tion: dummy labels, error weighting, or confi- dence thresholds. Exposure problems can only be addressed by careful research design, and dual-use problems seem hardly addressable on the level of the individual researcher, but require the concerted effort of our community.</p><p>We hope this paper can point out ethical consid- erations for collecting our data, designing the ex- perimental setup, and assessing the potential ap- plication of our systems, and help start an open discussion in the field about the limitations and problems of our methodology. <ref type="bibr">David Bamman, Chris Dyer, and Noah A. Smith. 2014</ref>.</p><p>Distributed representations of geographically situ- ated language. In Proceedings of the 52nd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Lin- guistics, pages 828-834. Proceedings of ACL. Raffi Khatchadourian.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2015.">The Dooms- day Invention:</head><p>Will artificial intelligence bring us utopia or destruction?</p><p>The New Yorker (magazine), November 23. http://www.newyorker.com/magazine/ 2015/11/23/doomsday-invention- artificial-intelligence-nick-bostrom Retrieved <ref type="bibr">Feb 24, 2016</ref> </p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Topic overexposure creates biases Both exclu- sion and overgeneralization can be addressedFigure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: ACL title keywords over time</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" validated="false"><head>.</head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Hatim Khouzami, Romain Laroche, and Fabrice 
Lefevre, 2015. Proceedings of the 16th Annual 
Meeting of the Special Interest Group on Dis-
course and Dialogue, chapter Optimising Turn-
Taking Strategies With Reinforcement Learning, 
pages 315-324. Association for Computational Lin-
guistics. 

Adam DI Kramer, Jamie E Guillory, and Jeffrey T Han-
cock. 2014. Experimental evidence of massive-
scale emotional contagion through social networks. 
Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences, 
111(24):8788-8790. 

Kornel Laskowski. 2010. Modeling norms of turn-
taking in multi-party conversation. In Proceedings 
of the 48th Annual Meeting of the Association for 
Computational Linguistics, pages 999-1008. Asso-
ciation for Computational Linguistics. 

Wendy Liu and Derek Ruths. 2013. What's in a name? 
using first names as features for gender inference in 
twitter. In Analyzing Microtext: 2013 AAAI Spring 
Symposium. 

Benjamin Mandel, Aron Culotta, John Boulahanis, 
Danielle Stark, Bonnie Lewis, and Jeremy Ro-
drigue, 2012. Proceedings of the Second Workshop 
on Language in Social Media, chapter A Demo-
graphic Analysis of Online Sentiment during Hur-
ricane Irene, pages 27-36. Association for Compu-
tational Linguistics. 

Tony McEnery. 2002. Ethical and legal issues in 
corpus construction. In Proceedings of the Third 
International Conference on Language Resources 
and Evaluation (LREC'02). European Language Re-
sources Association (ELRA). 

Robert K Merton. 1973. The normative structure of 
science. The sociology of science: Theoretical and 
empirical investigations, 267. 

Sara Mills. 2012. Gender matters: Feminist linguistic 
analysis. Equinox Pub. 

Ehsan Mohammady and Aron Culotta, 2014. Proceed-
ings of the Joint Workshop on Social Dynamics and 
Personal Attributes in Social Media, chapter Using 
County Demographics to Infer Attributes of Twitter 
Users, pages 7-16. Association for Computational 
Linguistics. 

Frederick Mosteller and David L Wallace. 1963. In-
ference in an authorship problem: A comparative 
study of discrimination methods applied to the au-
thorship of the disputed federalist papers. Journal of 

the American Statistical Association, 58(302):275-
309. 

Robert Munro. 
2013. 
NLP for all 
languages. 
Idibon 
Blog, 
May 
22 
http://idibon.com/nlp-for-all 
Re-
trieved May 17, 2016. 

Dong Nguyen, Noah A Smith, and Carolyn P Rosé. 
2011. Author age prediction from text using lin-
ear regression. In Proceedings of the 5th ACL-
HLT Workshop on Language Technology for Cul-
tural Heritage, Social Sciences, and Humanities, 
pages 115-123. Association for Computational Lin-
guistics. 

Cathy O'Neil. 
2016. 
The Ethi-
cal Data Scientist. Slate, 
February 4 
http://www.slate.com/articles/ 
technology/future tense/2016/02/ 
how to bring better ethics to data 
science.html Retrieved Feb 24, 2016. </table></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> With few exceptions, such as dialogue research (Joel Tetreault, pers. comm.)</note>

			<note place="foot" n="2"> Héctor Martínez Alonso, personal communication 3 Except for annotation: there are a number of papers on the status of crowdsource workers (Fort et al., 2011; Pavlick et al., 2014).Couillault et al. (2014) also briefly discuss annotators, but mainly in the context of quality control.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="4"> Thanks to Barbara Plank for the analysis!</note>

			<note place="foot" n="5"> For a perspective in a related field see https: //web.eecs.umich.edu/ ˜ kuipers/opinions/ no-military-funding.html</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgements</head><p>The authors would like to thank Joel Tetrault, Rachel Tatman, Joel C. Wallenberg, the members of the COASTAL group, and the anonymous re-viewers for their detailed and invaluable feedback. The first author was funded under the ERC Start-ing Grant LOWLANDS No. 313695. The second author was funded by the Netherlands Organiza-tion for Scientific Research under grant number 016.114.625.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="annex">
			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Journal of linguistic anthropology</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Asif</forename><surname>Agha</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="38" to="59" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Voice, footing, enregisterment</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">If all you have is a bit of the Bible: Learning POS taggers for truly low-resource languages</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dirk</forename><surname>Zeljko Agi´cagi´c</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Anders</forename><surname>Hovy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Søgaard</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 53rd annual meeting of the ACL</title>
		<meeting>the 53rd annual meeting of the ACL</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Empirical evaluation of profile characteristics for gender classification on twitter</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ugo</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Jalal S Alowibdi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Philip</forename><surname>Buy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Yu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Machine Learning and Applications (ICMLA), 2013 12th International Conference on</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>IEEE</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="365" to="369" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ashton</forename><surname>Anderson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dan</forename><surname>Mcfarland</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dan</forename><surname>Jurafsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the ACL-2012 Special Workshop on Rediscovering 50 Years of Discoveries</title>
		<meeting>the ACL-2012 Special Workshop on Rediscovering 50 Years of Discoveries</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="13" to="21" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Towards a computational history of the ACL</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Identifying real or fake articles: Towards better language modeling</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sameer</forename><surname>Badaskar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sachin</forename><surname>Agarwal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Shilpa</forename><surname>Arora</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Third International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing</title>
		<meeting>the Third International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>II</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Censorship and deletion practices in Chinese social media</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Bamman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O&amp;apos;</forename><surname>Brendan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Noah</forename><surname>Connor</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Smith</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">First Monday</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">17</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Finding deceptive opinion spam by any stretch of the imagination</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Myle</forename><surname>Ott</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yejin</forename><surname>Choi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Claire</forename><surname>Cardie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">Jeffrey</forename><surname>Hancock</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 49th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics: Human Language Technologies</title>
		<meeting>the 49th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics: Human Language Technologies</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="309" to="319" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The language demographics of amazon mechanical turk</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ellie</forename><surname>Pavlick</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Matt</forename><surname>Post</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ann</forename><surname>Irvine</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dmitry</forename><surname>Kachaev</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chris</forename><surname>Callison-Burch</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Transactions of the Association of Computational Linguistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="79" to="92" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Personality traits on twitterorhow to get 1,500 personality tests in a week</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Barbara</forename><surname>Plank</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dirk</forename><surname>Hovy</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 6th Workshop on Computational Approaches to Subjectivity, Sentiment and Social Media Analysis</title>
		<meeting>the 6th Workshop on Computational Approaches to Subjectivity, Sentiment and Social Media Analysis</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="92" to="98" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Written dialog and social power: Manifestations of different types of power in dialog behavior</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Vinodkumar</forename><surname>Prabhakaran</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Owen</forename><surname>Rambow</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Sixth International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing</title>
		<meeting>the Sixth International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="216" to="224" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Asian Federation of Natural Language Processing</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Staying on topic: An indicator of power in political debates</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ashima</forename><surname>Vinodkumar Prabhakaran</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Owen</forename><surname>Arora</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Rambow</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2014 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP)</title>
		<meeting>the 2014 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1481" to="1486" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">An analysis of the user occupational class through twitter content</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Daniel</forename><surname>Preotiuc-Pietro</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Vasileios</forename><surname>Lampos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nikolaos</forename><surname>Aletras</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ACL</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Studying user income through language, behaviour and affect in social media</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Daniel</forename><surname>Preot¸iucpreot¸iuc-Pietro</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Svitlana</forename><surname>Volkova</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">PloS one</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">138717</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Vasileios Lampos, Yoram Bachrach, and Nikolaos Aletras</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Staking out the unclear ethical terrain of online social experiments</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Cornelius</forename><surname>Puschmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Engin</forename><surname>Bozdag</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Internet Policy Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The moral character of cryptographic work</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Phillip</forename><surname>Rogaway</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>IACR-Cryptology ePrint Archive</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
<note type="report_type">Technical report</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Age prediction in blogs: A study of style, content, and online behavior in pre-and post-social media generations</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sara</forename><surname>Rosenthal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kathleen</forename><surname>Mckeown</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 49th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics: Human Language Technologies</title>
		<meeting>the 49th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics: Human Language Technologies</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="763" to="772" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Research priorities for robust and beneficial artificial intelligence</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Stuart</forename><surname>Russell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Daniel</forename><surname>Dewey</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Max</forename><surname>Tegmark</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Janos</forename><surname>Kramar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Richard</forename><surname>Mallah</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>Future of Life Institute</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
<note type="report_type">Technical report</note>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
