<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T10:36+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Finding Optimists and Pessimists on Twitter</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date>August 7-12, 2016</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xianzhi</forename><surname>Ruan</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">University of Michigan Ann Arbor</orgName>
								<address>
									<region>MI</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Steven</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Wilson</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">University of Michigan Ann Arbor</orgName>
								<address>
									<region>MI</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rada</forename><surname>Mihalcea</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">University of Michigan Ann Arbor</orgName>
								<address>
									<region>MI</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Finding Optimists and Pessimists on Twitter</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 54th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
						<meeting>the 54th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics <address><addrLine>Berlin, Germany</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="320" to="325"/>
							<date type="published">August 7-12, 2016</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Optimism is linked to various personality factors as well as both psychological and physical health, but how does it relate to the way a person tweets? We analyze the online activity of a set of Twit-ter users in order to determine how well machine learning algorithms can detect a person&apos;s outlook on life by reading their tweets. A sample of tweets from each user is manually annotated in order to establish ground truth labels, and classifiers are trained to distinguish between optimistic and pessimistic users. Our results suggest that the words in people&apos;s tweets provide ample evidence to identify them as optimists, pessimists, or somewhere in between. Additionally, several applications of these trained models are explored.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Optimists believe that future events are going to work out for the best; pessimists expect the worst <ref type="bibr">(Carver et al., 2010)</ref>. Research has shown that op- timism is correlated with many positive life out- comes including improvements in life expectancy ( <ref type="bibr">Diener and Chan, 2011)</ref>, physical health <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Peterson and Bossio, 2001)</ref>, and mental health ( <ref type="bibr">Achat et al., 2000</ref>). Previously, it was found that optimism and pessimism are differentiable but related: pes- simism was principally associated with neuroti- cism and negative affect while optimism was pri- marily associated with extraversion and positive affect <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Marshall et al., 1992</ref>). Another study found that optimism was correlated with personality fac- tors, including extraversion, emotional stability, conscientiousness, and agreeableness <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Sharpe et al., 2011</ref>).</p><p>It is clear that optimism relates to a wide vari- ety of psychological and social variables, but how might optimism influence the way a person uti- lizes a social media platform? What features dis- tinguish optimistic users from pessimistic ones?</p><p>In order to answer these questions, we must first establish a means by which we can measure peo- ple's levels of optimism and pessimism. The Life Orientation Test (LOT) is commonly used to as- sess the degree to which a person is an optimist ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Scheier and Carver, 1985)</ref>. This short survey asks respondents to evaluate their own agreement with a number of short statements using a five- point scale. However, distributing such a sur- vey over a large population requires both time and a form of incentive. Recent work has shown that open-ended text samples can be computation- ally analyzed to provide a more comprehensive view of a person's personal values than can be achieved using a more constrained, forced choice survey ( <ref type="bibr">Boyd et al., 2015)</ref>. Furthermore, we know that language use is an independent and meaning- ful way of exploring personality <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Pennebaker and King, 1999)</ref>, and personality is correlated with op- timism <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Sharpe et al., 2011</ref>). Given a large enough text corpus, it may therefore be possible to build computational models that can automatically rec- ognize optimism itself by looking at the words people use. The vast amount of publicly available social media data provides an excellent source of data that can be used to build models of users' psy- chological traits, as was done in previous studies that trained machines to predict aspects of person- ality from tweets <ref type="bibr">(Golbeck et al., 2011;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Sumner et al., 2012)</ref>.</p><p>A tool that could identify optimists and pes- simists by analyzing their text would aid in large scale studies of optimism among social media or other web users by providing a large number of subjects to analyze. This would open the door to massive studies of the relationships between opti- mism, pessimism, and a range of online behaviors. On the other hand, an optimism classification sys- tem could help improve the social platform itself. For example, by learning more about the psycho- logical traits of its users, Twitter could improve its "who to follow" suggestions so that they reflect people who have a similar outlook on life.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Data and Method</head><p>As a data source, we chose Twitter because it is widely used and is ripe with short pieces of text (i.e., tweets) containing people's everyday thoughts, observations, and conversations. We used Twitter's basic search function to look for users whose tweets include words and phrases that indicate that they might identify as optimistic or pessimistic. Looking for phrases such as "I am op- timistic" within a user's tweets to find potentially optimistic users, we identified 714 candidates. Finding pessimistic Twitter users proved more dif- ficult because users would not usually tweet some- thing negative such as "I am pessimistic" and present themselves in an unflattering way. We in- stead searched for keywords such as "hate," "un- fair," and "disgust," which may indicate a pes- simistic nature. This led to 640 potential pes- simists. For each user, we crawled their 2,000 most recent tweets (or all their tweets if the user had less than 2,000). In order to verify that the ac- counts identified were owned mostly by individ- ual users (as opposed to organizations), we man- ually inspected a random sample of 50 accounts and found only one that appeared to be related to an organization.</p><p>Using the collected data set, which we expected would be more representative of optimistic or pes- simistic nature than the norm based on the con- tent of their tweets, we selected a fraction of the users to create a ground truth set for our task. We used Amazon Mechanical Turk (MTurk) 1 to ob- tain human annotatations for a subset of our cor- pus. We randomly selected 500 users who were retrieved by the optimistic queries and 500 users found when searching for pessimists. For each user, we randomly selected 15 tweets for a total of 15,000 tweets to be labeled on a scale of −3 (very pessimistic) to 3 (very optimistic) by five indepen- dent annotators. Before labeling began, we pro- vided clear definitions of optimism and pessimism 1 http://www.mturk.com to the annotators.</p><p>In order to pick the tweets from each user that had a stronger emotional signal, we took advan- tage of the "positive emotions" and "negative emo- tions" word categories included in the Linguistic Inquiry and Word Count Tool ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Pennebaker et al., 2001</ref>). <ref type="bibr">2</ref> If any of the original 15 tweets did not contain at least one word from either category, the tweet was removed and a new tweet was chosen at random to replace it. This process was repeated until we had a set of 15 tweets per user with- out skewing that user's true distribution of positive and negative tweets.</p><p>During the MTurk annotation, to identify work- ers who were quickly selecting options without even reading the tweets, we added a "check" ques- tion that asked the workers to choose a specific value for that question. All the workers who did not correctly answer this "check" question were removed from the annotation. When a worker's annotations had to be thrown out, the tweets were put back onto MTurk for reannotation. Addition- ally, we compared the scores of each annotator with the average score and removed workers who deviated significantly from the others. The final agreement (Krippendorf's alpha) between the five annotators was measured at 0.731, assuming an in- terval scale.</p><p>For each individual tweet, we assigned a la- bel of "optimistic," "pessimistic," or "neutral". Any tweet with an average score greater than one (slightly optimistic or higher in the annotation task) was considered an "optimistic" tweet, and those with an average score less than one (slightly pessimistic or lower) were given the "pessimistic" class label. The tweets with average MTurk anno- tation scores between -1 and 1 were considered to be "neutral."</p><p>We also assigned a class label to each user. To accomplish this, we calculated the average of the assigned scores, sorted the Twitter users by their level of optimism, and considered the top 25% of users as optimists, the bottom 25% as pessimists, and the remaining ones as neutral.</p><p>Before moving on, we decided to investigate the online behaviors and attributes of the optimistic and pessimistic users in our new data set. A sum- mary of some of the differences between the two groups is shown in <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>. Interestingly the opti- mists have more followers and are following more  <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">mean followers  6238  1840  mean following  1898  1156  mean tweets  12156  28190  median followers  972  572  median following  718  443  median tweets  5687  17451  std. dev of tweets  17952  37851</ref>  <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>: Statistics for the most extreme 100 opti- mistic &amp; 100 pessimistic users.</p><note type="other">min number of tweets 108 28 max number of tweets 99344 231220 tweet rate 10.24 19.184 favorite count 4314.34 8761.2 listed count 112.62 10.23</note><p>other users than the more pessimistic users. On the other hand, the pessimists tend to tweet much more frequently, with a mean and median num- ber of tweets both more than twice as large as the optimist group. This is not just a factor of the pessimists having been around longer to build up a history of tweets-we also compute the "tweet rate" for each user by dividing their total number of tweets by the total number of days since the ac- tivation of their Twitter account. Looking at this variable, we see that the average number of tweets per day is much higher for the pessimists. Opti- mists are also included in more lists, while pes- simists choose to label things as a "favorite" more often.</p><p>In order to build computational models to dif- ferentiate between the optimistic and pessimistic users, we use five different methods from the scikit-learn python library 3 : Naive Bayes (NB), Nearest Neighbor (NN), Decision Tree (DT), Ran- dom Forest Classifier (RFC), Gradient Boosting Classifier (GBC) and Stochastic Gradient Descent (SGD). The default parameters are used for each. The preprocessing method was the same for all different classifiers: the text was preprocessed by removing mentions (@), web links, and the phrase RT. We also used the Emoji unicode tables to re- place all Emoji unicodes to their corresponding meanings (e.g., "&lt;smiling-face&gt;"). We tried per- forming classification both with and without re- moving stopwords to see what the effect was. For all different classifiers, we tested with different settings: with and without stopwords; and adding a user's profile information as additional features or not.  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Results</head><p>We first evaluate the ability of our classifiers to distinguish between optimistic and pessimistic tweets (two-way classification) or among opti- mistic, pessimistic, and neutral tweets (three- way classification). We randomly selected 1,000 tweets from each class. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 1</ref> shows the ten- fold cross validation results obtained using the six classifiers. During each classification, we made sure that tweets from the same user were not shared between the training and testing folds. In both cases, the best setting was using the Naive Bayes classifier and not including profile informa- tion as features. Stopword removal had no notice- able effect. Note that the majority baseline is a score of 50% in the two-class case, while it is 33% in the three-class case.</p><p>For additional insight, <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table 2</ref> shows some of the top features for the optimistic and pessimistic class, sorted by the probability of the feature given the class. We can see that, as one might ex- pect, the useful words for detecting optimists are generally very positive, while the pessimistic fea- tures are negative and sprinkled with profanity.</p><p>Since we formulated the problem as a three-way classification, it is reasonable that some words may have high scores for both optimistic and pes- simistic classes. These words distinguish opti- mism/pessimism from the neutral class.</p><p>We perform our next evaluation at the user level, which means that we consider all tweets from  <ref type="figure">Figure 2</ref>: Accuracy on the user-level prediction task for different data sizes.</p><p>a user as a single document. The classification is performed using a randomly selected set of 100, 200, 300, and 400 users from the annotated set (each set adds 100 new users to the previous group). In each case, the 25% users with high- est annotation score are considered the optimistic group, 25% users with lowest annotation score as pessimist group, and the other 50% of users is the neutral group. The results of the ten-fold cross val- idation are shown in <ref type="figure">Figure 2</ref>. In this setting, the Gradient Boosting Classifier usually outperforms the others and achieves an accuracy of 73.33% on the 400 user data set. We also sought to discover how accurate the classifiers would be if the objective was simply to identify the top N optimists or pessimists. For example, if we wanted to find the 10 users out of a group with the greatest number of optimistic tweets, how accurately could this be done? To  carry out this analysis, we sorted the users by the probabilities that they belonged to either the op- timistic class or the pessimistic class as predicted by a Naive Bayes classifier <ref type="figure">(Figure 3</ref>). Then, we compute the accuracy for the top N optimists and pessimists. As we can see, it is possible to predict the most pessimistic 14 users with perfect accu- racy. On the other hand, some of the most likely optimistic users actually belonged to another class based on the ground truth labels. With a larger number of users to classify, it becomes easier to correctly label optimists than pessimists.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Applications</head><p>What kinds of things can we learn with a tool for classifying optimists and pessimists? First, we look at groups of users from three major cities in the United States: Chicago, Los Angeles, and New York. We found users who listed their location as one of these three cities (494 users from Chicago, 433 from Los Angeles, 480 from New York), then collected 2,000 tweets from each user. Using our best models from the user-level experiments, we obtain predictions for the optimism/pessimism of the users. The breakdown of predicted optimists, pessimists, and neutral users is listed in <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">Table 3</ref>.</p><p>Chicago and New York are fairly balanced with roughly 40% of people falling into each category (leaving 20% as neutral). However, pessimists were predicted much more often than optimists in Los Angeles. For a second sample application, we went to the official twitter accounts of six presiden- tial candidates: Hillary Clinton, Donald Trump, Marco Rubio, Martin O'Malley, Bernie Sanders and Ben Carson. We randomly picked approxi- mately 500 followers of each of the candidates and predicted the optimism/pessimism of them <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">(Table  4</ref>). <ref type="bibr">4</ref> While these scores are only estimates, we see that O'Malley's followers tend to be the users who posted a greater number of optimistic tweets, while the users who tweeted lots of pessimistic tweets are those keeping up-to-date with Rubio's campaign. Overall, we see that most of the fol- lowers of these candidates are optimistic.  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Conclusions and Future Work</head><p>We have shown that we can use Twitter to collect a data set 5 of optimistic and pessimistic users, and predict the most (top 25%) optimistic/pessimistic users with greater than 70% accuracy. The opti- mistic users on Twitter tended to have more so- cial connections, but tweet less often than the pes- simists. In the future, we hope to explore the social effects of optimism, such as the degree to which optimistic users follow one another and whether or not optimistic comments receive more "favorites" and retweets. Finally, we would like to compare the optimism and pessimism scores that our model predicts with those received when taking the LOT in order to compare the text-based analysis with a widely used tool for measuring optimism.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>3</head><label></label><figDesc>http://scikit-learn.org/stable/ NN DT RFC GBC SGD NB</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: Tweet level classification accuracy for the two-way and three-way classification problems.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" validated="false"><head>Table 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Most discriminating features collected 
by the Naive Bayes classifier for the three-class 
tweet-level prediction setting. 

100 150 200 250 300 350 400 

45 

50 

55 

60 

65 

70 

75 

number of users 
model accuracy (%) 

NB 
NN 
DT 
RFC 
GBC 
SGD 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" validated="false"><head>Table 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Predicted optimism &amp; pessimism in three 
major cities 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4" validated="false"><head>Table 4 :</head><label>4</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Predicted optimism &amp; pessimism of those 
following some of the candidates for the 2016 
Presidential election. 

</table></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="2"> The 2007 version of LIWC was used</note>

			<note place="foot" n="4"> data collected late December, 2015 5 The data set introduced in this paper is available at http://lit.eecs.umich.edu/research/ downloads.</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgements</head><p>We would like to thank Seong Ju Park, Tian Bao, and Yihan Li for their assistance in the initial project that led to this work. This material is based in part upon work supported by the Na-tional Science Foundation award #1344257 and by grant #48503 from the John Templeton Foun-dation. Any opinions, findings, and conclusions or recommendations expressed in this material are those of the authors and do not necessarily reflect the views of the National Science Foundation or the John Templeton Foundation. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>References</head></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Distinguishing optimism from pessimism: Relations to fundamental dimensions of mood and personality</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Camille</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Grant N Marshall</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jeffrey</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Wortman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Linda</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Kusulas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ross R</forename><surname>Hervig</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Vickers</surname><genName>Jr</genName></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of personality and social psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">62</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1067</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1992" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Linguistic styles: language use as an individual difference</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>James</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Laura A</forename><surname>Pennebaker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>King</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of personality and social psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">77</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1296</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Linguistic inquiry and word count: Liwc</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Martha</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>James W Pennebaker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Roger J</forename><surname>Francis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Booth</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Mahway: Lawrence Erlbaum Associates</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">71</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Optimism and physical well-being</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christopher</forename><surname>Peterson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lisa</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Bossio</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Optimism &amp; pessimism: Implications for theory, research, and practice</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>APA</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="127" to="145" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Optimism, coping, and health: assessment and implications of generalized outcome expectancies</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Michael</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Charles S</forename><surname>Scheier</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Carver</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Health psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">219</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1985" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Optimism and the big five factors of personality: Beyond neuroticism and extraversion. Personality and Individual Differences</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Patrick</forename><surname>Sharpe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kelly A</forename><surname>Nicholas R Martin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Roth</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">51</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="946" to="951" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Predicting dark triad personality traits from twitter usage and a linguistic analysis of tweets</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chris</forename><surname>Sumner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alison</forename><surname>Byers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rachel</forename><surname>Boochever</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gregory J</forename><surname>Park</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Machine Learning and Applications (ICMLA)</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>IEEE</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="386" to="393" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>11th International Conference on</note>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
