<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T12:26+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Creating Interactive Macaronic Interfaces for Language Learning</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date>August 7-12, 2016</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Adithya</forename><surname>Renduchintala</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Johns Hopkins University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rebecca</forename><surname>Knowles</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Johns Hopkins University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Philipp</forename><surname>Koehn</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Johns Hopkins University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jason</forename><surname>Eisner</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Johns Hopkins University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Creating Interactive Macaronic Interfaces for Language Learning</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 54th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics-System Demonstrations</title>
						<meeting>the 54th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics-System Demonstrations <address><addrLine>Berlin, Germany</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="133" to="138"/>
							<date type="published">August 7-12, 2016</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>We present a prototype of a novel technology for second language instruction. Our learn-by-reading approach lets a human learner acquire new words and constructions by encountering them in context. To facilitate reading comprehension , our technology presents mixed native language (L1) and second language (L2) sentences to a learner and allows them to interact with the sentences to make the sentences easier (more L1-like) or harder (more L2-like) to read. Eventually , our system should continuously track a learner&apos;s knowledge and learning style by modeling their interactions, including performance on a pop quiz feature. This will allow our system to generate person-alized mixed-language texts for learners.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Growing interest in self-directed language learn- ing methods like <ref type="bibr">Duolingo (von Ahn, 2013)</ref>, along with recent advances in machine translation and the widespread ease of access to a variety of texts in a large number of languages, has given rise to a number of web-based tools related to language learning (ranging from dictionary apps to more interactive tools like Alpheios <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(Nelson, 2007)</ref> or Lingua.ly <ref type="bibr">(2013)</ref>). Most of these either focus on vocabulary learning or require hand-curated les- son plans. We present a prototype of a system for learning to read in a foreign language, which presents learners with text consisting of a mix of their native language (L1) and the language they are interested in learning (L2). We refer to sen- tences containing a mix of L1 and L2 text as mac- aronic 1 sentences. Along the continuum from fully L1 to fully L2 text are sentences with any combination of L1 and L2 vocabulary, syntax, and (potentially) morphology.</p><p>Proponents of language acquisition through ex- tensive reading, such as <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Krashen (1989)</ref>, argue that much of language acquisition takes place through incidental learning-when a learner is ex- posed to novel vocabulary or structures and must find a way to understand them in order to compre- hend the text. The trouble is that learning by read- ing already requires considerable L2 fluency. To bootstrap, we propose making L2 sentences more accessible to early learners by shifting these sen- tences along the macaronic spectrum towards L1, stopping at the "zone of proximal development" (Vygotski˘ ı, 2012) where the learner is able to com- prehend the text but only by stretching their L2 capacity. We aim in the future to customize maca- ronic sentences to each individual learner.</p><p>A reasonable concern is whether exposure to macaronic language might actually harm acquisi- tion of correct L2 (even though our interface uses color and font to mark the L1 "intrusions" into the L2 sentence). As some reassurance, our approach is analogous to the well-established paradigm of inventive spelling (or "invented spelling"), 2 in which early writers are encouraged to write in their native language without concern for cor- rect spelling, in part so they can more fully and happily engage with the writing challenge of composing longer and more authentic texts <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Clarke, 1988)</ref>. We also observe that simulta- neous dual language acquisition-from multilin- gual and code-switched language-is common for young children in many countries, who employ code-switching in a socially appropriate way and as "a resource . . . to fill gaps in their developing requires the speaker/writer to be fluent in both languages. Code-switching is governed by syntactic and pragmatic con- siderations, rather than by pedagogical or humorous ones. <ref type="bibr">2</ref> Spelling, like L2, is a type of linguistic knowledge that is acquired after L1 fluency and largely through incidental learning <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Krashen, 1993).</ref> languages" <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Genesee, 2009)</ref>. Still, it remains an open question whether older students can success- fully unlearn initial habits and move toward an in- creasingly complete and correct L2 model. We envision our technology being used along- side traditional classroom L2 instruction-the same instructional mix that leads parents to ac- cept inventive spelling <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Gentry, 2000</ref>). Traditional grammar-based instruction and assessment, which use "toy" sentences in pure L2, should provide fur- ther scaffolding for our users to acquire language by reading more advanced (but macaronic) text.</p><p>We provide details of the current user interface and discuss how content for our system can be au- tomatically generated using existing statistical ma- chine translation (SMT) methods, enabling learn- ers or teachers to choose their own texts to read. Our prototype is currently running on http: //www.clsp.jhu.edu:3030/ with sample content. Our interface lets the user navigate through the spectrum from L2 to L1, going beyond the single-word or single-phrase translations of- fered by other online tools such as <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Swych (2015)</ref>, or dictionary-like browser plugins.</p><p>Finally, we discuss plans to extend this proto- type and to integrate it with a continuously adapt- ing user model. To this end, our companion pa- per ( ) develops an initial model of macaronic sentence comprehension by novice L2 learners, using data collected from hu- man subjects via Amazon's Mechanical Turk ser- vice. In another paper ( , we carry out a controlled study of comprehension of individual L2 words in isolation and in L1 context.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Macaronic Interface</head><p>For the purposes of this demo we assume a na- tive English speaker (L1=English) who is learn- ing German (L2=German). However, our exist- ing interface can accommodate any pair of lan- guages whose writing systems share directional- ity. <ref type="bibr">3</ref> The primary goal of the interface is to em- power a learner to translate and reorder parts of a confusing foreign language sentence. These trans- lations and reorderings serve to make the German sentence more English-like. The interface also permits reverse transformations, letting the curi- ous learner "peek ahead" at how specific English words and constructions would surface in German. <ref type="bibr">3</ref> We also assume that the text is segmented into words. Using these fundamental interactions as build- ing blocks, we create an interactive framework for a language learner to explore this continuum of "English-like" to "foreign-like" sentences. By re- peated interaction with new content and exposure to recurring vocabulary items and linguistic pat- terns, we believe a learner can pick up vocabulary and other linguistic rules of the foreign language.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">Translation</head><p>The basic interface idea is that a line of macaronic text is equipped with hidden interlinear annota- tions. Notionally, English translations lurk below the macaronic text, and German ones above.</p><p>The Translation interaction allows the learner to change the text in the macaronic sentence from one language to another. Consider a macaronic sentence that is completely in the foreign state (i.e.,, entirely in German), as shown in <ref type="figure">Fig. 1a</ref>. Hovering on or under a German word shows a pre- view of a translation <ref type="figure">(Fig. 1b)</ref>. Clicking on the preview will cause the translation to "rise up" and replace the German word <ref type="figure">(Fig. 1c)</ref>.</p><p>To translate in the reverse direction, the user can hover and click above an English word <ref type="figure">(Fig. 1d)</ref>.</p><p>Since the same mechanism applies to all the words in the sentence, a learner can manipulate translations for each word independently. For ex- ample, <ref type="figure">Fig. 1e</ref> shows two words in English.</p><p>The version of our prototype displayed in <ref type="figure">Fig- ure 1</ref> blurs the preview tokens when a learner is hovering above or below a word. This blurred preview acts as a visual indication of a potential change to the sentence state (if clicked) but it also gives the learner a chance to think about what the translation might be, based on visual clues such as length and shape of the blurred text.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">Reordering</head><p>When the learner hovers slightly below the words nach Georg Büchner a Reordering arrow is displayed (as shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 2</ref>). The arrow is an indicator of reordering. In this example, the Ger- man past participle benannt appears at the end of the sentence (the conjugated form of the verb is ist benannt, or is named); this is the gram- matically correct location for the participle in Ger- man, while the English form should appear earlier in the equivalent English sentence.</p><p>Similar to the translation actions, reordering actions also have a directional attribute. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure  2b</ref> shows a German-to-English direction arrow. When the learner clicks the arrow, the interface re- arranges all the words involved in the reordering. The new word positions are shown in 2c. Once again, the user can undo: hovering just above nach Georg Büchner now shows a gray ar- row, which if clicked returns the phrase to its Ger- man word order (shown in 2d).</p><p>German phrases that are not in original German order are highlighted as a warning <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">(Figure 2c</ref>).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3">"Pop Quiz" Feature</head><p>So far, we have described the system's standard responses to a learner's actions. We now add oc- casional "pop quizzes." When a learner hovers be- low a German word (s 0 in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 3</ref>) and clicks the blurry English text, the system can either reveal the translation of the German word (state s 2 ) as de- scribed in section 2.1 or quiz the learner (state s 3 ). We implement the quiz by presenting a text input box to the learner: here the learner is expected to type what they believe the German word means. Once a guess is typed, the system indicates if the guess is correct (s 4 ) or incorrect(s 5 ) by flashing green or red highlights in the text box. The box then disappears (after 700ms) and the system au- tomatically proceeds to the reveal state s 2 . As this imposes a high cognitive load and increases the in- teraction complexity (typing vs. clicking), we in- tend to use the pop quiz infrequently. The pop quiz serves two vital functions. First, it further incentivizes the user to retain learned vo- cabulary. Second, it allows the system to update its model of the user's current L2 lexicon, macaronic comprehension, and learning style; this is work in progress (see section 4.2).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.4">Interaction Consistency</head><p>Again, we regard the macaronic sentence as a kind of interlinear text, written between two mostly in- visible sentences: German above and English be- low. In general, hovering above the macaronic sentence will reveal German words or word or- ders, which fall down into the macaronic sentence upon clicking. Hovering below will reveal English translations, which rise up upon clicking.</p><p>The words in the macaronic sentence are col- ored according to their language. We want the user to become accustomed to reading German, so the German words are in plain black text by de- fault, while the English words use a marked color and font (italic blue). Reordering arrows also fol- low the same color scheme: arrows that will make the macaronic sentence more "German-like" are gray, while arrows that make the sentence more "English-like" are blue. The summary of interac- tions is shown in <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Constructing Macaronic Translations</head><p>In this section, we describe the details of the un- derlying data structures needed to allow all the in- teractions mentioned in the previous section. A key requirement in the design of the data struc- ture was to support orthogonal actions in each sen- tence. Making all translation and reordering ac- tions independent of one another creates a large space of macaronic states for a learner to explore. At present, the input to our macaronic inter- face is bitext with word-to-word alignments pro- vided by a phrase-based SMT system (or, if de- sired, by hand). We employ Moses ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Koehn et al., 2007)</ref> to translate German sentences and gener- ate phrase alignments. News articles written in simple German from nachrichtenleicht. <ref type="bibr">de (Deutschlandfunk, 2016)</ref> were translated after training the SMT system on the WMT15 German- English corpus <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Bojar et al., 2015)</ref>.</p><p>We convert the word alignments into "mini- mal alignments" that are either one-to-one, one- to-many or many-to-one. <ref type="bibr">4</ref> This step ensures con- sistent reversibility of actions and prevents large phrases from being translated with a single click. <ref type="bibr">5</ref> The resulting bipartite graph can be regarded as <ref type="bibr">4</ref> For each many-to-many alignment returned by the SMT system, we remove alignment edges (lowest probability first) until the alignment is no longer many-to-many. Then we greedily add edges from unaligned tokens (highest probabil- ity first), subject to not creating many-to-many alignments and subject to minimizing the number of crossing edges, un- til all tokens are aligned.</p><p>5 Preliminary experiments showed that allowing large phrases to translate with one click resulted in abrupt jumps in the visualization, which users found hard to follow. The dotted lines show word-to-word alignments between the German sentence f0, f1, . . . , f7 and its English translation e0, e1, . . . , e6. The figure highlights 3 of the 7 units: u2, u3, u4.</p><p>Figure 5: A possible state of the sentence, which renders a subset of the tokens (shown in black). The rendering order (section 3.2) is not shown but is also part of the state. The string displayed in this case is "Und danach they run noch einen Marathon." (assuming no reordering). a collection of connected components, or units <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">(Fig. 4)</ref>. <ref type="bibr">6</ref> </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Translation Mechanism</head><p>In a given state of the macaronic sentence, each unit is displayed in either English or German. A translation action toggles the display language of the unit, leaving it in place. For example, in <ref type="figure">Fig- ure 5</ref>, where the macaronic sentence is currently displaying f 4 f 5 = noch einen, a translation action will replace this with e 4 = a.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Reordering Mechanism</head><p>A reordering action changes the unit order of the current macaronic sentence. The out-put string "Und danach they run noch einen Marathon." is obtained from <ref type="figure">Figure  5</ref> only if unit u 2 (as labeled in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Figure 4</ref>) is ren- dered (in its current language) to the left of unit u 3 , which we write as u 2 &lt; u 3 . In this case, it is possible for the user to change the order of these units, because u 3 &lt; u 2 in German. <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Table 2</ref> shows the 8 possible combinations of ordering and trans- lation choices for this pair of units.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>String Rendered</head><p>Unit Ordering . . .they run. . .  The space of possible orderings for a sentence pair is defined by a bracketing ITG tree <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">(Wu, 1997)</ref>, which transforms the German ordering of the units into the English ordering by a collec- tion of nested binary swaps of subsequences. <ref type="bibr">7</ref> The ordering state of the macaronic sentence is given by the subset of these swaps that have been per- formed. A reordering action toggles one of the swaps in this collection.</p><p>Since we have a parser for German <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Rafferty and Manning, 2008)</ref>, we take care to select an ITG tree that is "compatible" with the German sentence's dependency structure, in the following sense: if the ITG tree combines two spans A and B, then there are not dependencies from words in A to words in B and vice-versa.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Discussion and Future Work</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">Machine Translation Challenges</head><p>When the English version of the sentence is pro- duced by an MT system, it may suffer from MT errors and/or poor alignments.</p><p>Even with correct MT, a given syntactic con- struction may be handled inconsistently on differ- ent occasions, depending on the particular words involved (as these affect what phrasal alignment is found and how we convert it to a minimal align- ment). Syntax-based MT could be used to design a more consistent interface that is also more closely tied to classroom L2 lessons.</p><p>Cross-linguistic divergences in the expression of information <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Dorr, 1994)</ref> could be confusing. For example, when moving through macaronic space from Kaffee gefällt Menschen (coffee pleases humans) to its translation humans like coffee, it may not be clear to the learner that the reordering is triggered by the fact that like is not a literal translation of gefällt. One way to improve this might be to have the system pass smoothly through a range of intermediate translations from word-by-word glosses to idiomatic phrasal translations, rather than always directly translating idioms. We might also see benefit in guiding our gradual translations with cognates (for example, rather than translate directly from the German Möhre to the English carrot, we might offer the cognate Karotte as an intermediate step).</p><p>We also plan to transition through words that are macaronic at the sub-word level. For example, hovering over the unfamiliar Ger- man word gesprochen might decompose it into ge-sprochen; then clicking on one of those morphemes might yield ge-talk or sprech-ed before reaching talked. This could guide learners towards an understanding of German tense marking and stem changes.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">User Adaptation and Evaluation</head><p>We would prefer to show the learner a macaronic sentence that provides just enough clues for the learner to be able to comprehend it, while still pushing them to figure out new vocabulary or new structures. Thus, we plan to situate this interface in a framework that continuously adapts as the user progresses. As the user learns new vocabu- lary, the system will automatically present them with more challenging sentences (containing less L1). In (  we show that we can predict a novice learner's guesses of L2 word meanings in macaronic sentences using a few simple features. We will subsequently track the user's learning by observing their mouse ac- tions and "pop quiz" responses (section 2).</p><p>While we have had users interact with our sys- tem in order to collect data about novice learn- ers' guesses, we are working toward an evaluation where our system is used to supplement classroom instruction for real foreign-language students.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Conclusion</head><p>In this work we present a prototype of an inter- active interface for learning to read in a foreign language. We expose the learner to L2 vocabulary and constructions in contexts that are comprehen- sible because they have been partially translated into the learner's native language, using statistical MT. Using MT affords flexibility: learners or in- structors can choose which texts to read, and learn- ers or the system can control which parts of a sen- tence are translated.</p><p>We are working towards integrating models of learner understanding  to produce personalized macaronic texts that give each learner just the right amount of challenge and support. In the long term, we would like to extend the approach to allow users also to produce macaronic language, draw- ing on techniques from grammatical error correc- tion or computer-aided translation to help them gradually remove L1 features from their writing (or speech) and make it more L2-like.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>(</head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 1: Actions that translate words.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2: Actions that reorder phrases.</figDesc><graphic url="image-12.png" coords="3,184.90,90.16,707.19,441.99" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Figure 3: State diagram of learner interaction (edges) and system's response(vertices). Edges can be traversed by clicking (c), hovering above (a), hovering below (b) or the enter (e) key. Unmarked edges indicate an automatic transition.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>Figure 4 :</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Figure 4: The dotted lines show word-to-word alignments between the German sentence f0, f1,. .. , f7 and its English translation e0, e1,. .. , e6. The figure highlights 3 of the 7 units: u2, u3, u4.</figDesc><graphic url="image-17.png" coords="4,307.28,201.12,218.26,85.28" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" validated="false"><head>Table 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Generating reordered strings using units.</figDesc><table></table></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> The term &quot;macaronic&quot; traditionally refers to a mashup of languages, often intended to be humorous. We use this term, rather than &quot;code-switching,&quot; since code-switching</note>

			<note place="foot" n="6"> In the sections below, we gloss over cases where a unit is discontiguous (in one language). Such units are handled specially (we omit details for reasons of space). If a unit would fall outside the bounds of what our special handling can handle, we fuse it with another unit.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="7"> Occasionally no such ITG tree exists, in which case we fuse units as needed until one does.</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>This material is based upon work supported by a seed grant from the Science of Learning Institute at Johns Hopkins University, and also by a Na-tional Science Foundation Graduate Research Fel-lowship (Grant No. DGE-1232825) to the second author. We would like to thank Chadia Abras for useful discussions.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Supplemental Material</head><p>• A video demonstration can be found here:</p><p>https://youtu.be/d5lxyeHIDWI • A live sample version is here: http:// www.clsp.jhu.edu:3030/signin</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ondřej</forename><surname>Bojar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rajen</forename><surname>Chatterjee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christian</forename><surname>Federmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Barry</forename><surname>Haddow</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Matthias</forename><surname>Huck</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chris</forename><surname>Hokamp</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Philipp</forename><surname>Koehn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Varvara</forename><surname>Logacheva</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christof</forename><surname>Monz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Matteo</forename><surname>Negri</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Matt</forename><surname>Post</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Carolina</forename><surname>Scarton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lucia</forename><surname>Specia</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marco</forename><surname>Turchi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Tenth Workshop on Statistical Machine Translation</title>
		<meeting>the Tenth Workshop on Statistical Machine Translation</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="46" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Findings of the 2015 Workshop on Statistical Machine Translation</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Invented versus traditional spelling in first graders&apos; writings: Effects on learning to spell and read</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Linda</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Clarke</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Research in the Teaching of English</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1988-10" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="281" to="309" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Deutschlandfunk</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://www.nachrichtenleicht.de/.Accessed" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2015" to="2024" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Machine translation divergences: A formal description and proposed solution</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bonnie</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Dorr</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Computational Linguistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="597" to="633" />
			<date type="published" when="1994" />
			<publisher>December</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Early childhood bilingualism: Perils and possibilities</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Fred</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Genesee</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Applied Research on Learning</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="21" />
			<date type="published" when="2009-04" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A retrospective on invented spelling and a look forward</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Richard</forename><surname>Gentry</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The Reading Teacher</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">54</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="318" to="332" />
			<date type="published" when="2000-11" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Analyzing learner understanding of novel L2 vocabulary</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rebecca</forename><surname>Knowles</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Adithya</forename><surname>Renduchintala</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Philipp</forename><surname>Koehn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jason</forename><surname>Eisner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>To appear</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Moses: Open source toolkit for statistical machine translation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Philipp</forename><surname>Koehn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hieu</forename><surname>Hoang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alexandra</forename><surname>Birch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chris</forename><surname>Callison-Burch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marcello</forename><surname>Federico</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nicola</forename><surname>Bertoldi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Brooke</forename><surname>Cowan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wade</forename><surname>Shen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christine</forename><surname>Moran</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Richard</forename><surname>Zens</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of ACL: Interactive Poster and Demonstration Sessions</title>
		<meeting>ACL: Interactive Poster and Demonstration Sessions</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="177" to="180" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">We acquire vocabulary and spelling by reading: Additional evidence for the input hypothesis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Stephen</forename><surname>Krashen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The Modern Language Journal</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">73</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="440" to="464" />
			<date type="published" when="1989" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">How well do people spell? Reading Improvement</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Krashen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
			<biblScope unit="page">30</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Lingua</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Ly</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://lingua.ly/.Accessed" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Lingua.ly</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2016" to="2020" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The Alpheios project</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mark</forename><surname>Nelson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://alpheios.net/.Accessed" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2016" to="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Parsing three German treebanks: Lexicalized and unlexicalized baselines</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Anna</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christopher D</forename><surname>Rafferty</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Manning</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Workshop on Parsing German</title>
		<meeting>the Workshop on Parsing German</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="40" to="46" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">User modeling in language learning with macaronic texts</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Adithya</forename><surname>Renduchintala</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rebecca</forename><surname>Knowles</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Philipp</forename><surname>Koehn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jason</forename><surname>Eisner</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of ACL</title>
		<meeting>ACL</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Swych</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://swych.it/.Ac-cessed" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2016" to="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Duolingo: Learn a language for free while helping to translate the web</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Luis Von Ahn</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2013 International Conference on Intelligent User Interfaces</title>
		<meeting>the 2013 International Conference on Intelligent User Interfaces</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="2" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Thought and Language (Revised and Expanded Edition)</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lev</forename><surname>Vygotski˘</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<publisher>MIT press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Stochastic inversion transduction grammars and bilingual parsing of parallel corpora</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dekai</forename><surname>Wu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Computational Linguistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">23</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="377" to="404" />
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
