<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T12:49+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Unsupervised Authorial Clustering Based on Syntactic Structure</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date>August 7-12, 2016</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alon</forename><surname>Daks</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Computer Science Division</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of California</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>94720</postCode>
									<settlement>Berkeley Berkeley</settlement>
									<region>CA</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Aidan</forename><surname>Clark</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Computer Science Division</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of California</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>94720</postCode>
									<settlement>Berkeley Berkeley</settlement>
									<region>CA</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Unsupervised Authorial Clustering Based on Syntactic Structure</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 54th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics-Student Research Workshop</title>
						<meeting>the 54th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics-Student Research Workshop <address><addrLine>Berlin, Germany</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="114" to="118"/>
							<date type="published">August 7-12, 2016</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>This paper proposes a new unsupervised technique for clustering a collection of documents written by distinct individuals into authorial components. We highlight the importance of utilizing syntactic structure to cluster documents by author, and demonstrate experimental results that show the method we outline performs on par with state-of-the-art techniques. Additionally , we argue that this feature set out-performs previous methods in cases where authors consciously emulate each other&apos;s style or are otherwise rhetorically similar.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Unsupervised authorial clustering is the process of partitioning n documents written by k distinct au- thors into k groups of documents segmented by authorship. Nothing is assumed about each docu- ment except that it was written by a single author. <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Koppel et al. (2011)</ref> formulated this problem in a paper focused on clustering five books from the Hebrew Bible. They also consider a 'multi-author document' version of the problem: decomposing sentences from a single composite document gen- erated by merging randomly sampled chunks of text from k authors. <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Akiva and Koppel (2013)</ref> fol- lowed that work with an expanded method, and <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Aldebei et al. (2015)</ref> have since presented an im- proved technique in the 'multi-author document' context by exploiting posterior probabilities of a Naive-Bayesian Model. We consider only the case of clustering n documents written by k authors because we believe that, in most cases of autho- rial decomposition, there is some minimum size of text (a 'document'), for which it can be reliably as- serted that only a single author is present. Further- more, this formulation precludes results dependent on a random document generation procedure.</p><p>In this paper, we argue that the biblical cluster- ing done by <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Koppel et al. (2011)</ref> and by <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Aldebei et al. (2015)</ref> do not represent a grouping around true authorship within the Bible, but rather around common topics or shared style. We demonstrate a general technique that can accurately discern multiple authors contained within the Books of Ezekiel and Jeremiah. Prior work assumes that each prophetic book reflects a single source, and does not consider the consensus among modern biblical scholars that the books of Ezekiel and Jeremiah were written by multiple individuals.</p><p>To cluster documents by true authorship, we propose that considering part-of-speech (POS) n- grams as features most distinctly identifies an indi- vidual writer. The use of syntactic structure in au- thorial research has been studied before. <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Baayen et al. (1996)</ref> introduced syntactic information mea- sures for authorship attribution and Stamatatos <ref type="bibr">(2009)</ref> argued that POS information could reflect a more reliable authorial fingerprint than lexical information. Both <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">Zheng et al. (2006)</ref> and <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Layton et al. (2013)</ref> propose that syntactic feature sets are reliable predictors for authorial attribu- tion, and <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Tschuggnall and Specht (2014)</ref> demon- strates, with modest success, authorial decompo- sition using pq-grams extracted from sentences' syntax trees. We found that by combining the fea- ture set of POS n-grams with a clustering approach similar to the one presented by <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Akiva (2013)</ref>, our method of decomposition attains higher accuracy than Tschuggnall's method, which also considers grammatical style. Additionally, in cases where authors are rhetorically similar, our framework outperforms techniques outlined by <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Akiva (2013)</ref> and <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Aldebei (2015)</ref>, which both rely on word oc- currences as features.</p><p>This paper is organized as follows: section 2 outlines our proposed framework, section 3 clari-fies our method in detail through an example, sec- tion 4 contains results, section 5 tests an expla- nation of our results, and section 6 concludes our findings and discusses future work.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Our Framework</head><p>Given n documents written by k distinct authors, where it is assumed that each document is written entirely by one of the k authors, our method pro- ceeds in the following way:</p><p>First, represent each document as a frequency vector reflecting all n-grams occurring in the 'POS-translated' document.</p><p>Second, cluster documents into k groups using an unsupervised clustering algorithm.</p><p>Third, determine 'core elements', documents that most strongly represent authorship attributes of their respective clusters.</p><p>Fourth, use 'core elements' to train a supervised classifier in order to improve accuracies of docu- ments that were not central to any cluster.</p><p>A key improvement our framework presents over prior techniques is in step one, where we represent documents in terms of POS n-grams. Specifically, each document, x i , is transformed into a 'POS-translated' version, x i , such that every word or punctuation symbol from the original doc- ument is replaced with its respective POS or punc- tuation token in the translated version. Consider the following sentences from a New York Times (NYT) column written by Paul Krugman: "Last week the Federal Reserve chose not to raise inter- est rates. It was the right decision." In the 'POS- translated' version these sentences appear as "JJ NN DT NNP NNP NN RB TO VB NN NNS PE- RIOD PRP VBD DT JJ NN PERIOD". <ref type="bibr">1</ref> We use a POS tagger from the Natural Language Toolkit to translate English documents ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Bird et al., 2009)</ref> and use hand annotations for the Hebrew Bible. Our framework will work with any text for which POS-annotations are obtainable. The requirement that k is a fixed parameter is a limitation of the set of unsupervised clustering algorithms available in step two.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Clarifying Details with NYT Columns</head><p>We shall describe a clustering of New York Times columns to clarify our framework. The NYT cor-</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">Authors 1st 2nd 3rd TF-PK 4</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>-4 5 -5 3 -4 TF-GC 3 -5 3 -4 4 -4 TF-MD 5 -5 3 -4 3 -5 GC-PK 4 -4 3 -5 3 -4 MD-PK 3 -5 3 -4 4 -4 GC-MD 3 -5 3 -4 4 -4</head><p>Table 1: The top three ranges for n-grams by F1 accuracy for each two-way split of NYT columnists. Here, TF = Thomas Friedman, GC = Gail Collins, MD = Maureen Dowd, PK = Paul Krugman. pus is used both because the author of each doc- ument is known with certainty and because it is a canonical dataset that has served as a benchmark for both <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Akiva and Koppel (2013)</ref> and <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Aldebei et al. (2015</ref> In step one, the documents are converted into their 'POS-translated' form as previously outlined. Each document is represented as a frequency vec- tor that reflects all 3, 4, and 5-grams that appear in the 'POS-translated' corpus. This range of n- grams was determined through validation of dif- ferent values for n across several datasets. Re- sults of this validation for the two way split over NYT columnists is displayed in <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>. These re- sults are consistent when validating against other datasets. Using 3, 4, and 5-grams, the resulting design matrix has dimension 629 by 302,395. We re-weight every element in the design matrix ac- cording to its term frequency-inverse document frequency.</p><p>In step two, we apply spectral clustering to the design matrix to partition the documents into two clusters. This is implemented with the Shi and Malik (2000) algorithm, which solves a convex relaxation of the normalized cuts problem on the affinity graph <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Pedregosa et al., 2011</ref>). Edge- weights of the affinity graph are computed using a linear kernel. In the case of clustering several (k &gt; 2) authors, we apply the <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Yu and Shi (2003)</ref> algorithm to perform multiclass spectral cluster- ing.</p><p>In step three, we calculate the centroid of each cluster produced by step two. For each document <ref type="table">Table 2</ref>: Results when clustering 629 documents written by Maureen Dowd and Paul Krugman into two clusters.</p><note type="other">Columnist Cluster I Cluster II Dowd 294 4 Krugman 3 328</note><p>x i , we determine θ i , the angle between that docu- ment and the centroid of its cluster, and call a doc- ument a 'core element' if θ i is within 2 standard deviations of the average of θ i in x i 's cluster. In step four, 'core elements' are used to train a 500 tree random forest where at each split the stan- dard heuristic of √ p features are considered (here p = 302, 395). Finally, we reclassify all 629 doc- uments according to this random forest to produce our final class labels, summarized in <ref type="table">Table 2</ref>. The final accuracy of the Dowd-Krugman clustering, measured as an F1-score, is 98.8%.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Results</head><p>All accuracy scores given in the rest of this pa- per are calculated using the F1-score. Because our technique contains stochastic elements, results re- flect an average of 20 runs.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">NYT Columns</head><p>When clustering over all six binary-pairs of NYT columnists, our framework achieves an average accuracy of 94.5%, ranging from 90.0% to 98.8%. <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Aldebei et al. (2015)</ref> addresses the slightly dif- ferent problem of decomposing artificially merged NYT documents, and acknowledging the distinc- tion between the two problems, our results are comparable to their accuracies which range from 93.3% to 96.1%.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">Sanditon: An Uncompleted Novel</head><p>Another canonical authorship test is that of the novel Sanditon, a text left incomplete at the death of its author, Jane Austen, and finished some years later by an anonymous person known as "Another Lady." She closely emulated Austen's style and added 19 chapters to Austen's original 11. Re- searchers have long examined this text and most recently <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Moon et al. (2006)</ref> analyzed Sanditon us- ing supervised techniques in the context of author- ship attribution. Much progress has been made in the field since then, but examining Sanditon has fallen out of style. Our framework clus- ters Austen's chapters from Another Lady's with 93.8% accuracy, only mislabeling two documents.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3">Obama-McCain &amp; Ezekiel-Jeremiah</head><p>In order to confirm our framework is accurate over a variety of documents, we considered campaign speeches from the 2008 presidential election. Col- lecting 27 speeches from President Obama and 20 from Senator McCain, we expected our technique to excel in this context. We found instead that our method performed exceptionally poorly, cluster- ing these speeches with only 74.2% accuracy. In- deed, we were further surprised to discover that by adjusting our framework to be similar to that pre- sented in <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Akiva and Koppel (2013)</ref> and <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Aldebei et al. (2015)</ref> -by replacing POS n-grams with or- dinary word occurrences in step one -our frame- work performed very well, clustering at 95.3%. Similarly, our framework performed poorly on the Books of Ezekiel and Jeremiah from the He- brew Bible. Using the English-translated King James Version, and considering each chapter as an individual document, our framework clusters the 48 chapters of Ezekiel and the 52 chapters of Jeremiah at 54.7%. <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Aldebei et al. (2015)</ref> reports 98.0% on this dataset, and when considering the original English text instead of the POS-translated text, our framework achieves 99.0%. The simulta- neous success of word features and failure of POS features on these two datasets seemed to com- pletely contradict our previous results.</p><p>We propose two explanations. First, perhaps too much syntactic structure is lost during translation. This could certainly be a factor, but does not ex- plain the Obama-McCain results. The second ex- planation comes from the wide consensus among biblical scholars that there was no single 'Ezekiel' or 'Jeremiah' entirely responsible for each book. Instead, the books are composites from a num- ber of authors, sometimes written over the span of hundreds of years <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(McKane, 1986;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b19">Zimmerli, 1979;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Mowinckel, 1914)</ref>. <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Koppel et al. (2011)</ref> ac- knowledges this shortcoming in their original pa- per, and suggest that in this authorial interpretation their clustering is one of style, not authorship. We hypothesize that in both failed cases, accuracy is low because our assumption that only two authors were represented among the documents is incor- rect. This theory holds for the Obama-McCain dataset, because Obama had up to three primary speechwriters during the '08 election and McCain likely had a similar number <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Parker, 2008)</ref>. Per- haps emulating syntactic patterns is more difficult than emulating word choice. If so, using word fea-  tures, a model can discern Obama's rhetoric from that of McCain. However, since the syntax of more than two individuals is present in the text, POS features cannot accurately cluster the docu- ments into two groups. Our goal is for POS fea- tures to cluster more accurately than word features when the true authorship of the documents is cor- rectly considered.</p><note type="other">Author Cluster I Cluster II Ezekiel 1 37 2 Ezekiel 2 1 8</note></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Testing Our Theory</head><p>We first attempt to cluster the Ezekiel and Jeremiah texts in the original Hebrew in order to test if too much syntactic structure is lost dur- ing translation. For the Hebrew text, we use hand-tagged POS information because a reliable automatic tagger was not available <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">(van Peursen et al., 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Roorda, 2015)</ref>. Clustering Ezekiel and Jeremiah using Hebrew POS features obtains 62.5% accuracy. This is an improvement over the English text, but still performs far worse than lex- ical feature sets. We next attempt to cluster the Ezekiel and Jeremiah texts according to the authorial strata within each book that is widely agreed upon by biblical scholars, in order to test if incorrect au- thorial assumptions were causing the decrease in accuracy. Unfortunately, there is no public break- down of Obama and McCain speeches by speech- writer, so testing our hypothesis is limited here to the biblical dataset.</p><p>We therefore cluster the Book of Ezekiel assum- ing there are two nested authors, which accord- ing to modern scholarship are Ezekiel 1 (chap- ters 1-39) and Ezekiel 2 (chapters 40-48) <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">(Zimmerli, 1979</ref>). Summarized in <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Table 3</ref>, accord- ing to this division our framework clusters the Ezekiel chapters with 93.6% accuracy, mislabel- ing only three documents. We also consider the Book of Jeremiah, which is composed of two pri- mary authors with four secondary authors. In clus- <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Ezekiel 1  32  2  5  0  Ezekiel 2  1  8  0  0  Jeremiah 1  0  0  21  2  Jeremiah 2  0  0  0  14   Table 5</ref>: Results when clustering Ezekiel 1 and 2 and Jeremiah 1 and 2 simultaneously with k = 4.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Author C I C II C III C IV</head><p>tering a corpus containing Jeremiah 1 (23 non- contiguous chapters) and Jeremiah 2 (14 non- contiguous chapters) <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(McKane, 1986)</ref>, our frame- work divides the 37 chapters into two groups with 94.5% accuracy, mislabeling only two documents. These results are summarized in <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">Table 4</ref>. When considering the 4-way split between Ezekiel 1, Ezekiel 2, Jeremiah 1 and Jeremiah 2, our method achieves 87.5% accuracy as summarized in <ref type="table">Ta- ble 5</ref>. When comparing these results with those ob- tained by looking at word frequencies in the orig- inal Hebrew texts partitioned into the four cor- rect authors, we find that our approach performs significantly better. With word frequencies as features, our framework clusters Ezekiel 1 from Ezekiel 2 with only 76.3% accuracy, Jeremiah 1 from Jeremiah 2 with only 74.9% accuracy, and crucially, clusters the four-way between both Ezekiels and both Jeremiahs with only 47.9% ac- curacy. While lexical features outperform syntac- tic features when considering incorrect authorship, syntactic features substantially outperform lexical features when considering the true authorial divi- sions of Ezekiel and Jeremiah.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Conclusion and Future Work</head><p>We have demonstrated a new framework for au- thorial clustering that not only clusters canon- ical datasets with state-of-the-art accuracy, but also discerns nested authorship within the Hebrew Bible more accurately than prior work. While we believe it is possible for an author to emulate an- other author's word choice, it is much more dif- ficult to emulate unconscious syntactic structure. These syntactic patterns, rather than lexical fre- quencies, may therefore be key to understanding authorial fingerprints. Finding testing data for this problem is difficult, since documents for which authorship is misconstrued or obfuscated but for which true authorship is known with certainty are rare. However, when clustering texts for which au- thorship is not known, one would wish to have a framework which most accurately discerns author-ship, rather than rhetorical similarity. We believe that our framework, and syntactic feature sets in particular, clusters documents based on authorship more accurately than prior work. While we have shown that POS feature sets can succeed indepen- dently, future work should examine augmenting syntactic and lexical feature sets in order to utilize the benefits of each.</p><p>Finally, authorial clustering performs poorly when the number of true and expected authors within a corpus do not match. An important next step is to automatically identify the number of au- thors contained within a set of documents. We believe that a more reliable method of generating 'core elements' is essential, and should not be re- liant on a predetermined number of authors.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" validated="false"><head>Table 3 : Results when clustering the Hebrew text of the Book of Ezekiel split over the two authors.</head><label>3</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Author 
Cluster I Cluster II 
Jeremiah 1 
21 
2 
Jeremiah 2 
0 
14 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" validated="false"><head>Table 4 :</head><label>4</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Results when clustering the Hebrew text of the 
Book of Jeremiah split over the two primary authors. 

</table></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> A list of POS tags and explanations: http://www.ling.upenn.edu/courses/ Fall 2003/ling001/penn treebank pos.html</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>We thank Laurent El Ghaoui, Professor of EECS and IEOR, UC Berkeley, and Ronald Hendel, Norma and Sam Dabby Professor of Hebrew Bible and Jewish Studies, UC Berkeley, for comments that greatly improved the paper.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A generic unsupervised method for decomposing multi-author documents</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Navot</forename><surname>Akiva</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Moshe</forename><surname>Koppel</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of the American Society for Information Science and Technology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2256" to="2264" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Unsupervised decomposition of a multi-author document based on naive-bayesian model</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Khaled</forename><surname>Aldebei</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xiangjian</forename><surname>He</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jie</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 53rd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics and the 7th International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing</title>
		<meeting>the 53rd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics and the 7th International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="501" to="505" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Short Papers</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Outside the cave of shadows: Using syntactic annotation to enhance authorship attribution</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Harald</forename><surname>Baayen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hans</forename><surname>Van Halteren</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Fiona</forename><surname>Tweedie</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Literary and Linguistic Computing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="121" to="131" />
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Natural Language Processing with Python</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Steven</forename><surname>Bird</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ewan</forename><surname>Klein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Edward</forename><surname>Loper</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<pubPlace>O&apos;Reilly Media</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Unsupervised decomposition of a document into authorial components</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Moshe</forename><surname>Koppel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Navot</forename><surname>Akiva</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Idan</forename><surname>Dershowitz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nachum</forename><surname>Dershowitz</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 49th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the 49th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1356" to="1364" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Automated unsupervised authorship analysis using evidence accumulation clustering</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Robert</forename><surname>Layton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Paul</forename><surname>Watters</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Richard</forename><surname>Dazeley</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Natural Language Engineering</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">A Critical and Exegetical Commentary on Jeremiah</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">William</forename><surname>Mckane</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1986" />
			<pubPlace>Edinburgh, Edinburgh, UK</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Document author classification using generalized discriminant analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Todd</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Moon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Peg</forename><surname>Howland</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jacob H</forename><surname>Gunther</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. Workshop on Text Mining, SIAM Int&apos;l Conf. on Data Mining</title>
		<meeting>Workshop on Text Mining, SIAM Int&apos;l Conf. on Data Mining</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sigmund</forename><surname>Mowinckel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Zur Komposition des Buches Jeremia</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Kristiania</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1914" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">What would obama say? New York Times</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ashley</forename><surname>Parker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008-01-20" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Scikit-learn: Machine learning in Python</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Pedregosa</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Varoquaux</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Gramfort</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Michel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Thirion</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Grisel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Blondel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Prettenhofer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Weiss</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Dubourg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Vanderplas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Passos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Cournapeau</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Brucher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Perrot</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Duchesnay</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Machine Learning Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2825" to="2830" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Laf-fabric software</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dirk</forename><surname>Roorda</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Normalized cuts and image segmentation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jianbo</forename><surname>Shi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jitendra</forename><surname>Malik</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEE Transactions On Pattern Analysis And Machine Intelligence</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="888" to="905" />
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A survey of modern authorship attribution methods</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Efstathios</forename><surname>Stamatatos</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of the American Society for Information Science and Technology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">60</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="538" to="556" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Enhancing authorship attribution by utilizing syntax tree profiles</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Tschuggnall</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gunther</forename><surname>Specht</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 14th Conference of the European Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the 14th Conference of the European Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="195" to="199" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Van Peursen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Sc</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Sikkel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Roorda</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Hebrew text database etcbc4b</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="doi">10.17026/dans-z6y-skyh.DANS</idno>
		<ptr target="http://dx.doi.org/10.17026/dans-z6y-skyh.DANS" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Multiclass spectral clustering</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Stella</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jianbo</forename><surname>Yu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Shi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Ninth IEEE International Conference on Computer Vision</title>
		<meeting>the Ninth IEEE International Conference on Computer Vision</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="313" to="319" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A framework for authorship identification of online messages: Writing-style features and classification techniques</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rong</forename><surname>Zheng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jiexun</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hsinchun</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Zan</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Am. Soc. Inf. Sci. Technol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">57</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="378" to="393" />
			<date type="published" when="2006-02" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Ezekiel 1-2: A Commentary on the Book of the Prophet Ezekiel</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Walther</forename><surname>Zimmerli</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1979" />
			<publisher>Fortress Press</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Philadelphia, Philadelphia, US</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
