<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T11:37+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">new/s/leak-Information Extraction and Visualization for Investigative Data Journalists</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date>August 7-12, 2016</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Seid</forename><forename type="middle">Muhie</forename><surname>Yimam</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Computer Science Department Technische Universität Darmstadt Graphic Interactive Systems Group Computer Science Department</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Technische Universität Darmstadt ‡ SPIEGEL-Verlag Hamburg</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Heiner</forename><surname>Ulrich</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Computer Science Department Technische Universität Darmstadt Graphic Interactive Systems Group Computer Science Department</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Technische Universität Darmstadt ‡ SPIEGEL-Verlag Hamburg</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tatiana</forename><surname>Von Landesberger</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Computer Science Department Technische Universität Darmstadt Graphic Interactive Systems Group Computer Science Department</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Technische Universität Darmstadt ‡ SPIEGEL-Verlag Hamburg</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marcel</forename><surname>Rosenbach</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Computer Science Department Technische Universität Darmstadt Graphic Interactive Systems Group Computer Science Department</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Technische Universität Darmstadt ‡ SPIEGEL-Verlag Hamburg</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michaela</forename><surname>Regneri</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Computer Science Department Technische Universität Darmstadt Graphic Interactive Systems Group Computer Science Department</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Technische Universität Darmstadt ‡ SPIEGEL-Verlag Hamburg</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alexander</forename><surname>Panchenko</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Computer Science Department Technische Universität Darmstadt Graphic Interactive Systems Group Computer Science Department</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Technische Universität Darmstadt ‡ SPIEGEL-Verlag Hamburg</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Franziska</forename><surname>Lehmann</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Computer Science Department Technische Universität Darmstadt Graphic Interactive Systems Group Computer Science Department</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Technische Universität Darmstadt ‡ SPIEGEL-Verlag Hamburg</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Uli</forename><surname>Fahrer</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Computer Science Department Technische Universität Darmstadt Graphic Interactive Systems Group Computer Science Department</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Technische Universität Darmstadt ‡ SPIEGEL-Verlag Hamburg</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chris</forename><surname>Biemann</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Computer Science Department Technische Universität Darmstadt Graphic Interactive Systems Group Computer Science Department</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Technische Universität Darmstadt ‡ SPIEGEL-Verlag Hamburg</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kathrin</forename><surname>Ballweg</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Computer Science Department Technische Universität Darmstadt Graphic Interactive Systems Group Computer Science Department</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Technische Universität Darmstadt ‡ SPIEGEL-Verlag Hamburg</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">†</forename><surname>Fg</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Computer Science Department Technische Universität Darmstadt Graphic Interactive Systems Group Computer Science Department</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Technische Universität Darmstadt ‡ SPIEGEL-Verlag Hamburg</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Language</forename><surname>Technology</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Computer Science Department Technische Universität Darmstadt Graphic Interactive Systems Group Computer Science Department</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Technische Universität Darmstadt ‡ SPIEGEL-Verlag Hamburg</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">new/s/leak-Information Extraction and Visualization for Investigative Data Journalists</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 54th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics-System Demonstrations</title>
						<meeting>the 54th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics-System Demonstrations <address><addrLine>Berlin, Germany</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="163" to="168"/>
							<date type="published">August 7-12, 2016</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>We present new/s/leak, a novel tool developed for and with the help of journalists , which enables the automatic analysis and discovery of newsworthy stories from large textual datasets. We rely on different NLP preprocessing steps such named entity tagging, extraction of time expressions , entity networks, relations and meta-data. The system features an intuitive web-based user interface based on network visualization combined with data exploring methods and various search and faceting mechanisms. We report the current state of the software and exemplify it with the WikiLeaks PlusD (Cablegate) data.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>This paper presents new/s/leak 1 , the network of searchable leaks, a journalistic software for inves- tigating and visualizing large textual datasets (see live demo here 2 ). Investigation of unstructured document collections is a laborious task: The sheer amount of content can be vast, for instance, the WikiLeaks PlusD 3 dataset contains around 250 thousand cables. Typically, these collections largely consist of unstructured text with additional metadata such as date, location or sender and re- ceiver of messages. The largest part of these documents are irrelevant for journalistic investi- gations, concealing the crucial storylines. For in- stance, war crime stories in WikiLeaks were hid- 1 http://newsleak.io 2 http://bev.lt.informatik.tu-darmstadt.de/ newsleak/ 3 https://wikileaks.org/plusd/about den and scattered among hundreds of thousands of routine conversations between officials. There- fore, if journalists do not know in advance what to look for in the document collections, they can only vaguely target all people and organizations (named entities) of public interest.</p><p>Currently, the discovery of novel and relevant stories in large data leaks requires many people and a large time budget, both of which are typi- cally not available to journalists: If the documents are confidential like datasets from an informer, only a few selected journalists will have access to the classified data, and those few will have to carry the whole workload. On the other hand, if the doc- uments are publicly available (e.g. a leak posted on the web), the texts have to be analyzed under enormous time pressure, because the journalistic value of each story decreases rapidly if other me- dia publish it before.</p><p>There is a plethora of tools (see Section 2) for data journalist that automatically reveal and visualize interesting correlations hidden within large number-centric datasets ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Janicke et al., 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Kucher and Kerren, 2014</ref>). However, these tools provide very limited automatic support with vi- sual guidance through plain text collections. Some tools include shallow natural language processing, but mostly restricted to English. There is no tool that works for multiple languages, handles a large number of text collections, analyzes and visual- izes named entities along with the relations be- tween them and allows editing what is considered as an entity. Moreover, available software is usu- ally not open source but rather expensive and often requires substantial training, which is unsuitable for a journalist under time pressure and no prior experience with such software.</p><p>The goal of new/s/leak is to provide journalists with a novel visual interactive data analysis sup- port that combines the latest advances from natural language processing approaches and information visualization. It enables journalists to swiftly pro- cess large collections of text documents in order to find interesting pieces of information.</p><p>This paper presents the core concepts and ar- chitecture behind the new/s/leak. We also show an in-depth analysis of user requirements and how we implement and address these. Finally, we dis- cuss our prototype, which will be made available in open source 4 under a lenient license. <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Kirkpatrick (2015)</ref> states that investigative jour- nalist should look at the facts, identify what is wrong with the situation, uncover the truth, and write a story that places the facts in context. This work explains traditional story discovery engine components which, on the technical side, consist of a knowledge base, an inference engine and an easy to use user interface for visualization.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Related work</head><p>Discussions with our partner journalists confirm this view: newsworthy stories are not evident from leaked documents, but following up on informa- tion from leaks might reveal relevant pointers for journalistic research.</p><p>Cohen et al. (2011) outline a vision for "a cloud for the crowd" system to support collaborative in- vestigative journalism, in which computational re- sources support human expertise for efficient and effective investigative journalism.</p><p>The DocumentCloud 5 and the Overview 6 project are the most popular tools comparable to the new/s/leak, both designed for journalists deal- ing with large set of documents. DocumentCloud is a tool for building a document archive for the material related to an investigation. Similarly to our system, people, places and organizations are recognized in documents. We put additional fo- cus on the UI by adding a graph-based visualiza- tion and better support for document browsing. Overview is designed to help journalists find sto- ries in large number of documents by topical clus- tering. This is a complementary approach to ours: rather than keyword-based topics, our tool centers around entities and text-extracted relations. Fur-ther, we added advanced editing capabilities for users to add entities and edit the whole network.</p><p>Aleph.grano.cc visualizes connections of peo- ple, places and organizations extracted from text documents, but leaves the relationship types un- derspecified. Detective.io, a platform for collabo- rative network analysis, does some of the visual- izations and annotations we are working on. How- ever, there is a crucial difference: Detective.io as- sumes a rigid data structure (e.g."corporate net- works") and the user has to fill the underlying database entirely manually. Our tool targets on unstructured sources and extracts networks from text, enabling navigation to the sources. Jigsaw 7 extracts named entities from text collections and computes various plots from them, but received lit- tle attention from journalists due to its unintuitive user interface.</p><p>With new/s/leak, we want to develop existing tools a step further, by combining the automation of entity and relationship extraction with an intu- itive and appealing visual interface.</p><p>New/s/leak is based on two prior systems devel- oped namely from the works of ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Benikova et al., 2014</ref>), Network of the Day 8 and ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Kochtchi et al., 2014</ref>), Network of Names 9 . Both tools automat- ically analyze named entities and their relation- ships and present an interactive network visual- ization that allows to retrieve the original sources for displayed relations. In the current project, we add support for faceted data browsing, a timeline, a better access to source documents and a possi- bility to tag and edit visualizations.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Objectives and User Requirements</head><p>The objective of new/s/leak is to support investiga- tive data journalists in finding important facts and stories in large unstructured text collections. The two key elements are an easy-to-use interactive vi- sualization and linguistic preprocessing.</p><p>To gain a more precise focus for our devel- opment, we conducted structured interviews with potential users. They seek for an answer to the question "Who does what to whom?" -possibly amended with "When and where?". At the same time, they always need access to the source docu- ments, to verify the machine-given answers. The outcome of these interviews are summarized in the following requirements. 1) Identify key persons, places and organizations. 2) Browse the collection, identify interesting doc- uments and read documents in detail.</p><p>3) Analyze the connections between entities. 4) Assess temporal evolution of the documents. 5) Explore geographic distribution of events. 6) Annotate documents with findings as well as edit the data to enhance data quality. 7) Save and share selected documents.</p><p>While some of these requirements (like docu- ment browsing) are standard search features, oth- ers (like annotation and sharing) are usually not yet integrated in journalism tools. The final ver- sion of our system will include all of these fea- tures.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Implementation details 4.1 System</head><p>The new/s/leak tool consists of two major parts shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref>: The backend provides various NLP tools for document pre-processing and docu- ment analysis (Sec. 5), interactive visualization for investigative journalism (Sec. 6). The implemen- tation of the backend and frontend components of new/s/leak are integrated in a modular way that allows e.g. adding a different relation extraction mechanism or support for multiple languages. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">Demo datasets</head><p>We demonstrate capabilities of our system on two well-known cases: 1) The well-investigated WikiLeaks PlusD "Ca- blegate" collection, a collection of diplomatic notes from over 45 years originating from US em- bassies all over the world.</p><p>2) The Enron email dataset ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Klimt and Yang, 2004</ref>) is a collection of email messages which is available publicly from the Enron Corporation.</p><p>The dataset comprises over 600,000 messages be- tween 158 employees. This example shows the tools' general applicability to email leaks.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Backend: information extraction</head><p>The new/s/leak backend uses different NLP tools for preprocessing and analysis, integrated with a relational database, a NoSQL document store and some specific retrieval methods. First, documents are pre-processed and converted to an interme- diate new/s/leak document representation. This format is generic enough to represent collections from any possible source, such as emails, rela- tional databases or XML documents.</p><p>In a second step, our NLP preprocessing ex- tracts important entities, metadata (like time and location), term co-occurrences, keywords, and re- lationships among entities. We store relevant doc- uments and extracted entities in a PostgreSQL 10 database and an ElasticSearch 11 index. We ex- plain the following steps using the Wikileaks Ca- blegate dataset as an example, but the tool is not limited to this single dataset.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.1">Preprocessing</head><p>The first step of new/s/leak workflow is prepro- cessing the input documents and represent them in new/s/leak's intermediate document representa- tion. Preprocessing of the Cablegate dataset re- quires truecasing the original documents which are mostly in capitals. The work of <ref type="bibr">Lita et al. (2003)</ref> indicates that truceasing improves the F- score of named entity recognition by 26%. We used a frequency based approach for case restor- ing based on a very large true-cased background corpus. Once case is restored, we extract meta- data from the document, including the document creation dates, subject, message sender document creator, and other metadata already marked in the dataset. Metadata is stored in a database as triples of (n, t, v) where n is the name, t is the data type (e.g. text or date) and v is the value of the meta- data. The tool further supports manual identifica- tion of metadata during the analysis and produc- tion stages.  Recognition of named entities and related terms are key steps in the investigative data-driven journalistic process. For this purpose, we first automatically identify four classes of entities, namely person (PER), organization (ORG), loca- tion (LOC) and miscellaneous (MISC) using the named entity recognition tool from Epic 12 . We as- sume relationships between entities whenever the two entities co-occur in a document. In order to extract relevant keywords regarding two entities, we follow the approach by <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Biemann et al. (2007)</ref>. Furthermore, we extract entity relation labels by computing document keywords using JTopia <ref type="bibr">13</ref> . JTopia extracts relevant key terms for search based on part of speech information. To label the rela- tionship between two entities, the most frequent keywords from the documents where the two en- tities appeared together is used. To extract tempo- ral expressions, we use the Heideltime <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(Strötgen, 2015)</ref> tool, which disambiguates temporal expres- sions based on document creation times. For the WikiLeaks dataset, it is possible to extract and dis- ambiguate more than 3.9 million temporal expres- sions.</p><p>All the extraction and processing work-flows of the new/s/leak components are implemented using the Apache Spark cluster computing framework for parallel computations. <ref type="table">Table 1</ref> shows the dif- ferent statistics for the WikiLeaks PlusD and En- ron datasets.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Frontend: interactive visualization</head><p>Journalists can browse through the document col- lection using an interactive visual interface (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 2</ref>). It enables faceted document exploration within several views: 1) Graph view: shows named entities and their re- lations. 2) Map view: shows document distribution in ge- ographic space. 3) Document timeline view: shows document fre-quency over time.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>4) Document view: is composed of a) document list and b) document text for reading.</head><p>The views are interactive so that the user can browse and explore the document collection on de- mand. The user starts with exploring entities and their connections in the graph view or by search- ing for entities and keywords. All interactions in the views define a filter that constrains the current document set, which in turn changes information displayed in the views. The user can assess docu- ment frequency in a map or in the timeline, drill down and select documents from the result list, and read them closely. User-selected entities are highlighted in the documents.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Graph view: entities and their co-occurrences</head><p>The graph view shows a set of entities as nodes and their connections as links. Node size denotes the frequency of an entity in the document col- lection, node color denotes the entity type. The co-occurrence of entities within the documents is shown by edge thickness and edge label. The user can explore the entities and their connec- tions via expanding the graph along the neighbors of a selected entity (plus button). The expanded entities are slowly faded in, so that the user can easily spot which entities appeared. Moreover, the user can drill down into the data by displaying the so-called ego network of a selected entity. Click- ing on nodes and edges retrieves the respective documents.</p><p>Map view. The map view shows the document frequency distribution over the geographic space. Users can hover over a country to see the number of documents mentioning this geographic area, ef- fectively using the map as faceted search.</p><p>Document timeline. The document timeline shows the number of documents over time. We use a bar chart with logarithmic scale as it better adheres to the exponential document distribution characteristics. The users can drill down in time to see the document distribution over years, months or days. It is also possible to select a time interval for which the corresponding documents are shown in the document view (see below).</p><p>Document view. The document view shows a list of documents with their title or subject as se- lected by the currently active filters. For large document collections, the documents are loaded on demand. The user can browse the list and identify documents for close reading (bold, open folder icon). The document text view shows the full text of the document, where the entities dis- played in the graph are underlined. The under- line color corresponds to the type of entity. If the user selected entities in the graph, these entities are highlighted with the background color of the entity. This "close reading" mode enables users to verify hypotheses they perceive in the "distant reading" <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Moretti, 2007)</ref> visualizations.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.1">Faceted search</head><p>The different levels of visualizations enable users to explore the dataset via navigation through doc- ument collection <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Miller and Remington, 2004</ref>). Another highly complementary paradigm for in- formation retrieval used in our system, and also one highly expected by users, is searching. Dur- ing navigation, users explore the document collec- tion interactively, browse with the help of the vi- sualization interfaces, zoom in and out, gradually discovering topics, entities and facts mentioned in the corpus.</p><p>In contrast, searching in our system as- sumes that a user issues a conventional faceted search (Tunkelang, 2009) query being a free com- bination of a full text queries with filters on docu- ment metadata. The result of such a faceted search is a set of documents that satisfy the specified facets, i.e. search conditions, formulated at query time, acting as a filter. Here facets can be any metadata initially associated with the document (e.g. date, sender or destination) extracted auto- matically (e.g. named entities or topics). Search results are presented to the user as a list of docu- ments or in a form of a graph that corresponds to the document view of our system (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 2</ref>).</p><p>Search and navigation compliment each other during a journalistic investigation. For instance, a user can get an idea about information available in the collection via interactive visualization inter- face (see Section 6). This navigation session may trigger a concrete journalistic hypothesis. In this case, during the next step a user may want to issue a specific search query to find documents that sup- port or falsify the hypothesis. To implement this search functionality, we rely on ElasticSearch.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7">User Study</head><p>We conducted a user study to analyze the usability of the provided functions in the interactive visual interface. We asked 10 volunteer students of var- ious major subjects to perform investigative tasks using our tool. The tasks covered all views. They included finding documents of a particular date, opening a document, selecting countries in a map, showing and expanding entity network, assessing entity type etc. We assessed subjective user expe- rience.</p><p>The results showed that the implemented visu- alizations were intuitive and the interactive func- tions were easy to use for the requested tasks. The volunteers especially appreciated the drill down in the timeline, the fading in of newly appeared nodes and edges in the graph. The legend and tooltips were very often used as a guidance in the interface. Upon users' feedback, we extended zooming and panning functions in the graph and included highlighting of open documents in the document list. We improved the graph layout and look for reducing edge and node overplotting.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="8">Conclusion and future work</head><p>In this paper, we presented new/s/leak, an in- vestigative tool to support data journalists in ex- tracting important storylines from large text doc- uments. The backend of new/s/leak comprises of different NLP tools for preprocessing, analyz- ing and extracting objects such as named enti- ties, relationships, term co-occurrences, keywords and event time expressions. In the frontend, new/s/leak provides network visualization with different views supporting navigating, annotating, and editing extracted information. We also devel- oped a demo system presenting the current state of the new/s/leak tool and conducted a user study to evaluate the effectiveness of the system.</p><p>We are currently extending the tool to meet the remaining journalists' requirements. In particu- lar, we include features for annotating entities and their relations with explanations, for saving a par- ticular view to share it with colleagues or for later use. Moreover, we will provide journalists with the possibility to further edit this sharable view. Additional features for manual data curation will enhance data quality for analysis while ensuring protection of sources and compliance with legal issues. We will also integrate adaptive annotation machine learning approach ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Yimam et al., 2016)</ref> into new/s/leak to automatically identify interest- ing objects based on the journalists' interaction and feedback. Further, we will investigate pulling in other information from linked open data and the web.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: Schema of new/s/leak for visual support of investigative analysis in text collections.</figDesc><graphic url="image-1.png" coords="3,72.00,481.34,218.26,80.31" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Dataset</head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2: Interactive Visualization Interface composed of graph view on entities, document distribution over time, list of selected documents and a map of document geo-distribution.</figDesc></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="4"> http://github.com/tudarmstadt-lt/newsleak 5 https://www.documentcloud.org/home 6 https://https://www.overviewdocs.com</note>

			<note place="foot" n="7"> http://www.cc.gatech.edu/gvu/ii/jigsaw 8 http://tagesnetzwerk.de 9 http://maggie.lt.informatik.tu-darmstadt. de/thesis/master/NetworksOfNames</note>

			<note place="foot" n="10"> http://www.postgresql.org 11 https://www.elastic.co</note>

			<note place="foot" n="12"> https://github.com/dlwh/epic 13 http://github.com/srijiths/jtopia</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgements</head><p>The authors are grateful to data journalists at Spiegel Verlag for their helpful insights into jour-nalistic work and for the identification of tool re-quirements. The authors wish to thank Lukas Ray-mann, Patrick Mell, Bettina Johanna Ballin, Nils Christopher Boeschen, Patrick Wilhelmi-Dworski and Florian Zouhar for their help with system im-plementation and conduction of the user study. The work is being funded by Volkswagen Foun-dation under Grant Nr. 90 847.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Network of the day: Aggregating and visualizing entity networks from online sources</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Benikova</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">U</forename><surname>Fahrer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Gabriel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Kaufmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Yimam</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Von Landesberger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Biemann</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. NLP4CMC Workshop at KONVENS</title>
		<meeting>NLP4CMC Workshop at KONVENS<address><addrLine>Hildesheim, Germany</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Leipzig Corpora Collection-monolingual corpora of standard size</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Biemann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Heyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">U</forename><surname>Quasthoff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Richter</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. Corpus Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>Corpus Linguistics<address><addrLine>Birmingham, UK</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Computational journalism: A call to arms to database researchers</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Cohen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Yu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. CIDR-11)</title>
		<meeting>CIDR-11)<address><addrLine>Asilomar, CA, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="148" to="151" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">On Close and Distant Reading in Digital Humanities: A Survey and Future Challenges</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Janicke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Franzini</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Cheema</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Scheuermann</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. EuroVis</title>
		<meeting>EuroVis<address><addrLine>Cagliari, Italy</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Putting the data science into journalism</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Kirkpatrick</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Commun. ACM</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">58</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="15" to="17" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Enron Corpus: A New Dataset for Email Classification Research</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Klimt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. ECML</title>
		<meeting>ECML<address><addrLine>Pisa, Italy</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="217" to="226" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Networks of names: Visual exploration and semi-automatic tagging of social networks from newspaper articles</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Kochtchi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Von Landesberger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Biemann</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Computer Graphics Forum</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">33</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="211" to="220" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Text visualization browser: A visual survey of text visualization techniques</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Kucher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Kerren</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>online textvis.lnu.se</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Kambhatla. 2003. tRuEcasIng</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">V</forename><surname>Lita</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Ittycheriah</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Roukos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. ACL &apos;03, Sapporo</title>
		<meeting>ACL &apos;03, Sapporo<address><addrLine>Japan</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Modeling information navigation: Implications for information architecture</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Miller</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Remington</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Human-computer interaction</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="225" to="271" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Graphs, maps, trees : abstract models for a literary history</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Moretti</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
			<pubPlace>Verso, London, UK</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Domain-sensitive Temporal Tagging for Event-centric Information Retrieval</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Strötgen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>University of Heidelberg</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
	<note>Ph.D. thesis</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Synthesis lectures on information concepts, retrieval, and services</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Tunkelang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="80" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Faceted search</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">An adaptive annotation approach for biomedical entity and relation recognition</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Yimam</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Biemann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Majnaric</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">ˇ</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Sabanovi´csabanovi´c</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Holzinger</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Brain Informatics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="12" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
