<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T12:02+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Natural Language Generation enhances human decision-making with uncertain information</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date>August 7-12, 2016</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dimitra</forename><surname>Gkatzia</surname></persName>
							<email>d.gkatzia@napier.ac.uk</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Oliver</forename><surname>Lemon</surname></persName>
							<email>o.lemon@hw.ac.uk</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Verena</forename><surname>Rieser</surname></persName>
							<email>v.t.rieser@hw.ac.uk</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">School of Computing Edinburgh</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">Interaction Lab Heriot-Watt University Edinburgh</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Napier University Edinburgh</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>EH10 5DT, EH14 4AS</postCode>
									<country>UK, UK</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="laboratory">Interaction Lab Heriot-Watt University Edinburgh</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>EH14 4AS</postCode>
									<country key="GB">UK</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Natural Language Generation enhances human decision-making with uncertain information</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 54th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
						<meeting>the 54th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics <address><addrLine>Berlin, Germany</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="264" to="268"/>
							<date type="published">August 7-12, 2016</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Decision-making is often dependent on uncertain data, e.g. data associated with confidence scores or probabilities. We present a comparison of different information presentations for uncertain data and, for the first time, measure their effects on human decision-making. We show that the use of Natural Language Generation (NLG) improves decision-making under uncertainty, compared to state-of-the-art graphical-based representation methods. In a task-based study with 442 adults, we found that presentations using NLG lead to 24% better decision-making on average than the graphical presentations, and to 44% better decision-making when NLG is combined with graphics. We also show that women achieve significantly better results when presented with NLG output (an 87% increase on average compared to graphical presentations).</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Natural Language Generation (NLG) technology can achieve comparable results to commonly used data visualisation techniques for supporting accu- rate human decision-making ( . In this paper, we investigate whether NLG technol- ogy can also be used to support decision-making when the underlying data is uncertain. Current data-to-text systems assume that the underlying data is precise and correct -an assumption which is heavily criticised by other disciplines concerned with decision support, such as medicine <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Gigerenzer and Muir Gray, 2011</ref>), environmental mod- elling <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Beven, 2009)</ref>, climate change ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Manning et al., 2004</ref>), or weather forecasting <ref type="bibr">(Kootval, 2008)</ref>. However, simply presenting numerical ex- pressions of risk and uncertainty is not enough. Psychological studies on decision making have found that a high percentage of people do not understand and can't act upon numerical uncer- tainty ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Cokely et al., 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr">Galesic and GarciaRetamero, 2010)</ref>. For example, only 28% of Ger- mans and 25% of Americans are able to answer the question: "Which of the following numbers rep- resents the biggest risk of getting a disease: 1 in 100, 1 in 1000, 1 in 10?" ( <ref type="bibr">Galesic and GarciaRetamero, 2010)</ref>.</p><p>So far, the NLG community has investigated the conversion of numbers into language <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(Power and Williams, 2012)</ref> and the use of vague <ref type="bibr">expressions (van Deemter, 2009)</ref>. In this work, we explore how to convert numerical representa- tions of uncertainty into Natural Language so as to maximise confidence and correct outcomes of hu- man decision-making. We consider the exemplar task of weather forecast generation. We initially present two NLG strategies which present the un- certainty in the input data. The two strategies are based on (1) the World Meteorological Organisa- tion (WMO) <ref type="bibr">(Kootval, 2008)</ref> guidelines and (2) commercial forecast presentations (e.g. from BBC presenters). We then evaluate the strategies against a state-of-the-art graphical system <ref type="bibr">(Stephens et al., 2011</ref>), which presents the uncertain data in a graphical way. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref> shows an example of this baseline graphical presentation. We use a game- based setup ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Gkatzia et al., 2015</ref>) to perform task- based evaluation, to investigate the effect that the different information presentation strategies have on human decision-making.</p><p>Weather forecast generation is a common topic within the NLG community, e.g. ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Konstas and Lapata, 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Angeli et al., 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Belz and Kow, 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Sripada et al., 2005</ref>). Previous approaches have not focused on how to communicate uncer- tain information or the best ways of referring to probabilities of meteorological phenomena to oc- cur. In addition, their evaluation is based on user ratings of grammatically, semantic correctness, fluency, coherence or via post-edit evaluation. Al- though these metrics are indicative of the quality of the text produced, they do not measure the im- pact the texts might have in people's comprehen- sion of uncertainty or on their ability to make de- cisions based on the information conveyed.</p><p>Our contributions to the field are as follows: (1) We study a principled mapping of uncertainty to Natural Language and provide recommendations and data for future NLG systems; (2) We intro- duce a game-based data collection environment which extends task-based evaluation by measuring the impact of NLG on decision-making (measur- ing user confidence and game/task success); and (3) We show that effects of the different represen- tations vary for different user groups, so that user adaptation is necessary when generating multi- modal presentations of uncertain information.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">The Extended Weather Game</head><p>In this section, we present our extended version of the MetOffice's Weather Game ( <ref type="bibr">Stephens et al., 2011</ref>). The player has to choose where to send an ice-cream vendor in order to maximise sales, given weather forecasts for four weeks and two loca- tions. These forecasts describe (1) predicted rain- fall ( <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 2</ref>) and (2) temperature levels together Likelihood of oc- currence Lexicalisation p &gt;0.99 "extremely likely" 0.90 ≤ p ≤ 0.99 "very likely" 0.70 ≤ p ≤ 0.89 "likely" 0.55 ≤ p ≤ 0.69 "probable -more likely than not" 0.45 ≤ p ≤ 0.54 "equally likely as not" 0.30 ≤ p ≤ 0.44 "possible -less likely than not" 0.10 ≤ p ≤ 0.29 "unlikely" 0.01 ≤ p ≤ 0.09 "very unlikely" p&lt;0.01 "extremely unlikely" <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>: WMO-based mapping of likelihoods.</p><p>with their likelihoods in three ways: (a) through graphical representations (which is the version of the original game), (b) through textual forecasts, and (c) through combined graphical and textual forecasts. We generated the textual format us- ing two rule-based NLG approaches as described in the next section. Users are asked to initially choose the best destination for the ice-cream ven- dor and then they are asked to state how confident they are with their choice. Based on their deci- sions and their confidence levels, the participants are finally presented with their "monetary gain". For example, the higher the likelihood of sunshine, the higher the monetary gain if the player has de- clared that s/he is confident that it is not going to rain and it doesn't actually rain. In the opposite scenario, the player would lose money. The de- cision on whether rain occurred is estimated by sampling the probability distribution. At the end of the game, users were scored according to their "risk literacy" following the Berlin Numeracy Test <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Cokely et al., 2012</ref>). Further details are presented in ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Gkatzia et al., 2015</ref>).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Natural Language Generation from Uncertain Information</head><p>We developed two NLG systems, WMO-based and NATURAL, using SimpleNLG (Gatt and Re- iter, 2009), which both generate textual descrip- tions of rainfall and temperature data addressing the uncertain nature of forecasts. WMO-based: This is a rule-based system which uses the guidelines recommended by the WMO (Kootval, 2008) for reporting uncertainty, as shown in <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>. Consider for instance a fore- cast of sunny intervals with 30% probability of rain. This WMO-based system will generate the following forecast: "Sunny intervals with rain be- ing possible -less likely than not". NATURAL: This system imitates forecasters and their natural way of reporting weather. The rules used in this system have been derived by observ- ing the way that experts (e.g. BBC weather re- porters) produce forecasts. For the previous exam- ple (sunny intervals with 30% probability of rain), this system will generate the following forecast: "Mainly dry with sunny spells".</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Evaluation</head><p>In order to investigate what helps people to better understand and act upon uncertainty in informa- tion presentations, we use five conditions within the context of the Extended Weather Game: 1. Graphics only: This representation shows the users only the graphical representation of the weather forecasts. For this condition we used the graphs that scored best in terms of human comprehension from (Stephens et al., 2011).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.">Multi-modal Representations:</head><p>− Graphics and NATURAL: This is a multi-modal representation consisting of graphics (as described in the previous con- dition) and text produced by the NATURAL system. − Graphics and WMO-based: This is also a multi-modal representation consisting of graphics and text produced by the WMO- based system.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.">NLG only:</head><p>− NATURAL only: This is a text-only rep- resentation as described above. − WMO-based system only: This is also a text-only representation.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Data</head><p>We recruited 442 unique players (197 females 1 , 241 males, 4 non-disclosed) using social me- dia. We collected 450 unique game instances (just a few people played the game twice). The anonymised data will be released as part of this submission.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Results</head><p>In order to investigate which representations as- sist people in decision-making under uncertainty, we analysed both the players' scores (in terms of monetary gain) and their predictions for rainfall with regard to their confidence scores. As we de- scribed in Section 2, the game calculates a mone- tary gain based on both the decisions and the con- fidence of the player, i.e. the decision-making abil- ity of the player. Regarding confidence, we asked users to declare how confident they are on a 10- point scale. In our analysis we therefore focus on both confidence and score at the game.   </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Monetary gains Confidence</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.1">Results for all adults</head><p>Multi-modal vs. Graphics-only: We found that use of multi-modal representations leads to gain- ing significantly higher game scores (i.e. better decision-making) than the Graphics-only repre- sentation (p = 0.03, effect = +36.36). This is a 44% average increase in game score.</p><p>Multi-modal vs. NLG-only: However, there is no significant difference between the NLG only and the multi-modal representation, for game score. NLG vs. Graphics-only: We found that the NLG representations resulted in a 24.8% increase in av- erage task score (i.e. better decision-making) com- pared to the Graphics-only condition, see <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Table 2</ref>: an average score increase of over 20 points. There was no significant difference found between the WMO and NATURAL NLG conditions. Confidence: For confidence, the multi-modal rep- resentation is significantly more effective than NLG only (p &lt; 0.01, effect = 17.7%). However, as <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Table 2</ref> shows, although adults did not feel very confident when presented with NLG only, they were able to make better decisions compared to being presented with graphics only. Demographic factors: We further found that prior experience on making decisions based on risk, familiarity with weather models, and cor- rect literacy test results are predictors of the play- ers' understanding of uncertainty, which is trans- lated in both confidence and game scores. In con- trast, we found that the education level, the gender, or being native speaker of English does not con- tribute to players' confidence and game scores.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.2">Results for Females</head><p>We found that females score significantly higher at the decision task when exposed to either of the NLG output presentations, when compared to the graphics-only presentation (p &lt; 0.05, effect = +53.03). This is an increase of 87%, also see <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">Table 3</ref>. In addition, the same group of users scores significantly higher when presented with the multi-modal output as compared to graphics only (p = 0.05, effect =60.74%). Interestingly, for  this group, the multi-modal presentation adds lit- tle more in effectiveness of decision-making than the NLG-only condition, but the multi-modal pre- sentations do enhance their confidence (+15%). We furthermore found that educated (i.e. holding a BSc or higher degree) females, who also cor- rectly answered the risk literacy test, feel signif- icantly more confident when presented with the multi-modal representations than with NLG only (p = 0.01, effect = 16.7%).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.3">Results for Males</head><p>We found that males obtained similar game scores with all the types of representation. This suggests that the overall improved scores (for All Adults) presented above, are largely due to the beneficial effects of NLG for women. In terms of confidence, males are more likely to be more confident if they are presented with graphics only (81% of the time) or a multi-modal representation (85% of the time) (p = 0.01).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7">Conclusions and Future Work</head><p>We present results from a game-based study on how to generate descriptions of uncertain data - an issue which so far has been unexplored by data-to-text systems. We find that there are sig- nificant gender differences between multi-modal, NLG, and graphical versions of the task, where for women, use of NLG results in a 87% increase in task success over graphics. Multimodal presenta- tions lead to a 44% increase for all adults, com- pared to graphics. People are also more confident of their judgements when using the multimodal representations. These are significant findings, as previous work has not distinguished between gen- ders when comparing different representations of data, e.g. ( . It also confirms re- search on gender effects in multi-modal systems, as for example reported in <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Foster and Oberlander, 2006</ref>; <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Rieser and Lemon, 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr">Weiss et al., 2012</ref>). The results are also related to educational research, which shows that women perform bet- ter in verbal-logical tasks than visual-spatial tasks <ref type="bibr">(Zhu, 2007</ref>). An interesting investigation for fu- ture research is the interplay between uncertainty, risk-taking behaviour and gender, as for example reported in <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">(Sarin and Wieland, 2016</ref>).</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: Graphics for temperature data.</figDesc><graphic url="image-1.png" coords="2,72.00,62.83,226.75,241.72" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2: Screenshot of the Extended Weather Game (Rainfall: Graphics and WMO condition).</figDesc><graphic url="image-2.png" coords="3,128.70,62.79,340.18,254.17" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Graphs</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" validated="false"><head>Table 2 : Average Monetary gains and Confidence scores (All Adults).</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3" validated="false"><head>Table 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Average Monetary gains and Confidence 
scores (Females). 

</table></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> Women made up 44.5% of the subjects.</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>This research received funding from the EPSRC projects GUI (EP/L026775/1), DILiGENt (EP/M005429/1) and MaDrI-gAL (EP/N017536/1).</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A simple domain-independent probabilistic approach to generation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gabor</forename><surname>Angeli</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Percy</forename><surname>Liang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dan</forename><surname>Klein</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP)</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Extracting parallel fragments from comparable corpora for data-to-text generation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Anja</forename><surname>Belz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Eric</forename><surname>Kow</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">6th International Natural Language Generation Conference (INLG)</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Environmental Modelling: An Uncertain Future? Routledge</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Keith</forename><surname>Beven</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Edward</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Cokely</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mirta</forename><surname>Galesic</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Eric</forename><surname>Schulz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Saima</forename><surname>Ghazal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rocio</forename><surname>Garcia-Retamero</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Measuring risk literacy: The berlin numeracy test. Judgment and Decision Making</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="25" to="47" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Datadriven generation of emphatic facial displays</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mary</forename><forename type="middle">Ellen</forename><surname>Foster</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jon</forename><surname>Oberlander</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of the 11th Conference of the European Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics (EACL)</title>
		<meeting>of the 11th Conference of the European Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics (EACL)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Statistical numeracy for health: A cross-cultural comparison with probabilistic national samples</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mirta</forename><surname>Galesic</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rocio</forename><surname>Garcia-Retamero</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Archives of Internal Medicine</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">170</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="462" to="468" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">SimpleNLG: A realisation engine for practical applications</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Albert</forename><surname>Gatt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ehud</forename><surname>Reiter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>In ENLG</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">From Data to Text in the Neonatal Intensive Care Unit: Using NLG Technology for Decision Support and Information Management</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Albert</forename><surname>Gatt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Francois</forename><surname>Portet</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ehud</forename><surname>Reiter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">James</forename><surname>Hunter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Saad</forename><surname>Mahamood</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wendy</forename><surname>Moncur</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Somayajulu</forename><surname>Sripada</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<publisher>AI Communications</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="153" to="186" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Better doctors, better patients, better decisions: Envisioning health care 2020</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Gigerenzer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Muir Gray</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<publisher>Cambridge MIT Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A game-based setup for data collection and task-based evaluation of uncertain information presentation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dimitra</forename><surname>Gkatzia</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Amanda</forename><forename type="middle">Cercas</forename><surname>Curry</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Verena</forename><surname>Rieser</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Oliver</forename><surname>Lemon</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 15th European Workshop on Natural Language Generation (ENLG)</title>
		<meeting>the 15th European Workshop on Natural Language Generation (ENLG)<address><addrLine>Brighton, UK</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015-09" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="112" to="113" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Association for Computational Linguistics</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Unsupervised concept-to-text generation with hypergraphs</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ioannis</forename><surname>Konstas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mirella</forename><surname>Lapata</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Conference of the North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics (NAACL)</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Guidelines on Communicating Forecast Uncertainty. World Meteorological Organisation</title>
		<editor>Haleh Kootval</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Martin</forename><surname>Manning</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michel</forename><surname>Petit</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Easterling</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">James</forename><surname>Murphy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Anand</forename><surname>Patwardhan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hans-Holger</forename><surname>Rogner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rob</forename><surname>Swart</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gary</forename><surname>Yohe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">IPCC Workshop on Describing Scientific Uncertainties in Climate Change to Support Analysis of Risk and of Options</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Generating numerical approximations</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Richard</forename><surname>Power</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sandra</forename><surname>Williams</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Computational Linguistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">38</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="113" to="134" />
			<date type="published" when="2012-03" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Learning effective multimodal dialogue strategies from wizard-of-oz data: Bootstrapping and evaluation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Rieser</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Lemon</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of ACL</title>
		<meeting>ACL</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="638" to="646" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Risk aversion for decisions under uncertainty: Are there gender differences?</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rakesh</forename><surname>Sarin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alice</forename><surname>Wieland</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Behavioral and Experimental Economics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">60</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="8" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Evaluation of an NLG system using postedit data</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Somayajulu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ehud</forename><surname>Sripada</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lezan</forename><surname>Reiter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Hawizy</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence (IJCAI)</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
