<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T10:16+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Improved Parsing for Argument-Clusters Coordination</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date>August 7-12, 2016</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jessica</forename><surname>Ficler</surname></persName>
							<email>jessica.ficler@gmail.com</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Computer Science Department</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Computer Science Department Bar</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Ilan University</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="IL">Israel</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yoav</forename><surname>Goldberg</surname></persName>
							<email>yoav.goldbreg@gmail.com</email>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">Ilan University</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="IL">Israel</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Improved Parsing for Argument-Clusters Coordination</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 54th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
						<meeting>the 54th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics <address><addrLine>Berlin, Germany</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="72" to="76"/>
							<date type="published">August 7-12, 2016</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Syntactic parsers perform poorly in prediction of Argument-Cluster Coordination (ACC). We change the PTB representation of ACC to be more suitable for learning by a statistical PCFG parser, affecting 125 trees in the training set. Training on the modified trees yields a slight improvement in EVALB scores on sections 22 and 23. The main evaluation is on a corpus of 4th grade science exams, in which ACC structures are prevalent. On this corpus, we obtain an impressive ×2.7 improvement in recovering ACC structures compared to a parser trained on the original PTB trees.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Many natural language processing systems make use of syntactic representations of sentences. These representations are produced by parsers, which often produce incorrect analyses. Many of the mistakes are in coordination structures, and structures involving non-constituent coordination, such as Argument Cluster Coordination, Right Node-Raising and Gapping <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Dowty, 1988)</ref>, are es- pecially hard.</p><p>Coordination is a common syntactic phenomena and work has been done to improve coordination structures predication in the general case <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Hogan, 2007;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Shimbo and Hara, 2007;</ref>. In this work we focus on one particular coordination structure: Argument Clus- ter Coordination (ACC). While ACC are not com- mon in the Penn TreeBank ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Marcus et al., 1993)</ref>, they commonly appear in other corpora. For ex- ample, in a dataset of questions from the Regents 4th grade science exam (the Aristo Challenge), 14% of the sentences include ACC.</p><p>ACC is characterized by non-constituent se- quences that are parallel in structure. For instance, in "I bought John a microphone on Monday and Richie a guitar on Saturday", the conjunction is between "John a microphone on Monday" and "Richie a guitar on Saturday" which are both non- constituents and include parallel arguments: the NPs "John" and "Richie"; the NPs "a micro- phone" and "a guitar"; and the PPs "on Monday" and "on Saturday".</p><p>Previous NLP research on the Argument Clus- ters Coordination <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Mouret, 2006</ref>) as well as the Penn TreeBank annotation guidelines <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Marcus et al., 1993;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Bies et al., 1995</ref>) focused mainly on providing representation schemes capable of ex- pressing the linguistic nuances that may appear in such coordinations. The resulting representations are relatively complex, and are not easily learn- able by current day parsers, including parsers that refine the grammar by learning latent annotations ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Petrov et al., 2006</ref>), which are thought to be more agnostic to the annotations scheme of the trees. In this work, we suggest an alternative, simpler rep- resentation scheme which is capable of represent- ing most of the Argument Cluster coordination cases in the Penn Treebank, and is better suited for training a parser. We show that by changing the annotation of 125 trees, we get a parser which is substantially better at handling ACC structures, and is also marginally better at parsing general sentences.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Arguments Cluster Coordination in the Penn Tree Bank</head><p>Argument Cluster Coordinations are represented in the PTB with two or more conjoined VPs, where the first VP contains a verb and indexed ar- guments, and the rest of the VPs lack a verb and include arguments with indices corresponding to those of the first conjoined VP. For example, con- sider the PTB representation of "The Q ratio was only 65% in 1987 and 68.9% in 1988": The main VP includes two conjoined VPs. The first VP includes the verb was and two indexed ar- guments: "only 65%" (1) and "in 1987" (2). The second VP does not include a verb, but only two arguments, that are co-indexed with the parallel ar- gument at the first conjoined VP. ACC structures in the PTB may include modi- fiers that are annotated under the main VP, and the conjoined VPs may includes arguments that are not part of the cluster. These are annotated with no index, i.e. "insurance costs" in <ref type="bibr">[1a]</ref>.</p><p>ACC structures are not common in the PTB. The training set includes only 141 ACC structures of which are conjoined by and or or. Some of them are complex but most (78%) have the follow- ing pattern (NT is used to denote non-terminals): These structures can be characterized as follows: (1) the first token of the first conjoined VP is a verb; (2) the indexed arguments are direct chil- dren of the conjoined VPs; (3) the number of the indexed arguments is the same for each conjoined VP.</p><p>Almost all of these cases (98%) are symmetric: each of the conjoined VPs has the same types of indexed arguments. Non-symmetric clusters (e.g. We argue that while the PTB representation for ACC gives a clear structure and covers all the ACC forms, it is not a good representation for learn- ing PCFG parsers from. The arguments in the clusters are linked via co-indexation, breaking the context-free assumptions that PCFG parsers rely on. PCFG parsers ignore the indexes, essentially losing all the information about the ACC con- struction. Moreover, ignoring the indexes result in "weird" CFG rules such as VP → NP PP. Not only that the RHS of these rules do not include a verbal component, it is also a very common struc- ture for NPs. This makes the parser very likely to either mis-analyze the argument cluster as a noun- phrase, or to analyze some NPs as (supposedly ACC) VPs. The parallel nature of the construction is also lost. To improve the parser performance for ACC structures prediction, we suggest an alterna- tive constituency representation for ACC phrases which is easier to learn.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Alternative Representation for ACC</head><p>Our proposed representation for ACC respects the context-free nature of the parser. In order to avoid incorrect syntactic derivations and derivations that allows conjoining of clusters with other phrases, as well as to express the symmetry that occur in many ACC phrases, we change the PTB represen- tation for ACC as follows: <ref type="formula">(1)</ref> we move the verb and non-indexed elements out of the first argu- ment cluster to under the main VP; (2) each ar- gument cluster is treated as a phrase, with new non-terminal symbols specific to argument clus- ters; (3) the conjunction of clusters also receives a dedicated phrase level. For example see compari- son between the original and new representations: The main verb driven as well as the particle up and the non-indexed argument insurance costs are moved to the external VP. The two argument clus- ters (formerly VPs) receive dedicated phrase la- bels ACC X , where X reflects the syntactic types of the indexed elements (e.g. ACC N P −P P for the first cluster in [1b] above). The most common cases are ACC N P −P P which appears in 41.6% of the clusters, ACC ADJP −P P with 21.2% of the clusters and ACC P P −P P with 5.3% of the clus- ters.</p><p>Finally, we introduce a new phrase type (ACCP H X ) for the coordination of the two clus- ters. Here X denotes the main element in the clus- ters, determined heuristically by taking the first of the following types that appear in any of the clus- ters: NP, PP, ADJP, SBAR. Cases where the clus- ters contains an ADVP element are usually special (e.g. the following structure is missing "people" in the second cluster: ((NP 8000 people) (in Spain)) and ((NP 2000) (ADVP abroad))). For such cases, we add "ADVP" to the ACCP H level label. Ta- ble 1 lists the ACCP H level labels and their num- ber of the appearances in the 125 modified trees. <ref type="bibr">1</ref> The representation is capable of representing common cases of ACC where the cluster elements are siblings. We similarly handle also some of the more complex cases, in which an extra layer ap- pears between an indexed argument and the con- joined VP to host an empty element, such as in the following case with an extra S layer above single-B-3:   in each of the following two years". Our changes are local and appear in small num- ber of trees (0.003% of the PTB train set). We also ignore more complex cases of ACC. Yet, training the parser with the modified trees significantly im- proves the parser results on ACC structures.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Experiments</head><p>We converted 125 trees with ACC structures in the training sets (sections 2-21) of the PTB to the new representation, and trained the Berkeley parser ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Petrov et al., 2006</ref>) with its default settings.</p><p>As the PTB test and dev sets have only 12 ACC structures that are coordinated by and or or, we evaluate the parser on Regents, a dataset in which ACC structures are prevalent (details below). As Regents does not include syntactic structures, we focus on the ACC phenomena and evaluate the parsers' ability to correctly identify the spans of the clusters and the arguments in them.</p><p>To verify that the new representation does not harm general parsing performance, we also eval-   <ref type="table">Table 3</ref>: The parser Recall score in recover- ing ACC conjunct spans on the Regents dataset. ACC P T B : the set is annotated with the verb in- side the first cluster. ACC OU R : the set is anno- tated following our approach.</p><p>uate the parer on the traditional development and test sets (sections 22 and 23). As can be seen in <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">Table 2</ref>, the parser results are slightly better when trained with the modified trees. <ref type="bibr">2</ref> </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">Regents data-set</head><p>Regents -a dataset of questions from the Regents 4th grade science exam (the Aristo Challenge), 3 includes 281 sentences with coordination phrases, where 54 of them include Argument Cluster co- ordination. We manually annotated the sentences by marking the conjuncts spans for the constituent coordination phrases, e.g.:</p><p>Wendy (ran 19 miles) and (walked 9 miles)</p><p>as well as the spans of each component of the argument-cluster coordinations, including the in- ner span of each argument: The bracketing in this set follow our proposed ACC bracketing, and we refer to it as ACC OU R . We also created a version in which the bracket- ing follow the PTB scheme, with the verb included in span of the first cluster, e.g.: We refer to this dataset as ACC P T B .</p><p>We evaluate the parsers' ability to correctly re- cover the components of the coordination struc- tures by computing the percentage of gold anno- tated phrases where the number of predicted con- junct is correct and all conjuncts spans (round brackets) are predicted correctly (Recall). For example, consider the following gold annotated phrase:</p><p>A restaurant served (9 pizzas during lunch) and (6 during dinner) today A prediction of ("9 pizzas during lunch", "6 during dinner today") is considered as incorrect because the second conjunct boundaries are not matched to the gold annotation.</p><p>We compare the Recall score that the parser achieves when it is trained on the modified trees to the score when the parser is trained on the PTB trees.</p><p>When evaluated on all coordination cases in the Regents dataset (both ACC and other cases of con- stituent coordination), the parser trained on the modified trees was successful in recovering 54.3% of the spans, compared to only 47% when trained on the original PTB trees.</p><p>We now focus on specifically on the ACC cases <ref type="table">(Table 3)</ref>. When evaluating the PTB-trained parser on ACC P T B , it correctly recovers only 13% of the ACC boundaries. Somewhat sur- prisingly, the PTB-trained parser performs better when evaluated against ACC OU R , correctly re- covering 24.1% of the structures. This highlights how unnatural the original ACC representation is for the parser: it predicts the alternative represen- tation more often than it predicts the one it was trained on. When the parser is trained on the mod- ified trees, results on ACC OU R jump to 64.8%, correctly recovering ×2.7 more structures.</p><p>The previous results were on recovering the spans of the coordinated elements (the round brackets in the examples above). When mea- suring the Recall in recovering any of the argu- ments themselves (the elements surrounded by square brackets), the parser trained on the mod- ified trees recovers 72.46% of the arguments in clusters, compared to only 58.29% recovery by the PTB-trained parser. We also measure in what percentage of the cases in which both the cluster boundaries (round brackets) were recovered cor- rectly, all the internal structure (square brackets) was recovered correctly as well. The score is 80% when the parser trained on the modified trees com-pared to 61.5% when it is trained on the PTB-trees.</p><p>Overall, the parser trained on the modified trees significantly outperforms the one trained on the original trees in all the evaluation scenarios.</p><p>Another interesting evaluation is the ability of the parser that is trained on the modified trees to determine whether a coordination is of Argument Clusters type (that is, whether the predicted co- ordination spans are marked with the ACCPH la- bel). <ref type="bibr">4</ref> The results are a Recall of 57.4% and Pre- cision of 83.78%. When we further require that both the head be marked as ACCPH and the in- ternal structure be correct, the results are 48.14% Recall and 70.27% Precision.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Conclusions</head><p>By focusing on the details of a single and rela- tively rare syntactic construction, argument clus- ters coordination, we have been able to signifi- cantly improve parsing results for this construc- tion, while also slightly improving general parsing results. More broadly, while most current research efforts in natural language processing and in syn- tactic parsing in particular is devoted to the de- sign of general-purpose, data-agnostic techniques, such methods work on the common phenomena while often neglecting the very long tail of impor- tant constructions. This work shows that there are gains to be had also from focusing on the details of particular linguistic phenomena, and changing the data such that it is easier for a "data agnostic" system to learn.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>"</head><label></label><figDesc>He made [these gestures] 1 N P [to the red group] 2 P P and [for us] 2 P P [nothing] 1 N P ") exist but are less common.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>in which we remove the empty NP as well as the extra S layer:</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><head>1</head><label></label><figDesc>Parsers that apply latent annotations to the grammar, such as the Berkeley Parser (Petrov et al., 2006) we use in our experiments, can potentially learn some of our proposed refinements on their own. However, as we show in the ex- periments section, the performance of the Berkeley Parser on ACC structures significantly improve when applying our transformations prior to training.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_6"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Mary paid ([$11.08] [for berries]) , ([$14.33] [for apples]) , and ([$9.31] [for peaches])</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_7"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Mary ([paid] [$11.08] [for berries]) , ([$14.33] [for apples]) , and ([$9.31] [for peaches])</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" validated="false"><head>Table 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Parsing results (EVALB) on PTB Sec-
tions 22 (DEV) and 23 (TEST). 

PTB Trees Modified Trees 
ACC P T B 
13.0 
-
ACC OU R 
24.1 
64.8 

</table></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="2"> The same trend holds also if we exclude the 12 modified trees from the evaluation sets. 3 http://allenai.org/content/data/Regents.zip</note>

			<note place="foot" n="4"> This measurement is relevant only when parsing based on our proposed annotation, and cannot be measured for parse trees based the original PTB annotation.</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>This work was supported by The Allen Insti-tute for Artificial Intelligence as well as the Ger-man Research Foundation via the German-Israeli Project Cooperation (DIP, grant DA 1600/1-1).</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Bracketing guidelines for treebank ii style penn treebank project</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ann</forename><surname>Bies</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mark</forename><surname>Ferguson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Karen</forename><surname>Katz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Robert</forename><surname>Macintyre</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Victoria</forename><surname>Tredinnick</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Grace</forename><surname>Kim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mary</forename><forename type="middle">Ann</forename><surname>Marcinkiewicz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Britta</forename><surname>Schasberger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">97</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">100</biblScope>
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>University of Pennsylvania</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Type raising, functional composition, and non-constituent conjunction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Dowty</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Categorial grammars and natural language structures</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1988" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="153" to="197" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Coordinate structure analysis with global structural constraints and alignmentbased local features</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kazuo</forename><surname>Hara</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Masashi</forename><surname>Shimbo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hideharu</forename><surname>Okuma</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yuji</forename><surname>Matsumoto</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Joint Conference of the 47th Annual Meeting of the ACL and the 4th International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing of the AFNLP</title>
		<meeting>the Joint Conference of the 47th Annual Meeting of the ACL and the 4th International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing of the AFNLP</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="967" to="975" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Association for Computational Linguistics</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Coordinate noun phrase disambiguation in a generative parsing model. Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Deirdre</forename><surname>Hogan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The cambridge grammar of english</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rodney</forename><surname>Huddleston</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Geoffrey</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Pullum</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
			<publisher>Cambridge University Press</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1273" to="1362" />
			<pubPlace>Language. Cambridge</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Building a large annotated corpus of english: The penn treebank</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mary</forename><forename type="middle">Ann</forename><surname>Mitchell P Marcus</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Beatrice</forename><surname>Marcinkiewicz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Santorini</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Computational linguistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="313" to="330" />
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A phrase structure approach to argument cluster coordination</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">François</forename><surname>Mouret</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the HPSG06 Conference</title>
		<meeting>the HPSG06 Conference</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>CSLI online Publications</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="247" to="267" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Bypassed alignment graph for learning coordination in japanese sentences</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hideharu</forename><surname>Okuma</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kazuo</forename><surname>Hara</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Masashi</forename><surname>Shimbo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yuji</forename><surname>Matsumoto</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the ACL-IJCNLP 2009 Conference Short Papers</title>
		<meeting>the ACL-IJCNLP 2009 Conference Short Papers</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="5" to="8" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Association for Computational Linguistics</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Learning accurate, compact, and interpretable tree annotation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Slav</forename><surname>Petrov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Leon</forename><surname>Barrett</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Romain</forename><surname>Thibaux</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dan</forename><surname>Klein</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 21st International Conference on Computational Linguistics and the 44th annual meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the 21st International Conference on Computational Linguistics and the 44th annual meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="433" to="440" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A discriminative learning model for coordinate conjunctions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Masashi</forename><surname>Shimbo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kazuo</forename><surname>Hara</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">EMNLP-CoNLL</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="610" to="619" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
