<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T10:16+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Controlled and Balanced Dataset for Japanese Lexical Simplification</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date>August 7-12, 2016</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tomonori</forename><surname>Kodaira</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Tokyo Metropolitan University Hino City</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Tokyo</settlement>
									<country key="JP">Japan</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tomoyuki</forename><surname>Kajiwara</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Tokyo Metropolitan University Hino City</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Tokyo</settlement>
									<country key="JP">Japan</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mamoru</forename><surname>Komachi</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Tokyo Metropolitan University Hino City</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Tokyo</settlement>
									<country key="JP">Japan</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Controlled and Balanced Dataset for Japanese Lexical Simplification</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 54th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics-Student Research Workshop</title>
						<meeting>the 54th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics-Student Research Workshop <address><addrLine>Berlin, Germany</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="7"/>
							<date type="published">August 7-12, 2016</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>We propose a new dataset for evaluating a Japanese lexical simplification method. Previous datasets have several deficiencies. All of them substitute only a single target word, and some of them extract sentences only from newswire corpus. In addition, most of these datasets do not allow ties and integrate simplification ranking from all the annotators without considering the quality. In contrast, our dataset has the following advantages: (1) it is the first controlled and balanced dataset for Japanese lexical simplification with high correlation with human judgment and (2) the consistency of the simplification ranking is improved by allowing candidates to have ties and by considering the reliability of annotators.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Lexical simplification is the task to find and sub- stitute a complex word or phrase in a sentence with its simpler synonymous expression. We de- fine complex word as a word that has lexical and subjective difficulty in a sentence. It can help in reading comprehension for children and language learners <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(De Belder and Moens, 2010)</ref>. This task is a rather easier task which prepare a pair of com- plex and simple representations than a challeng- ing task which changes the substitute pair in a given context ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Specia et al., 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Kajiwara and Yamamoto, 2015)</ref>. Construction of a benchmark dataset is important to ensure the reliability and reproducibility of evaluation. However, few re- sources are available for the automatic evaluation of lexical simplification. <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Specia et al. (2012)</ref> and De Belder and Moens (2010) created benchmark datasets for evaluating English lexical simplifica- tion. In addition, <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Horn et al. (2014)</ref> extracted sim- plification candidates and constructed an evalua- tion dataset using English Wikipedia and Simple English Wikipedia. In contrast, such a parallel cor- pus does not exist in Japanese. <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Kajiwara and Yamamoto (2015)</ref> constructed an evaluation dataset for Japanese lexical simplification 1 in languages other than English.</p><p>However, there are four drawbacks in the dataset of <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Kajiwara and Yamamoto (2015)</ref>: (1) they extracted sentences only from a newswire corpus; (2) they substituted only a single target word; (3) they did not allow ties; and (4) they did not integrate simplification ranking consider- ing the quality.</p><p>Hence, we propose a new dataset addressing the problems in the dataset of <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Kajiwara and Yamamoto (2015)</ref>. The main contributions of our study are as follows:</p><p>• It is the first controlled and balanced dataset for Japanese lexical simplification. We ex- tract sentences from a balanced corpus and control sentences to have only one com- plex word. Experimental results show that our dataset is more suitable than previous datasets for evaluating systems with respect to correlation with human judgment.</p><p>• The consistency of simplification ranking is greatly improved by allowing candidates to have ties and by considering the reliability of annotators.</p><p>Our dataset is available at GitHub 2 .</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Related work</head><p>The evaluation dataset for the English Lexical Simplification task ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Specia et al., 2012</ref>) was an-  <ref type="table">Although using their techniques makes you feel exalted, I strongly feel I want to outrank my competitors in terms of skill.  paraphrase list         come alive  raised, excited  up  exalted  excited  heated  revitalized</ref> Figure 1: A part of the dataset of <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Kajiwara and Yamamoto (2015)</ref>.</p><p>notated on top of the evaluation dataset for English lexical substitution <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(McCarthy and Navigli, 2007)</ref>. They asked university students to rerank substi- tutes according to simplification ranking. Sen- tences in their dataset do not always contain com- plex words, and it is not appropriate to evaluate simplification systems if a test sentence does not include any complex words. In addition, De Belder and Moens (2012) built an evaluation dataset for English lexical simplifi- cation based on that developed by <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">McCarthy and Navigli (2007)</ref>. They used Amazon's Mechanical Turk to rank substitutes and employed the relia- bility of annotators to remove outlier annotators and/or downweight unreliable annotators. The re- liability was calculated on penalty based agree- ment <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(McCarthy and Navigli, 2007)</ref> and Fleiss' Kappa. Unlike the dataset of <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Specia et al. (2012)</ref>, sentences in their dataset contain at least one com- plex word, but they might contain more than one complex word. Again, it is not adequate for the automatic evaluation of lexical simplification be- cause the human ranking of the resulting simpli- fication might be affected by the context contain- ing complex words. Furthermore, De Belder and Moens' (2012) dataset is too small to be used for achieving a reliable evaluation of lexical simplifi- cation systems.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Problems in previous datasets for</head><p>Japanese lexical simplification</p><p>Kajiwara and Yamamoto (2015) followed <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Specia et al. (2012)</ref> to construct an evaluation dataset for Japanese lexical simplification. Namely, they split the data creation process into two steps: substitute extraction and simplification ranking. During the substitute extraction task, they col- lected substitutes of each target word in 10 differ- ent contexts. These contexts were randomly se- lected from a newswire corpus. The target word was a content word (noun, verb, adjective, or ad- verb), and was neither a simple word nor part of any compound words. They gathered substitutes from five annotators using crowdsourcing. These procedures were the same as for De <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Belder and Moens (2012)</ref>. During the simplification ranking task, annota- tors were asked to reorder the target word and its substitutes in a single order without allowing ties. They used crowdsourcing to find five annotators different from those who performed the substitute extraction task. Simplification ranking was inte- grated on the basis of the average of the simplifi- cation ranking from each annotator to generate a gold-standard ranking that might include ties. During the substitute extraction task, agreement among the annotators was 0.664, whereas during the simplification ranking task, Spearman's rank correlation coefficient score was 0.332. Spear- man's score of this work was lower than that of <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Specia et al. (2012)</ref> by 0.064. Thus, there was a big blur between annotators, and the simplifica- tion ranking collected using crowdsourcing tended to have a lower quality. (feel exalted)" is simplified, another complex word " (skill)" is left in a sentence. Lexi- cal simplification is a task of simplifying complex words in a sentence. Previous datasets may in- clude multiple complex words in a sentence but target only one complex word. Not only the tar- get word but also other complex words should be considered as well, but annotation of substitutes and simplification ranking to all complex words in a sentence produces a huge number of pat- terns, therefore takes a very high cost of anno- tation. For example, when three complex words which have 10 substitutes each in a sentence, an- notators should consider 10 3 patterns. Thus, it is desired that a sentence includes only simple words after the target word is substituted. Therefore, in this work, we extract sentences containing only one complex word.</p><p>Ties are not permitted in simplification rank- ing. When each annotator assigns a simplifica- tion ranking to a substitution list, a tie cannot be assigned in previous datasets ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Specia et al., 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Kajiwara and Yamamoto, 2015)</ref>. This deterio- rates ranking consistency if some substitutes have a similar simplicity. De Belder and Moens (2012) allow ties in simplification ranking and report con- siderably higher agreement among annotators than <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Specia et al. (2012)</ref>.</p><p>The method of ranking integration is na¨ıvena¨ıve. <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Kajiwara and Yamamoto (2015)</ref> and <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Specia et al. (2012)</ref> use an average score to integrate rankings, but it might be biased by outliers. De Belder and Moens (2012) report a slight increase in agreement by greedily removing annotators to maximize the agreement score.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Balanced dataset for evaluation of Japanese lexical simplification</head><p>We create a balanced dataset for the evaluation of Japanese lexical simplification. to perform substitute extraction, substitute evalua- tion, and substitute ranking. In each task, we re- quested the annotators to complete at least 95% of their previous assignments correctly. They were native Japanese speakers.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">Extracting sentences</head><p>Our work defines complex words as "High Level" words in the Lexicon for Japanese Language Edu- cation (Sunakawa et al., 2012). <ref type="bibr">4</ref> The word level is calculated by five teachers of Japanese, based on their experience and intuition. There were 7,940 high-level words out of 17,921 words in the lex- icon. In addition, target words of this work com- prised content words (nouns, verbs, adjectives, ad- verbs, adjectival nouns, sahen nouns, 5 and sahen verbs 6 ). Sentences that include a complex word were randomly extracted from the Balanced Corpus of Contemporary Written Japanese ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Maekawa et al., 2010</ref>). Sentences shorter than seven words or longer than 35 words were excluded. We excluded target words that appeared as a part of compound words. Following previous work, 10 contexts of occurrence were collected for each complex word. We assigned 30 complex words for each part of speech. The total number of sentences was 2,100 (30 words 10 sentences 7 parts of speech). We used a crowdsourcing application to annotate 1,800 sentences, and we asked university students majoring in computer science to annotate 300 sen- tences to investigate the quality of crowdsourcing.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">Extracting substitutes</head><p>Simplification candidates were collected using crowdsourcing techniques. For each complex word, five annotators wrote substitutes that did not <ref type="formula">(2012)</ref> yes En 430 100 (23.3) 60 (14.0) 160 (37.2) 110 (25.6) excluded <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Specia et al. (2012)</ref> yes En 2,010 580 (28.9) 520 (25.9) 560 (27.9) 350 (17.6) included <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Kajiwara and Yamamoto (2015)</ref> no Ja 2,330 630 (27.0) 720 (30.9) 500 (21.5) 480 (20.6) included This work yes Ja 2,010 570 (28.3) 570 (28.3) 580 (28.8) 290 (14.4) excluded <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>: Comparison of the datasets. In this work, nouns include sahen nouns, verbs include sahen verbs, and adjectives include adjectival nouns.  change the sense of the sentence. Substitutions could include particles in context. Conjugation was allowed to cover variations of both verbs and adjectives. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">Figure 3</ref> shows an example of annota- tion.</p><note type="other">Dataset balanced lang sents. noun () verb () adj. () adv. () outlier De Belder and Moens</note><p>To improve the quality of the lexical substi- tution, inappropriate substitutes were deleted for later use, as described in the next subsection.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3">Evaluating substitutes</head><p>Five annotators selected an appropriate word to include as a substitution that did not change the sense of the sentence. Substitutes that won a ma- jority were defined as correct. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Figure 4</ref> shows an example of annotation.</p><p>Nine complex words that were evaluated as not having substitutes were excluded at this point. As a result, 2,010 sentences were annotated, as de- scribed in next subsection.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.4">Ranking substitutes</head><p>Five annotators arranged substitutes and complex words according to the simplification ranking. An- notators were permitted to assign a tie, but they could select up to four items to be in a tie because we intended to prohibit an insincere person from selecting a tie for all items. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Figure 5</ref> shows an ex- ample of annotation.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.5">Integrating simplification ranking</head><p>Annotators' rankings were integrated into one ranking, using a maximum likelihood estimation ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Matsui et al., 2014</ref>) to penalize deceptive annota- tors as was done by <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">De Belder and Moens (2012)</ref>. This method estimates the reliability of annotators in addition to determining the true order of rank- ings. We applied the reliability score to exclude extraordinary annotators. <ref type="table">Table 1</ref> shows the characteristics of our dataset. It is about the same size as previous work <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(Specia et al., 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Kajiwara and Yamamoto, 2015)</ref>. Our dataset has two advantages: (1) improved correla- tion with human judgment by making a controlled and balanced dataset, and (2) enhanced consis- tency by allowing ties in ranking and removing outlier annotators. In the following subsections, we evaluate our dataset in detail.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Result</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.1">Intrinsic evaluation</head><p>To evaluate the quality of the ranking integration, the Spearman rank correlation coefficient was cal- culated. The baseline integration ranking used an average score ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Kajiwara and Yamamoto, 2015)</ref>. Our proposed method excludes outlier annotators by using a reliability score calculated using the method developed by <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Matsui et al. (2014)</ref>.</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">1 |P | ∑ p 1 ,p 2 ∈P p 1 ∩ p 2 p 1 ∪ p 2 (1)</formula><p>Pairwise agreement is calculated between each pair of sets (p 1 , p 2 ∈ P ) from all the possible pair- ings (P) (Equation 1). The agreement among an- notators from the substitute evaluation phase was 0.669, and agreement among the students is 0.673, which is similar to the level found in crowdsourc- ing. This score is almost the same as that from <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Kajiwara and Yamamoto (2015)</ref>. On the contrary, 4 sentence  The most simplest method that is imitating safer is pretentiously smoke that Garam which is Indonesian cigarette. paraphrase list 1. 2. 3. , 4. 5. 6. 7. professing counterfeiting playing, professing playing pretending imitating falsifying    the Spearman rank correlation coefficient of the substitute ranking phase was 0.522. This score is higher than that from <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Kajiwara and Yamamoto (2015)</ref> by 0.190. This clearly shows the impor- tance of allowing ties during the substitute ranking task. <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">Table 2</ref> shows the results of the ranking inte- gration. Our method achieved better accuracy in ranking integration than previous methods <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(Specia et al., 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Kajiwara and Yamamoto, 2015)</ref> and is similar to the results from De <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Belder and Moens (2012)</ref>. This shows that the reliability score can be used for improving the quality. <ref type="table">Table 3</ref> shows the number of sentences and av- erage substitutes in each genre. In our dataset, the number of acquired substitutes is 8,636 words and the average number of substitutes is 4.30 words per sentence. <ref type="figure">Figure 6</ref> illustrates a part of our dataset. Substi- tutes that include particles are found in 75 context (3.7%). It is shown that if particles are not permit- ted in substitutes, we obtain only two substitutes (4 and 7). By permitting substitutes to include parti- cles, we are able to obtain 7 substitutes.</p><p>In ranking substitutes, Spearman rank correla- tion coefficient is 0.729, which is substantially higher than crowdsourcing's score. Thus, it is nec- essary to consider annotation method.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.2">Extrinsic evaluation</head><p>In this section, we evaluate our dataset using five simple lexical simplification methods. We calcu-   <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Kajiwara and Yamamoto (2015)</ref> or those of our dataset.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.2.1">Lexical simplification systems</head><p>We used several metrics for these experiments:</p><p>Frequency Because it is said that a high fre- quent word is simple, most frequent word is se- lected as a simplification candidate from substi- tutes using uni-gram frequency of Japanese Web N-gram ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Kudo and Kazawa, 2007)</ref>. This uni-gram frequency is counted from two billion sentences in Japanese Web text. <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Aramaki et al. (2013)</ref> claimed that a word used by many people is simple, so we pick the word used by the most of users. Number of Users were estimated from the Twitter corpus created by <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Aramaki et al. (2013)</ref>. The corpus con- tains 250 million tweets from 100,000 users.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Number of Users</head><p>Familiarity Assuming that a word which is known by many people is simple, replace a target word with substitutes according to the familiarity score using familiarity data constructed by <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Amano and Kondo (2000)</ref>. The familiarity score is an av- eraged score 28 annotators with seven grades.</p><p>JEV We hypothesized a word which is low dif- ficulty for non-native speakers is simple, so we select a word using a Japanese learner dictionary made by <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Sunakawa et al. (2012)</ref>. The word in dictionary has a difficulty score averaged by 5 Japanese teachers with their subjective annotation according to six grade system.</p><p>JLPT Same as above, but uses a different source called Japanese Language Proficient Test (JLPT). We choose the lowest level word using levels of JLPT. These levels are a scale of one to five.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.2.2">Evaluation</head><p>We ranked substitutes according to the metrics, and calculated the 1-best accuracy for each tar- get word. Finally, to compare two datasets, we used the Pearson product-moment correlation co- efficient between our dataset and the dataset of <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Kajiwara and Yamamoto (2015)</ref> against the anno- tated data. <ref type="table" target="#tab_5">Table 4</ref> shows the result of this experiment. The Pearson coefficient shows that our dataset corre- lates with human annotation better than the dataset of <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Kajiwara and Yamamoto (2015)</ref>, possibly be- cause we controlled each sentence to include only one complex word. Because our dataset is bal- anced, the accuracy of Web corpus-based metrics (Frequency and Number of Users) closer than the dataset of <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Kajiwara and Yamamoto (2015)</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Conclusion</head><p>We have presented a new controlled and balanced dataset for the evaluation of Japanese lexical sim- plification. Experimental results show that (1) our dataset is more consistent than the previous datasets and (2) lexical simplification methods us- ing our dataset correlate with human annotation better than the previous datasets. Future work in- cludes increasing the number of sentences, so as to leverage the dataset for machine learning-based simplification methods.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 shows</head><label>1</label><figDesc>a part of the dataset of Kajiwara and Yamamoto (2015). Our discussion in this pa- per is based on this example. Domain of the dataset is limited. Because Ka- jiwara and Yamamoto (2015) extracted sentences from a newswire corpus, their dataset has a poor variety of expression. English lexical simplifica- tion datasets (Specia et al., 2012; De Belder and Moens, 2012) do not have this problem because both of them use a balanced corpus of English (Sharoff, 2006). Complex words might exist in context. In Fig- ure 1, even when a target word such as "</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2: Process of constructing the dataset.</figDesc><graphic url="image-1.png" coords="3,86.13,59.80,173.51,168.01" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 2</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 3: Example of annotation of extracting substitutes. Annotators are provided with substitutes that preserve the meaning of target word which is shown bold in the sentence. In addition, annotators can write a substitute including particles.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>Figure 4 :</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Figure 4: Example of annotation of evaluating substitutes. Annotators choose substitutes that fit into the sentence from substitutes list.</figDesc><graphic url="image-3.png" coords="4,72.00,175.24,212.27,58.84" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head>Figure 5 :</head><label>5</label><figDesc>Figure 5: Example of annotation of ranking substitutes. Annotators write rank in blank. Additionally, they are allowed to write a tie.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><head>3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Detail of sentences and substitutes in our dataset. (BCCWJ comprise three main subcorpora: publication (P), library (L), special-purpose (O). PB = book, PM = magazine, PN = newswire, LB = book, OW = white paper, OT = textbook, OP =PR paper, OB = bestselling books, OC = Yahoo! Answers, OY = Yahoo! Blogs, OL = Law, OM = Magazine) baseline outlier removal Average 0.541 0.580</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" validated="false"><head>Table</head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><table></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3" validated="false"><head>Table 2 : Correlation of ranking integration.</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_5" validated="false"><head>Table 4 :</head><label>4</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Accuracy and correlation of the datasets. 

late 1-best accuracy in our dataset and the dataset 
of Kajiwara and Yamamoto (2015). Annotated 
data is collected by our and Kajiwara and Ya-
mamoto (2015)'s work in ranking substitutes task, 
and which size is 21,700 ((2010 + 2330) 5) 
rankings. Then, we calculate correlation between 
the accuracies of annotated data and either those 
of </table></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="4"> http://jhlee.sakura.ne.jp/JEV.html 5 Sahen noun is a kind of noun that can form a verb by adding a generic verb &quot;suru (do)&quot; to the noun. (e.g. &quot; repair&quot;) 6 Sahen verb is a sahen noun that accompanies with &quot;suru&quot;. (e.g. &quot; (do repair)&quot;)</note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">On the NTT psycholinguistic databases &quot;lexical properties of Japanese</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Shigeaki</forename><surname>Amano</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kimihisa</forename><surname>Kondo</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of the Phonetic Society of Japan</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="44" to="50" />
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Word in a dictionary is used by numerous users</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Eiji</forename><surname>Aramaki</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sachiko</forename><surname>Maskawa</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mai</forename><surname>Miyabe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mizuki</forename><surname>Morita</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sachi</forename><surname>Yasuda</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceeding of International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing</title>
		<meeting>eeding of International Joint Conference on Natural Language essing</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="874" to="877" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Text simplification for children</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jan</forename><forename type="middle">De</forename><surname>Belder</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marie-Francine</forename><surname>Moens</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the SIGIR Workshop on Accessible Search Systems</title>
		<meeting>the SIGIR Workshop on Accessible Search Systems</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="19" to="26" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A dataset for the evaluation of lexical simplification</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jan</forename><forename type="middle">De</forename><surname>Belder</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marie-Francine</forename><surname>Moens</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 13th International Conference on Computational Linguistics and Intelligent Text Processing</title>
		<meeting>the 13th International Conference on Computational Linguistics and Intelligent Text Processing</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="426" to="437" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Learning a lexical simplifier using Wikipedia</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Colby</forename><surname>Horn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Cathryn</forename><surname>Manduca</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Kauchak</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 52nd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the 52nd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Short Papers</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="458" to="463" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Evaluation dataset and system for Japanese lexical simplification</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tomoyuki</forename><surname>Kajiwara</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kazuhide</forename><surname>Yamamoto</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the ACL-IJCNLP 2015 Student Research Workshop</title>
		<meeting>the ACL-IJCNLP 2015 Student Research Workshop</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="35" to="40" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Japanese Web N-gram Version 1. Linguistic Data Consoritium</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Taku</forename><surname>Kudo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hideto</forename><surname>Kazawa</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Design, compilation, and preliminary analyses of balanced corpus of contemporary written Japanese</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kikuo</forename><surname>Maekawa</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Makoto</forename><surname>Yamazaki</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Takehiko</forename><surname>Maruyama</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Masaya</forename><surname>Yamaguchi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hideki</forename><surname>Ogura</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wakako</forename><surname>Kashino</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Toshinobu</forename><surname>Ogiso</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hanae</forename><surname>Koiso</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yasuharu</forename><surname>Den</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Seventh International Conference on Language Resources and Evaluation</title>
		<meeting>the Seventh International Conference on Language Resources and Evaluation</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1483" to="1486" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Crowdordering</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Toshiko</forename><surname>Matsui</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yukino</forename><surname>Baba</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Toshihiro</forename><surname>Kamishima</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hisashi</forename><surname>Kashima</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 18th Pacific-Asia Conference on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining</title>
		<meeting>the 18th Pacific-Asia Conference on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="336" to="347" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Semeval2007 task 10: English lexical substitution task</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Diana</forename><surname>Mccarthy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Roberto</forename><surname>Navigli</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 4th International Workshop on Semantic Evaluations</title>
		<meeting>the 4th International Workshop on Semantic Evaluations</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="48" to="53" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Open-source corpora: Using the net to fish for linguistic data</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Serge</forename><surname>Sharoff</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Corpus Linguistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="435" to="462" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">SemEval-2012 task 1: English lexical simplification</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lucia</forename><surname>Specia</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rada</forename><surname>Sujay Kumar Jauhar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Mihalcea</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 6th International Workshop on Semantic Evaluation</title>
		<meeting>the 6th International Workshop on Semantic Evaluation</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="347" to="355" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The construction of a database to support the compilation of Japanese learners dictionaries</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yuriko</forename><surname>Sunakawa</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jae-Ho</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mari</forename><surname>Takahara</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of the Acta Linguistica Asiatica</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="97" to="115" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
