<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T11:00+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Which Tumblr Post Should I Read Next?</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date>August 7-12, 2016</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Zornitsa</forename><surname>Kozareva</surname></persName>
							<email>zornitsa@kozareva.com</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Institute of Chemical Research</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Kyoto University</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>701 First Avenue Sunnyvale</addrLine>
									<postCode>94089, 611-0011</postCode>
									<settlement>Yahoo</settlement>
									<region>CA</region>
									<country key="JP">Japan</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Makoto</forename><surname>Yamada</surname></persName>
							<email>myamada@kuicr.kyoto-u.ac.jp</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Institute of Chemical Research</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Kyoto University</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>701 First Avenue Sunnyvale</addrLine>
									<postCode>94089, 611-0011</postCode>
									<settlement>Yahoo</settlement>
									<region>CA</region>
									<country key="JP">Japan</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Which Tumblr Post Should I Read Next?</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 54th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
						<meeting>the 54th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics <address><addrLine>Berlin, Germany</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="332" to="336"/>
							<date type="published">August 7-12, 2016</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Microblogging sites have emerged as major platforms for bloggers to create and consume posts as well as to follow other bloggers and get informed of their updates. Due to the large number of users, and the huge amount of posts they create, it becomes extremely difficult to identify relevant and interesting blog posts. In this paper, we propose a novel convex collective matrix completion (CCMC) method that effectively utilizes user-item matrix and incorporates additional user activity and topic-based signals to recommend relevant content. The key advantage of CCMC over existing methods is that it can obtain a globally optimal solution and can easily scale to large-scale matrices using Hazan&apos;s algorithm. To the best of our knowledge, this is the first work which applies and studies CCMC as a recommendation method in social media. We conduct a large scale study and show significant improvement over existing state-of-the-art approaches.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>The usage of social media sites has significantly increased over the years. Every minute people up- load thousands of new videos on YouTube, write blogs on Tumblr 1 , take pictures on Flickr and In- stagram, and send messages on Twitter and Face- book. This has lead to an information overload that makes it hard for people to search and dis- cover relevant information.</p><p>Social media sites have attempted to mitigate this problem by allowing users to follow, or sub- scribe to updates from specific users. However, as <ref type="bibr">1</ref> www.tumblr.com the number of followers grows over time, the in- formation overload problem returns. One possible solution to this problem is the usage of recommen- dation systems, which can display to users items and followers that are related to their interests and past activities.</p><p>Over time recommender methods have signifi- cantly evolved. By observing the history of user- item interactions, the systems learn the prefer- ences of the users and use this information to ac- curately filter through vast amount of items and allowing the user to quickly discover new, inter- esting and relevant items such as movies, clothes, books and posts. There is a substantial body of work on building recommendation systems for discovering new items, following people in social media platforms, predicting what people like ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Purushotham et al., 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Chua et al., 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Kim et al., 2013</ref>). However, these models either do not consider the characteristics of user-item adoption behaviors or cannot scale to the magnitude of data.</p><p>It is important to note that the problem of rec- ommending blog posts differs from the traditional collaborative filtering settings, such as the Net- flix rating prediction problem in two main as- pects. First, the interactions between the users and blogs are binary in the form of follows and there is no explicit rating information available about the user's preference. The follow informa- tion can be represented as an unidirectional un- weighted graph and popular proximity measures based on the structural properties of the graph have been applied to the problem ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Yin et al., 2011</ref>). Second, the blog recommendation inherently has richer side information additional to the conven- tional user-item matrix (i.e. follower graph).</p><p>In Tumblr, text data includes a lot of informa- tion, since posts have no limitation in length, com- pared to other microblogging sites such as Twit- ter. While such user generated content charac-terizes various blogs, user activity is a more di- rect and informative signal of user preference as users can explicitly express their interests by lik- ing and reblogging a post. This implies that users who liked or reblogged the same posts are likely to follow similar blogs. The challenge is how to combine multiple sources of information (text and activity) at the same time. For the purpose, we propose a novel convex collective matrix comple- tion (CCMC) social media recommender model, which can scale to million by million matrix using Hazan's algorithm <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Gunasekar et al., 2015)</ref>. Our contributions are as follows:</p><p>• We propose a novel CCMC based Tumblr blog post recommendation model. • We represent users and blogs with an exten- sive set of side information sources such as the user/blog activity and text/tags.</p><p>• We conduct extensive experimental evaluations on Tumblr data and show that our approach sig- nificantly outperforms existing methods.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Convex Collective Matrix Completion</head><p>In this section, we formulate the Tumblr blog post recommendation task as collective matrix factor- ization problem and we describe our large-scale convect collective matrix completion method with Hazan's algorithm (Gunasekar et al., 2015).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">Model Description</head><p>Let X 1 ∈ {0, 1} nr 1 ×nc 1 denote the user-blog (fol- lower) matrix, where n r 1 is the number of users and n c 1 is the number of blogs. In this matrix, if the user i likes blog j, the (i, j)th element is set to 1. In addition to the user-blog matrix, we have other auxiliary matrices denoted by X 2 ∈ R nr 2 ×nc 2 and X 3 ∈ R nr 3 ×nc 3 . For example, if we have an user activity matrix, we can use it as X 2 , where n r 2 = n r 1 and n c 2 is the number of activities. Moreover, if we have the content infor- mation of articles, we can use them as X 3 . In this case, n c 1 = n c 3 is the number of blogs, and n r 3 is the number of topics in LDA. Note that, X 1 tends to be a sparse matrix, while X 2 and X 3 tend to be denser matrices. The final goal is to factorize X 1 with the help of the auxiliary matrices X 2 and/or X 3 . First, we form a large matrix M by concate- nating all matrices [X v ] V v=1 and then factorizing M together with the regularizations.</p><p>In this paper, we adopt a convex approach ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Bouchard et al., 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Gunasekar et al., 2015</ref>).</p><p>For example, for V = 3 , the matrix M is given as</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">M =     · X 1 X 2 · X 1 · · X 3 X 2 · · · · X 3 · ·     .<label>(1)</label></formula><p>This framework is called convex collective ma- trix completion (CMC) <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">(Singh and Gordon, 2008)</ref>.</p><p>The key advantage of the CCMC approach is that the sparse user-blog matrix X 1 is factorized pre- cisely with the help of the dense matrices X 2 and/or X 3 . Moreover, it has been recently shown that the sample complexity of the CCMC algo- rithm can be smaller than that of the simple matrix factorization approach (i.e., only factorize X 1 ) ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Gunasekar et al., 2015)</ref>. Finally, the CCMC method can easily incorporate multiple sources of information. Over time if Tumblr provides new signals or if we decide to incorporate new features, CCMC can easily adopt them. Therefore, we be- lieve that CCMC is very suitable for solving the Tumblr recommendation task.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">CCMC-Hazan Algorithm</head><p>One of the key challenges of CCMC for Tum- blr data is the scalability, since Tumblr has more than million users and hundred millions of blog posts. The original CCMC approach adopts Sin- gular Value Thresholding (SVT) to solve the prob- lem, and it works for small scale problems. How- ever, SVT needs to solve N × N dimensional eigenvalue decomposition on each iteration, and thus it is not feasible to deal directly with the Tumblr data. Recently, Gunasekar et al. pro- posed an Atomic norm minimization algorithm for CCMC ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Gunasekar et al., 2015</ref>) using the approx- imate SDP solver of Hazan <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Hazan, 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Jaggi and Sulovsky, 2010)</ref>. The optimization problem is given as</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">min Z0 V v=1 P Ωv (X v − P v (Z)) 2 F s.t. tr(Z) ≤ η,<label>(2)</label></formula><p>where X F is the Frobenius norm of matrix X , P Ωv , which extracts the elements in the set, Ω v is the set of non-zero indexes of X v , P v (Z) = Z v ∈ R nr v ×nc v , and η ≥ 0 is a regularization parameter. The Hazan's algorithm for CMF is summarized in Algorithm 1.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Algorithm 1 CCMC with Hazan's Algorithm of (2)</head><p>Parameters: T (Number of iterations) Rescale loss:</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">ˆ fη(Z) = v PΩ v (Xv − Pv(ηZ)) 2 F Initialize Z (1) for all t = 1, 2 . . . , T = 4 do Compute u (t) = approxEV − ˆ fη(Z (t) ), 1 t 2 2 αt := 2 2+t Z (t+1) = Z (t) + αtu (t) u (t) end forreturn [Pv(Z (T ) )] V v=1</formula><p>The advantage of CCMC-Hazan is that it needs to compute only a top eigenvector on each itera- tion. Practically, on each iteration t in Algorithm 1, we just need to compute an 1 t 2 -approximate largest eigenvalue of the sparse matrix with |Ω| non-zero elements, which needs O( |Ω| t ) compu- tation using Lanczos algorithm. On the other hand, the original CCMC algorithms adopt Sin- gular Value Thresholding (SVT) method, which converges much faster than CCMC-Hazan. How- ever, the SVT approach has to compute all eigen- values in each iteration. Thus, CCMC-Hazan is more suited for large-scale dataset than CCMC- SVT. The details of CMC with Hazan's algorithm, please refer to ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Gunasekar et al., 2015</ref>).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Task Definition</head><p>We define our task as given a set of users and their Tumblr post adoption behavior over a period of time, the goal is to build a model that can discover and recommend relevant Tumblr posts to the users.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Evaluation Setup and Data</head><p>We set up our Tumblr post evaluation framework by considering the posting or reblogging of an item j by a user i as an adopted item, and other- wise as unadopted. We present each user with top k items sorted by their predicted adoption score and evaluate how many of the recommended items (posts) were actually adopted by the users.</p><p>For our post recommendation study, we used Tumblr data from July until September. We used the data from July to August for training, and tested on the data from September. This experi- mental set up simulates A/B testing.</p><p>From the derived data, we sampled 15, 000 ac- tive users and 35, 000 posts resulting in 5 million user-item adoptions for training and 8.6 million user-item adoptions for testing. <ref type="bibr">2</ref> approxEV(X, computes the approximate top eigen vector of X upto error.</p><p>In post recommendation our CCMC-Hazan method uses an user-item matrix X 1 ∈ {0, 1} 15000×35000 and an item-topic matrix X 2 ∈ R 35000×1000 . To learn the topics we use Latent Dirichlet Allocation (LDA) ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Blei et al., 2003)</ref>. We represent a document as a collection of post de- scription, captions and hashtags. We use 1000 topics for our experiments. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref> shows some examples of the learned topics from the Tumblr posts. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Evaluation Metrics</head><p>To evaluate the performance of our collaborative matrix factorization approach for Tumblr post rec- ommendation, we calculate precision (P), recall (R) and normalized discounted cumulative gain (nDCG) for top-k recommended posts.</p><p>-P@k as the fraction of adopted items by each user in top-k items in the list. We aveage precision@k across all users.</p><p>-R@k as the fraction of adopted items that are successfully discovered in top-k ranked list out of all adopted items by each user. We average recall@k across all users.</p><p>-nDCG@k computes the weighted score of adopted items based on the position in the top-k list. We average nDCG@k of all users. We set k to 10 since recommending too many posts is unrealistic. While nDCG@k uses the po- sition of correct answer in the top-k ranked list, it does not penalize for unadopted posts or miss- ing adopted posts in the top-k ranked list. There- fore, to judge the performance of the algorithms, one has to consider all three metrics together. In- tuitively a good performing model is the one that has high P@k, R@k and nDCG@k.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3">Comparison Against State-of-art Models</head><p>In addition to evaluating the performance of our algorithm on Tumblr post recommendation, we also conducted a comparative study against exist- ing state-of-the-art models. Item-based <ref type="bibr">3</ref> The item-based model recommends items that are similar to what the users have al- ready adopted <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Karypis, 2001)</ref>. The model does not use textual information and only uses adopted items to compute the similarity between the items. The similarity metric is the Tanimoto Coefficient, which is used to handle binary ratings.</p><p>User-based The user-based model recommends items that are adopted by other users with simi- lar taste <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Herlocker et al., 1999</ref>). The model does not use textual information and only uses adopted items to compute the similarity between the users. Similar to the item-based recommendation, we use the Tanimoto Coefficient. We choose top k items using k-Nearest Neighbor of similar users. MC 4 Alternating least squares (ALS) is ma- trix completion (MC) based collaborative filter- ing model, which was originally introduced to model user-movie rating prediction using mean- square loss function with weighted λ regulariza- tion ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">Zhou et al., 2008)</ref>. The model does not use textual information or signals for adopted items. PMC <ref type="bibr">5</ref> Probabilistic Matrix Completion ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Salakhutdinov and Mnih, 2008</ref>) is a proba- bilistic linear model with Gaussian observation noise that handles very large data sets and is robust to sparse user-item matrix. Similar to MC, PMC models the user-item adoption as the product of two K-dimensional lower-rank user and item hidden variables. The model does not use textual information, but unlike the previous methods it uses information on unadopted items. CF Collaborative Filtering model with softmax function <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Guadagni and Little, 1983;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Manski, 1975;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b11">McFadden, 1974)</ref> captures the adoption and un-adoption behavior of users on items in social media. The model does not use textual informa- tion, but it uses signals on unadopted items. CF allows us to study the gain of performance in post recommendation when softmax function is used instead of the objective functions used in MC and PMC. CTR Collaborative Topic Regression ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Wang and Blei, 2011)</ref>   <ref type="table">Table 1</ref> shows the obtained results of the proposed CCMC-Hazan method against the remaining rec- ommendation models. The simple user and item based recommendations have the lowest perfor- mance. This shows that for accurate post rec- ommendation using direct post and user informa- tion is insufficient and one needs stronger context driven signals. This is shown in the performance of the CF and CTR methods, which model context information with LDA and perform better than the rest of the models. However, when we compare the performance of our collaborative matrix completion method, we can see that the rest of the models have sig- nificantly lower performance. The main reasons are due to the dense information of CCMC-Hazan method and the fact that our method optimizes a convex function whereas the MC, CF and CTF models can get stuck in local optima.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.4">Results</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Conclusions</head><p>Recommending blog posts is one of the major tasks for user engagement and revenue generation in online microblogging sites such as Tumblr. In this paper, we propose a convex collective matrix completion based recommendation method that effectively utilizes the user-item matrix as well as rich side information from users and/or items. We evaluate the proposed method on real-world dataset collected from Tumblr. Extensive exper- iments demonstrate the effectiveness of the pro- posed method in comparison to existing state-of- the-art approaches.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>335</head></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: LDA.</figDesc><graphic url="image-1.png" coords="3,307.28,210.50,226.76,108.32" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" validated="false"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>was originally introduced to recom- mend scientific articles. It combines collabora- tive filtering PMC and probabilistic topic model-</figDesc><table>3 https://mahout.apache.org 
4 www.graphlab.org 
5 http://www.cs.cmu.edu/ chongw/citeulike/ 

Method 
PRC@10 RCL@20 AUC 
Item-based 
0.24 
0.08 
0.42 
User-based 
0.32 
0.11 
0.51 
MC 
0.31 
0.11 
0.52 
PMC 
0.35 
0.12 
0.55 
CF 
0.36 
0.13 
0.56 
CTR 
0.39 
0.14 
0.59 
CCMC-Hazan 0.41 
0.16 
0.61 

Table 1: Tumblr Post Recommendation Results 

ing LDA. It captures two K-dimensional lower-
rank user and item hidden variables from user-item 
adoption matrix and the content of the items. This 
model uses textual information and signal for un-
adopted items. 

</table></figure>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgement</head><p>We would like to thank the anonymous review-ers for their valuable feedback and grant MEXT KAKENHI #16K16114.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Latent dirichlet allocation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Blei</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Andrew</forename><surname>Ng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Jordan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The Journal of Machine Learning Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="993" to="1022" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Convex collective matrix factorization</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Guillaume</forename><surname>Bouchard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Shengbo</forename><surname>Guo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dawei</forename><surname>Yin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">AISTATS</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Generative models for item adoptions using social correlation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Freddy Chong Tat</forename><surname>Chua</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hady</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Lauw</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ee-Peng</forename><surname>Lim</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE Trans. on Knowl. and Data Eng</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">25</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2036" to="2048" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A logit model of brand choice calibrated on scanner data</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Peter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">John</forename><surname>Guadagni</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Dc Little</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Marketing science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="203" to="238" />
			<date type="published" when="1983" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Consistent collective matrix completion under joint low rank structure</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Suriya</forename><surname>Gunasekar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Makoto</forename><surname>Yamada</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dawei</forename><surname>Yin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yi</forename><surname>Chang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">AISTATS</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Sparse Approximate Solutions to Semidefinite Programs</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Elad</forename><surname>Hazan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="306" to="316" />
			<pubPlace>Berlin Heidelberg</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">An algorithmic framework for performing collaborative filtering</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jonathan</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Herlocker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Joseph</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Konstan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Al</forename><surname>Borchers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">John</forename><surname>Riedl</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">SIGIR</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A simple algorithm for nuclear norm regularized problems</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Martin</forename><surname>Jaggi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marek</forename><surname>Sulovsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ICML</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Evaluation of item-based top-n recommendation algorithms</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">George</forename><surname>Karypis</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">CIKM</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Sentiment prediction using collaborative filtering</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jihie</forename><surname>Kim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jaebong</forename><surname>Yoo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ho</forename><surname>Lim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Huida</forename><surname>Qiu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Zornitsa</forename><surname>Kozareva</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Aram</forename><surname>Galstyan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ICWSM</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Maximum score estimation of the stochastic utility model of choice</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Charles F Manski</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Econometrics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="205" to="228" />
			<date type="published" when="1975" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Conditional logit analysis of qualitative choice behavior</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Daniel</forename><surname>Mcfadden</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Frontiers in Econometrics</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1974" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="105" to="142" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Collaborative topic regression with social matrix factorization for recommendation systems</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sanjay</forename><surname>Purushotham</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yan</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C.-C. Jay</forename><surname>Kuo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<publisher>CoRR</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ruslan</forename><surname>Salakhutdinov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Andriy</forename><surname>Mnih</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Bayesian probabilistic matrix factorization using markov chain monte carlo</title>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ICML</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Relational learning via collective matrix factorization</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Ajit</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Geoffrey</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Singh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Gordon</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">KDD</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Collaborative topic modeling for recommending scientific articles</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chong</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Blei</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">KDD</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Structural link analysis and prediction in microblogs</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Liangjie</forename><surname>Dawei Yin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Brian</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Hong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Davison</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">CIKM</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Large-scale parallel collaborative filtering for the netflix prize</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yunhong</forename><surname>Zhou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dennis</forename><surname>Wilkinson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Robert</forename><surname>Schreiber</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rong</forename><surname>Pan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">AAIM</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
