<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T12:10+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">How Naked is the Naked Truth? A Multilingual Lexicon of Nominal Compound Compositionality</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date>August 7-12, 2016</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Carlos</forename><surname>Ramisch</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory">LIF UMR 7279</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Aix Marseille Université</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">CNRS</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="FR">France</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Silvio</forename><surname>Cordeiro</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory">LIF UMR 7279</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Aix Marseille Université</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">CNRS</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="FR">France</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Institute of Informatics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Federal University of Rio Grande do Sul</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="BR">Brazil</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Leonardo</forename><surname>Zilio</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Institute of Informatics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Federal University of Rio Grande do Sul</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="BR">Brazil</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marco</forename><surname>Idiart</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="department">Institute of Physics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Federal University of Rio Grande do Sul</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="BR">Brazil</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Aline</forename><surname>Villavicencio</surname></persName>
							<email>avillavicencio@inf.ufrgs.br rswilkens@inf.ufrgs.br</email>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Institute of Informatics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Federal University of Rio Grande do Sul</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="BR">Brazil</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rodrigo</forename><surname>Wilkens</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Institute of Informatics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Federal University of Rio Grande do Sul</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="BR">Brazil</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">How Naked is the Naked Truth? A Multilingual Lexicon of Nominal Compound Compositionality</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 54th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
						<meeting>the 54th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics <address><addrLine>Berlin, Germany</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="156" to="161"/>
							<date type="published">August 7-12, 2016</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>We introduce a new multilingual resource containing judgments about nominal compound compositionality in English, French and Por-tuguese. It covers 3 × 180 noun-noun and adjective-noun compounds for which we provide numerical compositionality scores for the head word, for the modifier and for the compound as a whole, along with possible paraphrases. This resource was constructed by native speakers via crowdsourcing. It can serve as basis for evaluating tasks such as lexical substitution and compositionality prediction.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Multiword expressions (MWEs) are notoriously chal- lenging for NLP, due to their many potential levels of idiosyncrasy, from lexical to semantic and pragmatic to statistical <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">(Sag et al., 2002;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Ramisch, 2015)</ref>. One widely known problem is the semantic interpretation of noun compounds, which in English are noun phrases composed by a sequence of nouns. These MWEs often lack a structure from which to identify implicit seman- tic relations unambiguously. For instance, there is no indication that a brick wall is a wall made of bricks, while a cheese knife is not a knife made of cheese, but rather a knife for cutting cheese ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Girju et al., 2005</ref>).</p><p>Noun compounds are often idiomatic or non- compositional. That is, the meaning of the whole does not come directly from the meaning of the parts. For instance, a black Friday is not any Friday that is somehow black, but is the day following Thanksgiv- ing Day in the United States. Moreover, the contribu- tion of the semantics of each element for the meaning of the compound may vary considerably (e.g. police car vs. crocodile tears). Any NLP application that in- tends to deal with phrasal semantics adequately must be able to distinguish fairly compositional from fully id- iomatic compounds. For example, automatically trans- lating dead end literally into French (?fin morte) or Por- tuguese (?fim morto) would drastically alter the mean- ing of the original expression. In this paper we intro- duce a resource with human judgments about the se- mantics of compounds and their individual elements.</p><p>Eliciting quantitative judgments about composition- ality from non-linguists may be too abstract, even with accompanying guidelines and training. We propose a more constrained way of obtaining these judgments, with the participation of non-experts through crowd- sourcing. We first focus the participants' attention on compound interpretation in context, by requesting paraphrases in example sentences. Then, we inquire about the degree to which the meaning of a given com- pound arises from each of its elements. The assumption is that if the interpretation of the compound comes from both nouns (e.g. access road), then it is fully compo- sitional, whereas if it is unrelated to both nouns (e.g. nut case), then it is fully idiomatic. This indirect anno- tation does not require expert knowledge and provides reliable and stable data.</p><p>This paper presents a multilingual resource that models compounds compositionality, including both numerical scores and free paraphrases. Data is cur- rently available for 180 compounds in 3 different lan- guages: English, French and Portuguese. Such re- sources are extremely valuable, as they enable the de- velopment and evaluation of techniques for automatic compositionality prediction and lexical substitution. This paper is structured as follows: §2 discusses related work; §3 discusses the target compounds, the annota- tion schema and interface; §4 presents the results and §5 the conclusions and future work.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Related Work</head><p>There are many proposals in the literature to represent the semantics of nominal compounds. <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Lauer (1995)</ref> argues that prepositions (such as from, for, in) pro- vide information about the role of each noun in a com- pound (e.g. olive oil is oil from olives). These preposi- tions are explicitly part of some nominal compounds in Romance languages (e.g. huile d'olive in French and azeite de oliva in Portuguese). <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Girju et al. (2005)</ref> present and compare several inventories of semantic relations between nouns, from fine-grained to coarse senses. These relations include syntactic and semantic classes such as subject, instrument and location. Free paraphrases have also been used to model noun com- pound semantics. <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Nakov (2008)</ref> suggests using unsu- pervised generation of paraphrases combined with web search engines to classify nominal compounds. This was further extended in SemEval 2013, in a task where free paraphrases were ranked according to their rele- vance for explicitly describing the underlying semantic relations in the compounds ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Hendrickx et al., 2013</ref>). For instance, for the MWE flu virus, paraphrases in- volving the verbs cause, spread and create (virus that causes/spreads/creates flu) were in the top of the rank. Some authors model the meaning of compounds using numerical compositionality scores: low values mean completely idiomatic compounds while high val- ues represent compositional ones. Separate scores can be provided for the amount of meaning provided by each individual word. For instance, olive oil could be 80% related to olives and 100% related to oil, whereas dead end is 5% dead and 90% an end. Some datasets that employ a numerical representation for different types of MWE are:</p><p>• Baldwin and Villavicencio <ref type="formula">(2002)</ref>: binary type-level judgments for 3,078 English phrasal verbs, from which 14% are considered idiomatic.</p><p>• McCarthy et al. <ref type="formula">(2003)</ref>: type-based scores on a scale from 0 to 10 provided by three experts for 116 En- glish phrasal verbs.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>• Reddy et al. (2011): average of 30 judgments on a scale from 0 to 5 provided by native speakers via crowdsourcing for 90 English noun compounds. • Gurrutxaga and Alegria (2013): three-way classifi- cation (idiom, collocation, free combination) pro- vided by three experts for 1,200 Basque noun-verb expressions. • Roller et al. (2013): average of around 30 judgments</head><p>on a scale from 1 to 7 obtained through crowdsourc- ing for 244 German noun compounds.</p><p>• : individual binary judg- ments for non-compositionality and conventionality for 1,042 English noun compounds, annotated by 4 experts. One possible source of divergence among annotators is that some datasets do not take polysemy into ac- count. Authors ask annotators to think about the most common sense of an MWE without providing context. Some of these datasets address this issue by providing example sentences to attenuate this problem. We also employ this strategy in our questionnaires. The most similar datasets to ours are the ones presented by <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Reddy et al. (2011)</ref> and <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Hendrickx et al. (2013)</ref>. Our dataset combines the methodology from both of these, extend- ing it to French and Portuguese.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Dataset Construction</head><p>Although noun-noun compounds are rare in some lan- guages mainly due to syntactic reasons, these lan- guages present alternatives to this type of configura- tion. In French (FR) and Brazilian Portuguese (PT), the equivalents of English (EN) compounds of the form N 1 N 2 are usually:</p><p>1. N 2 PREP N 1 , connecting the nouns through a preposition and optional determiner; e.g. lung cancer (EN) → cancer du poumon (FR), câncer de pulmão (PT). 2. N 2 ADJ 1 , using a denominal adjective which is derived from N 1 ; e.g. cell death (EN) → mort cellulaire (FR), morte celular (PT). We describe the construction of datasets for English, French and Brazilian Portuguese. Given the two syn- tactic forms above, we focus on N 2 ADJ 1 for French and Portuguese, as its simpler structure resembles more closely the English noun-noun compound structure, and also because we have some ADJ 1 N 2 compounds in English as well (e.g. sacred cow). We collectively call our target constructions nominal compounds, as they have nouns as head of the phrase.</p><p>For each language, data collection involves the fol- lowing steps: (1) compound selection; (2) sentence se- lection; and (3) questionnaire design.</p><p>Compound selection The initial set of idiomatic and partially compositional candidates was constructed by introspection, independently for each language, since these may be harder to find in corpora because of lower frequency. This list of compounds was comple- mented by selecting entries from lists of frequent ad- jective+noun and noun+noun pairs. These were au- tomatically extracted through POS-sequence queries using the mwetoolkit (Ramisch, 2015) from ukWaC ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Baroni et al., 2009</ref>), frWaC and brWaC ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Boos et al., 2014</ref>). We removed all compounds in which the com- plement is not an adjective in Portuguese/French (e.g. PT noun-noun abelha rainha), those in which the head is not necessarily a noun (e.g. FR aller simple, as aller is also a verb) and those in which the literal sense is very common in the corpus (e.g. EN low blow). For each language, we attempted to select a balanced set of 60 idiomatic, 60 partially compositional and 60 fully compositional compounds by rough manual pre- annotation. <ref type="bibr">1</ref> Sentence selection For each compound, we selected 3 sentences from a WaC corpus where the compound is used with the same meaning. These sentences are used during the data collection process (described later) as disambiguating context for the annotators. We sort them by sentence length, in order to favor shorter sen- tences, and manually select 3 examples that satisfy these criteria:</p><p>• The occurrence of the compound must have the same meaning in all sentences.</p><p>• A sentence must contain enough context to enable mental disambiguation of the compound.</p><p>• Inter-sentence variability can be used to provide more information to the reader. Questionnaire design We collect data for each com- pound through a separate HIT (Human Intelligence Task). Each HIT page contains a list of instructions fol- lowed by the questionnaire associated with that com- pound. In the instructions, we briefly describe the task and require that the users fill in an external identifica- tion form, following <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Reddy et al. (2011)</ref>. This form provides us with demographics about the annotators, ensuring that they are native speakers of the target lan- guage. At the end of the form, they are also given extra example questions with annotated answers for training. After filling in the identification form, users can start working on the task. This section of the HIT is struc- tured in 5 subtasks:</p><p>1. Read the compound itself. 2. Read 3 sentences containing the compound.</p><p>3. Provide 2 to 3 synonym expressions for the target compound seen in the sentences. 4. Using a Likert scale from 0 to 5, judge how much of the meaning of the compound comes from word 1 (mod) and word 2 (head) separately, as shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref>. 5. Using a Likert scale from 0 to 5, judge how much of the meaning of the compound (comp) comes from its components. We have been consciously careful about requiring answers in an even-numbered scale (0-5 makes for 6 reply categories), as otherwise, undecided annotators would be biased towards the middle score. As an addi- tional help for the annotators, when the mouse hovers over a reply to a multiple-choice question, we present a guiding tooltip, as in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref>. We avoid incomplete HITs by making Subtasks 3-5 mandatory.</p><p>The order of subtasks has also been taken into ac- count. During a pilot test, we found that presenting the multiple-choice questions (Subtasks 4-5) before ask- ing for synonyms (Subtask 3) yielded lower agreement, as users were often less self-consistent in the multiple- choice questions (e.g. replying "non-compositional" for Subtask 4 but "compositional" for Subtask 5), even if they carefully selected their synonyms in response to Subtask 3. Asking for synonyms prior to the multiple- choice questions helps the user focus on the target meaning for the compound and also have more ex- amples (the synonyms) when considering the semantic contribution of each element of the compound.</p><p>For EN and FR, annotators were recruited and paid via Amazon Mechanical Turk. The quality of FR re- sults was manually controlled by only accepting HITs with reasonable paraphrases. During a pilot, we no- ticed the lack of qualified PT native speakers on the platform. For PT only, judgments were provided by volunteers through a standalone web interface that sim- ulated the HIT page.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Results</head><p>For each compound, we have collected judgments from around 15 HITs. The average of these scores, for EN 2 , FR and PT, are shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 2</ref>. The composition- ality judgments for the compounds confirm that they are balanced with respect to idiomaticity. Moreover, there seems to be a greater agreement between the score for the compound and that of its head (or mod- ifier) for the two extremes (totally idiomatic and fully compositional). For PT and FR, in particular, the com- pound score seems to be a lower bound to each member word's score.</p><p>We also looked at the distribution of each of the scores around the mean in terms of the standard devi- ation (σ). Ideally, if all the annotators agreed on com- positionality, σ should be low. We calculated for each language the number of compounds, heads and mod- ifiers with standard deviations greater than 1.5 <ref type="table">(Table  1)</ref>. The largest variations are for modifiers, which may reflect their potentially accessory role in the meaning of the compound in relation to the head.  <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>: Pearson correlation r and number of cases of high standard deviation σ. Out of all human judges, 3 of them annotated a large subset of 119 compounds in PT. For this subset, we re- port inter-annotator agreement. Pairwise weighted κ values range from .28 to .58 depending on the ques- tion (head, mod or comp) and on the annotator pair. Multi-rater α agreement ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Artstein and Poesio, 2008)</ref> values are α = .52 for head, α = .36 for mod and α = .42 for comp scores. We have also calculated the α score of an expert annotator with himself, performing the same task a few weeks later. The score ranges from 0.59 for modifiers and compounds to 0.69 for heads. This seems to confirm the hypothesis that modifiers are harder to annotate than heads. <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table 2</ref> presents the most controversial compounds, along with the ones that had highest agreement (lowest σ). The most consensual compounds are mostly 100% compositional and sometimes 100% idiomatic. Low σ values are consistent among the three questions, indi- cating that some compounds are simply easier to judge than others.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>EN</head><p>There are multiple reasons for divergences in the judgment scores. For some MWEs, our sentences were not enough for disambiguation; e.g. one of the fish story sentences talked about a whale and prompted literal in- terpretations of fish for some judges). Other differences have been caused by the interpretation of uncommon words; e.g. the PT noun olhado does not appear by it- self very often; some judges seem to have interpreted it as an adjective and thus concluded that mau-olhado (evil eye, lit. bad-glance) has a fully non-compositional head. Finally, some differences have been caused by whether speakers had incorporated a new meaning into their lexicon; e.g. EN speakers agreed on the level of head and head+modifier compositionality for dirty word, but disagreed when judging the modifier: it is fully idiomatic for some, while just containing an un- common sense of dirty for others.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Conclusions and Future Work</head><p>We presented a multilingual dataset of nominal com- pounds containing human judgments about composi- tionality. It contains 180 compounds for each of the 3 target languages: English, French and Portuguese. An- notations are collected through crowdsourcing. Since the task is performed by native speakers who may not have a background in linguistics, it needs to be appro- priately constrained not to require expert knowledge. The resulting resource can be used for applications and tasks involving some degree of semantic processing, such as lexical substitution and text simplification. For the cases where the numerical judgments alone are not enough for a given task, our dataset also provides sets of paraphrases, which serve as a symbolic counterpart to those scores. The complete resource will be made freely available. <ref type="bibr">3</ref> As future work, we plan to validate these scores through compositionality prediction (Yaz-compound head mod comp English brass ring 3.9 ±2.0 3.7 ±1.9 3.7 ±1.8 fish story 4.8 ±0.4 1.5 ±1.8 1.7 ±1.8 tennis elbow 4.3 ±1.3 2.2 ±1.8 2.5 ±1.8 brick wall 3.5 ±1.9 3.2 ±2.2 3.8 ±1.7 dirty word 4.1 ±1.4 2.0 ±1.4 2.5 ±1.7 prison guard 4.8 ±0.4 4.9 ±0.3 4.9 ±0.3 graduate student 5.0 ±0.0 4.7 ±0.5 4.9 ±0.3 engine room 5.0 ±0.0 4.9 ±0.3 4.9 ±0.3 climate change 4.8 ±0.4 4.9 ±0.3 5.0 ±0.2 insurance company 4.9 ±0.5 5.0 ±0.0 5.0 ±0.0   <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">2015;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Salehi et al., 2015)</ref> and by incorporat- ing the scores and paraphrases into a machine transla- tion system. We also envisage extending the dataset for each of the languages and for additional languages.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: Evaluating compositionality regarding a compounds' head.</figDesc><graphic url="image-1.png" coords="3,113.83,62.81,367.40,70.95" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2: Average compositionality for compounds, heads and modifiers.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" validated="false"><head>Table 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Most polemic and consensual compounds in 
each language (average±σ score). 

dani et al., </table></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> We have not attempted to select equivalent compounds for all three languages. A compound in a given language may correspond to a single word in the other languages. Even when it does translate as a compound, its POS pattern and level of compositionality may be widely different.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="2"> We include the 90 compounds from Reddy et al. (2011), which are compatible with the new dataset.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="3"> http://pageperso.lif.univ-mrs. fr/~carlos.ramisch/?page=downloads/ compounds</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>This work has been partly funded by projects PARSEME-FR (ANR-14-CERA-0001), AIM-WEST <ref type="table">(FAPERGS-INRIA</ref> </p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Inter-coder agreement for computational linguistics</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ron</forename><surname>Artstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Massimo</forename><surname>Poesio</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Computational Linguistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">34</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="555" to="596" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Extracting the unextractable: A case study on verbparticles</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Timothy</forename><surname>Baldwin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Aline</forename><surname>Villavicencio</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of CoNLL 2002, COLING02</title>
		<meeting>CoNLL 2002, COLING02</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACL</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="7" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The wacky wide web: a collection of very large linguistically processed webcrawled corpora. Language Resources and Evaluation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marco</forename><surname>Baroni</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Silvia</forename><surname>Bernardini</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Adriano</forename><surname>Ferraresi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Eros</forename><surname>Zanchetta</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009-09" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">43</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="209" to="226" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Identification of multiword expressions in the brWaC</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rodrigo</forename><surname>Boos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kassius</forename><surname>Prestes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Aline</forename><surname>Villavicencio</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ELRA, May. ACL Anthology Identifier</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="14" to="1429" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Proceedings of LREC 2014</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A multiword expression data set: Annotating non-compositionality and conventionalization for english noun compounds</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Meghdad</forename><surname>Farahmand</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Aaron</forename><surname>Smith</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Joakim</forename><surname>Nivre</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of NAACL-HLT</title>
		<meeting>NAACL-HLT</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="29" to="33" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">On the semantics of noun compounds</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Roxana</forename><surname>Girju</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dan</forename><surname>Moldovan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marta</forename><surname>Tatu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Daniel</forename><surname>Antohe</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Computer speech &amp; language</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="479" to="496" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Combining different features of idiomaticity for the automatic classification of noun+verb expressions in Basque</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Antton</forename><surname>Gurrutxaga</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Iñaki</forename><surname>Alegria</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 9th Workshop on Multiword Expressions</title>
		<meeting>the 9th Workshop on Multiword Expressions</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACL</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2013-06" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="116" to="125" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Semeval-2013 task 4: Free paraphrases of noun compounds</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Iris</forename><surname>Hendrickx</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Zornitsa</forename><surname>Kozareva</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Preslav</forename><surname>Nakov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ó</forename><surname>Diarmuid</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Stan</forename><surname>Séaghdha</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tony</forename><surname>Szpakowicz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Veale</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of *SEM 2013</title>
		<meeting>*SEM 2013</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACL</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2013-06" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="138" to="143" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">How much is enough?: Data requirements for statistical NLP</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mark</forename><surname>Lauer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="abs/cmp-lg/9509001" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
			<publisher>CoRR</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Detecting a continuum of compositionality in phrasal verbs</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Diana</forename><surname>Mccarthy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bill</forename><surname>Keller</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">John</forename><surname>Carroll</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the ACL 2003 Workshop on Multiword Expressions, MWE &apos;03</title>
		<meeting>the ACL 2003 Workshop on Multiword Expressions, MWE &apos;03</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACL</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="73" to="80" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Paraphrasing verbs for noun compound interpretation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Preslav</forename><surname>Nakov</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of the LREC Workshop Towards a Shared Task for MWEs (MWE 2008)</title>
		<meeting>of the LREC Workshop Towards a Shared Task for MWEs (MWE 2008)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="46" to="49" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Multiword Expressions Acquisition-A Generic and Open Framework. Theory and Applications of Natural Language Processing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Carlos</forename><surname>Ramisch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">An empirical study on compositionality in compound nouns</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Siva</forename><surname>Reddy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Diana</forename><surname>Mccarthy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Suresh</forename><surname>Manandhar</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of IJCNLP 2011</title>
		<meeting>IJCNLP 2011</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011-11" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The (un)expected effects of applying standard cleansing models to human ratings on compositionality</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Stephen</forename><surname>Roller</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sabine</forename><surname>Schulte Im Walde</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Silke</forename><surname>Scheible</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 9th Workshop on Multiword Expressions</title>
		<meeting>the 9th Workshop on Multiword Expressions</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACL</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2013-06" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="32" to="41" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Multiword expressions: A pain in the neck for NLP</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Sag</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Baldwin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Bond</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Copestake</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Flickinger</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of CICLing2002</title>
		<meeting>CICLing2002</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="15" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A word embedding approach to predicting the compositionality of multiword expressions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bahar</forename><surname>Salehi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Paul</forename><surname>Cook</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Timothy</forename><surname>Baldwin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of NAACL-HLT 2015</title>
		<meeting>NAACL-HLT 2015</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACL</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2015-05" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="977" to="983" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Learning semantic composition to detect non-compositionality of multiword expressions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Majid</forename><surname>Yazdani</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Meghdad</forename><surname>Farahmand</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">James</forename><surname>Henderson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of EMNLP 2015</title>
		<meeting>EMNLP 2015</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACL</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2015-09" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1733" to="1742" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
