<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T11:43+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Implicit Polarity and Implicit Aspect Recognition in Opinion Mining</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date>August 7-12, 2016</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Huan-Yuan</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
							<email>hhchen@ntu.edu.tw</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science and Information Engineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">National Taiwan University</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Taipei</settlement>
									<country key="TW">Taiwan</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hsin-Hsi</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science and Information Engineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">National Taiwan University</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Taipei</settlement>
									<country key="TW">Taiwan</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Implicit Polarity and Implicit Aspect Recognition in Opinion Mining</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 54th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
						<meeting>the 54th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics <address><addrLine>Berlin, Germany</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="20" to="25"/>
							<date type="published">August 7-12, 2016</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>This paper deals with a double-implicit problem in opinion mining and sentiment analysis. We aim at identifying aspects and polarities of opinionated statements not consisting of opinion words and aspect terms. As a case study, opinion words and aspect terms are first extracted from Chinese hotel reviews, and then grouped into positive (negative) clusters and aspect term clusters. We observe that an implicit opinion and its neighbor explicit opinion tend to have the same aspect and polarity. Under the observation, we construct an implicit opinions corpus annotated with aspect class labels and polarity automatically. Aspect and polarity classifiers trained by using this corpus is used to recognize aspect and polarity of implicit opinions.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Opinions are classified into explicit and implicit ones depending on the subjectivity and objectivity <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Liu, 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr">Zhang and Liu, 2014)</ref>. It is more chal- lenging to detect implicit opinions than explicit ones due to the lack of explicit opinion words in the sentences. Aspects refer to facets of the target entities in opinions. They are also categorized into explicit and implicit ones depending on the occur- rences of aspect terms. Recognizing implicit as- pects in implicit opinions is much more challeng- ing because both opinion words and aspect terms are absent in opinionated statements.</p><p>Implicit opinions often describe the situations at which persons concern in their reviews. (S1) and (S2) are two examples selected from positive and negative rating rows respectively in hotel reviews. They do not mention any explicit opinion words and aspect terms. The situation of "many restau- rants nearby" infers the convenience for eating, while the situation of "a lot of ants" infers the dirt- iness of a room. The implicit opinion describes not only the situation at which customers feel, but also infers the reason why they have such feelings. Im- plicit opinions are positive in (S1) and negative in (S2), and the implied aspects are location and cleanness.</p><p>(S1) 附近有很多餐廳。(There are many restau- rants nearby.) (S2) 房間裡有很多螞蟻。(There are a lot of ants in the room.)</p><p>The implicit opinions may be subjective in some cases. For example, (S1) may be placed in negative rating row in a hotel review. Its implicit interpreta- tion will become "There are many restaurants nearby, and thus the air pollution is severe and the smell of the air is very bad."</p><p>People may describe a situation first, and then reveal their attitudes and judgments. (S3) is an ex- ample. The first clause (only ten meters to the subway entrance) describes a situation, while the second clause (the location is good) is an explicit opinion. In Chinese review, an explicit opinion can also be specified before a situation description. (S4) is an example. In both cases, the polarity and the aspect of the situation are consistent with those of the explicit opinions.</p><p>(S3) 到地鐵出入口僅十米，地段好。(Only ten meters to the subway entrance, good location.) (S4) 地點不錯，可步行至周圍三個捷運站。 (Location is good, within walking distance of three MRTs around.)</p><p>This paper aims at extracting implicit opinions and identifying their implicit aspects and polarity. We will extract opinions from Chinese hotel re- views, then transfer polarity and aspect from ex- plicit expressions to the corresponding implicit opinions, and train aspect and polarity classifiers. We evaluate the performance of polarity and as- pect recognition on implicit opinions.</p><p>Almost all previous approaches identify implicit aspects in explicit opinions. They extract opinion words from opinionated sentences, regard them as implicit aspect clues, and find aspects through opinion word-aspect term mapping. The lack of opinion words in implicit opinions results in no in- dicators in mapping. To the best of our knowledge, this paper is the first one to resolve a double- implicit problem in opinion mining and sentiment analysis.</p><p>This paper is organized as follows. Section 2 gives a survey on implicit aspect recognition in opinion mining and sentiment analysis. Section 3 constructs an implicit opinions corpus labelled with aspect classes and polarity automatically. Sec- tion 4 presents classifiers for implicit polarity and implicit aspect recognition. Section 5 shows and discusses the experimental results.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Related Work</head><p>Hu and Liu (2004) present the first feature-based opinion summarization system. They point out ex- plicit and implicit product features, and extract ex- plicit features by using association miner and prun- ing strategies. The opinionated sentences along with their polarity are listed under individual prod- uct features. <ref type="bibr">Popescu and Etzioni (2005)</ref> introduce an opinion extraction system OPINE. OPINE ex- tracts explicit product features based on Point-wise Mutual Information. This work does not discuss the implicit feature generation. <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Liu et al. (2005)</ref> present an association mining approach to extract both explicit and implicit features in their opinion observer, but the implicit features discussed occur explicitly in an overt form, e.g., <ref type="bibr">[MB]</ref> indicates a product feature &lt;memory&gt;. <ref type="bibr">Su et al. (2008)</ref> define an implicit feature as the product feature which does not occur explicitly, but can be inferred from the surrounding opinion word. They propose a mutual reinforcement ap- proach to cluster product features and opinion words simultaneously, and extract implicit features based on opinion words. In the subsequent work, different methodologies are proposed to identify the association between opinion words and aspect terms (called also product features), thus implicit aspects are inferred from opinion word-aspect term mapping ( <ref type="bibr">Bagheri et al., 2013</ref>).</p><p>Zhen et al. (2011) propose a two-phase co- occurrence association rule mining approach. <ref type="bibr">Yu et al. (2011)</ref> generate a review hierarchy based on as- pects. Implicit aspect of a review can be deter- mined by the cosine similarity of the review vector and the vector for each aspect node in the review hierarchy. <ref type="bibr">Zeng and Li (2013)</ref> regard identification of implicit features as a classification problem, and consider reviews for each clustered opinion-pair as training set. <ref type="bibr">Wang et al. (2013)</ref> employ five collo- cation methods including frequency, PMI, fre- quency⁄PMI, t-test and chi-square test to measure the association between opinion words and aspect terms.</p><p>Cruz et al. <ref type="formula">(2014)</ref> manually annotate implicit aspects and implicit aspect indicators (IAI) on the customer review datasets in <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Hu and Liu (2004)</ref>, and employ Conditional Random Fields to recog- nize IAI. <ref type="bibr">Poria et al. (2014)</ref> identify implicit aspect clues (IACs) in a document. Both approaches es- tablish IAI (IAC) and aspect mapping.</p><p>Mukherjee and Liu <ref type="formula">(2012)</ref> propose two statisti- cal models to deal with aspect categorization prob- lem. They use hotel reviews from tripadvisor.com, and point out categorizing aspects is a subjective task. Total 9 major aspects based on commonsense knowledge, including Dining, Staff, Maintenance, Check In, Cleanliness, Comfort, Amenities, Loca- tion and Value for Money, are considered. <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Kim et al. (2013)</ref> further analyze general aspects and spe- cific aspects, and discuss how aspect structure is helpful. <ref type="bibr">Zhao et al. (2015)</ref> present a fine-grained corpus for sentiment analysis.</p><p>Our work is different from the previous ones in two-fold: (1) opinion is implicit, so that no opinion words can be used as clues; and (2) aspect is im- plicit, so that no aspect terms can be found. The di- rect opinion word and aspect mapping is not feasi- ble in implicit polarity and implicit aspect recogni- tion. We focus on the construction of an implicit opinions corpus for double-implicit recognition. The aspect categorization is not the major concern.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Constructing Implicit Opinions Corpus</head><p>This section first defines the implicit opinions, col- lects a Chinese hotel dataset, identifies opinion and aspect clusters from the dataset, and constructs im- plicit opinion corpus labelled with aspect class and polarity.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Definitions of Implicit Opinions</head><p>A sentence in a review can be partitioned into sev- eral segments separated by punctuation marks. The following show four possible types of segments based on the occurrences of opinion words and as- pect terms, where + and -denote occurrence and non-occurrence. Segments of types (T1) and (T2) contain explicit opinion words, while segments of types (T3) and (T4) contain no opinion words. They appear together with and without aspect terms.</p><p>(T1) (+opinion word, +aspect term) e.g., 地點不錯 (location is good) (T2) (+opinion word, -aspect term) e.g., 很便宜 (very cheap) (T3) (-opinion word, +aspect term) e.g., 地理位置 (location) (T4) (-opinion word,-aspect term) e.g., 到油麻地地鐵站只要兩分鐘 (Just two minutes to Yau Ma Tei MRT Station) Segments of either type can not only appear in- dividually, but also can be combined with other types of segments to form a sentence. Segments of types (T1) and (T2) are opinionated. Segments of type (T3) are opinionated implicitly when they ap- pear in positive/negative rating row. Segments of type (T4) can be opinionated or non-opinionated. It is interpreted as an opinionated segment clearly when it is placed in rating row individually.</p><p>(S5) is a sentence consisting of 5 segments of types T3, T2, T1, T4 and T3, respectively. The 4 th segment, i.e., feeling a little like shanty towns, is a double-implicit opinion. Its polarity and aspect (negative and environment) can be inferred from the 3 rd segment, i.e., the surrounding environment is really bad. In this paper, we deal with opinionated segments of type (T4). On the one hand, we extract pairs of segments of types T1-T4 or T4-T1 from a Chinese hotel review dataset. The segments of type T4 will be annotated with opinion words and aspect terms extracted from their paired segments of type T1. The segments of type T4 along with their annota- tions form a training corpus. On the other hand, the test segments of types (T4) will be labelled with polarity and aspect by polarity and aspect classifi- ers.</p><p>At first glance, we do not need to perform the classification task on T4 segments since we can di- rectly use polarity and aspect of T1 segments. The scenario is just for test purpose because we do not have large-scale manually-labelled data. In the lat- ter experiments, we will also consider the cases of T4 segments existing individually in rating rows. That will reflect the real situations.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Extraction of Implicit Opinions</head><p>Opinion words and aspect terms are the indicators to define the four types (T1)-(T4). As a case study, we collect a Chinese hotel review dataset from booking.com. It consists of 144,158 positive re- views and 113,844 negative reviews about 20,973 hotels from 49 international cities. Here only Chi- nese reviews are kept. We use Stanford NLP tools to segment, POS tag, and parse all the reviews.</p><p>At first, we construct an opinion dictionary from this dataset. Words of POS tags VA, VV, AD, and JJ are candidates of opinion words. We adopt Chi- square test and point-wise mutual information to filter out less confident words from the candidate set, respectively. We examine the union of the re- maining words manually and construct an opinion dictionary consisting of 374 positive and 408 nega- tive opinion words.</p><p>Then, we construct an aspect dictionary based on opinion words. A word meeting the following four conditions is regarded as an aspect term can- didate: (1) its POS is NN, (2) it occurs at least 100 times, (3) it is accompanied with an opinion word within the same segment, and (4) their dependency is nsubj. We examine 183 proposed candidates manually and construct an aspect dictionary con- sisting of 153 aspect terms.</p><p>In an extreme case, a review does not contain any opinion words and aspect terms. It may be a single segment or multiple segments of type T4. Reviews are listed under positive and negative rat- ing rows, so we know their polarity, but not aspect. <ref type="table">Table 1</ref> shows the statistics of such kinds of re- views in the hotel dataset. Interestingly, 2.07% of positive reviews are pure T4, and 7.29% of nega- tive reviews are pure T4. That demonstrates dou- ble-implicit is a practical issue and customers tend to express negative opinions implicitly.  T4 reviews set consisting of single segments only is called PT4S hereafter. <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Table 2</ref> shows the statistics of segments of types T1, T2, T3, and T4. Only 21.01% of segments con- tain both opinion words and aspect terms, and 33.14% of segments do not contain any opinion words and aspect terms. We further examine the type combinations of two successive segments. There are 103 possible punctuation marks between any two segments, including common ones like "，", "。", "?", and "!", and some special ones like "~~~". To avoid misinterpretation of the spe- cial marks, we considers only those segment pairs linked by commas. Moreover, to obtain an auto- matically labelled dataset, the ambiguous sequence of segments, X-T4-Y, where X and Y of types T1, T2, or T3, are removed. Total 31,136 T4-T1/T1-T4 segment pairs remain. They are used to derive an implicit opinions corpus for learning and testing polarity classifier and aspect classifiers. This data set is called T41 hereafter.</p><p>In most of the cases we observed, segment of type T2 or T3 does not pass its aspect or opinion to nearby segments of type T4. (S6) is an example of a triple of segments of type T1-T4-T3, which in- troduces ambiguity between aspect and opinion as- signment. The aspect of segment of type T1, i.e., the equipment, competes with that of segment of type T3, the toilet. In this case, the safety deposit box, which is the undetected aspect of the segment of type T4, and the toilet are two sub-aspects of the equipment. The latter two clauses are supplemen- tary description of the first clause.</p><p>(S6) 設施比較舊，保險箱不好使，馬桶上水 時有故障 (The equipment is old, the safety deposit box is hard to use, and the toilet sometimes stucks while refilling.)</p><p>This work bases on the postulation -say, an im- plicit opinion and its neighbor explicit opinion tending to have the same aspect and polarity, to construct a training corpus automatically. We ran- domly sampled 1% of pairs of segments of type T1-T4 or T4-T1 in a training corpus (see Section 4) to verify whether our assumption holds. In this set- up, we discard clauses that contain parsing errors and those are too short to represent both aspects and opinions. The result is promising. On average, 70.46% of the pairs follow the observation. In par- ticular, the pairs keep the property more often (i.e., 74.51%) when the polarity of T1 is negative.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Double-Implicit Opinion Analysis</head><p>We assign polarity and aspect of a T4-type seg- ment in T41 dataset based on the information from its paired T1-type segment. Negation in the T1- type segment will reverse the polarity. To avoid data sparseness, 153 aspect terms are partitioned into 10 aspect classes based on common sense knowledge, including food, hotel, price, room, in- ternet, staff, services, facilities, neighborhood, and general. The criterion in the selection of the cate- gory of aspects is not the major concern in this pa- per. For example, facilities and services may be merged into the same aspect category. The 31,136 labelled T4-type segments in T41 dataset are di- vided into training and test sets consisting of 23,352 and 7,784 segments, respectively. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 1</ref> shows the segment length distribution of T41-train, T41-test, T41, and PT4S datasets. The length is measured by number of Chinese words in a segment. X-axis and Y-axis denote length of segments and ratio, respectively. Seg- ments in PT4S dataset are shorter than those in T41 dataset. Segments of 2 and 3 words occupy 48.61%. <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">Table 3</ref> shows the polarity distribution in these datasets. Because T41 dataset is divided into T41-train and T41-test datasets uniformly, their polarity distribution is the same, i.e., positive: positive 79.64% 79.63% 79.68% 27.93% negative 20.36% 20.37% 20.32% 72.07%  <ref type="table">Table 4</ref>: Accuracy of implicit polarity and aspect recognition.</p><p>negative=4:1. Comparatively, positive:negative= 1:2.58 in PT4S dataset. The two test sets bias to- ward different polarities. We employ T41-train dataset to train binary po- larity classifier and 10-way aspect classifiers, and test on T41-test dataset. We also explore T41 da- taset to train polarity classifier, and test on PT4S dataset. T41-testing evaluates both implicit polarity and implicit aspect recognition. Note the ground truth is generated automatically. PT4S-testing evaluates implicit polarity only based on the hu- man-annotated ground truth.</p><p>We consider bag of words (BOW) and word vectors generated by word2vec (W2V) as features, where word vectors are pre-trained by using the part-of-tagged Chinese sentences extracted from the ClueWeb09 dataset <ref type="bibr">(CMU, 2009;</ref><ref type="bibr">Yu et al., 2012</ref>). Moreover, we adopt SVM with linear ker- nel and SVM with RBF kernel learning algorithms in Scikit-Learn library <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Pedregosa et al., 2011</ref>), and run cross-validation multiple times on the training set to facilitate a grid search on hyperparameters with F-measure as the metric to optimize.</p><p>Besides, we also explore Convolutional Neural Networks (CNN) <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Kim, 2014)</ref>. <ref type="table">Table 4</ref> summariz- es the accuracy of implicit polarity and implicit as- pect recognition, where (p) and (a) after dataset denote polarity and aspect performance of that da- taset, respectively. CNN achieves the best implicit polarity and aspect recognition in T41-test dataset. However, its implicit polarity accuracy is de- creased to 67.96%. It may be due to overfitting in small amount of training data. Different dropout rates ( <ref type="bibr">Srivastava et al., 2014</ref>) can be explored. SVM with linear kernel (BOW) gets the best micro average accuracy (77.91%) in implicit polarity recognition. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 2</ref> shows the accuracies of the implicit po- larity recognition on segments of different lengths. It is challenging to predict the implicit polarity and aspect for segments of very short length. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 1</ref> depicts one-word segments occupy 5%-10%. One word segment like "旺角" (Mong Kok) is ambigu- ous. If we neglect such segments, the micro aver- age accuracy in implicit polarity recognition using SVM with linear kernel (BOW) is increased to 79.94%, and the accuracy in implicit aspect recog- nition (10-way classification) becomes 46.01%.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Conclusion and Future Work</head><p>In this paper, we address the double-implicit issue in opinion mining and sentiment analysis, and pro- pose a protocol to derive a labelled corpus for im- plicit polarity and implicit aspect analysis. SVM with linear kernel (BOW) is robust in implicit po- larity recognition. Ten-way classification for im- plicit aspect recognition still has space to improve. This work bases on the aspect-and-polarity- transfer postulation to construct a training corpus automatically. We randomly sample T4 segments from T4-T1 or T1-T4 pairs and check them manu- ally. We find that 70.46% of the pairs follow the observation. The experimental setup is reasonable for evaluation with PT4S dataset because it is la- belled by users themselves. To derive a more relia- ble training set, distinguishing if T4 is non- opinionated needs to be investigated further.</p><p>Moreover, we neglect the cases T4-X (X-T4), where X is either T2 or T3, in the selection of training set. It is also challenging when either opin- ion word or aspect term is absent from the cue segment. In this paper, we provide some case stud- ies of these scenarios, but how to utilize the partial information in implicit polarity and implicit aspect recognition is a future work.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>(S5) [T3 旅館在小巷子裡]，[T2 安全沒有問題]， [T1 但附近環境確實不好]，[T4 有點棚戶區的感 覺]，[T3 周圍沒有飯店]。([T3 hotel in the alley]， [T2 security is no problem]，[T1 but the surround- ing environment is really bad]，[T4 feeling a little like shanty towns]，[T3 no hotels around])</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: Length distribution in experimental datasets.</figDesc><graphic url="image-1.png" coords="4,335.18,617.46,125.04,85.92" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2: Accuracies of segments of different lengths.</figDesc><graphic url="image-6.png" coords="5,314.18,105.90,210.96,137.40" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" validated="false"><head>Table 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Statistics of segment types. 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" validated="false"><head>Table 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Polarity distribution in experimental datasets. 

(%) 
BOW 
linear 

W2V 
linear 

BOW 
RBF 

W2V 
RBF 

W2V 
CNN 
T41-test (p) 
78.55 
73.67 
81.54 
79.76 
85.04 
PT4S (p) 
77.30 
77.64 
72.01 
72.22 
67.96 
MicroAvg 
77.91 
75.69 
76.67 
75.91 
76.32 
T41-test (a) 
43.25 
41.50 
46.35 
46.13 
55.90 

</table></figure>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>This research was partially supported by Ministry of Science and Technology, Taiwan, under grant MOST-102-2221-E-002-103-MY3. We thank the anonymous reviewers for their constructive com-ments to revise this paper. <ref type="bibr">Scikitlearn</ref> </p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Aspect Extraction through Semi-Supervised Modeling</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Arjun</forename><surname>Mukherjee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bing</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 50th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the 50th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="339" to="348" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Care More about Customers: Unsupervised Domain-independent Aspect Detection for Sentiment Analysis of Customer Reviews, KnowledgeBased Systems</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ayoub</forename><surname>Bagheria</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mohamad</forename><surname>Saraeeb</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Franciska</forename><surname>De</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jong</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">52</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="201" to="213" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Implicit Aspect Indicator Extraction for Aspect-based Opinion Mining</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ivan</forename><surname>Cruz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alexander</forename><surname>Gelbukh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Grigori</forename><surname>Sidorov</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">International Journal of Computational Linguistics and Applications</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="135" to="152" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Mining and Summarizing Customer Reviews</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Minqing</forename><surname>Hu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bing</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the ACM SIGKDD International Conference on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining</title>
		<meeting>the ACM SIGKDD International Conference on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="168" to="177" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Convolutional Neural Networks for Sentence Classification</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yoon</forename><surname>Kim</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2014 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP)</title>
		<meeting>the 2014 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1746" to="1751" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A Hierarchical Aspect-Sentiment Model for Online Reviews</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Suin</forename><surname>Kim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jianwen</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Zheng</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alice</forename><surname>Oh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Shixia</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Twenty-Seventh AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence</title>
		<meeting>the Twenty-Seventh AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="526" to="533" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Sentiment Analysis and Opinion Mining</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bing</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<publisher>Morgan &amp; Claypool Publishers</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Opinion Observer: Analyzing and Comparing Opinions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bing</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Minqing</forename><surname>Hu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Junsheng</forename><surname>Cheng</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 14th International Conference on World Wide Web</title>
		<meeting>the 14th International Conference on World Wide Web</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1024" to="1025" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Fabian</forename><surname>Pedregosa</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gael</forename><surname>Varoquaux</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alexandre</forename><surname>Gramfort</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Vincent</forename><surname>Michel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bertrand</forename><surname>Thirion</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Olivier</forename><surname>Grisel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mathieu</forename><surname>Blondel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Peter</forename><surname>Prettenhofer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Matthieu Brucher, Matthieu Perrot, and Edouard Duchesnay</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Ron Weiss, Vincent Dubourg, Jake Vanderplas, Alexandre Passos, David Cournapeau</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
