<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T12:59+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">An Advanced Press Review System Combining Deep News Analysis and Machine Learning Algorithms</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
				<availability status="unknown"><p>Copyright Association for Computational Linguistics</p>
				</availability>
				<date>August 7-12, 2016. 2016</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Danuta</forename><surname>Ploch</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">DAI-Labor</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Technische Universität Berlin Ernst-Reuter-Platz 7</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>10587</postCode>
									<settlement>Berlin</settlement>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Andreas</forename><surname>Lommatzsch</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">DAI-Labor</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Technische Universität Berlin Ernst-Reuter-Platz 7</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>10587</postCode>
									<settlement>Berlin</settlement>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Florian</forename><surname>Schultze</surname></persName>
							<email>florian.schultze@campus.tu-berlin.de</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">DAI-Labor</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Technische Universität Berlin Ernst-Reuter-Platz 7</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>10587</postCode>
									<settlement>Berlin</settlement>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">An Advanced Press Review System Combining Deep News Analysis and Machine Learning Algorithms</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 54th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics-System Demonstrations</title>
						<meeting>the 54th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics-System Demonstrations <address><addrLine>Berlin, Germany</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="109" to="114"/>
							<date type="published">August 7-12, 2016. 2016</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>In our media-driven world the perception of companies and institutions in the media is of major importance. The creation of press reviews analyzing the media response to company-related events is a complex and time-consuming task. In this demo we present a system that combines advanced text mining and machine learning approaches in an extensible press review system. The system collects documents from heterogeneous sources and enriches the documents applying different mining, filtering, classification, and ag-gregation algorithms. We present a system tailored to the needs of the press department of a major German University. We explain how the different components have been trained and evaluated. The system enables us demonstrating the live analyzes of news and social media streams as well as the strengths of advanced text mining algorithms for creating a comprehensive media analysis.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>The analysis of news related to companies and in- stitution is a complex task often performed by hu- man experts. Due to the growing amount of news and articles published in social media, large col- lections of data must be analyzed. In order to sup- port the efficient creation of press reviews pow- erful tools are needed for the automatic aggrega- tion and deep analysis of news. This motivates us to develop an extensible framework allowing us to combine advanced machine learning algorithms for filtering, extracting, and visualizing relevant information.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.1">The analyzed Scenario</head><p>In this work we present a system developed for the press department of the Berlin Institute of Tech- nology (TUB). The system should be able to col- lect news as well as social media articles related to the TUB or to any other of the Berlin's univer- sities. The system is subject to a collection of re- quirements: The system should detect duplicates or texts with minor variations. Persons and facul- ties mentioned in news articles are of special inter- est for a fine-grained analysis. The system should detect known entities and create detailed statistics. Events drive the news. The system should detect and follow news related to the Berlin's universi- ties. Readers of news often drain in information. The system should aggregate and visualize rele- vant documents in a concise way by computing key figures (e.g. describing the sentiment score for news) and calculating statistics giving a quick overview on the characteristics of the news stream. The results of the news analysis should be acces- sible in a web application.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.2">Challenges</head><p>The automatic creation of press reviews leads to several challenges. The system has to integrate all important sources and to filter irrelevant doc- uments. A specific challenge is that abbrevia- tions are often used for institutions having a long name. In our scenario the "Technische Univer- sität Berlin" is frequently called "TUB" or "TU". The press review system must infer from the con- text whether an article is relevant or not. The au- tomatic analysis and enrichment requires a vari- ety of algorithms, including duplicates detection, identification and disambiguation of named enti- ties, and sentiment analysis. The sentiment analy- sis for news articles is a hard challenge since most journalists seek to write objectively. Nevertheless, news induces emotions relevant in the automatic analysis of news documents. Since the system has been developed for a major German university, the language analysis focuses on German texts.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.3">Structure of the Work</head><p>The remaining work is structured as follows. In Section 2 we explain the basics of text mining al- gorithms and discuss existing press review sys- tems. The architecture and the implemented al- gorithms are presented in Section 3. In Section 4 the visualization of the elicited data is described in further detail. Section 5 explains the most impor- tant use cases and presents the evaluation results with respect to the functionality of the press re- view portal. A conclusion and an outlook to future work is given in Section 6.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Related Work</head><p>We review advanced text mining algorithms and existing press review systems.</p><p>There are a lot of commercial press review sys- tems such as http://www.bluereport.net/de/, http://www.pressemonitor.de/ or https:// www.ausschnitt.de/.</p><p>The systems focus on printed newspapers but also provide press reviews for online published articles. Traditionally, the systems provide excerpts related to predefined search terms. In general, the companies offer a wide variety of analysis services but the applied algorithms are neither open nor explained. With the pricing models in mind a lot of work is still performed by human experts. Based on the com- panies' information policy and the marketing lan- guage on the websites it is unclear to what ex- tent machine learning or text mining algorithms are used.</p><p>Several research-oriented systems complement commercial press review systems. An exemplary application for large scale news analysis is LY- DIA. LYDIA focuses on named entity detection.</p><p>Its key feature is answering questions such as "who is being talked about, by whom, when, and where?" ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Lloyd et al., 2005</ref>). The SEMANTIC PRESS system ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Picchi et al., 2008)</ref> uses an al- ternative approach. It presents the most discussed themes in the Italian-spoken web. An example for German media resonance analysis is the system explained by <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Scholz, 2011)</ref>. It fo- cuses on entity extraction and sentiment analysis. Similar researches were done by <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Hanjalic et al., 1998)</ref> and <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Zhang et al., 2009</ref>).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Approach</head><p>We develop an open framework enabling us in- tegrating different information sources and ma- chine learning algorithms. The system allows us considering news portals, search engines, RSS feeds, and messages published on TWITTER. We deploy a flexible processing pipeline enriching freshly crawled documents as well as a batch en- gine used for clustering and generating newslet- ters. Our framework is open for the integration of new sources and algorithms allowing us incremen- tally extending and improving our system.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">System Architecture</head><p>The structure of the developed system is shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Fig. 1</ref>. The system consists of four major build- ing blocks. The crawler component collects po- tentially relevant documents and tweets. The doc- uments are persisted in a database. The process- ing components enrich the crawled documents and run several different machine learning algorithms. Based on the meta-data and the computed annota- tions the relevance of documents is computed and near duplicates are identified. The batch process- ing pipeline is a second pipeline used for process- ing documents from the database in predefined in- tervals. Both processing pipelines can be easily extended. The use of a database decouples the crawling from the processing allowing an efficient and concurrent computation of annotations.</p><p>The enriched documents are presented to the user in a web application and summarized in a pe- riodically created newsletter.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Text Mining Components</head><p>In this Section we present the algorithms imple- mented for the different components in detail and discuss specific adaptations.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Validation</head><p>Several crawlers collect potentially relevant doc- uments subsequently analyzed by the validation component. The crawlers use APIs of major search engines and the TWITTER streaming API. We define for each source a component optimiz- ing the queries in order to ensure that all relevant documents are crawled (taking into account the limits of the sources). Due to the fact that sev- eral sources only support simple term queries (in- stead of phrase queries), an additional filtering is required. For this purpose we manually labeled   <ref type="bibr">1981)</ref>. The algorithm randomly selects a prede- fined number of text shingles and computes the hash codes. Duplicates are identified by count- ing the fraction of identical shingles in two doc- uments. We adjust the optimal parameter settings (shingle size, number of considered shingles) on a validation dataset.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Named Entity Detection</head><p>The named entity detection component recognizes and disambiguates persons mentioned in news ar- ticles. For the recognition part it uses several components from "Stanford CoreNLP" which are explained in ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Manning et al., 2014</ref>). In par- ticular, the component applies the parser, POS- tagger, and Named Entity Recognizer (NER) to detect mentions of professors, researchers and other university-related experts mentioned in the news articles. Based on the output of the "Stanford CoreNLP" tools the module enriches each identi- fied person with their titles and associated organi- zation, provided the news article contains the nec- essary information within a window of n words. In addition, the person's name is decomposed into a given name and a surname. In order to iden- tify person mentions unambiguously the module applies local and global disambiguation strategy. The local disambiguation resolves co-referent per- son mentions within one news article. It assem- bles a representation of each person as complete as possible. The global disambiguation performs a cross-document co-reference resolution. It con- siders all person attributes and words calculated from the text surrounding a person mention. Each person from a news article is compared to entries already stored in the database. In the course of similarity calculation all types of information (per- son attributes and bag-of-word) are weighted dif- ferently. If the similarity between a newly detected person and a person from the database exceeds a predefined threshold, the persons are merged in the database. Otherwise, a new person entry is cre- ated.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Assignment of Faculties</head><p>Usually, universities are structured in several fac- ulties. The presence of single faculties in the me- dia may be an important quality indicator for the universities. Our approach to assigning news ar- ticles to a faculty is person-based. Therefore, we first gather the names of all employees from the faculty websites. In this way we create a register of person names aligned with faculty affiliation.</p><p>In order to measure the media response of a spe- cific faculty, the implemented component analyzes news articles according to mentions of persons re- lated to the faculty. The implementation of our ap- proach bases on an inverted index containing each document's full text. We search the documents for person names from our register. If our algo- rithm identifies a faculty-related person, it assigns the news article to the corresponding faculty.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Event Detection</head><p>The event detection component clusters news ar- ticles dealing with one concrete news event such as the Queen's Lecture or the Long Night of the Sciences in Berlin. Our approach uses a combi- nation of the Canopy and the k-means algorithm for clustering which is described by <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(McCallum et al., 2000</ref>). In order to improve the accuracy of the clustering we enable a part-of-speech tag- ger. We exclude all words that do not contribute to the content like articles, conjunctions, and prepo- sitions; we proceed with the resulting subset of the text. Since the k-means algorithm needs to be initialized with a fixed number of clusters k our component performs two stages. First, the compo- nent estimates the number of clusters by applying Canopy. We adjust Canopy's hyper-parameters on a manually annotated validation dataset. Then, the calculated canopies serve as input centroids for the second step, the k-means clustering. Finally, each cluster corresponds to a real-life event.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Sentiment Analysis</head><p>Despite of the objective nature of news articles, they are still a valuable source of sentiment in- formation. They may express opinions of cited entities or may contain content influencing the reader's perception regarding a university. Our system incorporates two sentiment analysis com- ponents.</p><p>The first component implements a lexicon- based approach. It uses the SentiWS sentiment dictionary ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Remus et al., 2010</ref>) containing posi- tively and negatively connoted words with posi- tive and negative scores respectively. In order to calculate the sentiment score of an entire news ar- ticle it counts the values of positive and negative words occurring in the news article. The com- ponent takes into account negation by exploiting a list of inverting words. If an inverting word precedes a positive or negative connoted word, it changes its polarity.</p><p>The second approach uses machine learning techniques. We build a training dataset with about 2,400 randomly selected sentences from crawled documents. We annotate the sentences to have a positive, negative, or neutral sentiment. For the annotation we use the rules from <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Clematide et al., 2012</ref>). Based on the created dataset we train a Multi-nominal Naive Bayes classifier able to classify each sentence of a news article into one of the three sentiment classes. We represent each sentence in the vector space model apply- ing common text preprocessing steps. Beside uni- grams we also include bigrams into the vectors to cover sentiment-related expressions such as "very good". The overall sentiment of a news article is computed based on all single sentence classi- fications. The classifier achieves promising results providing deep insights into the sentiment distri- bution within a news article. A more detailed ex- planation can be found in <ref type="bibr">(Bütow et al., 2016</ref>).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Visualization</head><p>We implemented a web-based user interface visu- alizing the collected and annotated documents and tweets. The web portal provides two major views.</p><p>(1) The Newsletter or live view shows the most re- cently collected news. <ref type="formula">(2)</ref> The Newsarchive view aggregates documents collected in the past and al- lows the creation of statistics as well as the visual- ization of events identified by clustering news re- lated to one topic. The live view shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 2</ref> helps to ex-plore the news on a daily basis. It gives users a fast overview of the most recently published news articles, shows which sources publish news re- lated to the Berlins universities and visualizes the most important key figures. The view presents the documents as a list, each document provided with the extracted meta-data, such as the corre- sponding universities. If a document deals with the Berlin Institute of Technology, the faculty con- nected with the news item is also listed. In addi- tion, the computed sentiment score and a short ex- planation for the sentiment score are displayed. A statistic showing the aggregated sentiment scores for one day for the major Berlins universities is presented in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Figure 4</ref>. Each cluster has an icon assigned to the related univer- sity and a title derived a document of the cluster. A selected cluster appears above the time-line with its corresponding news articles, the date and the ten most frequent terms in that cluster.</p><p>The archive view allows users analyzing the documents collected in the past. Users can search for documents or analyze the stream of news in de- tail. A powerful tool helping users to identify the most important events is the view that groups news documents by events on a timeline <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">(Figure 3)</ref>. The view lists all articles related to the selected events and shows the related institutions. The archive view also provides statistics. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">Figure 6</ref> visualizes the number of documents related to the faculties of the TUB in a predefined time frame. These dia- gram supports a quick comparison of different fac- ulties.</p><p>In addition to the statistics aggregating informa- tion collected over a timeframe, the systems pro- vides views giving insights into single news arti- cles. As discussed, we implemented a sentiment classifier working based on sentences. The senti- ments scores computed for each sentence are visu- alized in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Figure 5</ref>.    </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">The Demonstration</head><p>The demo is accessible at http://presse. dai-labor.de/pressreview/ with the following credentials: username demo and password pressespiegel.</p><p>The system follows the live news stream and al- lows users discovering the most recent news as well analyzing documents collected in the past. The web applications provides views for "regular" users but also detailed information and statistics for experts giving more fine-grained insights in the applied methods.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Conclusion and Future Work</head><p>We developed a powerful system that fulfills the requirements of a press review in the context of Berlin's universities. The system combines several different text mining algorithms and incorporates various visualizations helping users understanding the news and social media contributions. The sys- tem is open (upon request). It allows accessing the documents and their annotations by querying the database. The system can be extended by adding new modules to the processing pipelines. Hence, the system can be easily adapted for the specific requirements of other companies and for comput- ing additional metrics. As future work we plan to conduct comprehensive user studies in order to op- timize the algorithms to the needs of our users. We continuously work on adding blogs and RSS feeds providing information potentially relevant for our use case. We also plan an improved support for documents in other languages. Considering the identification of relevant persons, we aim to create an extended entity dataset and train a deep neural network. Furthermore, we plan the integration of additional machine learning algorithms for sum- marizing multiple documents related to events as well as algorithms for tracking the evolution of topics and sentiments over longer time frames.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: The figure visualizes the system architecture. Potentially relevant news documents and twitter messages collected by the crawlers are stored in the news database. The Processing Pipeline applies different text mining algorithms to each new document. The Batch Processing is executed on all documents periodically. The elicited data and documents are represented by a second application, the News-Portal which is built with GROOVY and GRAILS.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2: The Figure shows the front page of the system. It visualizes the Twitter messages on the left sidebar, the news articles in the middle and the corresponding sentiments on the right-hand side. The information for each displayed document are the title, a snippet, the date, the keywords used by the crawler and the source. A filter box is placed above the tweets allowing users filtering tweets by date and universities.</figDesc><graphic url="image-1.png" coords="4,307.28,494.43,218.25,122.70" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Figure 3: The Figure shows the time-line as one part of the news archive. At the bottom the timeline arranges different clusters of messages. Each cluster has an icon assigned to the related university and a title derived a document of the cluster. A selected cluster appears above the time-line with its corresponding news articles, the date and the ten most frequent terms in that cluster.</figDesc><graphic url="image-2.png" coords="5,72.00,274.96,218.25,122.70" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>Figure 4 :</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Figure 4: The Figure visualizes a diagram summarizing the results of the news aggregation and sentiment analysis for the current day. The diagram shows the distribution of the positive, negative, and neutral documents assigned to the corresponding university. In addition, the number of collected documents and the average sentiment scores are shown in this panel.</figDesc><graphic url="image-3.png" coords="5,307.28,110.10,218.25,122.70" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head>Figure 5 :</head><label>5</label><figDesc>Figure 5: The Figure visualizes the sentiments computed for each sentence in a document. Sentences classified as negative are shaded in red; sentences classified as positive are shaded in green. The checkbox above the full text allows users to hide positive, negative, and neutral sentences.</figDesc><graphic url="image-4.png" coords="5,307.28,367.45,218.27,120.13" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><head>Figure 6 :</head><label>6</label><figDesc>Figure 6: The Figure visualizes the number of news articles related to the "Technische Universiät Berlin" depending on the different faculties.</figDesc><graphic url="image-5.png" coords="5,307.28,595.13,218.25,122.70" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_6"><head>113</head><label>113</label><figDesc></figDesc></figure>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>The research leading to these results was per-formed in the CrowdRec project, which has re-ceived funding from the European Union Sev-enth Framework Programme FP7/2007-2013 un-der grant agreement No. 610594.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Sentiment Analysis with Machine Learning Algorithms on German News Articles</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Florian</forename><surname>Bütow</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Florian</forename><surname>Schultze</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Leopold</forename><surname>Strauch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://www.dai-labor.de/publikationen/1052" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>Berlin Institute of Technology</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
<note type="report_type">Technical report</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">MLSA-A Multi-layered Reference Corpus for German Sentiment Analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Simon</forename><surname>Clematide</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Stefan</forename><surname>Gindl</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Manfred</forename><surname>Klenner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Stefanos</forename><surname>Petrakis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Robert</forename><surname>Remus</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Josef</forename><surname>Ruppenhofer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ulli</forename><surname>Waltinger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Wiegand</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Procs. of the 8th Intl. Conf. on Lang. Res. and Evaluation</title>
		<meeting>s. of the 8th Intl. Conf. on Lang. Res. and Evaluation</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3551" to="3556" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Semiautomatic news analysis, indexing, and classification system based on topic preselection</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alan</forename><surname>Hanjalic</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Reginald</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Lagendijk</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jan</forename><surname>Biemond</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. SPIE</title>
		<meeting>SPIE</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">3656</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="86" to="97" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Lydia: A system for large-scale news analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Levon</forename><surname>Lloyd</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dimitrios</forename><surname>Kechagias</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Steven</forename><surname>Skiena</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">String Processing and Information Retrieval</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="161" to="166" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christopher</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Manning</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mihai</forename><surname>Surdeanu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">John</forename><surname>Bauer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jenny</forename><forename type="middle">Rose</forename><surname>Finkel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Steven</forename><surname>Bethard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Mcclosky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">The Stanford CoreNLP Natural Language Processing Toolkit. In ACL (System Demonstrations)</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="55" to="60" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Efficient clustering of high-dimensional data sets with application to reference matching</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Andrew</forename><surname>Mccallum</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kamal</forename><surname>Nigam</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lyle</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Ungar</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Procs. of the 6th ACM SIGKDD Intl. Conf. on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining, KDD &apos;00</title>
		<meeting>s. of the 6th ACM SIGKDD Intl. Conf. on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining, KDD &apos;00<address><addrLine>NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="169" to="178" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Mining the news with semantic press</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Eugenio</forename><surname>Picchi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Cucurullo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Francesca</forename><surname>Sassolini</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Bertagna</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Procs. of the 8th Intl. Conf. on Language Resources and Evaluation</title>
		<meeting>s. of the 8th Intl. Conf. on Language Resources and Evaluation</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="141" to="144" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Fingerprinting by random polynomials</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Michael O Rabin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1981" />
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>Center for Research in Computing Techn., Aiken Computation Laboratory, Univ</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">SentiWS-A Publicly Available Germanlanguage Resource for Sentiment Analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Robert</forename><surname>Remus</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Uwe</forename><surname>Quasthoff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gerhard</forename><surname>Heyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of the Intl. Conf. on Language Resources and Evaluation, LREC 2010</title>
		<meeting>of the Intl. Conf. on Language Resources and Evaluation, LREC 2010<address><addrLine>Valletta, Malta</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010-05" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="17" to="23" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>European Language Resources Association</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Ein Ansatz zu Opinion Mining und Themenverfolgung für eine Medienresonanzanalyse</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Thomas</forename><surname>Scholz</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Procs. of the 23rd GI-WS Grundlagen von Datenbanken</title>
		<meeting>s. of the 23rd GI-WS Grundlagen von Datenbanken</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1613" to="0073" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Automatic online news monitoring and classification for syndromic surveillance</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yulei</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yan</forename><surname>Dang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hsinchun</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mark</forename><surname>Thurmond</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Cathy</forename><surname>Larson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Smart Business Networks: Concepts and Empirical Evidence</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">47</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="508" to="517" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
