<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T10:17+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Coordination Annotation Extension in the Penn Tree Bank</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
				<availability status="unknown"><p>Copyright Association for Computational Linguistics</p>
				</availability>
				<date>August 7-12, 2016. 2016</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jessica</forename><surname>Ficler</surname></persName>
							<email>jessica.ficler@gmail.com</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Computer Science Department</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Computer Science Department Bar</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Ilan University</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="IL">Israel</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yoav</forename><surname>Goldberg</surname></persName>
							<email>yoav.goldberg@gmail.com</email>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">Ilan University</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="IL">Israel</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Coordination Annotation Extension in the Penn Tree Bank</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 54th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
						<meeting>the 54th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics <address><addrLine>Berlin, Germany</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="834" to="842"/>
							<date type="published">August 7-12, 2016. 2016</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Coordination is an important and common syntactic construction which is not handled well by state of the art parsers. Coordinations in the Penn Treebank are missing internal structure in many cases, do not include explicit marking of the conjuncts and contain various errors and inconsistencies. In this work, we initiated manual annotation process for solving these issues. We identify the different elements in a coordination phrase and label each element with its function. We add phrase boundaries when these are missing, unify inconsistencies , and fix errors. The outcome is an extension of the PTB that includes consistent and detailed structures for coordinations. We make the coordination annotation publicly available, in hope that they will facilitate further research into coordination disambiguation. 1</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>The Penn Treebank (PTB) <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(Marcus et al., 1993)</ref> is perhaps the most commonly used resource for training and evaluating syntax-based natural lan- guage processing systems. Despite its widespread adoption and undisputed usefulness, some of the annotations in PTB are not optimal, and could be improved. The work of <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Vadas and Curran (2007)</ref> identified and addressed one such annotation defi- ciency -the lack of internal structure in base NPs. In this work we focus on the annotation of coordi- nating conjunctions.</p><p>Coordinating conjunctions (e.g. "John and Mary", "to be or not to be") are a very common syntactic construction, appearing in 38.8% of the sentences in the PTB. As noted by <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Hogan (2007)</ref>, coordination annotation in the PTB are not con- sistent, include errors, and lack internal structure in many cases ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Hara et al., 2009;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Hogan, 2007;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Shimbo and Hara, 2007)</ref>. Another issue is that PTB does not mark whether a punctuation is part of the coordination or not. This was resolved by <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Maier et al. (2012)</ref> which annotated punctuation in the PTB .</p><p>These errors, inconsistencies, and in particular the lack of internal structural annotation turned re- searchers that were interested specifically in co- ordination disambiguation away from the PTB and towards much smaller, domain specific efforts such as the Genia Treebank ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Kim et al., 2003</ref>) of biomedical texts ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Hara et al., 2009;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Shimbo and Hara, 2007)</ref>.</p><p>In addition, we also find that the PTB annota- tion make it hard, and often impossible, to cor- rectly identify the elements that are being coordi- nated, and tell them apart from other elements that may appear in a coordination construction. While most of the coordination phrases are simple and include only conjuncts and a coordinator, many cases include additional elements with other syn- tactic functions , such as markers (e.g. "Both Al- ice and Bob"), connectives (e.g. "Fast and thus useful") and shared elements (e.g. "Bob's prin- ciples and opinions") ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Huddleston et al., 2002</ref>). The PTB annotations do not differentiate between these elements. For example, consider the follow- ing coordination phrases which begin with a PP: Even though the first element is a conjunct only in (a), both phrases are represented with the marked elements as siblings.</p><p>Our goal in this work is to fix these deficiencies. We aim for an annotation in which:</p><p>• All coordination phrases are explicitly marked and are differentiated from non- coordination structures.</p><p>• Each element in the coordination structure is explicitly marked with its role within the co- ordination structure.</p><p>• Similar structures are assigned a consistent annotation.</p><p>We also aim to fix existing errors involving coordi- nation, so that the resulting corpus includes as few errors as possible. On top of these objectives, we also like to stay as close as possible to the original PTB structures. We identify the different elements that can par- ticipate in a coordination phrase, and enrich the PTB by labeling each element with its function. We add phrase boundaries when these are missing, unify inconsistencies, and fix errors. This is done based on a combination of automatic processing and manual annotation. The result is an extension of the PTB trees that include consistent and more detailed coordination structures. We release our annotation as a diff over the PTB.</p><p>The extended coordination annotation fills an important gap in wide-scale syntactic annotation of English syntax, and is a necessary first step to- wards research on improving coordination disam- biguation.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Background</head><p>Coordination is a very common syntactic struc- ture in which two or more elements are linked. An example for a coordination structure is "Al- ice and Bob traveled to Mars". The elements (Al- ice and Bob) are called the conjuncts and and is called the coordinator. Other coordinator words include or, nor and but. Any grammatical function can be coordinated. For examples: "[relatively active] ADJP but [unfocused] ADJP " ; "[in] <ref type="bibr">IN and [out]</ref> IN the market". While it is common for the conjuncts to be of the same syntactic category, coordination of elements with different syntactic categories are also possible (e.g. "Alice will visit Earth [tomorrow] N P or [in the next decade] P P ").</p><p>Less common coordinations are those with non- constituent elements. These are cases such as "equal to or higher than", and coordinations from the type of Argument-Cluster (e.g. "Alice has vis- ited 4 planets in 2014 and 3 more since then") and Gapping (e.g. "Bob lives in Earth and Alice in Saturn") <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Dowty, 1988</ref>).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">Elements of Coordination Structure</head><p>While the canonical coordination cases involve conjuncts linked with a coordinator, other ele- ments may also take part in the coordination struc- ture: markers, connective adjectives, parentheti- cals, and shared arguments and modifiers. These elements are often part of the same syntactic phrase as the conjuncts, and should be taken into account in coordination structure annotation. We elaborate on the possible elements in a coordina- tion phrase:</p><p>Shared modifiers Modifiers that are related to each of the conjuncts in the phrase. For instance, in "Venus's density and mean temperature are very high", Venus's is a shared modifier of the con- juncts "density" and "mean temperature" 2 .</p><p>Shared arguments Phrases that function as ar- guments for each of the conjuncts. For instance, in "Bob cleaned and refueled the spaceship.", "the spaceship" and "Bob" are arguments of the con- juncts cleaned and refuel 3 .</p><p>Markers Determiners such as both and either that may appear at the beginning of the coordi- nation phrase <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Huddleston et al., 2002</ref>). As for example in "Both Alice and Bob are Aliens" and "Either Alice or Bob will drive the spaceship". In addition to the cases documented by Huddle- ston et al, our annotation of the Penn Treebank data reveals additional markers. For examples: "between 15 million and 20 million ; "first and second respectively".</p><p>Connective adjectives Adverbs such as so, yet, however, then, etc. that commonly appear right af- ter the coordinator ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Huddleston et al., 2002</ref>). For instance "We plan to meet in the middle of the way and then continue together".</p><p>Parenthetical Parenthetical remarks that may appear between the conjuncts. For examples:</p><p>"The vacation packages include hotel accommo- dations and, in some cases, tours"; "Some shows just don't impress, he says, and this is one of them".</p><p>Consider the coordinated PP phrase in "Alice traveled [both inside and outside the galaxy] P P ." Here, inside and outside are the conjuncts, both is a marker, and "the galaxy" is a shared argument. A good representation of the coordination struc- ture would allow us to identify the different ele- ments and their associated functions. As we show below, it is often not possible to reliably extract such information from the existing PTB annota- tion scheme.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Coordinations in the Penn Tree Bank</head><p>We now turn to describe how coordination is han- dled in the PTB, focusing on the parts where we find the annotation scheme to be deficient.</p><p>There is no explicit annotation for coordination phrases Some coordinators do not introduce a coordination structure. For example, the coordi- nator "and" can be a discourse marker connect- ing two sentences (e.g. "And they will even serve it themselves"), or introduce a parenthetical (e.g. "The Wall Street Journal is an excellent publica- tion that I enjoy reading (and must read) daily"). These are not explicitly differentiate in the PTB from the case where "and" connects between at least two elements (e.g. "loyalty and trust").</p><p>NPs without internal structure The PTB guidelines ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Bies et al., 1995)</ref> avoid giving any structure to NPs with nominal modifiers. Follow- ing this, 4759 NPs that include coordination were left flat, i.e. all the words in the phrase are at the same level. For example (NP (NNP chairman) (CC and) (NP chief executive officer)) which is an- notated in the PTB as: It is impossible to reliably extract conjunct boundaries from such structures. Although work has been done for giving internal structures for flat NPs ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Vadas and Curran, 2007)</ref>, only 48% of the flat NP coordinators that include more than two nouns were given an internal structure, leaving 1744 cases of flat NPs with ambiguous conjunct boundaries.</p><p>Coordination parts are not categorized Co- ordination phrases may include markers, shared modifiers, shared arguments, connective adjec- tives and parentheticals. Such elements are anno- tated on the same level as the conjuncts <ref type="bibr">4</ref> . This is true not only in the case of flat NPs but also in cases where the coordination phrase elements do have internal structures. For examples:</p><p>• The Both marker in (NP (DT both) (NP the self) (CC and) (NP the audience))</p><p>• The parenthetical maybe in (NP (NP predic- tive tests) (CC and) (PRN , maybe ,) (NP new therapies))</p><p>• The shared-modifier "the economy's" in (NP (NP the economy's) (NNS ups) (CC and) (NNS downs))</p><p>Automatic categorization of the phrases ele- ments is not trivial. Consider the coordination phrase "a phone, a job, and even into a school", which is annotated in the PTB where the NPs "a phone" and "a job", the ADVP "even" and the PP "into a school" are siblings. A human reader can easily deduce that the conjuncts are "a phone", "a job" and "into a school", while "even" is a connective. However, for an automatic analyzer, this structure is ambiguous: NPs can be conjoined with ADVPs as well as PPs, and a coordination phrase of the form NP NP CC ADVP PP has at least two possible interpretations: (1) Coord Co- ord CC Conn Coord (2) Coord Coord CC Coord Shared.</p><p>Inconsistency in shared elements and mark- ers level The PTB guidelines allows inconsis- tency in the case of shared ADVP pre-modifiers of VPs (e.g. "deliberately chewed and winked"). The pre-modifier may be annotated in the same level of the VP ((ADVP deliberately) (VP chewed and winked)) or inside it (VP (ADVP deliberately) chewed and winked)). In addition to this docu- mented inconsistency, we also found markers that are inconsistently annotated in and outside the co- ordination phrase, such as respectively which is tagged as sibling to the conjuncts in (NP (NP Feb. 1 1990) (CC and) <ref type="bibr">(NP May. 3 1990)</ref>, (ADVP re- spectively)) and as sibling to the conjuncts par- ent in (VP (VBD were) (NP 7.37% and 7.42%), (ADVP respectively)).</p><p>Inconsistency in comparative quantity coordi- nation Quantity phrases with a second conjunct of more, less, so, two and up are inconsistently tagged. Consider the following sentences: "[50] <ref type="bibr">[or]</ref> [so] projects are locked up", "Street esti- mates of [$ 1] [or so] are low". The coordina- tion phrase is similar in both the sentences but is annotated differently.</p><p>Various errors The PTB coordination struc- tures include errors. Some are related to flat co- ordinations <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Hogan, 2007)</ref>. In addition, we found cases where a conjunct is not annotated as a com- plete phrase, but with two sequenced phrases. For instance, the conjuncts in the sentence "But less than two years later, the LDP started to crumble, and dissent rose to unprecedented heights" are "the LDP started to crumble" and "dissent rose to unprecedented heights". In the PTB, this sentence is annotated where the first conjunct is splitted into two phrases: "[the LDP] [started to crumble], and [dissent rose to unprecedented heights]".</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Extended Coordination Annotation</head><p>The PTB annotation of coordinations makes it dif- ficult to identify phrases containing coordination and to distinguish the conjuncts from the other parts of a coordination phrase. In addition it con- tains various errors, inconsistencies and coordina- tion phrases with no internal structure. We pro- pose an improved representation which aims to solve these problems, while keeping the deviation from the original PTB trees to a minimum.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">Explicit Function Marking</head><p>We add function labels to non-terminal symbols of nodes participating in coordination structures. The function labels are indicated by appending a -XXX suffix to the non-terminal symbol, where the XXX mark the function of the node. Phrases containing a coordination are marked with a CCP label. Nodes directly dominated by a CCP node are assigned one of the following labels accord- ing to their function: CC for coordinators, CO- ORD for conjuncts, MARK for markers <ref type="bibr">5</ref> , CONN for connectives and parentheticals, and SHARED for shared modifiers/arguments. For shared el- ements, we deal only with those that are inside the coordination phrase. We do not assign func- tion labels to punctuation symbols and empty el- ements. For example, our annotation for the sen- tence ". . . he observed among his fellow students and, more important, among his officers and in- structors . . . " is:   <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table 1</ref>: The number of labels that were added to the Penn Treebank by type.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">Changes in Tree Structure</head><p>As a guiding principle, we try not to change the structure of the original PTB trees. The excep- tions to this rule are cases where the structure is changed to provide internal structure when it is missing, as well as when fixing systematic inconsistencies and occasional errors.</p><p>1. In flat coordination structures which include elements with more than one word, we add brack- ets to delimit the element spans. For instance, in the flat NP in <ref type="bibr">[1]</ref> we add brackets to delimit the conjunct "chief executive officer". The full phrase structure is: (NP-CCP (NN-COORD chairman) (CC-CC and) (NP-COORD chief executive offi- cer)).</p><p>2. Comparative quantity phrases ("5 dollars or less") are inconsistently analyzed in the PTB. When needed, we add an extra bracket with a QP label so they are consistently analyzed as "5 dollars [or less] QP ". Note that we do not consider these cases as coordination phrases.</p><p>3. We add brackets to delimit the coordination phrase in flat cases that include coordination be- tween modifiers while the head is annotated in the same phrase: company, which is the head of the phrase, is originally annotated at the same level as the conjuncts broadcast and publishing, and the determiner the. In such cases, the determiner and modifiers are related to the head which is not part of the coordination phrase, requiring the extra bracketing level to delimit the coordination. This is in contrast to the case of coordination between verbs (e.g "Bob (VP cleaned and refueled the spaceship)"), where the non coordinated elements ("the spaceship") are shared.</p><p>4. When a conjunct is split into two phrases or more due to an error, we add extra brackets to de- limit the conjunct as a complete phrase:   <ref type="table">Table 2</ref>: The number of subtrees in the Penn Tree- bank that were changed in our annotation by type. 5. We consolidate cases where markers and ADVP pre-modifiers are annotated outside the coordina- tion phrase, so they are consistently annotated in- side the coordination phrase. <ref type="table">Table 2</ref> summarizes the numbers and types of subtrees that receive a new tree structure in the en- hanced version of the Penn Treebank.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>1) Flat structures 1872 (2) Comparative quantity phrases 52 (3) Coordination between modifiers 1264 (4) Coordination with errors 213 (5) ADVP inconsistency 206</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">The Annotation Process</head><p>Some of the changes can be done automatically, while other require human judgment. Our annota- tion procedure combines automatic rules and man- ual annotation that was performed by a dedicated annotator that was trained for this purpose.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.1">Explicit marking of coordination phrases</head><p>We automatically annotate coordination phrases with a CCP function label. We consider a phrase as coordination phrase if it includes a coordinator and at least one phrase on each side of the coor- dinator, unlike coordinators that function as dis- course markers or introduce parentheticals, which appear as the first element in the phrase.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.2">Assigning internal structure to flat coordinations</head><p>Flat coordinations that include only a coordinator and two conjuncts (e.g. (NP (NNP Poland) (CC and) (NNP Hungary))) are trivial and are left with the same structure. For the rest of the flat co- ordinations (3498 cases), we manually annotated the elements spans. For example, given the flat</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">NP: "[General] N N P [Electric] N N P [Co.] N N P [executives] N N S [and] CC [lawyers] N N S ".</formula><p>The annotator is expected to provide the analysis:</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">"[General Electric Co.]</formula><p>[executives] <ref type="bibr">[and]</ref> [lawyers]". We then add brackets around multi- token elements (e.g. "General Electric Co."), and set the label according the syntactic structure. The annotation was done while ignoring inner struc- tures that were given in the NP-Bracketing exten- sion of <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Vadas and Curran (2007)</ref>. We compare agreement with their annotations in the next sec- tion.</p><p>To handle cases such as in 4. <ref type="bibr">2(3)</ref>, where the co- ordination is between modifiers of a head which is annotated in the PTB on the same level of the con- juncts, we first identify potential candidate phrases of this type by looking for coordination phrases where the last element was not tagged by the an- notator as a conjunct. Out of this set, we re- move cases where we can reliably identify the non-conjunct element as a marker. For the rest of the cases, we distinguish between NP phrases and non-NP phrases. For NP phrases, we auto- matically add extra brackets to delimit the coor- dination phrase span so that it includes only the coordinated modifiers. For the rest of the phrases we found that an such automatic procedure was not feasible (consider the ADVP phrases: (ADVP (RBR farther) (CC and) (RBR farther) (RB apart)) ; (ADVP (RB up) (CC and) (RB down) (NP (NNP Florida))). The first phrase head is apart while in the second phrase, Florida is a complement). We manually annotated the coordination phrase boundary in these cases.</p><p>When adding an extra tree level in this cases, we set its syntactic label to UCP when the conjuncts are from different types and same as the conjuncts label when the conjuncts are from the same type. <ref type="bibr">6</ref> </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.3">Annotating roles within coordination phrases</head><p>Cases where there are only a coordinator and two siblings in the coordinated phrase are trivial to automatically annotate, marking both siblings as conjuncts: To categorize the phrase elements for the rest of the coordination phrases, we first manually marked the conjuncts in the sentence (for flat structures, the conjuncts were already annotated in the internal structure annotation phase). The annotator was given a sentence where the coor- dinator and the coordination phrase boundaries are marked.</p><p>For example "Coke has been able to improve (bottlers' efficiency and production, {and} in some cases, marketing)". The annotation task was to mark the conjuncts. <ref type="bibr">7</ref> We automatically concluded the types of the other elements according to their relative position -elements before or after the conjuncts are categorized as markers/shared, while an element between conjuncts is a connec- tive or the coordinator itself.</p><p>Mismatches with the PTB phrase bound- aries In 5% of the cases of coordination with inner structure, a conjunct span as it was an- notated by our annotator was not consistent with the elements spans in the PTB. For ex- ample, the annotator provided the following annotation:</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">"(The [economic loss], [jobs lost], [anguish],[frustration] {and}</formula><p>[humiliation]) are beyond measure", treat- ing the determiner "The" as a shared modifier. In contrast, the PTB analysis considers "The" as part of the first conjunct ("[The economic loss]").</p><p>The vast majority of the mismatches were on the point of a specific word such as the (as demon- strated in the above example), to, a and punctu- ation symbols. In a small number of cases the mismatch was because of an ambiguity. For exam- ple, in "The declaration immediately made the counties eligible for (temporary housing, grants {and} low-cost loans to cover uninsured property losses)" the an- notator marked "temporary housing", "grants", and "low-cost loans" as conjuncts (leaving "to cover uninsured property loss" as a shared modifier, while the PTB annotation considers "to cover. . . " as part of the last conjunct. Following our desiderata of minimizing changes to existing tree structures, in a case of a mismatch we extend the conjunct spans to be consistent with the PTB phrasing (each such case was manually verified).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.4">Handling inconsistencies and errors</head><p>We automatically recognize ADVPs that appear right before a VP coordination phrase and mark- ers that are adjunct to a coordination phrase. We change the structure such that such ADVPs and markers appear inside the coordination phrase.</p><p>Quantity phrases that includes two conjuncts with a second conjunct of more, less, so, two and up are automatically recognized and consolidated by adding an extra level.</p><p>Errors in conjuncts span are found during the manual annotation that is done for the categoriza- tion. When the manual annotation includes a con- junct that is originally a combination of two sib- lings phrases, we add extra brackets and name the new level according to the syntactic structure.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Annotator Agreement</head><p>We evaluate the resulting corpus with inter- annotators agreement for coordination phrases with inner structure as well as agreement with the flat conjuncts that were annotated in the NP bracketing annotation effort of <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Vadas and Curran (2007)</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.1">Inter-annotator agreement</head><p>To test the inter-annotator agreement, we were as- sisted with an additional linguist who annotated 1000 out of 7823 coordination phrases with inner structure. We measured the number of coordina- tion phrases where the spans are inconsistent at least in one conjunct. The annotators originally agreed in 92.8% of the sentences. After revision, the agreement increased to 98.1%. The disagree- ments occurred in semantically ambiguous cases. For instance, "potato salad, baked beans and pud- ding, plus coffee or iced tea" was tagged differ- ently by the 2 annotators. One considered "pud- ding" as the last conjunct and the other marked "pudding, plus coffee or iced tea".</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.2">Agreement with NP Bracketing for flat coordinations</head><p>The NP Bracketing extension of <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Vadas and Curran (2007)</ref> includes inner structures for flat NP phrases R P F1 PTB + NPB 90.41 86.12 88.21 PTB + NPB + CCP 90.83 91.18 91.01 <ref type="table">Table 3: The parser results on section 22.</ref> in the PTB, that are given an internal structure us- ing the NML tag. For instance, in (NP (NNP Air) (NNP Force) (NN contract)), "Air Force" is con- sidered as an independent entity and thus is de- limited with the NML tag: (NP (NML (NNP Air) (NNP Force)) (NN contract)).</p><p>As mentioned, 48% (1655 sentences) of the NP flat coordination were disambiguated in this effort. 8 For these, the agreement on the con- juncts spans with the way they were marked by our annotators is 88%. The disagreements were in cases where a modifier is ambiguous. For exam- ples consider "luxury" in "The luxury airline and casino company", "scientific" in "scientific insti- tutions or researchers" and "Japanese" in "some Japanese government officials and businessmen". In cases of disagreement we followed our annota- tors decisions. <ref type="bibr">9</ref> </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7">Experiments</head><p>We evaluate the impact of the new annotation on the PTB parsing accuracy. We use the state- of-the-art Berkeley parser ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Petrov et al., 2006</ref>), and compare the original PTB annotations (in- cluding Vadas and Curran's base-NP bracketing -PTB+NPB) to the coordination annotations in this work (PTB+NPB+CCP). We use sections 2- 21 for training, and report accuracies on the tra- ditional dev set (section 22). The parse trees are scored using EVALB <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Sekine and Collins, 1997)</ref>.</p><p>Structural Changes We start by considering how the changes in tree structures affect the parser performance. We compared the parsing perfor- mance when trained and tested on PTB+NPB, to the parsing performance when trained and tested on PTB+NPB+CCP. The new function labels were ignored in both training and testing. The results</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Gold</head><p>Pred CC CCP COORD MARK SHARED CONN <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">None Err  CC  849  1  5  CCP  552  1  91  205  COORD  3  1405  2  184 200  MARK  9  2  1  SHARED  1  29  85  3  CONN  1  4  2  None  4  124  113  4  26  14   Table 4</ref>: Confusion-matrix over the predicted function labels. None indicate no function label (a con- stituent which is not directly inside a CCP phrase). Err indicate cases in which the gold span was not predicted by the parser.</p><p>are presented in <ref type="table">Table 3</ref>. Parsing accuracy on the coordination-enhanced corpus is higher than on the original trees. However, the numbers are not strictly comparable, as the test sets contain trees with somewhat different number of con- stituents. To get a fairer comparison, we also eval- uate the parsers on the subset of trees in section 22 whose structures did not change. We check two conditions: trees that include coordination, and trees that do not include coordination. Here, we see a small drop in parsing accuracy when using the new annotation. When trained and tested on PTB+NPB+CCP, the parser results are slightly de- creased compared to PTB+NPB -from 89.89% F1 to 89.4% F1 for trees with coordination and from 91.78% F1 to 91.75% F1 for trees without coordi- nation. However, the drop is small and it is clear that the changes did not make the corpus substan- tially harder to parse. We also note that the pars- ing results for trees including coordinations are lower than those for trees without coordination, highlighting the challenge in parsing coordination structures.</p><p>Function Labels How good is the parser in pre- dicting the function labels, distinguishing between conjuncts, markers, connectives and shared modi- fiers? When we train and test the parser on trees that include the function labels, we see a rather large drop in accuracy: from 89.89% F1 (for trees that include a coordination) to 85.27% F1. A closer look reveals that a large part of this drop is superficial: taking function labels into account cause errors in coordination scope to be punished multiple times. <ref type="bibr">10</ref> When we train the parser with new annotation adds structure to the previously flat NPs, unifies inconsistencies, fix errors, and marks the role of different participants in the coordina- tion structure with respect to the coordination. We make our annotation available to the NLP commu- nity. This resource is a necessary first step towards better disambiguation of coordination structures in syntactic parsers.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>(</head><label></label><figDesc>a) "[in the open market] P P , [in private transac- tions] or [otherwise]." (b) "[According to Fred Demler] P P , [High- land Valley has already started operating] and [Cananea is expected to do so soon]."</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" validated="true"><head>Table 1 summarizes</head><label>1</label><figDesc>the number of labels for each type in the enhanced version of the Penn Treebank.</figDesc><table>Function label 
# 
CC 
24,572 
CCP 
24,450 
COORD 
52,512 
SHARED 
3372 
CONN 
526 
MARK 
522 

</table></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> The data is available in: https://github.com/Jess1ca/CoordinationExtPTB</note>

			<note place="foot" n="2"> Here, the NP containing the coordination (&quot;Venus&apos;s density and mean temperature&quot;) is itself an argument of &quot;are very high&quot;. 3 While both are shared arguments, standard syntactic analyses consider the subject (Bob) to be outside the VP containing the coordination, and the direct object (the spaceship) as a part of the VP.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="4"> shared arguments may appear in the PTB outside the coordination phrase. For example He is an argument for bought and for sold in ((He) ((bought) (and) (sold) (stocks))).</note>

			<note place="foot" n="5"> both, either, between, first, neither, not, not only, respectively and together</note>

			<note place="foot" n="6"> When the conjuncts are in POS level, a corresponding syntactic label is set. For example: (NP-CCP (NN-COORD head) (CC-CC and) (NNS-COORD shoulders))</note>

			<note place="foot" n="7"> The coordination phrase boundaries were taken from the PTB annotations and were used to focus the annotators attention, rather than to restrict the annotation. The annotators were allowed to override them if they thought they were erronous. We did not encounter such cases.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="8"> We consider a flat NP coordination as disambiguated if it includes a coordinator and two other elements, i.e.: (NML (NML (NN eye) (NN care)) (CC and) (NML (NN skin) (NN care))) ; (NML (NN buy) (CC or) (NN sell)). 9 A by-product of this process is a list of ambiguous modifier attachment cases, which can be used for future research on coordination disambiguation, for example in designing error metrics that take such annotator disagreements into account.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="10"> Consider the gold structure (NP (NP-CCP (DT-MARK a) (NP-COORD b) (CC and) (NP-COORD c) (PP-SHARED d))) and the incorrect prediction (NP (DT a) (NP-CCP (NPfunction labels but ignore them at evaluation time, the results climb back up to 87.45% F1. Furthermore, looking at coordination phrases whose structure was perfectly predicted (65.09% of the cases), the parser assigned the correct function label for all the coordination parts in 98.91% of the cases. The combined results suggest that while the parser is reasonably effective at assigning the correct function labels, there is still work to be done on this form of disambiguation. The availability of function labels annotation allows us to take a finer-grained look at the parsing behavior on coordination. Table 4 lists the parser assigned labels against the gold labels. Common cases of error are (1) conjuncts identificationwhere 200 out of 1794 gold conjuncts were assigned an incorrect span and 113 non-conjunct spans were predicted as participating as conjuncts in a coordination phrase; and (2) Shared elements identification, where 74.57% of the gold shared elements were analyzed as either out of the coordination phrase or as part of the last coordinates. These numbers suggest possible areas of future research with respect to coordination disambiguation which are likely to provide high gains. 8 Conclusions Coordination is a frequent and important syntactic phenomena, that pose a great challenge to automatic syntactic annotation. Unfortunately, the current state of coordination annotation in the PTB is lacking. We present a version of the PTB with improved annotation for coordination structure. The COORD b) (CC and) (NP-COORD c)) (PP d)). When taking only the syntactic labels into account there is only the mistake of the coordination span. When taking the coordination roles into account, there are two additional mistakes-the missing labels for a and d.</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>This work was supported by The Allen Insti-tute for Artificial Intelligence as well as the Ger-man Research Foundation via the German-Israeli Project Cooperation (DIP, grant DA 1600/1-1).</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Bracketing guidelines for treebank ii style penn treebank project</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ann</forename><surname>Bies</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mark</forename><surname>Ferguson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Karen</forename><surname>Katz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Robert</forename><surname>Macintyre</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Victoria</forename><surname>Tredinnick</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Grace</forename><surname>Kim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mary</forename><forename type="middle">Ann</forename><surname>Marcinkiewicz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Britta</forename><surname>Schasberger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">97</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">100</biblScope>
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>University of Pennsylvania</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Type raising, functional composition, and non-constituent conjunction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Dowty</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Categorial grammars and natural language structures</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1988" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="153" to="197" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Coordinate structure analysis with global structural constraints and alignmentbased local features</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kazuo</forename><surname>Hara</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Masashi</forename><surname>Shimbo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hideharu</forename><surname>Okuma</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yuji</forename><surname>Matsumoto</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Joint Conference of the 47th Annual Meeting of the ACL and the 4th International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing of the AFNLP</title>
		<meeting>the Joint Conference of the 47th Annual Meeting of the ACL and the 4th International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing of the AFNLP</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="967" to="975" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Association for Computational Linguistics</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Coordinate noun phrase disambiguation in a generative parsing model. Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Deirdre</forename><surname>Hogan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The cambridge grammar of english</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rodney</forename><surname>Huddleston</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Geoffrey</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Pullum</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
			<publisher>Cambridge University Press</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1273" to="1362" />
			<pubPlace>Language. Cambridge</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Genia corpusa semantically annotated corpus for bio-textmining</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J-D</forename><surname>Kim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tomoko</forename><surname>Ohta</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yuka</forename><surname>Tateisi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Junichi</forename><surname>Tsujii</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Bioinformatics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="180" to="182" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>suppl</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Annotating coordination in the penn treebank</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wolfgang</forename><surname>Maier</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Erhard</forename><surname>Hinrichs</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sandra</forename><surname>Kübler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Julia</forename><surname>Krivanek</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Sixth Linguistic Annotation Workshop</title>
		<meeting>the Sixth Linguistic Annotation Workshop</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="166" to="174" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Building a large annotated corpus of english: The penn treebank</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mary</forename><forename type="middle">Ann</forename><surname>Mitchell P Marcus</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Beatrice</forename><surname>Marcinkiewicz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Santorini</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Computational linguistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="313" to="330" />
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Learning accurate, compact, and interpretable tree annotation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Slav</forename><surname>Petrov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Leon</forename><surname>Barrett</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Romain</forename><surname>Thibaux</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dan</forename><surname>Klein</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 21st International Conference on Computational Linguistics and the 44th annual meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the 21st International Conference on Computational Linguistics and the 44th annual meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="433" to="440" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Evalb bracket scoring program</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Satoshi</forename><surname>Sekine</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Collins</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://nlp.cs.nyu.edu/evalb/EVALB.tgz" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A discriminative learning model for coordinate conjunctions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Masashi</forename><surname>Shimbo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kazuo</forename><surname>Hara</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">EMNLP-CoNLL</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="610" to="619" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Adding noun phrase structure to the penn treebank</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Vadas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">James</forename><surname>Curran</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ANNUAL MEETING-ASSOCIATION FOR COMPUTATIONAL LINGUISTICS</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">45</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">240</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
