<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T10:23+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main"></title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract/>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Introduction</head><p>This volume contains the abstracts of the ACL 2017 tutorials. This year we had a joint call-for-tutorials, coordinated with the EACL and EMNLP co-chairs (6 co-chairs in total). We received 26 submissions for the joint ACL/EACL/EMNLP call, and it was a difficult task to make a final selection. The six co-chairs applied the following criteria for evaluation: relevance to ACL community, quality of proposal, quality of instructor, estimate of attendance, relevance of area. The tutorials were then assigned to venues trying to respect proposers' preferences and to balance topics across venues. Nine tutorials had ACL as the preferred conference, from which one was rejected, two were redirected to EMNLP and the rest (six of them) was accepted. All six are organised as half-day tutorials.</p><p>We are very grateful to Alex Klementiev and Lucia Specia (EACL tutorial chairs), Nathan Schneider and Alexandra Birch (EMNLP tutorial chairs), Priscilla Rasmussen and Anoop Sarkar (local chairs), Wei Lu, Sameer Singh and Margaret Mitchell (publication chairs), Min-Yen Kan and Regina Barzilay (program co-chairs) and of course Chris Callison-Burch (general chair) for various kinds of help, advice and assistance offered during the process of putting the tutorial programme and materials together. Most importantly, we would like to thank the tutorial presenters for the time and effort in preparing and presenting the tutorials.  </p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>We hope you will enjoy the tutorials! ACL 2017 Tutorial Chairs Maja Popovi´cPopovi´c, Humboldt-Universität zu Berlin Jordan Boyd-Graber, University of Colorado, Boulder iii Tutorial Chairs: Maja Popovi´cPopovi´c, Humboldt-Universität zu Berlin Jordan Boyd-Graber, University of Colorado, Boulder v</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" validated="false"><head>Table of Contents</head><label>of</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>NLP for Precision Medicine 
Hoifung Poon, Chris Quirk and Kristina Toutanova . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . 1 

Multimodal Machine Learning: Integrating Language, Vision and Speech 
Louis-Philippe Morency and Tadas Baltrušaitis . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . 3 

Deep Learning for Semantic Composition 
Xiaodan Zhu and Edward Grefenstette . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . 6 

Deep Learning for Dialogue Systems 
Yun-Nung Chen, Asli Celikyilmaz and Dilek Hakkani-Tür . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . 8 

Beyond Words: Deep Learning for Multiword Expressions and Collocations 
Valia Kordoni . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . 15 

Tutorial: Making Better Use of the Crowd 
Jennifer Wortman Vughan . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . 17 

vii 

Conference Program 

Sunday, July 30th 

Morning Session 

9:00-12:30 
NLP for Precision Medicine 
Hoifung Poon, Chris Quirk and Kristina Toutanova 

9:00-12:30 
Multimodal Machine Learning: Integrating Language, Vision and Speech 
Louis-Philippe-Morency and Tadas Baltrušaitis 

9:00-12:30 
Deep Learning for Semantic Composition 
Xiaodan Zhu and Edward Grefenstette 

Afternoon Session 

14:00-17:30 Deep Learning for Dialogue Systems 
Yun-Nung Chen, Asli Celikyilmaz and Dilek Hakkani-Tür 

14:00-17:30 Beyond Words: Deep Learning for Multiword Expressions and Collocations 
Valia Kordon 

14:00-17:30 Tutorial: Making Better Use of the Crowd 
Jennifer Wortman Vughan 

ix </table></figure>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl/>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
