<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T12:39+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main"></title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Allyson</forename><surname>Ettinger</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Cecilia</forename><forename type="middle">Ovesdotter</forename><surname>Alm</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Timothy</forename><surname>Baldwin</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Julian</forename><surname>Brooke</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">John</forename><surname>Carroll</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Eduard</forename><surname>Hovy</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><roleName>University</roleName><forename type="first">Eric</forename><surname>Laporte</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Paris-Est</forename><surname>Marne-La-Vallée</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Haizhou</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Annie</forename><surname>Louis</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Rochester Institute of Technology Marine Carpuat</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">University of Maryland Spandana Gella</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">University of Edinburgh Matthieu Labeau</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit3">University Paris-Saclay</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit4">University of Maryland</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Mark Dredze</addrLine>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Johns Hopkins University</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">The University of Melbourne Kalika Bali</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit3">Microsoft Research</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="IN">India</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="department">Danqi Chen</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">The University of Melbourne</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">University of Sussex</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit3">Stanford University</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit4">Carnegie Mellon University</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit5">University of Maryland Kristiina Jokinen</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit6">University of Cambridge</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit7">Kyoto University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff3">
								<orgName type="department">Ebay Research Diana McCarthy</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">STAR Institute for Infocomm Research Junyi Jessy Li</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">University of Pennsylvania Zhenghua Li</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">Soochow University</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit3">University of Essex</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit4">Harvey Mudd College Mitchell Marcus</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit5">University of Pennsylvania Prashant Mathur</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit6">University of Cambridge Saif Mohammad</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit7">National Research Council</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="CA">Canada</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<note>iii Organizers: Faculty Advisors: Program Committee: Alexandre Allauzen, University Paris-Saclay Hadi Amiri, University of Maryland Antonios Anastasopoulos, University of Notre Dame Bharat Ram Ambati, Apple Inc. Lauriane Aufrant, University Paris-Saclay Wanxiang Che, Harbin Institute of Technology David Chiang, University of Notre Dame Kyunghyun Cho, New York University Tejaswini Deoskar, University of Amsterdam Long Duong, Voicebox Technologies Lea Frermann, University of Edinburgh Kevin Gimpel, Toyota Technological Institute at Chicago Ralph Grishman, New York University Alvin Grissom, University of Colorado Jiang Guo, Harbin Institute of Technology Xiaodong He, Microsoft Research, USA</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract/>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Introduction</head><p>Welcome to the ACL 2017 Student Research Workshop! The ACL 2017 Student Research Workshop (SRW) is a forum for student researchers in computational linguistics and natural language processing. The workshop provides a unique opportunity for student participants to present their work and receive valuable feedback from the international research community as well as from selected mentors.</p><p>Following the tradition of the previous years' student research workshops, we have two tracks: research papers and research proposals. The research paper track is a venue for Ph.D. students, Masters students, and advanced undergraduates to describe completed work or work-in-progress along with preliminary results. The research proposal track is offered for advanced Masters and Ph.D. students who have decided on a thesis topic and are interested in feedback on their proposal and ideas about future directions for their work.</p><p>We received in total 58 submissions: 16 research proposals and 42 research papers. We accepted 6 research proposals and 17 research papers, giving an acceptance rate of 40% overall. This year, all of the accepted papers will be presented as posters in an evening poster session during the main conference.</p><p>Mentoring is at the heart of the SRW. In keeping with previous years, students had the opportunity to participate in a pre-submission mentoring program prior to the submission deadline. This program offered students a chance to receive comments from an experienced researcher, in order to improve the quality of the writing and presentation before making their submission. Twenty-two authors participated in the pre-submission mentoring. In addition, authors of accepted SRW papers are matched with mentors who will meet with the students in person during the workshop. Each mentor prepares in- depth comments and questions prior to the student's presentation, and provides discussion and feedback during the workshop.  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Taesun Moon, IBM Research Maria Nadejde, University of Edinburgh Karthik Narasimhan, Massachusetts Institute of Technology Shashi Narayanan, University of Edinburgh Graham Neubig, Carnegie Mellon University</head><note type="other">Yannick Parmentier, University of Orléans Gerald Penn, University of Toronto Emily Pitler, Google Research, USA Massimo Poesio, University of Essex Emily Prud'</note></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>hommeaux, Rochester Institute of Technology Avinesh PVS, Technishe Universität Darmstadt Siva Reddy, University of Edinburgh Brian Roark, Google Research, USA Michael Roth, University of Illinois Urbana-Champaign Markus Saers, Hong Kong University of Science and Technology David Schlangen, Bielefeld University Carina Silberer, Saarland University Ekaterina Shutova, University of Cambridge Sunayana Sitaram, Microsoft Research, India Kevin Small, Amazon Richard Sproat, Google Research, USA Christoph Teichmann, University of Potsdam Sowmya Vajjala, Iowa State University Marlies van der Wees, University of Amsterdam William Yang Wang, Carnegie Mellon University Bonnie Webber, University of Edinburgh Alessandra Zarcone, Saarland University Meishan Zhang, Singapore University of Technology and Design Yuan Zhang, Massachusetts Institute of Technology Yue Zhang, Singapore University of Technology and Design vi</head></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Computational Characterization of Mental States: A Natural Language Processing Approach Facundo Carrillo . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . 1 Improving Distributed Representations of Tweets -Present and Future Ganesh Jawahar . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . 4 Bilingual Word Embeddings with Bucketed CNN for Parallel Sentence Extraction Jeenu Grover and Pabitra Mitra . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . 11 nQuery -A Natural Language Statement to SQL Query Generator Nandan Sukthankar, Sanket Maharnawar, Pranay Deshmukh, Yashodhara Haribhakta and Vibhavari Kamble. . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . .17 V for Vocab: An Intelligent Flashcard Application Nihal V. Nayak, Tanmay Chinchore, Aishwarya Hanumanth Rao, Shane Michael Martin, Sagar Nagaraj Simha, G. M. Lingaraju and H. S. Jamadagni . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . 24</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" validated="false"><head>Table of Contents</head><label>of</label><figDesc></figDesc><table></table></figure>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl/>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
