<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T12:01+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Twitter Demographic Classification Using Deep Multi-modal Multi-task Learning</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
				<availability status="unknown"><p>Copyright Association for Computational Linguistics</p>
				</availability>
				<date>July 30-August 4, 2017. July 30-August 4, 2017</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Prashanth</forename><surname>Vijayaraghavan</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Soroush</forename><surname>Vosoughi</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Deb</forename><surname>Roy</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Twitter Demographic Classification Using Deep Multi-modal Multi-task Learning</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 55th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (Volume 2: Short Papers)</title>
						<meeting>the 55th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (Volume 2: Short Papers) <address><addrLine>Vancouver, Canada; Vancouver, Canada</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="478" to="483"/>
							<date type="published">July 30-August 4, 2017. July 30-August 4, 2017</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="DOI">10.18653/v1/p17-2076</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Twitter should be an ideal place to get a fresh read on how different issues are playing with the public, one that&apos;s potentially more reflective of democracy in this new media age than traditional polls. Poll-sters typically ask people a fixed set of questions, while in social media people use their own voices to speak about whatever is on their minds. However, the demographic distribution of users on Twitter is not representative of the general population. In this paper, we present a demographic classifier for gender, age, political orientation and location on Twitter. We collected and curated a robust Twit-ter demographic dataset for this task. Our classifier uses a deep multi-modal multi-task learning architecture to reach a state-of-the-art performance, achieving an F1-score of 0.89, 0.82, 0.86, and 0.68 for gender , age, political orientation, and location respectively.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>While the most ambitious polls are based on stan- dardized interviews with a few thousand people, millions are tweeting freely and publicly in their own voices about issues they care about. This data offers a vibrant 24/7 snapshot of people's response to various events and topics.</p><p>However, the people using Twitter are not rep- resentative of the general US population <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Greenwood et al., 2016)</ref>. Therefore, if one is to use Twit- ter to understand the public's views on various, it is essential to understand the demographic of the users on Twitter. A robust demographic classifica- tion algorithm can also be utilized for detection of * The first two authors contributed equally to this work. non-human account, especially in the context of bots involved in the spread of rumors and false in- formation on Twitter <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(Vosoughi, 2015)</ref>.</p><p>In this paper, we present a state-of-the-art de- mographic classifier for Twitter. We focus on four different demographic categories: (a) Gender, (b) Age, (c) Political Orientation and (d) Location. We implement different variants of the deep multi- modal multi-task learning architecture to infer these demographic categories.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Features</head><p>Our deep multi-modal multi-task learning mod- els (DMT-Demographic Models) use features ex- tracted from the users' Twitter profile (such as name, profile picture, and description), the users following network and the users historical tweets (what they have said in the past). Below, we ex- plain how these features are extracted and used.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">Name</head><p>The name specified by users in their profile is mainly used for gender prediction. We used three datasets for gender associations of common names:</p><p>• We used the data from US Census Bureau data which contains male and female 1 first names along with frequency of names for the sample male and female population with re- spect to 1990 census.</p><p>• We obtained yearly data for the 100 most popular female and male names between 1960 and 2010 and calculate the overall fre- quency of a name being used in each list.</p><p>• We also have a list of European names and popular first from other countries associated with gender information 2 .</p><p>Using the above datasets, we associate each name with a vector of size 2 representing the prob- ability that the name occurs in male list and female list based on frequency available in the datasets.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">Following Network</head><p>Network Features can be a signal in prediction of some of the demographic parameters. But it is dif- ficult to utilize the complete list of followers and following information of each and every user due to curse of dimensionality. Therefore, we build an binary vector of size N dim for each user with each index of the vector representing a popular Twitter profiles associated with age, political orientation or location and the value (1, 0) represents if the user is following the profile or not. These profiles are short-listed based on the following techniques:</p><p>• We search for user accounts on Twitter for task specific keywords like teenager, 80s, 90s for Age prediction; Democrat, Republican for political orientation and state names for location prediction.</p><p>• We take advantage of the data collected from our earlier work ( ) in processing news stories, classifying named entities into various categories and mapping them to Twitter handles. We use the political personalities mapped onto Twitter to the list of twitter profiles that can potentially act as a signal for our prediction tasks.</p><p>Sample Twitter handles associated with each of the tasks are given in <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>. For gender, the han- dles were too generic, so we expect that there are inherent latent features that can contribute towards gender prediction based on the shortlisted Twit- ter handles. We experiment with one or two fully- connected layers and compress the information to a N emb -sized vector.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3">Profile Description</head><p>The profile description can be really useful to pre- dict all the demographic parameters. Since, GRU is computationally less expensive than LSTM and performs better than standard RNN, we use a gated recurrent network (GRU) ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Chung et al., 2014</ref>). At each time step t, GRU unit takes a word embedding x t and a hidden state h t as input. The internal transition operations of the GRU are defined as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">z t = σ(W (z) x t + U (z) h t−1 + b (z) )</formula><p>(1)</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">r t = σ(W (r) x t + U (r) h t−1 + b (r) )<label>(2)</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_2">˜ h t = tanh(W x t + r t · U h t−1 + b ( h) (3) h t = z t · h t−1 + (1 − z t ) ˜ h t (4)</formula><p>where </p><formula xml:id="formula_3">W (z) , W (r) , W ∈ IR d h ×d i , U (z) , U (r) , U ∈ IR d h ×d h and</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.4">Profile Picture</head><p>Age and gender prediction can exploit the features extracted from profile picture. We extract dense feature representation from the image using the In- ception architecture ( <ref type="bibr">Szegedy et al., 2015</ref>). Since we deal with multiple tasks, we experiment with two different layers (pool 3 and mixed 1 0) repre- sentations from the Inception architecture. The output vector sizes are I V = 2048 and I M = 64 × 2048 respectively.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.5">Tweets</head><p>Finally, we also use tweets for our multitask learn- ing problem. In our experiments, we restrict it to user's recent K tweets. The list of tweets, each of which is word sequence (</p><formula xml:id="formula_4">S i = [w i 1 , w i 2 , ..., w i N ])</formula><p>, are encoded using a positional encoding scheme as used in <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Sukhbaatar et al., 2015)</ref>. (For a more sophisticated encoding of the tweets, one can use the Tweet2Vec by , however the algorithm requires a massive training dataset, which might not be available to everyone) For the positional encoding scheme, the sentence representation is computed by</p><formula xml:id="formula_5">P i = N j=1 l j · w i j (5)</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Task</head><p>Sample Twitter Handles Age @80s Kidz, @The1980sGirl, @60s70sKids, @IL0VEthe80s, @90syears, @The90sLife Pol-Orien @realDonaldTrump, @HillaryClinton, @youngdemocrat, @GOP, @NancyPelosi Location @california, @UWBadgers, @UtahGov, @UMichFootball, @PureMichigan <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>: Sample Twitter handles used to create the network features for each task.</p><p>N is the maximum number of words in a sentence and l j is a column vector with structure</p><formula xml:id="formula_6">l p j = (1 − j/N ) − (p/q)(1 − 2j/N ) (6)</formula><p>where p is the embedding index and q is the di- mension of the embedding. The tweet representa- tion obtained from the positional encoding sum- marizes the word tokens in the sentence. We ex- plore tweet features as (1) a vector by summing up all the K-tweet embeddings T q ∈ IR q , (2) a ma- trix by concatenating all the K-tweet embeddings T Kq ∈ IR K×q</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">DMT-Demographic Models</head><p>Some of the latent information from one task can be useful to predict another task. Therefore, we propose three variants of deep multi-modal multi- task learning demographic models to leverage the multi-modal nature of data. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref> gives an il- lustration of our proposed models. In this section, we explain the single task output layer followed by the various models.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Vanilla DMT-Demographic Model</head><p>This model takes vector features extracted from various user details (explained in section 2) repre- sented by D F , T q , N emb , I V for description, tweet, network and image features respectively. The fea- ture vectors are concatenated and passed through a fully-connected layer. The output of the fully- connected layer is a compressed latent feature vec- tor of size h. This shared latent vector is given to a task-specific output layer explained in Section 4. For gender prediction task, name features are con- catenated with latent vector before feeding it to the output layer.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Attention-based DMT-Demographic Model</head><p>All the modalities do not contribute equally to each of our tasks. Hence, for each task, we con- catenate the weighted modal feature representa- tions obtained through attention mechanism and then pass it through a fully-connected layer to get a latent feature vector. Formally, the extracted fea- tures vectors represented by D F , T q , N emb , I V are concatenated to get a matrix M ∈ IR d×4 where d is the dimension of each feature. If the extracted features are not of the same dimension d, then we introduce a fully-connected layer and transform it to a d-sized vector. The attention over different modal features are computed as follows.</p><formula xml:id="formula_7">α = sof tmax(W (2) tanh(W (1) M + b (1) ) + b (2) )<label>(7)</label></formula><p>where α ∈ IR 1×d . We multiply each of the fea- ture vectors by their corresponding α value to get a weighted feature representation. These weighted representation are concatenated before passing it through a fully-connected layer. The latent vec- tor obtained from the fully connected layer is now task-specific and not shared between tasks. The la- tent vector is given to a task-specific output layer.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3">Hierarchical Attention-based DMT - Demographic Model</head><p>This model is a slight variant of the previous model. In this model, we introduce another level of attention mechanism over the extracted features. The main intuition behind this approach is to have more attention on individual features based on their importance for a task. For example, certain words like 'male','husband' in user's description might be more suitable for gender prediction than any other task. So we weigh such words higher than the other words in the description during gender prediction task. However, these weights might not be applicable for a location prediction task. Hence, we implement a hierarchical attention mechanism that has task-specific weighted feature extraction followed by task-specific attention over the modalities.  sions of weight parameters are feature-specific. For the sake of convenience, let β (F ) be the weights similar to α associated with a feature F . For each feature F, we perform a weighted sum over the extracted representation matrix to obtain a vector representation. Let M (F ) denote the ma- trix representation of an extracted feature F, then the vector representation V (F ) of the feature F can be computed as follows.</p><formula xml:id="formula_8">V (F ) = r F r=1 β (F ) r M (F ) r<label>(8)</label></formula><p>where r F is the maximum number of rows in the representation matrix M (F ) associated with fea- ture F. These vector representations of all the fea- tures are fed to layers similar to attention-based DMT model. It is important to note that all the models incor- porate name features with the final latent vector representation for gender prediction task.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Output Layer</head><p>Given a specific task A, we feed the latent feature vector h (A) , obtained after applying any of the ex- plained models, to a softmax layer depending on the classification task. So the task-specific repre- sentations are fed to task-specific output layers.</p><formula xml:id="formula_9">˜ y (A) = sof tmax(W (A) h (A) + b (A) ),<label>(9)</label></formula><p>where˜ywhere˜ where˜y (A) is a distribution over various cate- gories associated with task A.</p><p>For each task A, we minimize the cross-entropy of the predicted and true distributions.</p><formula xml:id="formula_10">L (A) (˜ y (A) , y (A) ) = N i=1 C (A) j=1 y j(A) i log(˜ y j(A) i ) (10) where y j(A) i</formula><p>and˜yand˜ and˜y i j (A) are the true label and prediction probabilities for task A, N denotes the total number of training samples and C (A) is the total number of classes associated with the task A. Thus, the parameters of our network are optimized for global objective function given by:</p><formula xml:id="formula_11">η = A∈X L (A) (˜ y (A) , y (A) ) (11)</formula><p>where X={Age, Location, Political Orientation, Gender}</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Data Collection &amp; Evaluation</head><p>We agglomerated data based on user tweets and their profile description. With access to Twitter API, we were able to get the timeline and pro- file information of a subset of users. We perform simple analysis of tweets and user description and those that contain phrases like "I'm a girl / woman / guy / man / husband / wife / mother/ father", "I am a democrat / republican / liberal / conservative" or "I support hillary / trump", "Happy 30th birth- day to me","I'm 30 years old", "Born in 1980" etc. and their variants are shortlisted. These phrases act as indicators of gender, political orientation and age. For location prediction task, we used a com- bination of two different Twitter fields to collect</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Task</head><p>Test Data Size Majority Classifier (%) Gender 9,960 53% Age 6,580 43% Pol-Orien 5,255 52% Location 16,956 9% In order to avoid selection bias in the dataset collected, we introduce some noise in the training set by randomly removing the terms (from tweet or description) used for shortlisting the user pro- file. The total size of the training set is 50,859. We evaluate our models on task-specific annotated (mechanical turk) data or data collected based on different phrase indicators from user's tweet or de- scription that was not a part of training set. The de- tails of the test set are given in <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">Table 2</ref>. The macro F1-score of different DMT-Demographic models (plus two baseline non-neural network based mod- els) on the test data can be seen in <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">Table 3</ref>. Hierarchical-Attention model performs well ahead of the other two models for almost all the tasks. However, the performance of all the models fall flat for location prediction task. Location-specific feature augmentation can be explored to improve its performance further.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Related Work</head><p>The main distinctions of several of these models with DMT-Demographic models are that (a) most previous literature use only tweet content analy- sis to predict demographic information <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Nguyen et al., 2013)</ref> while our model leverages different modals of user information including profile pic- ture, (b) though some of the works use interest- ing network information they do not leverage other user details as potential signals ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Colleoni et al., 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Culotta et al., 2015)</ref>, (c) many of the models involve a lot of feature engineering like extracting location indicative words for geolocation predic- tion, etc. ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Han et al., 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Sloan et al., 2015)</ref>, (d) our model learns shared and task-specific layer pa- rameters as we handle the demographic prediction  problem as a multi-task learning problem using different modalities like image (profile picture), text (tweets and user description) and network fea- tures (following).</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: Illustration of variants of the DMT-Demographic Model. Left: Vanilla DMT-Demographic Model; Center: Attention-based DMT-Demographic Model; Right: Hierarchical Attention-based DMTDemographic Model.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" validated="false"><head>Table 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Task-specific details of test data. 

data: (a) latitude, longitude from geo-tagged user 
tweets, (b) Location field in user profile informa-
tion. The various categories associated with each 
of the tasks are: (a) Gender: M,F (b) Age: &lt; 30, 
30 − 60, &gt; 60 (c) Political Orientation: Democrat, 
Republican (d) Location: All states in USA. 
</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4" validated="false"><head>Table 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Task-specific Macro F1-score for differ-
ent DMT-Demographic models. 

</table></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> https://www2.census.gov/topics/genealogy/1990surnames/</note>

			<note place="foot" n="2"> https://hackage.haskell.org/package/gender0.1.1.0/src/data/nam dict.txt.UTF8</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7">Conclusion</head><p>In this paper, we presented a state-of-the-art demo-graphic classifier for identifying the gender, age, political orientation and the location of users on Twitter. We also collected and curated a novel Twitter demographic dataset and explored differ-ent variants of deep multi-modal multi-task learn-ing architectures, settling on the Hierarchical-Attention DMT as the top performing model, achieving an F1-score of 0.89, 0.82, 0.86, and 0.68 for gender, age, political orientation, and location respectively.</p><p>In the future, we intend to use the demographic classifier presented in this paper to study the de-mographic biases present on Twitter.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">On the properties of neural machine translation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kyunghyun</forename><surname>Cho</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bart</forename><surname>Van Merriënboer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dzmitry</forename><surname>Bahdanau</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yoshua</forename><surname>Bengio</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:1409.1259</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
<note type="report_type">Encoder-decoder approaches. arXiv preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Junyoung</forename><surname>Chung</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Caglar</forename><surname>Gulcehre</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kyunghyun</forename><surname>Cho</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yoshua</forename><surname>Bengio</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:1412.3555</idno>
		<title level="m">Empirical evaluation of gated recurrent neural networks on sequence modeling</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
<note type="report_type">arXiv preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Echo chamber or public sphere? predicting political orientation and measuring political homophily in twitter using big data</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Elanor</forename><surname>Colleoni</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alessandro</forename><surname>Rozza</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Adam</forename><surname>Arvidsson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Communication</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">64</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="317" to="332" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Predicting the demographics of twitter users from website traffic data</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Aron</forename><surname>Culotta</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ravi</forename><surname>Kumar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jennifer</forename><surname>Cutler</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">AAAI</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="72" to="78" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Demographics of social media users in 2016</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Shannon</forename><surname>Greenwood</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Andrew</forename><surname>Perrin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Maeve</forename><surname>Duggan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://www.pewinternet.org/2016/11/11/social-media-update-2016" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2017" to="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Textbased twitter user geolocation prediction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bo</forename><surname>Han</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Paul</forename><surname>Cook</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Timothy</forename><surname>Baldwin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Artificial Intelligence Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">49</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="451" to="500" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">how old do you think i am?&quot; a study of language and age in twitter</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dong-Phuong</forename><surname>Nguyen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rilana</forename><surname>Gravel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Theo</forename><surname>Trieschnigg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Meder</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Who tweets? deriving the demographic characteristics of age, occupation and social class from twitter user meta-data</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Luke</forename><surname>Sloan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jeffrey</forename><surname>Morgan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Pete</forename><surname>Burnap</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Matthew</forename><surname>Williams</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">PloS one</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">115545</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">End-to-end memory networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sainbayar</forename><surname>Sukhbaatar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jason</forename><surname>Weston</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rob</forename><surname>Fergus</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Advances in neural information processing systems</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2440" to="2448" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christian</forename><surname>Szegedy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Vincent</forename><surname>Vanhoucke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:1512.00567</idno>
		<title level="m">Sergey Ioffe, Jonathon Shlens, and Zbigniew Wojna. 2015. Rethinking the inception architecture for computer vision</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
<note type="report_type">arXiv preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Automatic detection and categorization of election-related tweets</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Prashanth</forename><surname>Vijayaraghavan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Soroush</forename><surname>Vosoughi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Deb</forename><surname>Roy</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Tenth International AAAI Conference on Web and Social Media</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Automatic detection and verification of rumors on Twitter</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Soroush</forename><surname>Vosoughi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>Massachusetts Institute of Technology</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
<note type="report_type">Ph.D. thesis</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Tweet2vec: Learning tweet embeddings using character-level cnn-lstm encoder-decoder</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Soroush</forename><surname>Vosoughi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Prashanth</forename><surname>Vijayaraghavan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Deb</forename><surname>Roy</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 39th International ACM SIGIR conference on Research and Development in Information Retrieval</title>
		<meeting>the 39th International ACM SIGIR conference on Research and Development in Information Retrieval</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1041" to="1044" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
