<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T12:20+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Annotating tense, mood and voice for</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date>July 30-August 4, 2017. July 30-August 4, 2017</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">French</forename><surname>English</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">German</forename><forename type="middle">Anita</forename><surname>Ramm</surname></persName>
							<email>ramm@ims.uni-stuttgart.de</email>
							<affiliation key="aff3">
								<orgName type="department">Centrum für Informations-und Sprachverarbeitung</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Ludwig-Maximilians-Universität München</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sharid</forename><surname>Loáiciga</surname></persName>
							<email>sharid.loaiciga@unige.ch</email>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Département de Linguistique</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Université de Genève</orgName>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Linguistics and Philology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Uppsala University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Annemarie</forename><surname>Friedrich</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff3">
								<orgName type="department">Centrum für Informations-und Sprachverarbeitung</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Ludwig-Maximilians-Universität München</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alexander</forename><surname>Fraser</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff3">
								<orgName type="department">Centrum für Informations-und Sprachverarbeitung</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Ludwig-Maximilians-Universität München</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Institut für Maschinelle Sprachverarbeitung</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Universität Stuttgart</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Annotating tense, mood and voice for</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 55th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics-System Demonstrations</title>
						<meeting>the 55th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics-System Demonstrations <address><addrLine>Vancouver, Canada; Vancouver, Canada</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="6"/>
							<date type="published">July 30-August 4, 2017. July 30-August 4, 2017</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="DOI">10.18653/v1/P17-4001</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>We present the first open-source tool for annotating morphosyntactic tense, mood and voice for English, French and Ger-man verbal complexes. The annotation is based on a set of language-specific rules, which are applied on dependency trees and leverage information about lemmas, morphological properties and POS-tags of the verbs. Our tool has an average accuracy of about 76%. The tense, mood and voice features are useful both as features in computational modeling and for corpus-linguistic research.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Natural language employs, among other devices such as temporal adverbials, tense and aspect to locate situations in time and to describe their tem- poral structure <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Deo, 2012)</ref>. The tool presented here addresses the automatic annotation of mor- phosyntactic tense, i.e., the tense-aspect combi- nations, expressed in the morphology and syntax of verbal complexes (VC). VCs are sequences of verbal tokens within a verbal phrase. We address German, French and English, in which the mor- phology and syntax also includes information on mood and voice. Morphosyntactic tenses do not always correspond to semantic tense <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Deo, 2012)</ref>. For example, the morphosyntactic tense of the En- glish sentence "He is leaving at noon." is present progressive, while the semantic tense is future. In the remainder of this paper, we use the term tense to refer to the morphological tense and aspect in- formation encoded in finite verbal complexes.</p><p>Corpus-linguistic research, as well as automatic modeling of mono-and cross-lingual use of tense, mood and voice will strongly profit from a reliable automatic method for identifying these clausal features. They may, for instance, be used to clas- sify texts with respect to the epoch or region in which they have been produced, or for assigning texts to a specific author. Moreover, in cross- lingual research, tense, mood, and voice have been used to model the translation of tense between different language pairs <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Santos, 2004;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Loáiciga et al., 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Ramm and Fraser, 2016)</ref>). Identi- fying the morphosyntactic tense is also a neces- sary prerequisite for identifying the semantic tense in synthetic languages such as English, French or German <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Reichart and Rappoport, 2010)</ref>. The extracted tense-mood-voice (TMV) features may also be useful for training models in computational linguistics, e.g., for modeling of temporal relations <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Costa and Branco, 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b12">UzZaman et al., 2013)</ref>.</p><p>As illustrated by the examples in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref>, rel- evant information for determining TMV is given by syntactic dependencies and partially by part- of-speech (POS) tags output by analyzers such as Mate <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Bohnet and Nivre, 2012)</ref>. However, the parser's output is not sufficient for determining TMV features; morphological features and lexical information needs to be taken into account as well. Learning TMV features from an annotated corpus would be an alternative; however, to the best of our knowledge, no such large-scale corpora exist.</p><p>A sentence may contain more than one VC, and the tokens belonging to a VC are not always con- tiguous in the sentence (see VCs A and B in the English sentence in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref>). In a first step, our tool identifies the tokens that belong to a VC by analysing their POS tags as well as the syntactic dependency parse of the sentence. Next, TMV values are assigned according to language specific hand-crafted sets of rules, which have been devel- oped based on extensive data analysis. (2) Extraction of verbal complexes based on dependencies; (3) Assignment of TMV features based on POS sequences, morphological features and lexical rules:</p><p>A will be examined formation about the VCs into a TSV file which can easily be used for further processing. Contributions. To the best of our knowledge, our system represents the first open-source 2 sys- tem which implements a reliable set of derivation rules for annotating tense, mood and voice for En- glish, French and German. Furthermore, the on- line demo 3 version of the tool allows for fast text processing without installing the tool.</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">MD[will] VB[be] VBN → futureI indicative passive B hope VBP → present indicative active C sagt VFIN[pres/ind] → present indicative active D seien beantwortet worden VAFIN[pres/ind] VVPP VVPP[worden] → present indicative passive E sera examinéeexamin´examinée V[ind/fut] VPP[part/past] → futureI indicative passive F espèreesp`espère V[ind/pst] → present indicative active</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Properties of the verbal complexes</head><p>In this section, we describe the morphosyntactic features that we extract for verbal complexes.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">Finite and non-finite VCs</head><p>We define a verbal complex (VC) as a sequence of verbs within a verbal phrase, i.e. a sentence may include more than one VC. In addition to the verbs, a VC can also contain verbal particles and negation words but not arguments. We distinguish between finite VCs which need to have at least one finite verb (e.g. "sagt" in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref>), and non-finite VCs which do not; the latter consist of verb forms such as gerunds, participles or infinitives (e.g. "to support"). Infinitives in English and German have to occur with the particles to or zu, respectively, while in French, infinitives may occur alone. We do not assign the TMV features to non-finite VCs. Our tool marks finiteness of a VC using a binary feature "yes" (finite) and "no" (non-finite).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">Tense, mood, voice</head><p>The identification of TMV features for a VC re- quires the analysis of lexical and grammatical in- formation, such as inflections, given by the combi- nation of verbs. For example, the English present continuous requires the auxiliary be in present tense and the gerundive form of the main verb (e.g. "(I) am speaking").</p><p>Mood refers to the distinction between indica- tive and subjunctive. Both of these values are expressed in the inflection of finite verbs in all the considered languages. For example, the En- glish verb "shall" is indicative, while its subjunc- tive form is "should." In English, tense forms used in subjunctive mood are often called conditionals; for German, they are referred to as Konjunktiv.</p><p>Voice differentiates between active and passive constructions. In all three languages, the passive voice can be recognized by searching for a specific verb. For example, the passive voice in English requires the auxiliary be in a tense-specific form, e.g., "(I) am being seen" for present progressive or "(he) has been seen" for present perfect.</p><p>Details on how our tool automatically identifies TMV features will be described in Section 3.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3">Negation</head><p>VCs may include negation. Our tool outputs a bi- nary negation value to VCs depending on whether a negation word (identified by checking for a language-specific POS-tag) is part of the verbal dependency chain. If a negation exists, the feature value is "yes", and "no" otherwise.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.4">Main verb</head><p>Within a VC, the main verb bears the semantic meaning. For example, in the English VC "would have read," the participle "read" is considered to be the main verb. The main verb feature may con- tain a single verb or a combination of a verb with the verb particle. In the following, we describe the detection of the main verbs for each of the three languages under consideration.</p><p>English and French. In English and French VCs, the very last verb in the VC is considered to be the main verb. For example, in the English VC "will be examined", "examined" is marked as the main verb. Verb particles are considered as a part of the main verb and are attached to the cor- responding main verb, e.g., the main verb of the non-finite English VC "to move up" is "move-up."</p><p>German In general, the main verbs in German have specific POS-tags (VV*) (see, for example, ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Scheible et al., 2013)</ref>). In most German VCs, there is only one verb with such a POS-tag. How- ever, there are a few exceptions. For exam- ple, the recipient passive is built with full verbs bekommen, kriegen, as well as lernen, lassen, bleiben and an additional meaning-bearing full verb. Thus, in such constructions, there are two verbs tagged as VV* (e.g. "Ich bekomme V V F IN das Buch geschenkt V V P P ." ("I receive the book donated")). Recipient verbs are not treated as main verbs if they occur with an additional full verb. In case there are no verbs tagged with VV*, the last verb in the chain is considered to be the main verb.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Deriving tense, mood and voice</head><p>In this section, we give a short overview of the methods used to derive TMV information.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Extraction of VCs</head><p>The tokens of a VC are not necessarily contiguous. They may be separated by a coordination, adver- bials, etc., or even include nested VCs as in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure  1</ref>. This makes it necessary to take syntactic de- pendencies into account. The extraction of VCs in our tool is based on dependency parse trees in the CoNLL format. <ref type="bibr">4</ref> The first step is the identi- fication of all VC-beginning elements v b within a sentence, which include finite verbs (English, French and German) and infinitival particles (En- glish, German). They are identified by searching for specific POS-tags. For each v b , the remain- ing elements of the VC are collected by following the dependency relations between verbs. Consider for example the finite verb "will" in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref>. It is identified as a v b because of its POS tag MD. We now follow the dependency path from "will" to "be" and from "be" to "examined". The result- ing VC is thus "will be examined."  <ref type="table">tense  voice  example (active voice)</ref> ind present (I) work presProg (I) am working presPerf (I) have worked presPerfProg (I) have been working past (I) worked pastProg (I) was working pastPerf (I) had worked pastPerfProg act (I) have been working yes futureI pass (I) will work futureIProg (I) will be working futureII (I) will have worked futureIIProg (I) will have been working subj condI (I) would work condIProg (I) would be working condII (I) would have worked condIIProg (I) would have been working no - - - to work <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>: TMV combinations for English.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">TMV extraction rules</head><p>English. The rules for English make use of the combinations of the functions of the verbs within a given VC. Such functions are for instance finite verb or passive auxiliary. According to the POS combination of a VC and lexical information, first, the function of each verb within the VC is deter- mined. Subsequently, the combination of the de- rived functions is mapped to TMV values. For ex- ample, the following functions will be assigned to the verbs of the VC "will be examined" in Fig- ure 1: "will" → finite-modal, "be"→ passive- auxiliary, "examined" → past-participle. This particular combination of verb functions leads to the TMV combination futureI/indicative/passive. <ref type="table">Table 1</ref> contains the set of possible TMV combi- nations that our tool extracts for English.</p><p>French. The rules for French are defined on the basis of the reduction of the verbs to their mor- phological features. The morphological features of the verbs are derived from the morphologi- cal analysis of the verbs, as well as their POS- tags. The rules specify TMV values for each of the possible sequences of the morphological fea- tures. For example, the VC "sera examinée" is mapped to the morphological feature combination V-indfut-V-partpast which, according to our rule set, leads to the TMV futureI/indicative/passive. In some cases, the lexical information is used to decide between ambiguous configurations. For ex- ample, some perfect/active forms are ambiguous with present/passive forms. For instance, "Jean est parti" and "Jean est menacé" are both composed of the verb "est" + past participle, but they have dif- ferent meaning: "Jean has left" vs. "Jean is threat- ened." Information about the finite verb helps to   distinguish between the two constructions. <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">Table  2</ref> shows the French TMV combinations.</p><p>German. The rules are based on POS tags, mor- phological analysis of the finite verbs and the lem- mas of the verbs. We group the rules by the num- ber of tokens contained in the VC, as we have ob- served that each combination of TMV features re- quires a particular number of tokens in the VC. For each length, we specify which tense and mood of the finite verb lead to a specific TMV. Similarly to French, in some contexts, we need to use lexical information to decide on TMV.</p><p>Take for example the VC "seien beantwortet worden" from <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref>. Its POS sequence is VAFIN-VVPP-VAPP, so we use rules defined for the POS length of 3. We first check the mood of the finite verb "seien" which is subj (subjunc- tive). The combination of subj with the morpho- logical tense of the finite verb pres leads to the mood value konjunktivI and the tense value past. As the verb werden, which is used for passive con- structions in German, occurs in the VC, we derive the voice value passive. Thus, the resulting anno- tation is past/konjunktivI/passive. <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">Table 3</ref> shows TMV value combinations for German.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3">Extraction of voice</head><p>In all three languages, it is difficult to distin- guish between stative passive and tenses in the active voice. For instance, the German VCs "ist geschrieben (is written)" and "ist gegangen (has gone)" are both built with the auxiliary sein and a past participle. The combination of POS tags is same for both cases, and the morphological fea- tures of the finite verb (pres/ind) correspond to the German perfect tense in active voice. This, how- ever, holds only for verbs of movement and a few other verbs. Verbs such as "schreiben (to write)" are in this specific context present/passive (sta- tive passive in present tense) and not perfect/active which is the case for the VC "ist gegangen".</p><p>To disambiguate between these constructions, we use a semi-automatically crafted list of the German and French verbs that form per- fect/active with the auxiliary sein/ˆ etre (be) instead of haben/avoir (have), which is used for the ma- jority of the verbs. We extract these lists from dif- ferent corpora by counting how often verbs occur with sein/haben andêtreandˆandêtre/avoir, respectively. We manually validate the resulting verb lists.</p><p>When a VC with a POS sequence that is am- biguous in the above explained way is detected, we check whether the main verb is in the list of "sein/ˆ etre" verbs. If that is the case, the corre- sponding active tense is annotated. Otherwise, the VC is assigned the corresponding passive tense.</p><p>In the case of English, the disambiguation is somewhat easier. To differentiate between "is written" and "has written," we use information about the finite verb within the VC. In the case where we have be, we assume to have passive voice in combination with an appropriate tense. In case of have, the voice is active.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Annotation tool</head><p>The tool is implemented in Python. It takes as in- put the parsed text file in the CoNLL format. For the rule development, as well as evaluation, we used the Mate parser <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Bohnet and Nivre, 2012)</ref>, which can be applied on all of the three languages addressed here. For German and French, we use the joint model for parsing, tagging and morpho- logical analysis including lemmatization. For En- glish, only tagging and parsing is required. In gen- eral, the TMV annotation tool is applicable on the output of arbitrary parsers as long as their models use the same POS-and dependency tags as Mate.</p><p>The tool outputs a TSV file with TMV annota- tions. An example output is shown in <ref type="table">Table 4</ref>. The columns are specified as follows: sentence num- ber, indices of the elements of a VC separated by a comma, elements of a VC separated by a comma, finite, main verb (if more than one, separated by a comma), tense, mood, voice, progressive (only for English), coordination and negation. The German TSV output has an additional column with bound- aries of a clause in which a VC is placed. <ref type="bibr">5</ref> We ad- ditionally provide a script for the conversion of the annotations into HTML format which allows for quick and easy examination of the annotations.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Evaluation</head><p>We manually evaluate annotations for 157 German VCs, 151 English Vcs and 137 French VCs ex- tracted from a set of randomly chosen sentences from Europarl ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Koehn, 2005)</ref>. The results are shown in  For French, the overall acurracy is 75%, while the accuracy of German and English annotations is 76%. Based on the manually annotated sam- ple, we estimate that 23/59/85% (for EN/DE/FR) of the erroneous annotations are due to parsing errors. For instance, in the case of English, the VC extraction process sometimes adds gerunds to the VC and interprets them as a present participle. Similarly, for French, a past participle is added, which erroneously causes the voice assignment to be passive. Contrary to German and English, French has higher mood accuracy, since mood is largely encoded unambiguously in the verb mor- phology. For German, false or missing morpho- logical annotation of the finite verbs causes some errors, and there are cases not covered by our rules for identifying stative passive.</p><p>Our rule sets have been developed based on ex- tensive data analysis. This evaluation presents a sent verb main num id <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">(s)  VC  verb  fin  tense  mood  voice  neg coord  1 6,7  has climbed  climbed yes presPerf indicative active no  no  2 4,5</ref> has crossed crossed yes presPerf indicative active no no 2 13,14 can 't increase increase yes present indicative active yes no <ref type="table">Table 4</ref>: TSV output of the annotation tool for two English sentences: "Since then, the index has climbed above 10,000. Now that gold has crossed the magic $1,000 barrier, why can't it increase ten-fold, too?" snapshot of the tool's performance. The findings of this analysis will lead to improvement of the rules' precision in future development iterations.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Conclusion</head><p>We have presented an automatic tool which an- notates English, French and German verbal com- plexes with tense, mood and voice. Our tool com- pensates for the lack of annotated data on this sub- ject. It allows for large-scale studies of verbal tenses and their use within and across the three languages. This includes for instance typological studies of the temporal interpretation of tenses, or discourse studies interested in the referential prop- erties of tense. Large-scale annotated data with reliable accuracy also creates the possibility to train classifiers, machine translation systems and other NLP tools. The same approach for extracting tense, aspect and mood could also be implemented for other languages.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: Example for TMV extraction.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3" validated="true"><head>Table 2 : TMV Combinations for French.</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>finite mood 
tense 
voice 
example (active voice) 

ind 

present 
(ich) arbeite 
perfect 
(ich) habe gearbeitet 
imperfect 
(ich) arbeitete 
pluperfect act 
(ich) hatte gearbeitet 
yes 
futureI 
pass 
(ich) werde arbeiten 
futureII 
(ich) werde gearbeitet haben 

konjI 
present 
(er) arbeite/arbeitete 
past 
(er) habe/hätte gearbeitet 
konjII futureI+II 
(er) würde arbeiten / gear-
beitet haben 
no 
-
-
-
zu arbeiten 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4" validated="false"><head>Table 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>TMV combinations for German.</figDesc><table></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_5" validated="true"><head>Table 5 .</head><label>5</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Language tense mood voice 
all 

EN 
81.5 
88.1 
86.1 76.8 
DE 
80.8 
84.0 
81.5 76.4 
FR 
86.1 
93.4 
82.5 75.2 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_6" validated="false"><head>Table 5 :</head><label>5</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Accuracy of TMV features according to 
manual evaluation. 

</table></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> http://www.sfs.uni-tuebingen.de/ascl/ ressourcen/corpora/tueba-dz.html 2 https://github.com/aniramm/ tmv-annotator</note>

			<note place="foot" n="3"> https://clarin09.ims.uni-stuttgart. de/tmv/</note>

			<note place="foot" n="4"> In this work, we use the Mate parser for all three languages. https://code.google.com/archive/p/ mate-tools/wikis/ParserAndModels.wiki.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="5"> The clause boundary identification is based on the sentence punctuation (e.g. comma, colon, semicolon, hyphen, etc). For more sophisticated clause boundary identification for German, please refer to (Sidarenka et al., 2015).</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgment</head><p>This work has received funding from the DFG grant Models of Morphosyntax for Statistical Ma-chine Translation (Phase 2), the European Union's Horizon 2020 research and innovation programme under grant agreement No. 644402 (HimL), and from the European Research Council (ERC) under grant agreement No. 640550.</p><p>We thank André Blessing for developing the demo version of the tool.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A transitionbased system for joint part-of-speech tagging and labeled non-projective dependency parsing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bernd</forename><surname>Bohnet</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Joakim</forename><surname>Nivre</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2012 Joint Conference on EMNLP</title>
		<meeting>the 2012 Joint Conference on EMNLP<address><addrLine>Jeju Island, Korea</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Aspectual type and temporal relation classification</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Francisco</forename><surname>Costa</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">António</forename><surname>Branco</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 13th Conference of the EACL. Avignon</title>
		<meeting>the 13th Conference of the EACL. Avignon<address><addrLine>France</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The Oxford Handbook of Tense and Aspect</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ashwini</forename><surname>Deo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<editor>Robert I. Binnick</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<publisher>OUP</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Morphology</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Automatic recognition of habituals: a three-way classification of clausal aspect</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Annemarie</forename><surname>Friedrich</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Manfred</forename><surname>Pinkal</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2015 Conference on EMNLP</title>
		<meeting>the 2015 Conference on EMNLP<address><addrLine>Lisbon, Portugal</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Europarl: A parallel corpus for statistical machine translation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Philipp</forename><surname>Koehn</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Conference Proceedings: the tenth Machine Translation Summit</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Phuket, Thailand</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">English-French verb phrase alignment in Europarl for tense translation modeling</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sharid</forename><surname>Loáiciga</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Thomas</forename><surname>Meyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Andrei</forename><surname>Popescubelis</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 9th International Conference on LREC</title>
		<meeting>the 9th International Conference on LREC<address><addrLine>Reykjavik, Iceland</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Proposition Bank: An Annotated Corpus of Semantic Roles</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Martha</forename><surname>Palmer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Daniel</forename><surname>Gildea</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Paul</forename><surname>Kingsbury</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Computational Linguistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">31</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="71" to="106" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Modeling verbal inflection for English to German SMT</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Anita</forename><surname>Ramm</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alexander</forename><surname>Fraser</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the the First Conference on Machine Translation (WMT)</title>
		<meeting>the the First Conference on Machine Translation (WMT)<address><addrLine>Berlin, Germany</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Tense sense disambiguation: a new syntactic polysemy task</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Roi</forename><surname>Reichart</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ari</forename><surname>Rappoport</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2010 Conference on EMNLP</title>
		<meeting>the 2010 Conference on EMNLP<address><addrLine>Massachusetts, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Translation-based corpus studies Contrasting English and Portuguese tense and aspect systems</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Diana</forename><surname>Santos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
			<pubPlace>Rodopi</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A compact but linguistically detailed database for german verb subcategorisation relying on dependency parses from a web corpus: Tool, guidelines and resource</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Silke</forename><surname>Scheible</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sabine</forename><surname>Schulte Im Walde</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marion</forename><surname>Weller</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Max</forename><surname>Kisselew</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the WAC-8</title>
		<meeting>the WAC-8<address><addrLine>Lancaster, UK</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Discourse segmentation of German texts</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Uladzimir</forename><surname>Sidarenka</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Andreas</forename><surname>Peldszus</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Manfred</forename><surname>Stede</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal for Language Technology and Computational Linguistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">30</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="71" to="98" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">SemEval-2013 Task 1: TempEvalEvents, and Temporal Relations</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Naushad</forename><surname>Uzzaman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hector</forename><surname>Llorens</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Leon</forename><surname>Derczynski</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">James</forename><surname>Allen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marc</forename><surname>Verhagen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">James</forename><surname>Pustejovsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the SemEval</title>
		<meeting>the SemEval<address><addrLine>Atlanta, Georgia</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
