<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T10:38+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Extended Named Entity Recognition API and Its Applications in Language Education</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
				<availability status="unknown"><p>Copyright Association for Computational Linguistics</p>
				</availability>
				<date>July 30-August 4, 2017. July 30-August 4, 2017</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tuan</forename><forename type="middle">Duc</forename><surname>Nguyen</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Khai</forename><surname>Mai</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Thai-Hoang</forename><surname>Pham</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Minh</forename><forename type="middle">Trung</forename><surname>Nguyen</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Truc-Vien T.</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Nguyen</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Takashi</forename><surname>Eguchi</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ryohei</forename><surname>Sasano</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Satoshi</forename><surname>Sekine</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Extended Named Entity Recognition API and Its Applications in Language Education</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of ACL 2017, System Demonstrations</title>
						<meeting>ACL 2017, System Demonstrations <address><addrLine>Vancouver, Canada; Vancouver, Canada</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="37" to="42"/>
							<date type="published">July 30-August 4, 2017. July 30-August 4, 2017</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="DOI">10.18653/v1/p17-4007</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>We present an Extended Named Entity Recognition API to recognize various types of entities and classify the entities into 200 different categories. Each entity is classified into a hierarchy of entity categories , in which the categories near the root are more general than the categories near the leaves of the hierarchy. This category information can be used in various applications such as language educational applications, online news services and recommendation engines. We show an application of the API in a Japanese online news service for Japanese language learners .</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Named entity recognition (NER) is one of the most fundamental tasks in Information Retrieval, Information Extraction and Question Answer- ing ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Bellot et al., 2002;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Nadeau and Sekine, 2007)</ref>. A high quality named entity recognition API (Ap- plication Programming Interface) is therefore im- portant for higher level tasks such as entity re- trieval, recommendation and automatic dialogue generation. To extend the ability of named en- tity recognition, <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Sekine et al. (Sekine et al., 2002;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Sekine and Nobata, 2004</ref>) have proposed an Ex- tended Named Entity (ENE) hierarchy, which re- fines the definition of named entity. The ENE hi- erarchy is a three-level hierarchy, which contains more than ten coarse-grained categories at the top level and 200 fine-grained categories at the leaf level.</p><p>The top level of the hierarchy includes tradi- tional named entity categories, such as Person, Lo- cation or Organization. The middle level and leaf level refine the top level categories to more fine-   <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 1</ref> shows a partial hi- erarchy for the top level category Organization. In Extended Named Entity recognition (ENER) problem, given an input sentence, such as "Donald Trump was officially nominated by the Republican Party", the system must recognize and classify the ENEs in the sentence, such as "Donald Trump" as Person and "Republican Party" as Political Party.</p><p>In this paper, we present the architecture de- sign and implementation of an ENER API for Japanese. We named this API as "AL+ ENER API". The proposed architecture works well with a large number of training data samples and re- sponses fast enough to use in practical applica- tions. To illustrate the effectiveness of the AL+ ENER API, we describe an application of the API for automatic extraction of glossaries in a Japanese online news service for Japanese language learn- ers. Feedbacks from the users show that the pre- sented ENER API gives high precision on the glossary creation task.</p><p>The rest of this paper is organized as follows. Section 2 describes the design and implementa- tion of the ENER API. Experiment results are pre- sented in Section 3 to evaluate the performance of the API. Section 4 describes an application of the ENER API into an online news service for Japanese learners, the method to get user feed- backs from this service to improve the ENER sys- tem, and the statistics obtained from the user feed-backs. Section 5 reviews related systems and com- pares with the presented system. Finally, Section 6 concludes the paper.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Extended Named Entity Recognition API</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">Overview of the AL+ ENER API</head><p>The AL+ ENER API is an API for Extended Named Entity recognition, which takes an input sentence and outputs a JSON containing a list of ENEs in the sentence, as shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 2</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>AL+ ENER API</head><p>Obama is the 44th president of the United States Input Output [ { "surface" : "Obama", "entity" : "PERSON", "start" : 0, "length" : 5}, { "surface" : "44th", "entity" : "ORDINAL_NUMBER", …}, { "surface" : "president", "entity" : "POSITION_VOCATION", …}, { "surface" : "United States", "entity" : "COUNTRY", … } ] Different from traditional NER APIs, this ENER API is capable of tagging 200 categories 1 , including some entities that are actually not named entities (therefore, they are called "extended" named entities, as described in <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Sekine and Nobata, 2004)</ref>). In <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 2</ref>, "president" is not a traditional named entity, but it is tagged as POSITION VOCATION, which is a category in the ENE hierarchy. For each entity, we output its surface (e.g., "president"), its ENE tag ("PO- SITION VOCATION"), its index in the input sen- tence (the "start" field in the JSON) and its length. A developer who uses the ENER API can utilize the start and length information to calculate the exact position of the entity in the input sentence. The ENE tag can then be used in various sub- sequent tasks such as Relation Extraction (RE), Question Answering (QA) or automatic dialogue generation. The AL+ ENER API is freely accessi- ble online. <ref type="bibr">2</ref> Currently, the API supports Japanese only, but we are also developing an API for En- glish ENER. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Figure 3</ref> shows an example input sen- tence and output ENE tags. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">Extended Named Entity recognition algorithms</head><p>Existing NER systems often use Conditinal Ran- dom Fields (CRFs) <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(McCallum and Li, 2003;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Finkel et al., 2005</ref>), HMM (Zhou and Su, 2002) or SVM ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Yamada et al., 2002;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Takeuchi and Collier, 2002;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Sasano and Kurohashi, 2008)</ref> to assign tags to the tokens in an input sentence. However, these methods are supposed to work with only small number of categories (e.g., 10 categories).</p><p>In the ENER problem, the number of categories is 200, which is very large, compared with the num- ber in traditional NER. Consequently, traditional approaches might not achieve good performance and even be infeasible. Actually, we have tried to use CRF for 200 classes, but the training process took too long time and did not finish.</p><p>In this system, we use a combination approach to recognize ENEs. We first implement four base algorithms, namely, CRF-SVM hierarchi- cal ENER, RNN-based ENER, Wikification-based ENER and Rule-based ENER. We then combine these algorithms by a selection method, as shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">Figure 4</ref>.  In the Rule-based method, we extend the rule- based method in ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Sekine and Nobata, 2004</ref>) (by adding new rules for the new categories that are not recognized in their work) and we also use a dictionary containing 1.6 million Wikipedia enti- ties. In the 1.6 million entities in the dictionary, only 70 thousands entities are assigned ENE tags by human, the rest are assigned by an existing Wikipedia ENE labeling algorithm ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Suzuki et al., 2016)</ref>, which gives a score for each (entity, ENE category) pair. For the entities that are assigned automatically, we only take the entities with high scores to ensure that the algorithm assigns correct labels. If the rules fail to extract some entities, we extract all noun-phrases and lookup in the dictio- nary to check if they can be ENEs or not.</p><p>We use a training dataset which contains ENE- tagged sentences to train a CRF model to tag input sentences with the top-level ENE categories (in the training dataset, we get the correct labels for these ENEs from the parent or grandparent category in the ENE hierarchy). As illustrated in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 1</ref>, at the top level, we only have 11 ENE categories that we need to recognize by CRF-SVM (other cate- gories such as Date, Time, Number can be rec- ognized by rules), thus using a CRF model here would achieve comparable performance with ex- isting NER systems. After tagging the sentences with the top-level ENE categories, we can con- vert the ENER problem into a simple classification problem (not a sequence labeling problem any- more), thus we can use SVM to classify the ex- tracted ENEs at the top level into leaf-level cate- gories. Therefore, we have a CRF model to tag the input sentences with top-level categories, and sev- eral SVM models (each for a top-level category) to classify the ENEs into the leaf-level ENE cate- gories. The features that we use in CRF and SVM are bag-of-words, POS-tag, the number of digits in the word, the Brown cluster of the current word, the appearance of the word as a substring of a word in the Wikipedia ENE dictionary, the orthography features (the word is written in Kanji, Hiragana, Katakana or Romaji), whether the word is capi- talized, and the last 2-3 characters. Because the number of leaf-level categories in each top-level category is also not too large (e.g., less than 15), SVM can achieve a reasonable performance at this step.</p><p>We also train an LSTM (Long-Short Term Memory network), a kind of RNN (Recurrent Neural Network) to recognize ENEs. We use LSTM because it is appropriate for sequence la- beling problems. The inputs of the LSTM are the word embedding of the current word and the POS- tag of the current word. The POS-tags are auto- matically generated using JUMAN 3 , a Japanese morphological analyzer. The word embedding is obtained by training a word2vec model with <ref type="bibr">3</ref> http://nlp.ist.i.kyoto-u.ac.jp/EN/?JUMAN Japanese Wikipedia text. We hope that LSTM can memorize the patterns in the training data and in- terpolate to the CRF-SVM method in many cases.</p><p>To cope with free-text ENEs, we use Wikifi- cation approach. Free-text ENEs refer to the en- tities that can be of any text, such as a movie name or a song name (e.g., "What is your name" is a famous movie name in Japanese). If these names are famous, they often become the titles of some Wikipedia articles. Consequently, using Wikification-based approach could work well with these types of entities.</p><p>We also create an algorithm selection model by evaluating the F-scores of the four base algorithms (Rule, CRF-SVM, RNN and Wikification) with a development dataset (which is different from the test set). In the final phase, after having all la- bels from the four base algorithms for each entity, we select the label of the algorithm with the high- est F-score in the development set. Note that we use the best selection scheme at entity level, not at sentence level. This is because each base algo- rithm tends to achieve high performance on some specific categories, so if we select the best algo- rithm for each entity, we will achieve higher per- formance for the entire sentence.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Evaluation</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Data set</head><p>We hired seven annotators to create an ENE tagged dataset. Specifically, for each ENE category, the annotators created 100 Japanese sentences, each sentence includes at least one entity in the cor- responding category. The annotators then manu- ally tagged the sentences with ENE tags. After filtering out erroneous sentences (sentences with invalid tag format), we obtain totally 19,363 well- formed sentences. We divided the dataset into three subsets: the training set (70% of the total number of sentences), development set (15%) and test set (15%). <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Performance of the ENER API</head><p>We use the test set to evaluate the precision, re- call and F-score of the ENER API.  For categories with free text names (e.g, printing names) or very short name (e.g., AK-47, a type of weapon) the system can not predict the ENE very well because these names might appear in various contexts. We might prioritize Wikification method in these cases to improve the performance. On av- erage, we achieve an F1-score of 71.95%, which is a reasonable result for 200 categories.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3">Response time of the API</head><p>As ENER is often used by subsequent NLP tasks, the response speed of the ENER API must be fast enough for the subsequent tasks to achieve a high speed. Consequently, we executed the ENER API with the test dataset (containing 2869 sentences) and evaluated the response time of the API. The average response time of a sentence (a query) is 195 ms (0.195 second). This response speed is fast enough for various tasks such as generating answer for an intelligent chatbot or a search en- gine session. <ref type="figure">Figure 5</ref> shows the relation between the response time and the length of the input sen- tence (calculated by the number of tokens, each token is a word produced by the morphological an- alyzer). When the input sentence length increases, the response time increases nearly linearly (except when the sentence is too long, as we have a small number of such sentences so the variance is large). The typical sentence length in Japanese is from 10 to 20 tokens so the speed of the ENER is fast in most cases. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Application of the ENER API</head><p>In this section, we present a real-world application of the AL+ ENER API: glossary linking in an on- line news service.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">Mazii: an online news service for Japanese learners</head><p>The Mazii News service 4 is an online news ser- vice for Japanese learners. For each sentence in a news article, Mazii automatically analyzes it and creates a link for each word that it recognizes as an ENE or an entry in its dictionary. This will help Japanese learners to quickly reference to the words/entities when they do not understand the meaning of the words/entities. To recognize ENEs in a news article, Mazii inputs each sentence of the article into the AL+ ENER API (sentence bound- ary detection in Japanese is very simple because Japanese language has a special symbol for sen- tence boundary mark). Because the AL+ ENER API also returns the position (and the length) of the ENEs, Mazii can easily create a link to under- line the ENEs in the sentence. When a user clicks on a link, Mazii will open a popup window to pro- vide details information concerning the entity: the ENE category (with parent categories) of the en- tity, the definition of the entity (if any). <ref type="figure" target="#fig_7">Figure 6</ref> shows a screenshot of the Mazii ENE linking re- sults. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">Collecting user feedbacks</head><p>Mazii has more than 4 thousands daily active users and many users click on the linked ENEs. This provides us a big chance to obtain user feedbacks about the prediction results of the AL+ ENER API. We have implemented two interfaces to col- lect user feedbacks, as shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_7">Figure 6</ref>   In <ref type="figure" target="#fig_7">Figure 6</ref>, when a user clicks on an entity, we display the ENE hierarchy of the entity in a popup window. We also display two radio buttons: Cor- rect and Incorrect to let the user give us feed- backs. If the user chooses Incorrect then we also ask the user the correct category of the entity.</p><p>Using the method in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_7">Figure 6</ref>, we can only col- lect feedbacks when the users click on the enti- ties. However, the number of clicks is often much smaller than the number of views. To increase the user feedbacks, we invented a playcard game for language learners, as shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_9">Figure 7</ref>. When a user views an article, we show a frame with a ques- tion asking about the correct category of an ENE in the article (we also provide the sentence which includes the ENE to gather the context for the CRF-SVM and RNN models). If the user reacts to this frame (by pressing Correct/Incorrect button), we store the feedback and move to the next ENE in our database. This involves the user in a language learning game and helps he/she to study many new words as well as grammatical constructs.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3">User feedback statistics</head><p>In this section, we show some statistics that we derived from the user feedback log of the Mazii News service. We collected the user feedback log (including the view, click and correct log) in 3 months (from <ref type="bibr">Dec 2016</ref><ref type="bibr">to Feb 2017</ref>   <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">Table 3</ref> shows the experiment results. The correct ratio (%Correct) is 88.96% on 96 cate- gories with more than 100 views and have at least one user feedback. The table also shows the detailed numbers for some categories, sorted by number of views. The average click-through- rate (CTR=Click/View) is 8.7%, which is very high compared to the average CTR of display ads (about 0.4%) ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Zhang et al., 2014</ref>). This proves that the users are interested in the linked ENEs. More- over, the percentage of correct times shows that the ENER API is good enough to provide useful information to the users.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Related Work</head><p>The ENE hierarchy that we recognize in this pa- per is proposed in ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Sekine et al., 2002</ref>). ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Sekine and Nobata, 2004</ref>) proposed a Japanese rule-based ENER with a precision of 72% and recall of 80%. The performance of the rule-based ENER is good if the ENEs containing in the text are included in the dictionary or the rules can capture the patterns in which the ENEs appeared. However, ENEs of- ten evolve with time, new ENEs are frequently added and their meaning might be changed. Con- sequently, rule-based systems might not work well after a several years. In the presented system, we re-use the rules and dictionary in ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Sekine and Nobata, 2004</ref>) but we also add machine learning models to capture the evolution of the ENEs. The proposed model can be retrained at anytime if we have new training data. <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Iwakura et al. (Iwakura et al., 2011</ref>) proposed an ENER based on de- composition/concatenation of word chunks. They evaluated the system with 191 ENE categories and achieved an F-score of 81%. However, in their evaluation, they did not evaluate directly on input sentences, but only on correct chunks. Moreover, they did not deal with word boundaries as stated in their paper. Therefore, we cannot compare our results with theirs.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Conclusion</head><p>We presented an API for recognition of Extended Named Entities (ENEs). The API takes a sentence as input and outputs a JSON containing a list of ENEs with their categories. The API can recog- nize named entities at deep level with high accu- racy in a timely manner, and has been applied in real-life applications. We described an applica- tion of the ENER API to a Japanese online news service. The experimental results showed that the API achieves good performance and is fast enough for practical applications.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: Extended Named Entity hierarchy</figDesc><graphic url="image-1.png" coords="1,308.96,224.22,214.34,85.99" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2: AL+ ENE Recognition API</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>Figure 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Figure 3: An example input sentence and output ENE tags. Translated sentence with tags: "I caught 3/N Animal cicadas/Insect at Meiji Shrine/Worship Place".</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><head>Figure 4 :</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Figure 4: Overview of the proposed ENER algorithm</figDesc><graphic url="image-5.png" coords="2,309.01,526.48,214.80,69.43" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_6"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 5: Relation between input sentence length and response time of the API</figDesc><graphic url="image-6.png" coords="4,311.43,182.09,209.95,133.28" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_7"><head>Figure 6 :</head><label>6</label><figDesc>Figure 6: Mazii entity linking with AL+ ENER API, the underlined entities are linked. When a user clicks on a link (as shown in the Figure, a mention to a city in Japan is clicked), a popup window will open and show the ENE category hierarchy of the corresponding ENE.</figDesc><graphic url="image-7.png" coords="5,72.42,101.97,168.38,150.37" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_9"><head>Figure 7 :</head><label>7</label><figDesc>Figure 7: Collecting ENE user feedback from Mazii with playcard game</figDesc><graphic url="image-9.png" coords="5,114.91,492.71,132.45,90.41" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" validated="false"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>shows some statistics of the dataset.</figDesc><table>Dataset No. sentences No. tokens No. entities 
Train 
13,625 
266,454 
37,062 
Dev 
2,869 
58,529 
7,673 
Test 
2,869 
55,999 
7,711 

Table 1: Statistics of the datasets </table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" validated="true"><head>Table 2 shows</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Category 
Precision 
Recall F-score 
(%) 
(%) 
(%) 
Cabinet 
100.00 100.00 
100.00 
Intensity 
100.00 100.00 
100.00 
URL 
100.00 100.00 
100.00 
Phone Number 
100.00 
95.25 
97.56 
Email 
100.00 
93.33 
96.55 
Volume 
100.00 
93.10 
96.43 
... 
... 
... 
... 
Aircraft 
80.95 
65.38 
72.34 
Company Group 
68.42 
76.47 
72.22 
Continental Region 
74.29 
69.33 
71.72 
... 
... 
... 
... 
Printing Other 
50.00 
11.76 
19.05 
Name Other 
23.08 
15.00 
18.18 
Weapon 
9.09 
4.17 
5.71 
Average 
73.47 
70.50 
71.95 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" validated="false"><head>Table 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Precision, Recall, F-score of the ENER 
API on the test dataset 

the Precision, Recall and F-score of the ENER 
API on some specific categories as well as the 
average evaluation results of the entire 200 cate-
gories (in the last row). We achieved very high 
performance on the categories with small number 
of known entities (such as Cabinet) or the cate-
gories that the rules can capture almost all enti-
ties (such as Intensity, Volume, URL, and Email). 
</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3" validated="false"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>). We then count the number of views, clicks and number of feedbacks (number of times the Correct/Incorrect button is pressed) and number of Correct times for each ENE categories. We calculate the correct ra- tio (%Correct) by the number of corrects divided by number of feedbacks (Correct/Feedback).</figDesc><table>Category 
View Click Feedback %Correct 
Date 
360,625 7,100 
1,421 
95.50 
N Person 
139,191 1,934 
523 
98.47 
Province 
109,974 9,880 
439 
94.76 
... 
... 
... 
... 
... 
Animal Part 
6,514 
637 
8 
100.00 
Broadcast 
Program 
6,121 1,003 
21 
47.62 

Clothing 
4,079 
632 
14 
85.71 
... 
... 
... 
... 
... 
Fish 
656 
474 
2 
100.00 
Fungus 
615 
106 
1 
0.00 
Religion 
614 
227 
4 
100.00 
Total 
1,582,081 138,404 
5,198 
88.96 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4" validated="false"><head>Table 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Number views, clicks, feedbacks and 
percentage of correct times from the Mazii feed-
back log 

</table></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> The list of categories is here: http://nlp.cs.nyu.edu/ene/ 2 http://enerdev.alt.ai:8030/#!/Chatbot/</note>

			<note place="foot" n="4"> http://en.mazii.net/#/news</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>We would like to thank Yoshikazu Nishimura, Hideyuki Shibuki, Dr. Phuong Le-Hong and Maya Ando for their precious comments and suggestions on this work.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Coupling Named Entity Recognition, Vector-Space Model and Knowledge Bases for TREC 11 Question Answering Track</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Patrice</forename><surname>Bellot</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Eric</forename><surname>Crestan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marc</forename><surname>El-B` Eze</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Laurent</forename><surname>Gillard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Claude</forename><surname>De Loupy</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of TREC</title>
		<meeting>of TREC</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Incorporating Non-local Information into Information Extraction Systems by Gibbs Sampling</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jenny</forename><forename type="middle">Rose</forename><surname>Finkel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Trond</forename><surname>Grenager</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christopher</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Manning</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of ACL 2005</title>
		<meeting>of ACL 2005</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="363" to="370" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A Named Entity Recognition Method based on Decomposition and Concatenation of Word Chunks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tomoya</forename><surname>Iwakura</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hiroya</forename><surname>Takamura</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Manabu</forename><surname>Okumura</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of IJCNLP 2011</title>
		<meeting>of IJCNLP 2011</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="828" to="836" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Early Results for Named Entity Recognition with Conditional Random Fields, Feature Induction and Web-Enhanced Lexicons</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Andrew</forename><surname>Mccallum</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wei</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of CoNLL</title>
		<meeting>of CoNLL</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="188" to="191" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">A Survey of Named Entity Recognition and Classification. Linguisticae Investigationes</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Nadeau</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Satoshi</forename><surname>Sekine</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">30</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3" to="26" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Japanese Named Entity Recognition Using Structural Natural Language Processing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ryohei</forename><surname>Sasano</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sadao</forename><surname>Kurohashi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of IJCNLP</title>
		<meeting>of IJCNLP</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="607" to="612" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Definition, Dictionaries and Tagger for Extended Named Entity Hierarchy</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Satoshi</forename><surname>Sekine</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chikashi</forename><surname>Nobata</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of LREC</title>
		<meeting>of LREC</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1977" to="1980" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Extended Named Entity Hierarchy</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Satoshi</forename><surname>Sekine</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kiyoshi</forename><surname>Sudo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chikashi</forename><surname>Nobata</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of LREC 2002</title>
		<meeting>of LREC 2002</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1818" to="1824" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Fine-Grained Named Entity Classification with Wikipedia Article Vectors</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Masatoshi</forename><surname>Suzuki</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Koji</forename><surname>Matsuda</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Satoshi</forename><surname>Sekine</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Naoaki</forename><surname>Okazaki</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kentaro</forename><surname>Inui</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of Int&apos;l Conf. on Web Intelligence</title>
		<meeting>of Int&apos;l Conf. on Web Intelligence<address><addrLine>WI</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="483" to="486" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Use of Support Vector Machines in Extended Named Entity Recognition</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Koichi</forename><surname>Takeuchi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nigel</forename><surname>Collier</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of CoNLL</title>
		<meeting>of CoNLL</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Japanese Named Entity Extraction Using Support Vector Machine</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hiroyasu</forename><surname>Yamada</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Taku</forename><surname>Kudo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yuji</forename><surname>Matsumoto</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Transactions of Information Processing Society of Japan</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">43</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="44" to="53" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Optimal Real-Time Bidding for Display Advertising</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Weinan</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Shuai</forename><surname>Yuan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jun</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of KDD</title>
		<meeting>of KDD</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1077" to="1086" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Named Entity Recognition Using an HMM-Based Chunk Tagger</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Guodong</forename><surname>Zhou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jian</forename><surname>Su</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of ACL 2002</title>
		<meeting>of ACL 2002</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="473" to="480" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
