<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T11:46+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">List-only Entity Linking</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
				<availability status="unknown"><p>Copyright Association for Computational Linguistics</p>
				</availability>
				<date>July 30-August 4, 2017. July 30-August 4, 2017</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ying</forename><surname>Lin</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chin-Yew</forename><surname>Lin</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Heng</forename><surname>Ji</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">List-only Entity Linking</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 55th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (Volume 2: Short Papers)</title>
						<meeting>the 55th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (Volume 2: Short Papers) <address><addrLine>Vancouver, Canada; Vancouver, Canada</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="536" to="541"/>
							<date type="published">July 30-August 4, 2017. July 30-August 4, 2017</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="DOI">10.18653/v1/p17-2085</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Traditional Entity Linking (EL) technologies rely on rich structures and properties in the target knowledge base (KB). However, in many applications, the KB may be as simple and sparse as lists of names of the same type (e.g., lists of products). We call it as List-only Entity Linking problem. Fortunately, some mentions may have more cues for linking, which can be used as seed mentions to bridge other mentions and the uninformative entities. In this work, we select the most linkable mentions as seed mentions and disambiguate other mentions by comparing them with the seed mentions rather than directly with the entities. Our experiments on linking mentions to seven automatically mined lists show promising results and demonstrate the effectiveness of our approach. 1</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Traditional Entity Linking (EL) methods usually rely on rich structures and properties in the tar- get knowledge base (KB). These methods may not be effective in applications where detailed descrip- tions and properties of target entities are absent in the KB. Consider the following situations:</p><p>Disaster Response and Recovery. When a disaster strikes, people rush to the web and post tweets about the damage and casualties. Perform- ing EL to extract key information, such as devas- tated towns and donor agencies, can help us mon- itor the situation and coordinate rescue and recov- ery efforts. Although many involved entities are * Part of this work was done when the first author was on an internship at Microsoft Research Asia. <ref type="bibr">1</ref> The data set is available at: http://nlp.cs.rpi.edu/data/ link-only-entity-linking.html not well-known and usually absent in general KBs, we may be able to acquire lists of these entities from the local government as the target KB.</p><p>Voice of the Customer. EL also plays an important role in mining customer opinions from data generated on social platforms and e- commerce websites, thereby helping companies better understand the needs and expectations of their customers. However, the target products are often not covered by general KBs. For example, <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Cao et al., 2015</ref>) tested 32 names of General Mo- tors car models and only found 4 in Wikipedia. Although some companies may choose to main- tain a comprehensive product KB, it will be much more practical and less costly to provide only lists of product names. Under such circumstances, we need the ability to perform EL to ad-hoc name lists instead of a comprehensive KB, namely List-only Entity Link- ing. Take <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref> as an example. For a human reader, it is not difficult to figure out the referent entities of mentions in each document based on clues such as "basketball" and "LDA", whereas we will not be able to make such inference without the knowledge of the target entities. However, even if we lack the minimal knowledge (e.g., Jordan is a country), we are more confident to link mentions in d 1 , d 4 , and d 5 because they co-occur with other entities in the same list. We consider such men- tions that we are confident to link as seed men- tions, and use them to construct contextual and non-contextual information of the target entities to enhance entity disambiguation.</p><p>Therefore, in this work, we propose to tackle the problem of List-only Entity Linking through seed mentions. We automatically identify seed men- tions for each list using a two-step method based on the occurrence of entities and similarity be- tween mentions. After that, in the entity disam- biguation phase, we utilize the selected mentions as a bridge between uninformative entities and other mentions. Specifically, we comparing fea- tures of a non-seed mention to those of seed men- tions of its entity candidates to determine which entity it should be linked to.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Problem Definition</head><p>Given a mention m and the entity e that it refers to, we call e the referent entity of m and m the referential mention of e. In <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref>, for exam- ple, Michael Jordan 1 is the referent entity of "Jordan" in document d 6 , while "Jordan" in docu- ment d 2 is an non-referential mention for Michael Jordan 1 .</p><p>As <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref> shows, in the setting of List- only Entity Linking, there are a set of manu- ally or automatically generated entity lists E = {E 1 , E 2 , ..., E l } and a set of documents D = {d 1 , d 2 , ..., d n }. Entities in the same list are ho- mogeneous and share some common properties. In our experiment, each document d i contains a mention m i to link. Our goal is to link m i to its referent entity e i,j ∈ E j or returns NIL if it is un- linkable to any entities.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Approach</head><p>Our framework has two modules, entity candi- date retrieval and entity disambiguation as <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Fig- ure 2</ref> shows. For a mention "Jordan," we retrieve two candidate entities, Michael Jordan 1 and Michael Jordan 2 , from the entity lists. Next, we select a set of seed mentions for each entity from all documents. To determine the referent en- tity of "Jordan", we compare it with seed mentions of each candidate instead of the entity itself. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Entity Candidate Retrieval</head><p>For each mention m i , we first locate a set of en- tity candidates C i = {e i,j |e i,j ∈ E j } that it pos- sibly refers to. A mention and its referent entity may have different surface forms (e.g., "BMW" and Bayerische Motoren Werke). For this rea- son, we design a set of matching rules to improve the recall as shown in <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table 1</ref>.  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Entity Disambiguation</head><p>Next, we proceed to score each candidate e i,j and determine which one m i should be linked to. However, we have no knowledge of the target enti- ties except for names and thus can't directly com- pare m i with them. Rather, we propose to bridge the gap between mentions and entities through seed mentions. We illustrate the idea in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Figure 3</ref>. University of Pennsylvania is retrieved as an entity can- didate for mentions "University of Pennsylvania", "Penn", and "Pennsylvania." We are more confi- dent to link "University of Pennsylvania" in d I and "Penn" in d II to University of Pennsylvania because other entities in the University list, such as "Harvard" and "MIT," also appear in the same document. Thus, we select mentions in d I and d II as seed mentions. From d I and d II , we can extract both contextual features (e.g., "academic" and "re- search") and non-contextual features (e.g., the en- tity type is ORG). After that, we compare mentions in other documents with the seeds. We link "Penn" in d III to University of Pennsylvania be- cause its entity type and context are consistent with the seeds. "Pennsylvania" in d IV , however, is not linked because it is recognized as a loca- tion. To capture richer contextual information and minimize the effect of noise, we select more than one seed mention using a two-step approach as fol- lows. 1. Subset Selection. We assume that if multi- ple names in the same list co-occur within a docu- ment, they are all likely to be referential mentions of this list, such as "Michael Jordan" and "LeBron James" in d 1 . Hence, to identify seed mentions of list E j , we first narrow the scope down to a subset D (n) j of documents containing more than n mentions matching names in E j . We gradually increase the n until θ − size ≤ |D</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">(n) j | ≤ θ + size . θ − size</formula><p>and θ + size are set to 50 and 300 in our experiments. 2. Clustering. We expect most mentions in the selected subset are referential of list E j , while in fact the subset is likely to contain a small number of non-referential mentions. We need to eliminate them from the subset, otherwise they will intro- duce misleading features differing from the real seed mentions, hence hurting the performance of entity disambiguation. To separate referential and non-referential mentions in the selected subset, we make two assumptions: (1) Most mentions in the subset are referential, and (2) Referential mentions should be similar to each other while dissimilar from non-referential ones. Due to the lack of an- notated data, we approach this problem by per- forming clustering, which works in an unsuper- vised fashion. Specifically, we represent features (described later in this section) of each mention as a vector and measure the distance between two mentions using cosine distance. After that, we run the K-means++ algorithm on the subset to separate referential and non-referential mentions, and pick mentions in the largest cluster as seed mentions.</p><p>To determine the referent entity of mention m i , we calculate the confidence score of linking m i to e i,j ∈ E j using the average cosine similarity between m i and seed mentions of list E j :</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">c(m i , e i,j ) = 1 |S j | |S j | p=1 sim(m i , m s ), m s ∈ S j</formula><p>where S j is the seed set of E j . Lastly, we link m i to the candidate with the highest confidence score.</p><p>In this work, we use the following features. Entity Type. The entity type of a mention can be inferred from the text and used for dis- ambiguation. For example, if most seed men- tions for the University list are recognized as ORG, while "Harvard" in the sentence "Harvard was born and raised in Southwark, Surrey, England" is tagged as PER, it is unlikely to refer to Harvard University.</p><p>Textual Context. We also assume that refer- ential mentions of the same entity should share similar local contexts. We represent textual con- text using the average embedding of words within a window around the mention.</p><p>Punctuation. Punctuations preceding or fol- lowing a mention may help resolve ambiguity. For example, "MA" preceded by a comma is possible to refer to a state, since states are usually the last component of an address, such as "Boston, MA".</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Experiments</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">Data set</head><p>In our experiment, the construction of data set consists of two steps: collecting name lists from NeedleSeek 2 ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Shi et al., 2010</ref>) and extracting doc- uments from Wikipedia. NeedleSeek is a project aiming to mine semantic concepts from tera-scale data (ClueWeb09) and classify them into a wide range of semantic categories. For example, "KFC" is mined as a concept in the restaurant category, along with key sentences and attributes, such as employee number and founder.</p><p>To obtain target name lists, we select 7 se- mantic categories (see <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">Table 2</ref>) generated by NeedleSeek as target domains, and take the top concepts in each category as target entities. We manually map each name to its pertinent Wikipedia page as a target entity (e.g., Starbucks → enwiki:Starbucks 3 ). Thus, we collect lists containing 139 target entities in total. Note that category names are only for result presentation purpose and not taken as input to our model.  Next, we derive a data set from Wikipedia articles through wikilinks 4 , which are links to pages within English Wikipedia. For example, a wikilink [[Harvard University|Harvard]] appears as "Harvard" in text and links to the page enwiki:Harvard_University. Thus, we can consider "Harvard" as a name mention and enwiki:Harvard_University as its referent en- tity. Consider the following sentences: * ... then left toattend graduate school on a scholarship at made an appearance in an episode of...</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Category Name Examples</head><p>Because enwiki:Harvard_University is in the University list, the first mention will be con- sidered as referential, whereas the second one is non-referential. We also apply matching rules in <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table 1</ref> to obtain more non-referential mentions. After that, we extract sentences around wikilinks as a document.  From <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">Table 3</ref>, we can see that referential en- tities overwhelm non-referential ones in the ex- tracted corpus. In order to evaluate our model fairly, we perform downsampling to balance refer- ential and non-referential mentions, otherwise we can achieve high scores even if we link all mention to the target entities. In the balanced data set, there are 11, 065 unique entities.  <ref type="table">Table 4</ref>: Overall performance (%). R, P, and F rep- resent recall, precision, and F1 score, respectively.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">Entity Linking Results</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Category</head><p>As <ref type="table">Table 4</ref> demonstrates, our method shows promising results (87.0 F1 score) on the balanced data set. Nevertheless, we notice the low linking precisions for entities in the Character and State lists, which are caused by different reasons. For the Character list, mentions do not suffice to select high-quality seeds, whereas for the State list, fea- tures of referential and non-referential mentions are usually similar. Consider the following sen- tence:</p><p>* She witnessed his fatal shooting when they were together in the President's Box at Ford's Theatre on Tenth Street in Washington.</p><p>The mention "Washington" refers to "Washington, D.C.", which has the same entity type, LOCATION, as our target entity "Washington (state)". In addition, we see no obvious textual clue that indicates whether it refers to the State of Washington or not. Traditional EL approaches usually disambiguate such mentions through collective inference. They link "Ford's Theatre" and "Washington" to the KB simultaneously. Since there exists an explicit relation between "Ford's Theatre" and "Washington, D.C.", these two entities receive high confidence scores and thus are determined as the referents. Unfortunately, we cannot employ the knowledge-rich approach in the List-only Entity Linking scenario.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Related Work</head><p>In this paper, we define and study the List-only Entity Linking problem based on previous stud- ies on Target Entity Disambiguation ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Wang et al., 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Cao et al., 2015</ref>). The key difference is that they target at the disambiguation of a single list of entities, whereas we focus on entity linking to an arbitrary number of lists. Another similar prob- lem is Named Entity Disambiguation with Link- less Knowledge Bases (LNED) ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Li et al., 2016)</ref>. It assumes that entities are isolated in the "linkless" KB, while each entity still has a description.</p><p>Our idea of selecting seed mentions based on co-occurrence is similar to collective inference. Most state-of-the-art EL methods utilize collec- tive inference to link a set of coherent men- tions simultaneously by selecting the most coher- ent set of entity candidates on the KB side ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Pan et al., 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Huang et al., 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Cheng and Roth, 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Cassidy et al., 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Xu et al., 2012)</ref>. In this work, without explicit relations between entities in different lists, we only take the co- occurrence of mentions in the same list into con- sideration. Therefore, our method is unable to benefit from the co-occurrence of John Lennon and Give Peace a Chance although they are ac- tually strongly connected.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Conclusions and Future Work</head><p>In this paper, we proposed a novel framework to tackle the problem of List-only Entity Linking. The core of this framework is selecting seed men- tions for each entity list to bridge the gap between mentions and non-informative target entities. Our results show this EL framework works well for this task. At present, in the seed selection step, we simply consider all co-occurring mentions of enti- ties in the same list. In the future, we will employ more precise approaches to choose co-occurring mentions and mine relations between entities in separate lists to improve seed selection and entity disambiguation.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: Link mentions to target entities in different entity lists.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2: List-only Entity Linking Framework.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Abbreviation Acronym USDOD/USDD (United States Department of Defense), Initial Letters corp. (corporation), univ. (university) First and Last Letters Dr. (Doctor), PA (Pennsylvania) Omission Address a person by his/her given name or surname rather than full name</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>Figure 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Figure 3: Bridging the gap between uncertain mentions and target entities using seed mentions.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head>Figure 4 :</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Figure 4: Seed selection.</figDesc><graphic url="image-8.png" coords="3,74.84,590.57,87.52,85.40" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><head>[</head><label></label><figDesc>[Harvard University|Harvard University]]... * On October 6, 2012, [[Allison Harvard|Harvard]]</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" validated="false"><head>Table 1 : Alternative form matching rules.</head><label>1</label><figDesc></figDesc><table></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" validated="false"><head>Table 2 : Semantic categories from NeedleSeek.</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4" validated="false"><head>Table 3 : Data set stats.</head><label>3</label><figDesc></figDesc><table></table></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="2"> http://needleseek.msra.cn 3 enwiki: is short for https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/ 4 https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Help:Link</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>This work was supported by the DARPA DEFT No.FA8750-13-2-0041, U.S. DARPA LORELEI Program No. HR0011-15-C-0115, U.S. ARL NS-CTA No. W911NF-09-2-0053, and NSF IIS-1523198. The views and conclusions contained in this document are those of the authors and should not be interpreted as representing the official poli-cies, either expressed or implied, of the U.S. Gov-ernment. The U.S. Government is authorized to reproduce and distribute reprints for Government purposes notwithstanding any copyright notation here on.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Name list only? target entity disambiguation in short texts</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yixin</forename><surname>Cao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Juanzi</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xiaofei</forename><surname>Guo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Shuanhu</forename><surname>Bai</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ji</forename><surname>Heng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jie</forename><surname>Tang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="doi">10.18653/v1/D15-1077</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.18653/v1/D15-1077" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Analysis and enhancement of wikification for microblogs with context expansion</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Taylor</forename><surname>Cassidy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Heng</forename><surname>Ji</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lev-Arie</forename><surname>Ratinov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Arkaitz</forename><surname>Zubiaga</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hongzhao</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://aclweb.org/anthology/C12-1028" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Relational inference for wikification</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xiao</forename><surname>Cheng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dan</forename><surname>Roth</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">EMNLP</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Collective tweet wikification based on semi-supervised graph regularization</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hongzhao</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yunbo</forename><surname>Cao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xiaojiang</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Heng</forename><surname>Ji</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chin-Yew</forename><surname>Lin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="doi">10.3115/v1/P14-1036</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.3115/v1/P14-1036" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Entity disambiguation with linkless knowledge bases</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yang</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Shulong</forename><surname>Tan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Huan</forename><surname>Sun</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jiawei</forename><surname>Han</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dan</forename><surname>Roth</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xifeng</forename><surname>Yan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">WWW</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Unsupervised entity linking with abstract meaning representation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xiaoman</forename><surname>Pan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Taylor</forename><surname>Cassidy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ulf</forename><surname>Hermjakob</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ji</forename><surname>Heng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kevin</forename><surname>Knight</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="doi">10.3115/v1/N15-1119</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.3115/v1/N15-1119" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Corpus-based semantic class mining: Distributional vs. pattern-based approaches</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Shuming</forename><surname>Shi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Huibin</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xiaojie</forename><surname>Yuan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jirong</forename><surname>Wen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://aclweb.org/anthology/C10-1112" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Targeted disambiguation of adhoc, homogeneous sets of named entities</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chi</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kaushik</forename><surname>Chakrabarti</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tao</forename><surname>Cheng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Surajit</forename><surname>Chaudhuri</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="doi">10.1145/2187836.2187934</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1145/2187836.2187934" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">NLP-comp in TAC 2012 entity linking and slot-filling</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jian</forename><surname>Xu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Qin</forename><surname>Lu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jie</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ruifeng</forename><surname>Xu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://tac.nist.gov//publications/2012/papers.html" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
