<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T12:44+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Recognizing Counterfactual Thinking in Social Media Texts</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Youngseo</forename><surname>Son</surname></persName>
							<email>yson@cs.stonybrook.edu, ungar@cis.upenn.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Stony Brook University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Anneke</forename><surname>Buffone</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">University of Pennsylvania</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Anthony</forename><surname>Janocko</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">University of Pennsylvania</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Allegra</forename><surname>Larche</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">University of Pennsylvania</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Joseph</forename><surname>Raso</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">University of Pennsylvania</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kevin</forename><surname>Zembroski</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">University of Pennsylvania</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Andrew</forename><surname>Schwartz</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Stony Brook University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lyle</forename><surname>Ungar</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">University of Pennsylvania</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Recognizing Counterfactual Thinking in Social Media Texts</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Counterfactual statements, describing events that did not occur and their con-sequents, have been studied in areas including problem-solving, affect management , and behavior regulation. People with more counterfactual thinking tend to perceive life events as more personally meaningful. Nevertheless, counterfactuals have not been studied in computational linguistics. We create a counterfactual tweet dataset and explore approaches for detecting counterfactuals using rule-based and supervised statistical approaches. A combined rule-based and statistical approach yielded the best results (F1 = 0.77) outperforming either approach used alone.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Counterfactuals describe events that did not occur, and what would have happened (or not happened), had the event occurred (e.g., "If I hadn't broken my arm, I never would have met her."). More pre- cisely, counterfactual conditionals have the form "If it had been the case that A (or not A), it would have been the case that B (or not B)."</p><p>Counterfactuals have been studied in many dif- ferent domains. Logicians and philosophers fo- cus on literally logical relations between the an- tecedent and consequent of counterfactual forms and the outcomes <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Goodman, 1947)</ref>. In contrast, political scientists usually conduct counterfactual thought experiments for hypothetical tests on his- torical events, policies, or other aspects of a soci- ety and assess them <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">(Tetlock, 1996)</ref>.</p><p>Counterfactual thoughts are defined, especially in psychology, as mental representations of alter- natives to past events, actions, or states. Their use has been explored for correlations with many dif- ferent demographics (age, gender) and psycholog- ical variables (depression, religiosity) ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Kray et al., 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Markman and Miller, 2006</ref>).</p><p>Counterfactual thinking has been linked to per- ceiving life events as more meaningful, fated, and even as influenced by the divine ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Kray et al., 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Buffone et al., 2016)</ref>, as well as with problem- solving, because imagining alternate outcomes can easily bring to mind the steps needed for improvement <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Epstude and Roese, 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Roese, 1994)</ref>. It has also been shown to be associated with affect management, particularly when imag- ining realities that are worse than what actually happened <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Epstude and Roese, 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Roese, 1994)</ref> Despite the extensive research on counterfac- tual thinking, counterfactual language forms have not been studied in computational linguistics.</p><p>Language-based models to recognize counterfac- tual thinking in social media would potentially allow for psychological analysis on users based on their everyday language, avoiding the high ex- pense of capturing counterfactual thinking at a large scale using traditional psychological assess- ments.</p><p>Therefore, in this paper, we build a language- based model to recognize counterfactual forms in social media texts of Twitter and Facebook. There are many challenges for this task. First, counter- factual statements have a low base rate; we found only 2% of status updates on Facebook and 1% of tweets contain counterfactual statements. Sec- ondly, counterfactual statements can take on many forms in natural language. <ref type="bibr">1</ref> For example, they may or may not use explicit if-or then-clauses (e.g, consider "If I had not met him then I would be better off" versus "I wish I had not met him").</p><p>The low base rate and high variability of natu- ral language counterfactuals in social media texts make them difficult to recognize using simple lin- guistic or statistical features. We address these challenges by using a combined rule-based and statistical approach. Key to our success is defin- ing seven sub-types of counterfactuals, allowing better coverage of rarer sub-types.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Related Work</head><p>Identifying counterfactuals is in many ways sim- ilar to identifying discourse relations. In terms of relation classification, the counterfactual con- ditionals can be viewed as a subset of Condi- tion type of Contingency class in the Penn Dis- course Treebank (PDTB) ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Prasad et al., 2008)</ref> or the Condition relation of Rhetorical Structure The- ory (RST) <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Mann and Thompson, 1987)</ref>. Also, like all discourse relations in the PDTB, counter- factuals have implicit and explicit forms, and so cannot by uniquely identified by the presence of specific words.</p><p>There have been many researchers who have tried end-to-end discourse relation parsing with the PDTB and RST <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Biran and McKeown, 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Lin et al., 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Ji and Eisenstein, 2014</ref>). Many of them used dependency parsing or constituency parsing for argument detection or elementary dis- course unit (EDU) segmentation to infer the rela- tion between them. However, the short lengths and poor quality of parses of social media texts make dependency constituents unreliable. <ref type="bibr">2</ref> For exam- ple, posters frequently drop the subject of a sen- tence.</p><p>Other work mostly focuses on relation clas- sification with an assumption that arguments of the given relations are already identified <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Park and Cardie, 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Pitler et al., 2009</ref>). They ex- plore various learning algorithms and types of fea- tures in the given arguments of discourse relations. Then, they report which combinations give the best performance of each discourse relation.</p><p>Our work, while possible to view as a task in discourse relation classification, focuses on criti- cal features of counterfactuals rather than on ac- curate demarcation of each argument of the re- lation. Most downstream applications, such as psychological studies, require knowing the pres- ence/absence of counterfactuals rather than their exact extent.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Method</head><p>We use a combination of a rule-based approach and a supervised classifier to capture counterfac- tual statements from Twitter.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Data Set</head><p>No existing corpus of counterfactual statements was available, so we collected our own data set, starting from a random set of tweets from May 2014 and July 2014. As noted previously, couter- factual statements are rare, so we first limited the random tweet set to 1,637 containing keywords 3 that can signal counterfactuals (Train and Test row from <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>). Keywords were in part based on prior literature on spontaneous counterfactual gen- eration, such as should have, could have, at least, if only, or next time ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Sanna and Turley, 1996)</ref>. We identified further counterfactual forms (e.g. wish) based on visual inspection of the data. Next we used the overall list of keywords to draw samples of 500 tweets for further visual inspection. Words or phrases which had an unreasonably high false positive rate for containing counterfactuals were eliminated. Well-trained annotators then manually labeled each of the 1,637 tweets for counterfactu- als with a 9% postive rate, results in 153 counter- factuals and 1,484 negative samples. A random set of 500 of these instances were used in training and the rest were reserved for testing.</p><p>To build out our training set to capture exam- ples of all forms of counterfactuals, we added a train supplement from random tweets from 2012 and 2014 -at least thirty tweets from each of seven counterfactual forms we defined for our statistical model using the regular expressions 4 with brown- clusters and the tweet PTB tagging model (de- scribed next). With this process, we enabled the model to be less biased towards only the samples with the counterfactual cue phrases used for data collection. Additionally, the model learned syn- tactically different forms of counterfactuals identi- fied in prior work. To evaluate counterfactual form annotation, inter-annotator agreement was estab- lished on 1,637 tweets with a second rater with</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Dataset</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>CF</head><p>Non-CF <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Total  Train  49  451  500  + Supplement 768 498  1,266  Test  104 1,033  1,137   Table 1</ref>: Data Collection. 'CF' is counterfactual and 'Non-CF' is non-counterfactual achieving κ = 0.774 and human annotation F1 0.79.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Classification</head><p>We first use a rule-based model to capture counter- factual patterns from social media texts. We then use a statistical model (Linear SVM) to increase precision by identifying tricky false positives with forms similar to counterfactuals (e.g., "wish you the best").</p><p>Rule-based Classification. Our rule-based ap- proach is based on seven forms of counterfactuals <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">(Table 2</ref>). Central to our method is our theorizing, based on reading the literature, especially (Kray et al., 2010) and examining many counterfactual examples, that counterfactuals come in seven dif- ferent forms, shown with examples in <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">(Table 2)</ref>. First, we remove sentences ending in question marks predicted as 'end of sentence' by the tweet part-of-speech (POS) tagger <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Gimpel et al., 2011</ref>). We then use pattern matching with regular expres- sion using a combination of cue phrases (bold), POS tags, and word clusters. The word clusters, based on a set of Twitter Brown clusters 5 are used to capture the numerous variations of words in so- cial media texts (e.g., 'shuldve' for 'should have'). This approach requires matching both the token and its part-of-speech, since the POS tag of each token is important for counterfactual form. The rule-based approach is also useful in that it allows us to detect the arguments for counter- factual relations; conditional statement and conse- quent statement from Conjunctive Normal/ Con- verse form and Verb Inversion form, one coun- terfactual statement from Wish Verb and Could / Would / Should have. We customized Biran's de- marcation methods using the first verb phrase or the connective as a boundary to capture the more informative argument of the statement: For one argument detection, we demarcate from the cue phrase (e.g., would have) to the end of sentence. For two arguments, we demarcate from condi-tional word (e.g., if, unless) to the end of statement or before the start of the second verb phrase.</p><p>Part of Speech Tagging We use the Penn Tree- bank (PTB)-style Tweet POS tags 6 instead of Tweet POS tags ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Gimpel et al., 2011)</ref> as it contains more fine-grained categories and yields higher ac- curacy of pattern matching. For instance, Tweet POS tags do not differentiate modal verbs, past tense verbs, and other types of verbs, but catego- rize all of them as 'V'. However, in many forms of counterfactuals, the distinction between modal verbs and past particles from other types of verbs are critical (e.g., in Should / Could / Would Have forms). Finally, we conduct a postprocessing on the Tweet POS parsing results for the more ac- curate prediction. First, we delete RT tags along with the token since it is not informative for our task. Then, we convert 'USR' to nouns because the word token tagged as 'user' usually plays the role of a common noun from the discourse rela- tion perspective. Additionally, in order to enhance the POS tagging, we use the brown clusters to tag empirical variations of modal verbs as 'MD' and we define 'CCJ', a new tag to distinguish condi- tional conjunctions (i.e. Brown clusters for 'if') from other types of conjunctions.</p><p>Statistical Modeling. Each counterfactual form has a different number of arguments for the rela- tion, and different types of features that cause the most errors. Therefore, we analyze the errors of each form separately and use different approaches expected to ensure the best performance.</p><p>If a tweet matches rules for counterfactual forms 1, 2, 3, 4, or 5, it is further classified using a statistical model trained with features of sequen- tial words (n-gram) and POS tags of demarcated arguments and the whole sentence.</p><p>A statistical model is expected to capture some implicit relations between arguments as well as lexical and part-of-speech patterns, but may also hurt performance in situations where the rule- based approach achieves high precision. There- fore, we applied statistical approaches to counter- factual forms which cannot be easily differentiated by their superficial patterns. These forms were se- lected by both theoretical and empirical analysis; we discuss these forms further in our evaluation section.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Counterfactual Form Example</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.">Wish Verb I wish I had been richer 2. Conjunctive Normal</head><p>If everyone put differences aside and get along, everything would be so much enjoyable 3. Conjunctive Converse I would be stronger, if I had lifted weights 4. Modal Normal They should of shown this guy gettin shot, that woulda been TV gold.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.">Verb Inversion</head><p>Had I left the event early, I would not have met John 6. Should Have I should have joined the event early 7. (Would / Could) Have I would have been happier without John   </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Evaluation</head><p>As discussed, counterfactuals are not easily iden- tified by rules or specific words. Given their low base rate and multiplicity of forms, traditional machine learning approaches trained on a ran- dom tweet sample tend to label all tweets as the most frequent class (non-counterfactual). Use of a counterfactual-enriched training set increases the performance, but still gives a low F1 on the imbal- anced test set. Thus, in order to make the classifier robust to the imbalanced dataset, we designed a rule-based model with counterfactual forms, which resulted in significantly higher F1 than statistical model. Moreover, the rule-based model captures positive samples of all possible forms which might not exist in the training set. A combined approach gives the best result. As <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Table 3</ref> shows, our whole pipeline ('CF Parser' in <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Table 3</ref>) obtained the best overall performance with the combination of both approaches.</p><p>For Wish Verb form prediction gets a big per- formance boost from the statistical model be- cause of highly frequent false positives which have counterfactual-like forms such as birthday wishes or new year's day wishes. Among samples classi- fied as Wish Verb form the counterfactual predic- tion F1 increased from 0.82 to 0.90 after the final prediction by the statistical model. Finally, we conducted an ablation test to ana- lyze how each process of the pipeline affects the overall performance of the classifier <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">(Table 4)</ref>. The argument detection was less effective (F1 0.01 drop) than we expected due to the relatively simple and concise structure of tweets in general (Args in <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">Table 4</ref>).</p><p>Using only n-grams as features for the statis- tical model without PTB-style Tweet POS tags gives a relatively large drop (0.02) from F1. From the grammatical perspective, n-grams are less in- formative than POS tags for counterfactuals espe- cially considering that there are so many variations of each word token in social media (e.g., 'clda', 'coulda', and 'couldve' for 'could have').</p><p>We examined how the statistical model af- fected the final performance of each counterfac- tual form. The model we used for filtering out frequent false positives (e.g., birth day wishes) of Wish Verb form caused 0.03 F1 drop when it is removed. Also, the models trained with two- argument-relation forms (Conjunctive Normal / Converse, Modal Normal, and Verb Inversion) caused 0.04 F1 drop when they are removed from the pipeline, since the classifier cannot use subtle relations between arguments for its counterfactual prediction.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Conclusion</head><p>This is the first work to identify counterfactuals in social media, a task we hope more people will ad- dress. Our best results came from combining rule- based methods that exploit a theory of the differ- ent forms of counterfactual with focused statistical methods for reclassification of challenging forms. Our counterfactual predictor can now be applied to large collections of tweets and Facebook posts from people of known education, religiosity, po- litical orientation, well-being, and other attributes of interest to psychologists and political scientists, allowing further study of their theories of counter- factual use.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" validated="false"><head>Table 2 : Counterfactual Forms</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Performance CF Parser Rules only SVM 
Precision 
0.7131 
0.5864 
0.2381 
Recall 
0.8365 
0.9134 
0.9135 
F1 
0.7699 
0.7143 
0.3777 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" validated="true"><head>Table 3 : Performance of Classifiers</head><label>3</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Process 
F1 
Precision Recall 
Whole Pipeline 0.7699 0.7131 
0.8365 
-Args 
0.7595 0.6767 
0.8653 
-PTB 
0.7456 0.6854 
0.8173 
-Form 1 
0.7447 0.6592 
0.8557 
-Form 2,3,4,5 
0.7352 0.6241 
0.8942 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" validated="false"><head>Table 4 : Ablation Test for Each Process</head><label>4</label><figDesc></figDesc><table></table></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> Simply looking for words like &apos;if&apos; fails to produce useful results; only 2 percent of sentences of tweets containing &apos;if&apos; are counterfactuals.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="2"> In our preliminary experiments on our causality tweet dataset (κ = 0.61), Lin&apos;s parser (Lin et al., 2014) obtained 0.45 F1 while a linear support vector machine (SVM) with n-gram obtained 0.58 F1 for causality detection.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="3"> e.g., &apos;should&apos;, &apos;shulda&apos;; full list available in our supplementary data. 4 The regular expression table is included in our supplementary data.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="5"> http://www.cs.cmu.edu/ ˜ ark/TweetNLP/ clusters/50mpaths2</note>

			<note place="foot" n="6"> http://www.cs.cmu.edu/ ˜ ark/TweetNLP/ model.ritter_ptb_alldata_fixed.20130723</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>This project/publication was made possible, in part, through the support of a grant from Tem-pleton Religion Trust, TRT-0048. The opinions expressed in this publication are those of the au-thor(s) and do not necessarily reflect the views of the Templeton Religion Trust.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Pdtb discourse parsing as a tagging task: The two taggers approach</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Or</forename><surname>Biran</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kathleen</forename><surname>Mckeown</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 16th Annual Meeting of the Special Interest Group on Discourse and Dialogue</title>
		<meeting>the 16th Annual Meeting of the Special Interest Group on Discourse and Dialogue</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="96" to="104" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">There but for the grace of god counterfactuals influence religious belief and images of the divine</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Anneke</forename><surname>Buffone</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Shira</forename><surname>Gabriel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Poulin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Social Psychological and Personality Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="256" to="263" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The functional theory of counterfactual thinking</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kai</forename><surname>Epstude</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Neal J Roese</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Personality and Social Psychology Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="168" to="192" />
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Part-of-speech tagging for twitter: Annotation, features, and experiments</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kevin</forename><surname>Gimpel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nathan</forename><surname>Schneider</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O&amp;apos;</forename><surname>Brendan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dipanjan</forename><surname>Connor</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Daniel</forename><surname>Das</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jacob</forename><surname>Mills</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Eisenstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dani</forename><surname>Heilman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jeffrey</forename><surname>Yogatama</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Noah A</forename><surname>Flanigan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Smith</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 49th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics: Human Language Technologies</title>
		<meeting>the 49th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics: Human Language Technologies</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="42" to="47" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The problem of counterfactual conditionals</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nelson</forename><surname>Goodman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The Journal of Philosophy</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">44</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="113" to="128" />
			<date type="published" when="1947" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Representation learning for text-level discourse parsing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yangfeng</forename><surname>Ji</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jacob</forename><surname>Eisenstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ACL (1)</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="13" to="24" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">From what might have been to what must have been: counterfactual thinking creates meaning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Laura</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Linda</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Kray</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Katie</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>George</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Adam</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Liljenquist</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Philip</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Galinsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Tetlock</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Roese</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of personality and social psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">98</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">106</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A pdtb-styled end-to-end discourse parser</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ziheng</forename><surname>Lin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hwee</forename><forename type="middle">Tou</forename><surname>Ng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Min-Yen</forename><surname>Kan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Natural Language Engineering</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">02</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="151" to="184" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Rhetorical structure theory: A theory of text organization</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>William</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sandra</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Mann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Thompson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1987" />
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>University of Southern California, Information Sciences Institute</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Depression, control, and counterfactual thinking: Functional for whom?</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Audrey</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Keith D Markman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Miller</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Social and Clinical Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">25</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="210" to="227" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Improving implicit discourse relation recognition through feature set optimization</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Joonsuk</forename><surname>Park</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Claire</forename><surname>Cardie</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 13th Annual Meeting of the Special Interest Group on Discourse and Dialogue. Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the 13th Annual Meeting of the Special Interest Group on Discourse and Dialogue. Association for Computational Linguistics</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="108" to="112" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Automatic sense prediction for implicit discourse relations in text</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Emily</forename><surname>Pitler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Annie</forename><surname>Louis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ani</forename><surname>Nenkova</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Joint Conference of the 47th Annual Meeting of the ACL and the 4th International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing of the AFNLP</title>
		<meeting>the Joint Conference of the 47th Annual Meeting of the ACL and the 4th International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing of the AFNLP</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="683" to="691" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The penn discourse treebank 2.0</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rashmi</forename><surname>Prasad</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nikhil</forename><surname>Dinesh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alan</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Eleni</forename><surname>Miltsakaki</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Livio</forename><surname>Robaldo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Aravind</forename><surname>Joshi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bonnie</forename><surname>Webber</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of LREC</title>
		<meeting>LREC</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The functional basis of counterfactual thinking</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Neal J Roese</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of personality and Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">66</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">805</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1994" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Antecedents to spontaneous counterfactual thinking: Effects of expectancy violation and outcome valence</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Lawrence</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kandi Jo</forename><surname>Sanna</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Turley</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Personality and Social Psychology Bulletin</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="906" to="919" />
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Counterfactual thought experiments in world politics: Logical, methodological, and psychological perspectives</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Philip E Tetlock</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
			<publisher>Princeton University Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
