<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T10:02+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Computational Characterization of Mental States: A Natural Language Processing Approach</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
				<availability status="unknown"><p>Copyright Association for Computational Linguistics</p>
				</availability>
				<date>July 30-August 4, 2017. July 30-August 4, 2017</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Facundo</forename><surname>Carrillo</surname></persName>
							<email>fcarrillo@dc.uba.ar</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Computer Science Dept</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">School of Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Buenos Aires University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Computational Characterization of Mental States: A Natural Language Processing Approach</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of ACL 2017, Student Research Workshop</title>
						<meeting>ACL 2017, Student Research Workshop <address><addrLine>Vancouver, Canada; Vancouver, Canada</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="3"/>
							<date type="published">July 30-August 4, 2017. July 30-August 4, 2017</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="DOI">10.18653/v1/p17-3001</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Psychiatry is an area of medicine that strongly bases its diagnoses on the psychiatrists subjective appreciation. The task of diagnosis loosely resembles the common pipelines used in supervised learning schema. Therefore, we propose to augment the psychiatrists diagnosis toolbox with an artificial intelligence system based on natural language processing and machine learning algorithms. This approach has been validated in many works in which the performance of the diagnosis has been increased with the use of automatic classification .</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Psychiatry is an area of medicine that strongly bases its diagnoses on the psychiatrists subjective appreciation. More precisely, speech is used al- most exclusively as a window to the patients mind. Few other cues are available to objectively justify a diagnostic, unlike what happens in other disci- plines which count on laboratory tests or imag- ing procedures, such as X-rays. Daily practice is based on the use of semi-structured interviews and standardized tests to build the diagnoses, heavily relying on her personal experience. This method- ology has a big problem: diagnoses are commonly validated a posteriori in function of how the phar- macological treatment works. This validation can- not be done until months after the start of the treatment and, if the patient condition does not improve, the psychiatrist often changes the diag- nosis and along with the pharmacological treat- ment. This delay prolongs the patient's suffering until the correct diagnosis is found. According to NIMH, more than 1% and 2 % of US population is affected by <ref type="bibr">Schizophrenia and Bipolar Disorder,</ref> respectively. Moreover, the WHO reported that the global cost of mental illness reached $2.5T in 2010 ( <ref type="bibr">Mathers et al., 2008)</ref> .</p><p>The task of diagnosis, largely simplified, mainly consists of understanding the mind state through the extraction of patterns from the patient's speech and finding the best matching pathology in the standard diagnostic literature. This pipeline, con- sisting of extracting patterns and then classify- ing them, loosely resembles the common pipelines used in supervised learning schema. Therefore, we propose to augment the psychiatrists diagnosis toolbox with an artificial intelligence system based on natural language processing and machine learn- ing algorithms. The proposed system would assist in the diagnostic using a patients speech as input. The understanding and insights obtained from cus- tomizing these systems to specific pathologies is likely to be more broadly applicable to other NLP tasks, therefore we expect to make contributions not only for psychiatry but also within the com- puter science community. We intend to develop these ideas and evaluate them beyond the lab set- ting. Our end goal is to make it possible for a prac- titioner to integrate our tools into her daily practice with minimal effort.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Methodology</head><p>In order to complement the manual diagnosis it is necessary to have samples from real patients. To collect these samples, we have ongoing collabo- rations with different psychiatric institutions from many countries: United States, Colombia, Brazil and Argentina. These centers provide us with ac- cess to the relevant patient data and we jointly col- laborate testing different protocols in a variety lan- guages. We have already started studies with two pathologies: Schizophrenia and Bipolar Disorder.</p><p>Regarding our technical setup, we are using and 1 developing tools to capture different characteris- tics of the speech. In all cases, we work with high- quality transcriptions of speech. Our experiments are focused on analyzing different aspects of the speech: 1) Grammatical-morphological changes based on topology of Speech Graphs.  <ref type="bibr">Carrillo et al., 2015)</ref>) to mea- sure when consecutive sentences of spontaneous speech differ too much. The authors used this algorithm, combined with machine learning clas- sifiers, to predict which high-risk subjects would have their first psychotic episode within 2 years (with 100% accuracy) ( <ref type="bibr">Bedi et al., 2015</ref>). The lat- ter result was very relevant because it presented evidence that this automatic diagnostic methodol- ogy could not only perform at levels comparable to experts but also, under some conditions, even out- perform experts (classical medical tests achieved 40% of accuracy). Dr. Insel, former director of National Institute of Mental Health cited this work in his blog on his post: Look who is getting into mental health research as one.</p><note type="other">2) Coher- ence Algorithm: Semantic coherence using prox- imity in semantic embeddings. 3) Changes in Emotional language and other semantic</note><p>Regarding Emotional language, some re- searchers presented evidence of how some en- docrine regulations change the language. This methods are based on quantifying different emo- tional levels. This methodology has been used to diagnose depression and postpartum depres- sion by Eric Horvitz <ref type="bibr">(De Choudhury et al., 2013)</ref>. Others researchers also have used this method to diagnose patients with Parkinsons disease( <ref type="bibr">García et al., 2016</ref>).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Current Work</head><p>Currently, we are working on the coherence al- gorithm <ref type="bibr">(Bedi et al., 2015)</ref>, understanding some properties and its potential applications, such as automatic composition of text and feature extrac- tion for bot detection. Meanwhile, we are receiv- ing new speech samples from 3 different mental health hospitals in Argentina provided by patients with new pathologies like frontotemporal demen- tia and anxiety. We are also building methods to detect depression in young patients using the change of emotions in time.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Future work</head><p>The tasks for the following 2/3 years are: 1) Im- prove implementations of developed algorithms and make them open source. 2) Integrate the dif- ferent pipelines of features extraction and classi- fication to generate a generic classifier for sev- eral pathologies. 3) Build a mobile application for medical use (for this aim, Google has awarded our project with the Google Research Awards for Latin America 2016: Prognosis in a Box: Compu- tational Characterization of Mental State). At the moment the data is recorded and then transcribed by an external doctor. We want a full automatic procedure, from the moment when the doctor per- forms the interview to the moment when she re- ceives the results. 4) Write the PhD thesis.</p></div>		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="annex">
			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl/>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
