<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T10:17+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">V for Vocab: An Intelligent Flashcard Application</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
				<availability status="unknown"><p>Copyright Association for Computational Linguistics</p>
				</availability>
				<date>July 30-August 4, 2017. July 30-August 4, 2017</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nihal</forename><forename type="middle">V</forename><surname>Nayak</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tanmay</forename><surname>Chinchore</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Aishwarya</forename><surname>Hanumanth Rao</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Shane</forename><forename type="middle">Michael</forename><surname>Martin</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sagar</forename><forename type="middle">Nagaraj</forename><surname>Simha</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Lingaraju</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Jamadagni</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">V for Vocab: An Intelligent Flashcard Application</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of ACL 2017, Student Research Workshop</title>
						<meeting>ACL 2017, Student Research Workshop <address><addrLine>Vancouver, Canada; Vancouver, Canada</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="24" to="29"/>
							<date type="published">July 30-August 4, 2017. July 30-August 4, 2017</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="DOI">10.18653/v1/p17-3005</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Students choose to use flashcard applications available on the Internet to help memorize word-meaning pairs. This is helpful for tests such as GRE, TOEFL or IELTS, which emphasize on verbal skills. However, monotonous nature of flashcard applications can be diminished with the help of Cognitive Science through Testing Effect. Experimental evidences have shown that memory tests are an important tool for long term retention (Roediger and Karpicke, 2006). Based on these evi-dences, we developed a novel flashcard application called &quot;V for Vocab&quot; that implements short answer based tests for learning new words. Furthermore, we aid this by implementing our short answer grading algorithm which automatically scores the user&apos;s answer. The algorithm makes use of an alternate thesaurus instead of traditional Wordnet and delivers state-of-the-art performance on popular word similarity datasets. We also look to lay the foundation for analysis based on implicit data collected from our application.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>In recent times, we have seen how Internet has revolutionized the field of education through Mas- sive Open Online Courses (MOOCs). Universities are incorporating MOOCs as a part of their regu- lar coursework. Since most of these courses are in English, the students are expected to know the lan- guage before they are admitted to the university. In order to provide proof of English proficiency, students take up exams such as TOEFL (Test Of English as a Foreign Language), IELTS (Interna- tional English Language Testing System),etc. In addition, students are required to take up GRE (Graduate Record Examination) in some universi- ties. All these tests require the students to expand their vocabulary.</p><p>Students use several materials and applications in order to prepare for these tests. Amongst several techniques that have known to be effective for ac- quiring vocabulary, flashcard applications are the most popular. We believe the benefits of flashcard applications can be further amplified by incorpo- rating techniques from Cognitive Science. One such technique that has been supported by exper- imental results is the Testing Effect, also referred to as Test Enhanced Learning. This phenomenon suggests that taking a memory test not only as- sesses what one knows, but also enhances later re- tention ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Roediger and Karpicke, 2006)</ref>.</p><p>In this paper, we start by briefly discussing Test- ing Effect and other key works that influenced the development of the automatic short answer grad- ing algorithm, implemented in V for Vocab 1 for acquiring vocabulary. Next, we have an overview of the application along with the methodology we use to collect data. In the later section, we de- scribe our automatic short answer grading algo- rithm and present the evaluation results for vari- ants of this algorithm on popular word similarity datasets such as RG65, WS353, SimLex-999 and SimVerb 3500. To conclude, we present a discus- sion that provides fodder for future work in this application.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Background</head><p>We have seen that flashcards have gained a lot of popularity among language learners. Students ex- tensively use electronic flashcards while prepar- ing for tests such as TOEFL, GRE and IELTS. <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Wissman et al. (2012)</ref> surveyed the use of flash- cards among students and established that they are mostly used for memorization. To understand the decay of memory in humans, we delve into the concept of forgetting curve. Hermann Ebbinghaus was the first to investigate this concept way back in the 19th century. Since then, researchers have studied the benefits of several strategies which im- prove long term memory retention in an attempt to combat the forgetting curve. One such strategy is Testing Effect.</p><p>Our application is an amalgamation of the regu- lar flashcard concept and Testing Effect. <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Roediger and Karpicke (2006)</ref> showed that repeated test- ing facilitates long term retention when compared to repeated studying. Further investigation re- vealed that short answer based tests are more ef- fective in comparison to multiple choice question tests <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Larsen and Butler, 2013)</ref>. Experimental ev- idence also suggested that providing feedback to test takers improved their performance <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Mcdaniel and Fisher, 1991;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Pashler et al., 2005</ref>). This mo- tivated us to incorporate short answer based tests with feedback in V for Vocab. To automate the process of scoring these tests, we developed a grading algorithm.</p><p>Since production tests allow the users to be more expressive, we had to develop an algorithm to grade answers that range from a single word to several words. The task of grading anywhere be- tween a fill-in-the-gap and an essay is known as Automatic Short Answer Grading (ASAG) <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Burrows et al., 2015)</ref>. <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Thomas (2003)</ref> used a boolean pattern matching system to score answers which makes use of a thesauri and uses a boolean func- tion OR to check with alternate options. FreeText Author ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Jordan and Mitchell, 2009</ref>) provides an interface for teachers to give templates for the an- swer along with mandatory keywords. Different permutations for these templates are generated us- ing synonyms obtained from thesauri. On similar lines, we developed an algorithm which employs an online thesaurus as a knowledge base.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Our Application</head><p>V for Vocab is an electronic version of the flash- card concept for learning new words. On these flashcards, we populate words from a popular wordlist 2 supplemented with sentences from an online dictionary 3 . These words have been divided into 25 groups and are saved in a database. The word, meaning and sentence combinations present in the data were verified by a qualified person. The interface we provide for our users is an An- droid Application. The application is designed to be simple and intuitive and is modelled based on other popular flashcard softwares.</p><p>On signing up, the user is prompted with a sur- vey. The survey asks basic profile questions such as Name, Gender, Date of Birth, Occupation and  <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>: Statistical information regarding the data collected from our application where users had typed a meaning. The first column indicates the number of tokens or words in user's answers. N refers to the highest number of words typed by the user. The second column represents the percentage of raw answers or unprocessed responses, N = 16. The third column represents the percentage of answers after processing its bag of words, N = 8. However, after computing bag of words we saw of loss of 1.37% where the user's meaning was reduced to 0 words. In that case, the user's answer would not be graded.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Number of Words Raw Answers(%) Bag of words of answers(%)</head><p>Place of Origin. Apart from this, we ask whether the user is a voracious reader, whether the user is preparing for GRE and the background of the user. This background has been described by Edu- cational Testing Service (ETS) 4 , the organization that conducts tests such as TOEFL and GRE. As mentioned earlier, the user can study from any of the 25 groups. Flashcards from the selected group are shown to the user one at a time in ran- dom order. On the front of the card, we provide a text field where the user may type his/her un- derstanding of the word (Refer to <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1a)</ref>. Re- gardless of whether the user submits an answer, the back of the card shows the word, its part-of- speech, dictionary meaning and a sample sentence (Refer to <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1b)</ref>. This serves as feedback to the user as they review the meaning of the word. Before going to the next flashcard, we send im- plicit data to the server. If the user has submitted an answer, our algorithm scores it and returns back a score. On quitting, the user is prompted with a learning summary (Refer to <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1c</ref>).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Data Collection</head><p>During each flip of the card, V for Vocab collects implicit data from the phone in order to facilitate future analysis. The following data points are col- lected -</p><p>• Time spent on the front of the card in mil- liseconds</p><p>• Time spent on the back of the card in mil- liseconds</p><p>• Ambient Sensor value data in SI lux units</p><p>The ambient sensor value data is calculated by tapping into the mobile phone's light sensor. <ref type="bibr">4</ref> www.ets.org/s/gre/pdf/snapshot test taker data 2014.pdf These values are found to be dependent on the manufacturer of the light sensor. They are only re- trieved when there is a change in the sensor value data and stored in an array. In order to build a grading algorithm that suited V for Vocab, we first needed to understand the variation in the answers provided by our users. For   <ref type="table">Table 2</ref>: Pearson and Spearman rank correla- tion coefficients (separated by /; first one is Pear- son correlation) computed between the human- annotated similarity score and the score given by our algorithm for a given pair of words from each dataset (S.L : Spacy Lemmatizer and W.L. : Word- net Lemmatizer ) our analysis, we used 3027 data points collected over 2 months from different users. We found that in 1528 data points users had typed an an- swer. Based on statistical evidence, we observed that 58.507% of the answers were one word re- sponse. After performing bag of words computa- tion on these answers, 67.408% of them were re- duced to one word (See <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>). This meant that our algorithm had to be tailored to grade one word answers, yet be versatile enough so as to grade an- swers which contained more words.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Short Answer Grading Algorithm</head><p>The answers from the users included a mix of synonyms for the main word or a paraphrase for the definition of the word. Therefore, in order to grade, we first compute the textual similarity of the answer with the word itself and then with the meaning from our database. These are consid- ered as answer templates against which we com- pare the user's answers to compute the score. Our grader resembles the algorithm described in <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Pilehvar et al., 2013</ref>) with minuscule changes in simi- larity measure, which is defined by the ratio of the total number of synonym overlap between word pairs in the answer templates and the user's an- swers to the total number of words in the answer template (See Algorithm 1). It should be noted that the bag of words is passed to the algorithm for computing the score. The algorithm scores the answers and returns a decimal score in the range [0,1] with a score of 1 being the highest.</p><p>Traditionally, people have used Wordnet <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Miller, 1995)</ref> as a thesauri to find synonyms for a given word. Majority of the words in our wordlist being adjectives, Wordnet posed a disadvantage as it does not work well with adjectives. We also looked into word2vec ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Mikolov et al., 2013</ref>), but we decided to not go with that approach as we got a high similarity score between a word and its antonym. Therefore, we preferred to retrieve the synonyms using a python module called PyDictionary <ref type="bibr">5</ref> . This web scrapes synonyms from 21st Century Roget's Thesaurus <ref type="bibr">6</ref> .</p><p>We preprocess the user's answers with the help of a lemmatizer and stopwords list in order to com- pute the bag of words. The resulting bag of words is passed to the algorithm and it computes the strict synonym overlap between the user's answers and answer templates to calculate the score. <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">Table 3</ref> shows an example of the scores generated by our algorithm <ref type="bibr">7</ref> .</p><p>We developed this algorithm using lemmatiz- ers from two popular NLP libraries -NLTK and Spacy, independently. <ref type="table">Table 2</ref> shows our evalua- tion results on popular datasets. We noticed that the algorithm produced higher correlation with NLTK's Wordnet lemmatizer, even though no ex- plicit POS information was passed to the lemma- tizer.</p><p>In case of an error caused due to absence of syn- onyms while web scraping, our algorithm returned a score of 0 which we have included during evalu- ation with the datasets.  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>User's Answers</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Discussion and Future Work</head><p>With trends showing that many applications curate their business model around data, we believe that the data collected from our application is valuable. We have the unique opportunity of performing an- alytics on an individual user and on all users as a whole. By analyzing the individual's data, we can personalize the application to each user. One way would be to observe the user's scores on the words studied and subsequently categorize them into easy, medium and hard. We also have the po- tential to carry out exploratory analysis and bring out interesting patterns from our data. For exam- ple, we are hoping to discover an optimal duration to study words in a day so that the user can study effectively. Similarly, light sensor values could be used to understand how a user's learning would vary in a well lit environment versus a darker en- vironment. Spacing Effect is the robust phenomenon which states that spacing the learning events results in long term retention <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Kornell, 2009)</ref>. Anki, a pop- ular flashcard application incorporates a schedul- ing algorithm in order to implement spacing ef- fect. More recently we have seen Duolingo, a language learning application implement a ma- chine learning based spacing effect called Half- Life-Regression ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Settles and Meeder, 2016)</ref>. With Testing Effect in place, it would be beneficial to incorporate spacing effect as it has shown great promise in practical applications . A thorough jux- taposition of Testing Effect versus the combina- tion of Testing Effect with Spacing Effect, in terms of data, will help us better evaluate these memory techniques.</p><p>We can further improve the system through a mechanical turk. The turk could be any linguist or a person well versed with the language. The me- chanical turk compares the answer templates with the user's answer and provides a score that repre- sents how close the two are according to the turk's intuition. With labelled data, we can apply super- vised learning and improve the algorithm.</p><p>When learning a new language, people often try to remember a word and its translation in a lan- guage they already know. For example, a person well versed in English who is trying to learn Ger- man will try to recollect word-translation pairs. With a bit of content curation for German-English word pairs, our grading algorithm will work seam- lessly, as our algorithm is tailored to grade short answers in English. We believe that in future, V for Vocab can be ported to other languages as well.</p><p>Therefore, with the help of this application we are able to improve upon existing flashcard appli- cations and lay groundwork for intelligent flash- card systems.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: a) Front of the card showing a textbox b) Back of the card giving feedback to the user c) Session Scorecard</figDesc><graphic url="image-1.png" coords="2,77.42,72.76,131.76,208.01" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Algorithm 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Grading Algorithm Input: B1 &amp; B2, the sets of Bag of Words for Text1 &amp; Text2 Output: Similarity Score between Text1 &amp; Text2 1 score, match count, total count ← 0 2 for w i in B 1 do 3 total count ← total count + 1 4 for w j in B 2 do 5 f lag ← 0 6 for s i in synonym(w i ) do 7 for s j in synonym(w j ) do 8 if lemma(s i ) == lemma(s j ) then 9 match count ← match count + 1 10 f lag ← 1 11 break 12 shortend 13 if f lag == 1 then 14 break 15 if f lag == 1 then 16 break 17 score ← match count/total count 18 return score</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Dataset</head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" validated="false"><head>Table 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>The table shows the evaluation of user's 
short answer for the word -provident, with the 
meaning -providing for future needs; frugal. Mul-
tiple meanings are separated by a ;(semicolon). 

</table></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> https://goo.gl/1BBWN4</note>

			<note place="foot" n="2"> https://quizlet.com/6876275/barrons-800-highfrequency-gre-word-list-flash-cards/ 3 http://sentence.yourdictionary.com</note>

			<note place="foot" n="5"> https://pypi.python.org/pypi/PyDictionary/1.5.2 6 http://www.thesaurus.com 7 The answers in Table 3 are compiled from the actual data we have collected from our users</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>We thank the anonymous reviewers for their in-sightful comments. We also thank Dr. Vijaya Kumar B P, Professor at M S Ramaiah Institute of Technology, Bangalore for his valuable sug-gestions. This research was supported by Depart-ment of Electronic Systems Engineering (formerly CEDT), Indian Institute of Science.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The eras and trends of automatic short answer grading</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Steven</forename><surname>Burrows</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Iryna</forename><surname>Gurevych</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Benno</forename><surname>Stein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="doi">10.1007/s40593-014-0026-8</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1007/s40593-014-0026-8" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">International Journal of Artificial Intelligence in Education</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">25</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="60" to="117" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">e-assessment for learning? the potential of short-answer freetext questions with tailored feedback</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sally</forename><surname>Jordan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tom</forename><surname>Mitchell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://oro.open.ac.uk/15270/" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">British Journal of Educational Technology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">40</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="371" to="385" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Optimising learning using flashcards: Spacing is more effective than cramming</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nate</forename><surname>Kornell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="doi">10.1002/acp.1537</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1002/acp.1537" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Applied Cognitive Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">23</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1297" to="1317" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Oxford Textbook of Medical Education pages</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Douglas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Andrew</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Larsen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Butler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="443" to="452" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Testenhanced learning</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Tests and test feedback as learning sources. Contemporary</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Mark</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ronald</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Mcdaniel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Fisher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="doi">10.1016/0361-476x(91)90037-l</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/0361-476x(91)90037-l" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Educational Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">16</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="192" to="201" />
			<date type="published" when="1991" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Distributed representations of words and phrases and their compositionality</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tomas</forename><surname>Mikolov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ilya</forename><surname>Sutskever</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kai</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Greg</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Corrado</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jeff</forename><surname>Dean</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://papers.nips.cc/paper/5021-distributed-representations-of-words-and-phrases-and-their-compositionality.pdf" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Advances in Neural Information Processing Systems</title>
		<editor>C. J. C. Burges, L. Bottou, M. Welling, Z. Ghahramani, and K. Q. Weinberger</editor>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Curran Associates, Inc</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3111" to="3119" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Wordnet: A lexical database for english</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">George</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Miller</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="doi">10.1145/219717.219748</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1145/219717.219748" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Commun. ACM</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">38</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="39" to="41" />
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">When does feedback facilitate learning of words</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Harold</forename><surname>Pashler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nicholas</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Cepeda</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">John</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Wixted</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Doug</forename><surname>Rohrer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="doi">10.1037/0278-7393.31.1.3</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/0278-7393.31.1.3" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Journal of Experimental Psychology: Learning, Memory, and Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">31</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3" to="8" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Align, disambiguate and walk: A unified approach for measuring semantic similarity</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mohammad</forename><surname>Taher Pilehvar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Jurgens</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Roberto</forename><surname>Navigli</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://www.aclweb.org/anthology/P13-1132" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 51st Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the 51st Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics<address><addrLine>Sofia, Bulgaria</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1341" to="1351" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Long Papers). Association for Computational Linguistics</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Test-enhanced learning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Henry</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jeffrey</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Roediger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Karpicke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="doi">10.1111/j.1467-9280.2006.01693.x</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1467-9280.2006.01693.x" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="249" to="255" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A trainable spaced repetition model for language learning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Burr</forename><surname>Settles</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Brendan</forename><surname>Meeder</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://www.aclweb.org/anthology/P16-1174" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 54th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the 54th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics<address><addrLine>Berlin, Germany</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1848" to="1858" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Long Papers). Association for Computational Linguistics</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The evaluation of electronic marking of examinations</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Pete</forename><surname>Thomas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="doi">10.1145/961290.961528</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1145/961290.961528" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">SIGCSE Bull</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">35</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="50" to="54" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">How and when do students use flashcards</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kathryn</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Wissman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Katherine</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Rawson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mary</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Pyc</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Memory</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="568" to="579" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="doi">10.1080/09658211.2012.687052</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1080/09658211.2012.687052" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
