<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T12:28+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">English Event Detection With Translated Language Features</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
				<availability status="unknown"><p>Copyright Association for Computational Linguistics</p>
				</availability>
				<date>July 30-August 4, 2017. July 30-August 4, 2017</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sam</forename><surname>Wei</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Igor</forename><surname>Korostil</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Joel</forename><surname>Nothman</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ben</forename><surname>Hachey</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">English Event Detection With Translated Language Features</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 55th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (Volume 2: Short Papers)</title>
						<meeting>the 55th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (Volume 2: Short Papers) <address><addrLine>Vancouver, Canada; Vancouver, Canada</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="293" to="298"/>
							<date type="published">July 30-August 4, 2017. July 30-August 4, 2017</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="DOI">10.18653/v1/p17-2046</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>We propose novel radical features from automatic translation for event extraction. Event detection is a complex language processing task for which it is expensive to collect training data, making generali-sation challenging. We derive meaningful subword features from automatic translations into target language. Results suggest this method is particularly useful when using languages with writing systems that facilitate easy decomposition into subword features, e.g., logograms and Cangjie. The best result combines logogram features from Chinese and Japanese with syllable features from Korean, providing an additional 3.0 points f-score when added to state-of-the-art generalisation features on the TAC KBP 2015 Event Nugget task.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Event trigger detection is the task of identifying the mention that predicates the occurrence of an event and assigning it an event type (e.g., attack). Typical training data for event trigger detection in- cludes fewer than 200 annotated documents ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Ellis et al., 2015</ref>). Yet systems attempt to identify many event types (e.g., <ref type="bibr">38</ref> for the data used here), mak- ing data sparsity a particular challenge <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Ji, 2009;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Zhu et al., 2014</ref>).</p><p>Existing approaches use two main strategies for handling data sparsity. One strategy is to use lex- ical databases. Lexical databases have become a standard feature set for event detection. They make it easy to include synonyms and word-class information through hypernym relations. How- ever, they require substantial human effort to build and can have low coverage. Another approach is to induce word-class information through cluster- ing. Here cluster co-membership can be used to find synonyms and cluster identifiers provide ab- stracted word-class information.</p><p>We propose novel semantic features for English event detection derived from automatic transla- tions into thirteen languages. In particular, we explore the use of Cangjie 1 radicals in Chinese and Japanese. Where characters represent con- cepts, they have often been composed of smaller pictographic units, called radicals. For example: 明(bright) is composed of two radicals 日,月(sun, moon) with corresponding Latin letter sequence "AB". While this composition is often not produc- tive, we hypothesise that the recurrence of some radicals among related concepts' logograms may be exploited to identify semantic affinity.</p><p>Results suggest that (1) translated language fea- tures are especially useful if the target language has a writing system facilitating easy decomposi- tion into useful subword features; (2) logograms (e.g., Chinese, Japanese), radicals (e.g., Chinese, Japanese) and syllables (e.g., Japanese, Korean) prove beneficial and complementary; and (3) Chi- nese characters are particularly useful, compara- ble to WordNet. Adding the best translated lan- guage features to the final system improves F1 by 3.0 points over a state-of-the-art feature set on the TAC KBP 2015 nugget type detection task.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Background</head><p>Multilingual resources have been successfully ap- plied to various NLP tasks such as named entity recognition ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Klementiev and Roth, 2006</ref>), para- phrasing ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Bannard and Callison-Burch, 2005</ref>), sentiment analysis <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">(Wan, 2008)</ref>, and word sense disambiguation ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Lefever and Hoste, 2010)</ref>. <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Ji (2009)</ref> reports significantly improved event trigger extraction via cross-lingual clusters of En- glish translations to Chinese trigger words over large corpora. At runtime, these are used to replace low-confidence event triggers with other high-confidence predicates from the same cluster. We describe an approach leveraging cross-lingual information not only from words, but also at the level of characters and radicals. Like <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Zhu et al. (2014)</ref>, we use Google Translate and build bilin- gual feature vectors from the translations as well as original English sentences. While they address event trigger type classification only, we address both trigger detection and classification. We use new translated language features and evaluate with a range of languages. <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Li et al. (2012)</ref> show that monolingual Chinese event trigger extraction benefits from using com- positional semantics inferred from Chinese char- acters. We use similar Chinese character informa- tion as features for English event trigger detection also using maximum entropy modelling. Further- more, we introduce new radical features that take advantage of semantic compositionality of Chi- nese characters.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">Task</head><p>We address the event nugget detection task from the Text Analysis Conference Knowledge Base Population (TAC KBP) 2015 shared task <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(Mitamura and Hovy, 2015)</ref>, which includes trigger de- tection and classification. An event trigger is the smallest extent of text (usually a word or short continuous phrase) that predicates the occurrence of an event <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(LDC, 2015)</ref>. The task defines 9 event types and and 38 subtypes. Like most task par- ticipants, we formulate event trigger detection as a token-level classification task. We use a max- imum entropy classifier here, with IOB encoding ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Sang and Veenstra, 1999</ref>) to represent multi-word mentions.</p><p>For comparison, we implement the baseline and lexical generalisation features from <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Hong et al. (2015)</ref>. This was the best-performing system in the TAC 2015 nugget type detection task, with an F1 of 58.3. We do not replicate their semi- supervised techniques here as we want to iso- late the comparison of translated language features to other generalisation features. Since translated language features leverage off-the-shelf automatic translation, we believe the results here will gener- alise to semi-supervised learning as well.</p><p>Baseline Features (BASE) Our baseline sys- tem uses standard surface features used for event extraction. Features of the current token include the full word token as it appears in the sentence, its lemma, its part of speech (POS), its entity type, and a feature that indicates whether the first char- acter of the token is capitalised. Context features are computed for a window of one token on ei- ther side of the current token. They include lemma bigrams, POS bigrams and entity type bigrams. Finally, grammatical features are computed based on a dependency parse of the sentence. These in- clude dependency relation types for the governor and any dependents, conjoined relation type and lemma, conjoined relation type and POS, and con- joined relation type and entity type.</p><p>Lexical generalisation Features (LEX) We in- clude three generalisation feature sets from the lit- erature as a benchmark. The first lexical resource we use is <ref type="bibr">Nomlex (Macleod et al., 1998</ref>) -a dic- tionary of nouns that are generated from another verb class, usually verbs. We also use Brown clusters trained on the Reuters corpus ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Brown et al., 1992;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Turian et al., 2010)</ref>. Brown clusters group words into classes by performing a hier- archical clustering over distributional representa- tions of the contexts in which they appear. Fi- nally, we use WordNet <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Miller, 1995)</ref> -a lexical database that includes synonym relations and se- mantic type-of/hypernym relationships. These re- lations have been used to extend feature sets be- yond observed tokens which can help with identi- fication of rare or unseen event triggers.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Approach</head><p>We use machine translation (MT) service to ob- tain translated text. The translation is done at sen- tence level. We cache the translation results on files to ensure the experiments are repeatable. Be- low are example sentences translated from English into Chinese and Spanish.</p><p>EN The attack by insurgents happened yesterday.</p><p>ZH 叛亂分子的襲擊發生在昨天。 ES El ataque de los insurgentes pasó ayer.</p><p>(1)</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Translated Language Features (TRANS)</head><p>We generate three types of logogram features and use stem features for non-logogram languages.</p><p>Word features (word) Different words in En- glish can be translated into the same word in an- other language. For example there are 201 unique <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>: Attack event triggers. The radical "手" (Q, hand) frequently appears in the attack event triggers. Radicals "中 弓(刀)" (LN, knife) appear frequently when events are asso- ciated with actions that are performed with a knife</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">Chinese Character Radical Symbol Latin Radical English Word 打 手一弓 QMN hit 擊 十水手 JEQ strike 投 手竹弓水 QHNE throw 擲 手廿大中 QTKL throw 折(磨) 手竹一中 QHML torture 拆 手竹一卜 QHMY demolish 拷(打) 手十大尸 QJKS torture 割 十口中弓 JRLN cut 刺 木月中弓 DBLN stab</formula><p>English trigger words for attack events and only 160 unique words in their Chinese translations. Therefore if an English trigger word is not in the training data, the model might still recognise the trigger if it has seen the Chinese translation before.</p><p>Logogram character features (char) Chi- nese and Japanese logograms are compositions of one or more characters defining their meanings. Therefore, different words representing the same event often contain similar characters. There are 195 unique Chinese characters for the attack event triggers in the corpus. The most frequently ap- pearing characters are "擊" (strike, attack), "戰" (war, fight), "殺" (kill), "爭" (fight, dispute), and "炸" (bomb, explode).</p><p>Logogram Cangjie features (Cangjie) Chi- nese and Japanese characters can be further de- composed to smaller components called radicals. Certain radicals are more commonly found for a particular event type <ref type="table">(Table 1)</ref>. Cangjie is one of the methods to decompose Chinese characters. It was designed to use on computers with QWERTY keyboards so the radicals can be easily stored, in- dexed and searched by most computer systems. In addition to word and character features, we com- pute Cangjie features for logographic languages.</p><p>Stem features (stem) For many languages character and radical features cannot be generated. We generate stem features in addition to the word features where available. We use the NLTK Snow- ball stemmer for German, Spanish, Finnish, Hun- garian, Dutch and Russian; and the NLTK ISRI stemmer for Arabic. By including a range of lan- guages, we hope to separate the effect of syllabic from semantic components of logograms.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Translation Alignment</head><p>Translated language features require each English word to be aligned to one in the translated sen- tence. We use the translation service obtain all possible translations of a given English word, e.g.:</p><p>EN attack ZH 進攻, 砰擊, 發作, 攻擊, 攻打, 掊擊, 抨擊, ... ES acometida, ataque contra, agresión, ...</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>(2)</head><p>If one of these is in the translated sentence, then an alignment is made. If not, then we use the most likely word translation (underlined above).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Experiments</head><p>We use the TAC KBP 2015 English event nugget data ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Ellis et al., 2015</ref>) for the experi- ments. Development experiments use the train- ing data (LDC2015E73) and the evaluation data (LDC2015R26) is held out for final results. The development corpus contains a total of 158 docu- ments from two genres: 81 newswire documents and 77 discussion forum documents. We split this into 80% for training and 20% for development testing. We use Google Translate to obtain sen- tence and word translations into target languages and derive translated language features to help with the English task. Evaluation uses the offi- cial scorer from the shared task, where a trigger is counted as correct if both the trigger span and its event subtype are correctly identified.</p><p>Comparing languages First, we explore how translated language features perform across the thirteen languages. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref> shows how much each target language improves BASE on devel- opment data. We include all word, stem, charac- ter and Cangjie features as available for each lan- guage. Chinese, Japanese and Korean stand out, with improvements as high as 19.17 points f-score due mostly to large increases in recall. These re- sults suggest that languages with writing systems that facilitate easy decomposition into meaningful subword features are particularly useful.</p><p>Combining languages Next, we test whether system performance can be further improved us- ing TRANS features from multiple languages. We add target languages one at a time in order of indi- vidual performance, and find that Traditional Chi- nese, Japanese and Korean to Simplified Chinese together improve F1 by 2.5 points. This combined feature set is used in the remaining analysis and experimental results. Error analysis We explore characteristic er- rors for BASE+LEX versus BASE+TRANS for the attack event on evaluation data. We ran- domly sample twenty instances where one is cor- rect and the other is incorrect. Of six LEX FN er- rors, two are triggers not seen in the training data, e.g., 'wages' (Transfer-Money), and 'resignation' (End-Position). In other cases, there seem to be too few training instances, e.g., 'pardoning' (Par- don) only appears once in the training data. The TRANS FN error is due to a bad translation in which 'strike' (Attack) is a translated to the 'work stoppage' sense instead of the 'forceful hit' sense.</p><p>For both systems, most FP errors correspond to cases with challenging ambiguity. For instance, both systems label 'appeal' as Justice.Appeal event in two sentences where the word 'appeal' means 'ask for aid', instead of 'taking a court case to a higher court'. The translation was incorrect in this case. Similarly, 'report' appears six times in the training data as three different event types (Broadcast, Correspondence, Move-Person).</p><p>Long-tail generalisation <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Table 2</ref> shows type- level results for BASE+LEX and BASE+TRANS compared to BASE alone. The generalisation fea- ture sets outperform the baseline for all but three of the 38 event types. For Pardon, BASE ob- tains 97 F1 so there is little room for improve- ment. For Execute, LEX features have no ef- fect while TRANS doubles BASE F1. Contact is the only type where generalisation features are harmful. Ignoring ties, BASE+TRANS performs best on more types (13) than BASE+LEX (11). TRANS appears to help more with long-tail en- tity types that have fewer training instances (e.g., Bankruptcy, Appeal, Born). Encouragingly, this  analysis also suggests that LEX and TRANS can be complementary, with LEX doing particularly well on some types (e.g., Trial-Hearing, Corre- spond) and TRANS doing particularly well on oth- ers (e.g., Transfer-Money, Release-Parole).  This is 20.6 points higher than the baseline fea- tures alone, and improves both the precision of LEX and the recall of TRANS.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Final Results and Discussion</head><p>The main appeal of the approach here is that translated character and radical features are easy to obtain using off-the-shelf tools. This provides a simple technique to capture semantic information and leverage the word sense disambiguation en- coded in translation models trained over very large datasets. Given the positive results here, we plan to explore translation and alignment strategies to improve precision. We also plan to quantify the effect of different translation systems and system change over time.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Conclusion</head><p>We described an event detection system leverag- ing features from off-the-shelf automatic transla- tion to improve generalisation to new data. Chi- nese, Japanese and Korean prove especially useful as they provide natural decomposition into infor- mative subword features, i.e., characters (Chinese and Japanese), radicals (Chinese and Japanese) and syllables (Korean). None of the nine other lan- guages explored provide similar levels of natural decomposition and none provided additional ben- efit. The best system includes Chinese, Japanese and Korean character features. These translated language features improve f-score by 3 points on top of the English-only generalisation features from WordNet, Nomlex and Brown clusters.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: Effect of individual languages on development data, showing the difference in precision, recall and F1 compared to the BASE scores of 55.16, 20.62 and 30.02. AR:Arabic, DE:German, ES:Spanish, FI:Finnish, HI:Hindi, HU:Hungarian, JA:Japanese, KO:Korean, NL:Dutch, RU:Russian, TR:Turkish, ZH:Chinese (Simplified), ZHCN:Chinese (Traditional).</figDesc><graphic url="image-1.png" coords="4,72.00,62.81,453.54,142.77" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" validated="false"><head>Table 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Comparing instance count in training (Trn) and test 
(Tst) to F1 for BASE (BA), LEX (LX) and TRANS (TR). 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" validated="false"><head>Table 3 contains</head><label>3</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>final results on the held-out eval-
uation data. The final translated language fea-
ture set (TRANS) comprises word, character and 
Cangjie features from Traditional Chinese, Sim-
plified Chinese, Japanese and Korean. TRANS 
features provide a large F1 improvement of 17.4 
over the baseline (BASE), similar to the bench-
mark lexical generalisation features (LEX). They 
differ in precision-recall tradeoff, with higher re-
call but lower precision from TRANS. LEX and 
TRANS are complementary, giving F1 of 55.0. </table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3" validated="false"><head>Table 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Final results comparing translated language fea-
tures (TRANS) to benchmark lexical generalisation features 
(LEX). BASE+LEX is our implementation of the core Hong 
et al. classifier. TAC KPB 2015 #1 corresponds to reported re-
sults for Hong et al. including semi-supervised learning. TAC 
KPB 2015 shared task has 38 runs submitted from 14 teams. 

</table></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/ Cangjie_input_method</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>We wish to thank Will Radford and the anonymous reviewers for their helpful feedback. This research is funded by the Capital Markets Co-operative Re-search Centre. Ben Hachey is the recipient of an Australian Research Council Discovery Early Ca-reer Researcher Award (DE120102900).</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Paraphrasing with bilingual parallel corpora</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Colin</forename><surname>Bannard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chris</forename><surname>Callison-Burch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="doi">10.3115/1219840.1219914</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.3115/1219840.1219914" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="597" to="604" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Class-based n-gram models of natural language</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Peter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Peter</forename><forename type="middle">V</forename><surname>Brown</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Robert</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Desouza</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Vincent</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Mercer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jenifer</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Della Pietra</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Lai</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://www.aclweb.org/anthology/J/J92/J92-4003.pdf" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Computational Linguistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">18</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="467" to="479" />
			<date type="published" when="1992" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Overview of linguistic resources for the TAC KBP 2015 evaluations: Methodologies and results</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Joe</forename><surname>Ellis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jeremy</forename><surname>Getman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dana</forename><surname>Fore</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Neil</forename><surname>Kuster</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Zhiyi</forename><surname>Song</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ann</forename><surname>Bies</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Stephanie</forename><surname>Strassel</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Text Analysis Conference</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">RPI BLENDER TAC-KBP2015 system description</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yu</forename><surname>Hong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Di</forename><surname>Lu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dian</forename><surname>Yu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xiaoman</forename><surname>Pan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xiaobin</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yadong</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lifu</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Heng</forename><surname>Ji</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Text Analysis Conference</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Cross-lingual predicate cluster acquisition to improve bilingual event extraction by inductive learning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ji</forename><surname>Heng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://www.aclweb.org/anthology/W09-1704" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">NAACL Workshop on Unsupervised and Minimally Supervised Learning of Lexical Semantics</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="27" to="35" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Weakly supervised named entity transliteration and discovery from multilingual comparable corpora</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alexandre</forename><surname>Klementiev</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dan</forename><surname>Roth</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="doi">10.3115/1220175.1220278</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.3115/1220175.1220278" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">International Conference on Computational Linguistics and Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="817" to="824" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Rich ERE Annotation Guidelines Overview. Linguistic Data Consortium. Version 4.1. Accessed</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ldc</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://cairo.lti.cs.cmu.edu/kbp/2015/event/summary_rich_ere_v4.1.pdf" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015-11-14" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">SemEval2010 task 3: Cross-lingual word sense disambiguation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Els</forename><surname>Lefever</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Veronique</forename><surname>Hoste</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://www.aclweb.org/anthology/S10-1003" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">International Workshop on Semantic Evaluation</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="15" to="20" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Employing compositional semantics and discourse consistency in chinese event extraction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Peifeng</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Guodong</forename><surname>Zhou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Qiaoming</forename><surname>Zhu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Libin</forename><surname>Hou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://www.aclweb.org/anthology/D12-1092" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Joint Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing and Computational Natural Language Learning</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1006" to="1016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Nomlex: A lexicon of nominalizations</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Catherine</forename><surname>Macleod</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ralph</forename><surname>Grishman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Adam</forename><surname>Meyers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Leslie</forename><surname>Barrett</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ruth</forename><surname>Reeves</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Euralex International Congress</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="187" to="193" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Wordnet: A lexical database for english</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">George</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Miller</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="doi">10.1145/219717.219748</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1145/219717.219748" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Commun. ACM</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">38</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="39" to="41" />
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">TAC KBP Event Detection and Coreference Tasks for English. Version 1.0. Accessed</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Teruko</forename><surname>Mitamura</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Eduard</forename><surname>Hovy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://cairo.lti.cs.cmu.edu/kbp/2015/event/Event_Mention_Detection_and_Coreference-2015-v1.1.pdf" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015-11-14" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Representing text chunks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Erik</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Tjong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kim</forename><surname>Sang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jorn</forename><surname>Veenstra</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="doi">10.3115/977035.977059</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.3115/977035.977059" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Conference of the European Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="173" to="179" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Word representations: A simple and general method for semi-supervised learning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Joseph</forename><surname>Turian</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lev-Arie</forename><surname>Ratinov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yoshua</forename><surname>Bengio</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://www.aclweb.org/anthology/P10-1040" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="384" to="394" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Using bilingual knowledge and ensemble techniques for unsupervised Chinese sentiment analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xiaojun</forename><surname>Wan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://www.aclweb.org/anthology/D08-1058" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</title>
		<meeting>the Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="553" to="561" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Bilingual event extraction: a case study on trigger type determination</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Zhu</forename><surname>Zhu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Shoushan</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Guodong</forename><surname>Zhou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rui</forename><surname>Xia</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://www.aclweb.org/anthology/P14-2136" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="842" to="847" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
