<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T10:08+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Olelo: A Question Answering Application for Biomedicine</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
				<availability status="unknown"><p>Copyright Association for Computational Linguistics</p>
				</availability>
				<date>July 30-August 4, 2017. July 30-August 4, 2017</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mariana</forename><surname>Neves</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hendrik</forename><surname>Folkerts</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marcel</forename><surname>Jankrift</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Julian</forename><surname>Niedermeier</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Toni</forename><surname>Stachewicz</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sören</forename><surname>Tietböhl</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Milena</forename><surname>Kraus</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Matthias</forename><surname>Uflacker</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Olelo: A Question Answering Application for Biomedicine</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of ACL 2017, System Demonstrations</title>
						<meeting>ACL 2017, System Demonstrations <address><addrLine>Vancouver, Canada; Vancouver, Canada</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="61" to="66"/>
							<date type="published">July 30-August 4, 2017. July 30-August 4, 2017</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="DOI">10.18653/v1/p17-4011</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Despite the importance of the biomedi-cal domain, there are few reliable applications to support researchers and physicians for retrieving particular facts that fit their needs. Users typically rely on search engines that only support keyword-and filter-based searches. We present Olelo, a question answering system for biomedicine. Olelo is built on top of an in-memory database, integrates domain resources , such as document collections and terminologies, and uses various natural language processing components. Olelo is fast, intuitive and easy to use. We evaluated the systems on two use cases: answering questions related to a particular gene and on the BioASQ benchmark. Olelo is available at: http://hpi.de/ plattner/olelo.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Biomedical researchers and physicians regularly query the scientific literature for particular facts, e.g., a syndrome caused by mutations on a partic- ular gene or treatments for a certain disease. For this purposes, users usually rely on the PubMed search engine 1 , which indexes millions of publica- tions available in the Medline database. Similar to classical information retrieval (IR) systems, input to PubMed is usually in the form of keywords, and alternatively MeSH concepts, and output is usu- ally a list of documents.</p><p>For instance, when searching for diseases which could be caused by mutations on the CFTR gene, the user would simply write the gene name in PubMed's input field. For this example, he would 1 http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed be presented with a list of 9227 potentially rele- vant publications (as of <ref type="bibr">February/2017)</ref>.</p><p>There are plenty of other Web applications for searching and navigating through the scientific biomedical literature, as surveyed in <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Lu, 2011)</ref>. However, most of these systems rely on sim- ple natural language processing (NLP) techniques, such as tokenization and named-entity recognition (NER). Their functionalities are restricted to rank- ing documents with the support of domain termi- nologies, enriching publications with concepts and clustering similar documents.</p><p>Question answering (QA) can support biomed- ical professionals by allowing input in the form of natural questions and by providing exact an- swers and customized short summaries in re- turn ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Athenikos and Han, 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Neves and Leser, 2015)</ref>. We are aware of three of such systems for biomedicine (cf. Section 2), however, current so- lutions still fail to fulfill the needs of users: (i) In most of them, no question understanding is carried out on the questions. (ii) Those that do make use of more complex NLP techniques (e.g., HONQA <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Cruchet et al., 2009)</ref>) cannot output answers in real time. (iii) The output is usually in the form of a list of documents, instead of short answers. (iv) They provide no innovative or NLP-based means to further explore the scientific literature.</p><p>We present Olelo, a QA system for the biomed- ical domain. It indexes biomedical abstracts and full texts, relies on a fast in-memory database (IMDB) for storage and document indexing and implements various NLP procedures, such as domain-specific NER, question type detection, an- swer type detection and answer extraction. We evaluated the methods behind Olelo in the scope of the BioASQ challenge ( <ref type="bibr">Tsatsaronis et al., 2015)</ref>, the most comprehensive shared task on biomedical QA. We participated in the last three challenges and obtained top results for snippets retrieval and ideal answers (customized summaries) in the last two editions <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(Neves, 2014</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Neves, , 2015</ref>.</p><p>Olelo provides solutions for the shortcomings listed above: (i) It detects both the question type and answer type. (ii) It includes various NLP com- ponents and outputs answers in real time (cf. Sec- tion 5). (iii) It always outputs a short answer, either exact answers or short summaries, while also allowing users to explore the corresponding documents. (iv) Users can navigate through the answers and their corresponding semantic types, check MeSH definition for terms, create document collections, generate customized summaries and query for similar documents, among other tasks. Finally, Olelo is an open-access system and no login is required. We tested it in multiple Web browsers, but we recommend Chrome for optimal results.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Related Work</head><p>MEDIE 2 was one of the first QA-inspired sys- tem for biomedicine ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Miyao et al., 2006</ref>). It allows users to pose questions in the form of subject-object-verb (SOV) structures. For in- stance, the question "What does p53 activate?" needs to be split into its parts: "p53" (subject), "activate" (verb), and no object (i.e., the expected answer). MEDIE relies on domain ontologies, parsing and predicate-argument structures (PAS) to search Medline. However, SOV structures are not a user-friendly input, given that many of the biomedical users have no advanced knowledge on linguistics.</p><p>We are only aware of three other QA sys- tems for biomedicine: AskHermes 3 , EAGLi <ref type="bibr">4</ref> and HONQA <ref type="bibr">5</ref> . All of them support input in the form of questions but present result in a different ways.</p><p>AskHermes <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Cao et al., 2011</ref>) outputs lists of snippets and clusters of terms, but the result page is often far too long. Their methods involve reg- ular expressions for question understanding, ques- tion target classification, concept recognition and passage ranking based on the BM25 model. The document collection includes Medline articles and Wikipedia documents.</p><p>EAGLi ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Gobeill et al., 2015</ref>) provides answers based on concepts from the Gene Ontology (GO). Even when no answers are found for a question, EAGLi always outputs a list of relevant publica- tions. It indexes Medline documents locally in the Terrier IR platform and uses Okapi BM25 to rank documents. HONQA ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Cruchet et al., 2009</ref>) considers docu- ments from certified websites from the Health On the Net <ref type="figure">(HON)</ref> and supports French and Italian, besides the English language. The answer type de- tection is based on the UMLS database and the ar- chitecture of the systems seems to follow the typ- ical QA workflow. However, no further details are described in their publication.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">System Architecture</head><p>The architecture of Olelo follows the usual com- ponents of a QA system <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Athenikos and Han, 2010)</ref>, i.e., document indexing, question process- ing, passage retrieval and answer processing (cf. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref>). In this section we present a short overview of the many tasks inside each of these components. We previously published our meth- ods for multi-document summarization ( , which we applied not only for biomedical QA but also for gene-specific sum- maries. Finally, our participations on the BioASQ challenges also provide insights on previous and current methods behind our system <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(Neves, 2014</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Neves, , 2015</ref>. Document Indexing. We index the document collection and the questions into an IMDB <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Plattner, 2013</ref>), namely, the SAP HANA database. This database stores data in the main memory and includes other desirable features for on-line QA systems, such as multi-core processing, paral- lelization, lightweight compression and partition- ing. Our document collection currently consists of abstracts from Medline 6 and full text publica- tions from PubMed Central Open Access subset <ref type="bibr">7</ref> . The document collection is regularly updated to account for new publications.</p><p>When indexed in the database, documents and questions are processed using built-in text analy- sis procedures from the IMDB, namely, sentence splitting, tokenization, stemming, part-of-speech (POS) tagging and NER (cf. <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Table 1</ref>). The latter is   Question Processing. Olelo currently supports three types of questions: (i) factoid; (ii) definition; and (iii) summary. A factoid question requires one or more short answers in return, such as a list of disease names, definition questions query for a particular definition of a concept, while summary questions expect a short summary about a topic. Components in this step include the detection of the question type via simple regular expressions, followed by the detection of the answer type, in the case of factoid questions. This step also com- prises the detection of the headword via regular expression and the identification of its semantic types with the support of the previously detected named entities. The semantic types correspond to the ones defined by UMLS semantic types ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Bodenreider, 2004</ref>). Finally, a query is built based on surface forms of tokens, as well as previously detected MeSH and UMLS terms.</p><p>Passage Retrieval. The system ranks docu- ments and passages based on built-in features of the IMDB. It matches keywords from the query to the documents in an approximate way, including linguistic variations. We start by considering all keywords in the query and we drop some of them later if no document match is found.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Answer</head><p>Processing. An answer is produced de- pending on the question type. In case of a defini- tion question, the system simply shows the corre- sponding MeSH term along with its definition, as originally included in the MeSH terminology. In the case of factoid questions, Olelo returns MeSH terms which belong to the corresponding seman- tic type that was previously detected. Lastly, the system builds a customized summary for summary questions, based on the retrieved documents and on the query.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Use Cases</head><p>In this section we show two use cases of obtain- ing precise answers for particular questions. The examples include a question related to a specific gene and two questions from the BioASQ bench- mark. We also present a preliminary comparison of our systems to three others on-line biomedical QA applications.</p><p>The "Tutorial" page in Olelo contains more de- tails on the various functionalities of the system. Some few parameters can be set on the "Setting" page, such as the minimal year of publication, the size of the summary (in terms of number of sen- tence, default value is 5) and the number of doc- uments considered when generating a summary (default value is 20).</p><p>Gene-related question. This use case focuses on the gene CFTR, which was one of the cho- sen #GeneOfTheWeek in a campaign promoted in Twitter by the Ensembl database of genes. Mu- tations on genes are common causes of diseases, therefore, a user could post the following question to Olelo: "What are the diseases related to mu- tations on the CFTR gene?". Olelo returns a list of potential answers to the question (cf. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 2)</ref>, and indeed, "cystic fibrosis" is associated to the re- ferred gene <ref type="bibr">10</ref> . By clicking on "cystic fibrosis", its definition in MeSH is shown, and Olelo informs that 349 relevant document were found (blue but- ton on the bottom). By clicking on this button, a document is shown and this is indeed relevant, as we can confirm by reading the first sentence of its abstract. At this point, the user has many ways to navigate further on the topic, for instance: (a) flick through the rest of the documents; (b) create a summary for this document collection; (c) click on a term (in blue) to learn more about it; (d) vi- sualize full details on the publication (small icon besides its title); (e) navigate through the seman- tic types listed for cystic fibrosis; or (f) click on another disease name, i.e., "asthma".</p><p>BioASQ benchmark questions. Currently, <ref type="bibr">BioASQ (Tsatsaronis et al., 2015</ref>) is the most comprehensive benchmark for QA systems in biomedicine. We selected one summary and one factoid question to illustrate the results returned by Olelo for different question types. For the question "What is the Barr body?" (identifier 55152c0a46478f2f2c000004), the system returns a short summary whose first sentence indeed contains the answer to the question: "The Barr body is the inactive X chromosome in a female somatic cell." (PubMed article 21416650). On the other hand, for the factoid question "List chromosomes that have been linked to Arnold Chiari syndrome in the literature.", Olelo presents a list of chromosome names. Indeed, the fol- lowing are the official answers in the BioASQ benchmark: "1", "3", "5", "6", "8", "9", "12", "13", "15", "16", "18", "22", "X", "Y". For this particular example, Olelo outputs an even more comprehensive answer than BioASQ, as the MeSH terms include the word "chomosome".</p><p>Preliminary evaluation. We recently compared Olelo to the three other biomedical QA systems (cf. Section 2) by manually posing 10 randomly selected factoid questions from BioASQ. We man- ually recorded the response time of each system and the experiments were carried out outside of the network of our institute. HONQA did not pro- vide results for any of the questions because an error occurred in the system. Olelo found correct answers for four questions (in the returned sum- maries), EAGLi for two of them (in the titles of the returned documents) and AskHermes for one of them (among the many returned sentences). Re- garding the response time, Olelo was the fastest one (average of 8.8 seconds), followed by AskHer- mes (average of 10.1 seconds) and EAGLi (aver- age of 58.6 seconds).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Conclusions and Future Work</head><p>We presented our Olelo QA system for the biomedical domain. Olelo relies on built-in NLP procedures of an in-memory database and SQL procedures for the various QA components, such as multi-document summarization and detection of answer type. We have shown examples of the output provided by Olelo when obtaining informa- tion for a particular gene and for checking the an- swers for two questions from the BioASQ bench- mark.</p><p>Nevertheless, the methods behind Olelo still present room for improvement: (a) The system does not always detect factoid questions correctly given the simple rules it uses for question type de- tection. In these cases, Olelo generates a short summary from the corresponding relevant docu- ments. (b) Answers are limited to existing MeSH terms, which also support our system for further navigation (cf. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figures 2 and 3)</ref>. Indeed, our ex- periments show that we cannot provide answers for many of the questions which expect a gene or protein name, both weakly supported in MeSH, but very frequent in BioASQ ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Neves and Kraus, 2016)</ref>. (c) Our document and passage retrieval components currently rely on approximate match-  ing of tokens and named entities but do not con- sider state-of-the-art IR methods, such as TF-IDF. (d) The sentences that belong to a summary could have been better arranged. The fluency of the sum- maries is not optimal and we do not deal with co- references, such as pronouns (e.g., "we") which frequently occur in the original sentences. How- ever, when compared to other biomedical QA sys- tems, Olelo performs faster and provides focused answers for most of the questions, instead of a long list of documents. Finally, it provides means to further explore the biomedical literature.</p><p>Olelo is under permanent development and im- provements are already being implemented on multiple levels: (a) integration of more advanced NLP components, such as chunking and semantic role labeling; (b) support for yes/no questions and improvement of the extraction of exact answers based on deep learning; (c) integration of addi- tional biomedical documents, e.g., clinical trials, as well as documents in other languages.</p><p>Finally, in its current state, adaptation of our methods to a new domain would not require ma- jor changes. Minor changes are necessary on the question processing step, which relies on specific ontologies, as well as creating new dictionaries for the NER component. In summary, adaptation of the system would mainly consist on the integra- tion of new document collections and specific ter- minologies.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: Natural language processing components of Olelo question answering system.</figDesc><graphic url="image-1.png" coords="3,83.65,62.81,430.24,221.10" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2: List of answers (disease names) potentially caused by the CFTR gene (on the left) and an overview of one of the relevant publications which contains the answer (on the right).</figDesc><graphic url="image-3.png" coords="5,82.47,365.84,432.60,253.40" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Figure 3: Short paragraph for a summary question (on the left) and list of answers (chromosome names) for a factoid question (on the right), both from the BioASQ dataset.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" validated="false"><head>Table 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Statistics on documents, sentences and 
named entities (as of February/2017). 

based on customized dictionaries for the biomed-
ical domain, which we compiled based on two 
domain resources: the Medical Subject Headings 
(MeSH) 8 and the Unified Medical Language Sys-
tem (UMLS) 9 . 

</table></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="2"> http://www.nactem.ac.uk/medie/ 3 http://www.askhermes.org/ 4 http://eagl.unige.ch/EAGLi 5 http://www.hon.ch/QA/</note>

			<note place="foot" n="6"> https://www.nlm.nih.gov/bsd/ pmresources.html 7 https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/ tools/openftlist/</note>

			<note place="foot" n="8"> https://www.nlm.nih.gov/mesh/ 9 https://www.nlm.nih.gov/research/ umls/</note>

			<note place="foot" n="10"> http://www.ensembl.org/Homo_sapiens/ Gene/Summary?g=ENSG00000001626</note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Biomedical question answering: A survey</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Sofia</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hyoil</forename><surname>Athenikos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Han</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="doi">10.1016/j.cmpb.2009.10.003</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cmpb.2009.10.003" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Computer Methods and Programs in Biomedicine</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">99</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="24" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The unified medical language system (umls): integrating biomedical terminology</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Olivier</forename><surname>Bodenreider</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="doi">10.1093/nar/gkh061</idno>
		<idno>D267-D270</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1093/nar/gkh061" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nucleic Acids Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">32</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Askhermes: An online question answering system for complex clinical questions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yonggang</forename><surname>Cao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Feifan</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Pippa</forename><surname>Simpson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lamont</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Antieau</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Andrew</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Bennett</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">James</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Cimino</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">John</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Ely</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hong</forename><surname>Yu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/21256977" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Biomedical Informatics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">44</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="277" to="288" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">What about trust in the question answering world?</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sarah</forename><surname>Cruchet</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Arnaud</forename><surname>Gaudinat</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Thomas</forename><surname>Rindflesch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Celia</forename><surname>Boyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the AMIA Annual Symposium</title>
		<meeting>the AMIA Annual Symposium<address><addrLine>San Francisco, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="5" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Deep question answering for protein annotation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Julien</forename><surname>Gobeill</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Arnaud</forename><surname>Gaudinat</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Emilie</forename><surname>Pasche</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dina</forename><surname>Vishnyakova</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Pascale</forename><surname>Gaudet</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Amos</forename><surname>Bairoch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Patrick</forename><surname>Ruch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="doi">10.1093/database/bav081</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1093/database/bav081" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Database</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page">81</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Pubmed and beyond: a survey of web tools for searching biomedical literature</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Zhiyong</forename><surname>Lu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Semantic retrieval for the accurate identification of relational concepts in massive textbases</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yusuke</forename><surname>Miyao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tomoko</forename><surname>Ohta</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Katsuya</forename><surname>Masuda</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yoshimasa</forename><surname>Tsuruoka</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kazuhiro</forename><surname>Yoshida</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Takashi</forename><surname>Ninomiya</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jun&amp;apos;ichi</forename><surname>Tsujii</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="doi">10.3115/1220175.1220303</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.3115/1220175.1220303" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 21st International Conference on Computational Linguistics and the 44th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the 21st International Conference on Computational Linguistics and the 44th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics<address><addrLine>Stroudsburg, PA, USA, ACL-44</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1017" to="1024" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Hpi in-memory-based database system in task 2b of bioasq</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mariana</forename><surname>Neves</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://ceur-ws.org/Vol-1180/CLEF2014wn-QA-Neves2014.pdf" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Working Notes for CLEF 2014 Conference</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Sheffield, UK</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014-09-15" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1337" to="1347" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mariana</forename><surname>Neves</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://ceur-ws.org/Vol-1391/59-CR.pdf" />
		<title level="m">Hpi question answering system in the bioasq 2015 challenge. In Working Notes for CLEF 2015 Conference</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Toulouse, France</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>September 8-11</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Biomedlat corpus: Annotation of the lexical answer type for biomedical questions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mariana</forename><surname>Neves</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Milena</forename><surname>Kraus</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://aclweb.org/anthology/W16-4407" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Open Knowledge Base and Question Answering Workshop (OKBQA 2016</title>
		<meeting>the Open Knowledge Base and Question Answering Workshop (OKBQA 2016<address><addrLine>Osaka, Japan</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="49" to="58" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>The COLING 2016 Organizing Committee</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Question answering for biology</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mariana</forename><surname>Neves</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ulf</forename><surname>Leser</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Methods</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">74</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="36" to="46" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Text mining of biomedical literature</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="doi">10.1016/j.ymeth.2014.10.023</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ymeth.2014.10.023" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">A Course in In-Memory Data Management: The Inner Mechanics of In-Memory Databases</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hasso</forename><surname>Plattner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>1st edition</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Entitysupported summarization of biomedical abstracts</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Frederik</forename><surname>Schulze</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mariana</forename><surname>Neves</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://aclweb.org/anthology/W16-5105" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Fifth Workshop on Building and Evaluating Resources for Biomedical Text Mining</title>
		<meeting>the Fifth Workshop on Building and Evaluating Resources for Biomedical Text Mining<address><addrLine>Osaka, Japan</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="40" to="49" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>The COLING 2016 Organizing Committee</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Hpi question answering system in bioasq</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Frederik</forename><surname>Schulze</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ricarda</forename><surname>Schüler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tim</forename><surname>Draeger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Daniel</forename><surname>Dummer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alexander</forename><surname>Ernst</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Pedro</forename><surname>Flemming</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Cindy</forename><surname>Perscheid</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mariana</forename><surname>Neves</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://aclweb.org/anthology/W/W16/W16-3105.pdf" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Fourth BioASQ workshop at the Conference of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the Fourth BioASQ workshop at the Conference of the Association for Computational Linguistics</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="38" to="44" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
