<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T10:59+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Predicting Native Language from Gaze</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
				<availability status="unknown"><p>Copyright Association for Computational Linguistics</p>
				</availability>
				<date>July 30-August 4, 2017. July 30-August 4, 2017</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yevgeni</forename><surname>Berzak</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chie</forename><surname>Nakamura</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Suzanne</forename><surname>Flynn</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Boris</forename><surname>Katz</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Predicting Native Language from Gaze</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 55th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (Volume 1: Long Papers)</title>
						<meeting>the 55th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (Volume 1: Long Papers) <address><addrLine>Vancouver, Canada; Vancouver, Canada</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="541" to="551"/>
							<date type="published">July 30-August 4, 2017. July 30-August 4, 2017</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="DOI">10.18653/v1/p17-1050</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>A fundamental question in language learning concerns the role of a speaker&apos;s first language in second language acquisition. We present a novel methodology for studying this question: analysis of eye-movement patterns in second language reading of free-form text. Using this methodology, we demonstrate for the first time that the native language of English learners can be predicted from their gaze fixations when reading English. We provide analysis of classifier uncertainty and learned features, which indicates that differences in English reading are likely to be rooted in linguistic divergences across native languages. The presented framework complements production studies and offers new ground for advancing research on multilingualism. 1</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>The influence of a speaker's native language on learning and performance in a foreign language, also known as cross-linguistic transfer, has been studied for several decades in linguistics and psy- chology <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">(Odlin, 1989;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b23">Martohardjono and Flynn, 1995;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Jarvis and Pavlenko, 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Berkes and Flynn, 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Alonso, 2015)</ref>. The growing avail- ably of learner corpora has also sparked interest in cross-linguistic influence phenomena in NLP, where studies have explored the task of Native Language Identification (NLI) <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">(Tetreault et al., 2013)</ref>, as well as analysis of textual features in relation to the author's native language <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">(Jarvis and Crossley, 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b32">Swanson and Charniak, 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b21">Malmasi and Dras, 2014)</ref>. Despite these advances, the extent and nature of first language influence in second language processing remains far from be- ing established. Crucially, most prior work on this topic focused on production, while little is cur- rently known about cross-linguistic influence in language comprehension.</p><p>In this work, we present a novel framework for studying cross-linguistic influence in language comprehension using eyetracking for reading and free-form native English text. We collect and ana- lyze English newswire reading data from 182 par- ticipants, including 145 English as Second Lan- guage (ESL) learners from four different native language backgrounds: Chinese, Japanese, Por- tuguese and Spanish, as well as 37 native English speakers. Each participant reads 156 English sen- tences, half of which are shared across all partic- ipants, and the remaining half are individual to each participant. All the sentences are manually annotated with part-of-speech (POS) tags and syn- tactic dependency trees.</p><p>We then introduce the task of Native Language Identification from Reading (NLIR), which re- quires predicting a subject's native language from gaze while reading text in a second language. Fo- cusing on ESL participants and using a log-linear classifier with word fixation times normalized for reading speed as features, we obtain 71.03 NLIR accuracy in the shared sentences regime. We fur- ther demonstrate that NLIR can be generalized effectively to the individual sentences regime, in which each subject reads a different set of sen- tences, by grouping fixations according to linguis- tically motivated clustering criteria. In this regime, we obtain an NLIR accuracy of 51.03.</p><p>Further on, we provide classification and feature analyses, suggesting that the signal underlying NLIR is likely to be related to linguistic charac- teristics of the respective native languages. First, drawing on previous work on ESL production, we observe that classifier uncertainty in NLIR corre- lates with global linguistic similarities across na- tive languages. In other words, the more similar are the languages, the more similar are the read- ing patterns of their native speakers in English. Second, we perform feature analysis across na- tive and non-native English speakers, and discuss structural and lexical factors that could potentially drive some of the non-native reading patterns in each of our native languages. Taken together, our results provide evidence for a systematic influence of native language properties on reading, and by extension, on online processing and comprehen- sion in a second language.</p><p>To summarize, we introduce a novel frame- work for studying cross-linguistic influence in lan- guage learning by using eyetracking for reading free-form English text. We demonstrate the util- ity of this framework in the following ways. First, we obtain the first NLIR results, addressing both the shared and the individual textual input scenar- ios. We further show that reading preserves lin- guistic similarities across native languages of ESL readers, and perform feature analysis, highlight- ing key distinctive reading patterns in each native language. The proposed framework complements and extends production studies, and can inform linguistic inquiry on cross-linguistic influence.</p><p>This paper is structured as follows. In sec- tion 2 we present the data and our experimental setup. Section 3 describes our approach to NLIR and summarizes the classification results. We ana- lyze cross-linguistic influence in reading in section 4. In section 4.1 we examine NLIR classification uncertainty in relation to linguistic similarities be- tween native languages. In section 4.2 we discuss several key fixation features associated with dif- ferent native languages. Section 5 surveys related work, and section 6 concludes.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Experimental Setup Participants</head><p>We recruited 182 adult participants. Of those, 37 are native English speakers and 145 are ESL learn- ers from four native language backgrounds: Chi- nese, Japanese, Portuguese and Spanish. All the participants in the experiment are native speakers of only one language. The ESL speakers were tested for English proficiency using the grammar and listening sections of the Michigan English test (MET), which consist of 50 multiple choice ques- tions. The English proficiency score was calcu- lated as the number of correctly answered ques- tions on these modules. The majority of the par- ticipants scored in the intermediate-advanced pro- ficiency range. <ref type="table">Table 1</ref> presents the number of par- ticipants and the mean English proficiency score for each native language group. Additionally, we collected metadata on gender, age, level of ed- ucation, duration of English studies and usage, time spent in English speaking countries and pro- ficiency in any additional language spoken. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head># Participants English Score</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Reading Materials</head><p>We utilize 14,274 randomly selected sentences from the Wall Street Journal part of the Penn Tree- bank (WSJ-PTB) <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">(Marcus et al., 1993)</ref>. To sup- port reading convenience and measurement preci- sion, the maximal sentence length was set to 100 characters, leading to an average sentence length of 11.4 words. Word boundaries are defined as whitespaces. From this sentence pool, 78 sen- tences (900 words) were presented to all partic- ipants (henceforth shared sentences) and the re- maining 14,196 sentences were split into 182 in- dividual batches of 78 sentences (henceforth indi- vidual sentences, averaging 880 words per batch). All the sentences include syntactic annotations from the Universal Dependency Treebank project (UDT) ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">McDonald et al., 2013</ref>). The annotations include PTB POS tags <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">(Santorini, 1990)</ref>, Google universal POS tags ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">Petrov et al., 2012</ref>) and depen- dency trees. The dependency annotations of the UDT are converted automatically from the manual phrase structure tree annotations of the WSJ-PTB.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Gaze Data Collection</head><p>Each participant read 157 sentences. The first sentence was presented to familiarize participants with the experimental setup and was discarded during analysis. The following 156 sentences consisted of 78 shared and 78 individual sen-tences. The shared and the individual sentences were mixed randomly and presented to all partic- ipants in the same order. The experiment was di- vided into three parts, consisting of 52 sentences each. Participants were allowed to take a short break between experimental parts.</p><p>Each sentence was presented on a blank screen as a one-liner. The text appeared in Times font, with font size 23. To encourage attentive reading, upon completion of sentence reading participants answered a simple yes/no question about its con- tent, and were subsequently informed if they an- swered the question correctly. Both the sentences and the questions were triggered by a 300ms gaze on a fixation target (fixation circle for sentences and the letter "Q" for questions) which appeared on a blank screen and was co-located with the be- ginning of the text in the following screen.</p><p>Throughout the experiment, participants held a joystick with buttons for indicating completion of sentence reading and answering the comprehen- sion questions. Eye-movement of participants' dominant eye was recorded using a desktop mount Eyelink 1000 eyetracker, at a sampling rate of 1000Hz. Further details on the experimental setup are provided in appendix A.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Native Language Identification from Reading</head><p>Our first goal is to determine whether the native language of ESL learners can be decoded from their gaze patterns while reading English text. We address this question in two regimes, correspond- ing to our division of reading input into shared and individual sentences. In the shared regime, all the participants read the same set of sentences. Nor- malizing over the reading input, this regime facil- itates focusing on differences in reading behavior across readers. In the individual regime, we use the individual batches from our data to address the more challenging variant of the NLIR task in which the reading material given to each partici- pant is different.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Features</head><p>We seek to utilize features that can provide robust, simple and interpretable characterizations of read- ing patterns. To this end, we use speed normalized fixation duration measures over word sequences.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Fixation Measures</head><p>We utilize three measures of word fixation dura- tion:</p><p>• First Fixation duration (FF) Duration of the first fixation on a word.</p><p>• First Pass duration (FP) Time spent from first entering a word to first leaving it (includ- ing re-fixations within the word).</p><p>• Total Fixation duration (TF) The sum of all fixation times on a word.</p><p>We experiment with fixations over un- igram, bigram and trigram sequences seq i,k = w i , ..., w i+k−1 , k ∈ {1, 2, 3}, where for each metric M ∈ {F F, F P, T F } the fixation time for a sequence M seq i,k is defined as the sum of fixations on individual tokens M w in the sequence 2 .</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">M seq i,k = w ∈seq i,k M w (1)</formula><p>Importantly, we control for variation in reading speeds across subjects by normalizing each sub- jects's sequence fixation times. For each metric M and sequence seq i,k we normalize the sequence fixation time M seq i,k relative to the subject's se- quence fixation times in the textual context of the sequence. The context C is defined as the sen- tence in which the sequence appears for the Words in Fixed Context feature-set and the entire textual input for the Syntactic and Information clusters feature-sets (see definitions of feature-sets below). The normalization term S M,C,k is accordingly de- fined as the metric's fixation time per sequence of length k in the context:</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">S M,C,k = 1 |C| seq k ∈C M seq k (2)</formula><p>We then obtain a normalized fixation time M norm seq i,k as:</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">M norm seq i,k = M seq i,k S M,C,k<label>(3)</label></formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Feature Types</head><p>We use the above presented speed normalized fix- ation metrics to extract three feature-sets, Words in Fixed Context (WFC), Syntactic Clusters (SC) and Information Clusters (IC). WFC is a token-level feature-set that presupposes a fixed textual input for all participants. It is thus applicable only in the shared sentences regime. SC and IC are type- level features which provide abstractions over se- quences of words. Crucially, they can also be ap- plied when participants read different sentences.</p><p>• Words in Fixed Context (WFC) The WFC features capture fixation times on word se- quences in a specific sentence. This feature- set consists of FF, FP and TF times for each of the 900 unigram, 822 bigram, and 744 tri- gram word sequences comprising the shared sentences. The fixation times of each metric are normalized for each participant relative to their fixations on sequences of the same length in the surrounding sentence. As noted above, the WFC feature-set is not applicable in the individual regime, as it requires identi- cal sentences for all participants.</p><p>• • Information Clusters (IC) We also obtain average FF, FP and TF for words clustered according to their length, measured in num- ber of characters. Word length was previ- ously shown to be a strong predictor of infor- mation content (Piantadosi et al., 2011). As such, it provides an alternative abstraction to the syntactic clusters, combining both syntac- tic and lexical information. As with SC fea- tures, we take into account features that ap- pear at least once in the textual input of all participants. For our set of non-native lan- guages, we obtain for each fixation metric 15 unigram, 21 bigram and 23 trigram IC fea- tures in the shared regime, and 12 unigram, 18 bigram and 18 trigram IC features in the individual regime. Notably, this feature-set is very compact, and differently from the syn- tactic clusters, does not rely on the availabil- ity of external annotations.</p><p>In each feature-set, we perform a final prepro- cessing step for each individual feature, in which we derive a zero mean unit variance scaler from the training set feature values, and apply it to trans- form both the training and the test values of the feature to Z scores.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Model</head><p>The experiments are carried out using a log-linear model:</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">p(y|x; θ) = exp(θ · f (x, y)) y ∈Y exp(θ · f (x, y )) (4)</formula><p>where y is the reader's native language, x is the reading input and θ are the model parameters. The classifier is trained with gradient descent using L- BFGS ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Byrd et al., 1995</ref>).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3">Experimental Results</head><p>In table 2 we report 10-fold cross-validation re- sults on NLIR in the shared and the individual ex- perimental regimes for native speakers of Chinese, Japanese, Portuguese and Spanish. We introduce two baselines against which we compare the per- formance of our feature-sets. The majority base- line selects the native language with the largest number of participants. The random clusters base- line clusters words into groups randomly, with the number of groups set to the number of syntactic categories in our data.</p><p>In the shared regime, WFC fixations yield the highest classification rates, substantially outper- forming the cluster feature-sets and the two base- lines. The strongest result using this feature- set, 71.03, is obtained by combining unigram, bi- gram and trigram fixation times. In addition to this outcome, we note that training binary classi- fiers in this setup yields accuracies ranging from 68.49 for the language pair Portuguese and Span- ish, to 93.15 for Spanish and Japanese. These re- sults confirm the effectiveness of the shared input  Generally, we observe that adding bigram and trigram fixations in the shared regime leads to per- formance improvements compared to using un- igram features only. This trend does not hold for the individual sentences, presumably due to a combination of feature sparsity and context vari- ation in this regime. We also note that IC and SC features tend to perform better together than in separation, suggesting that the information en- coded using these feature-sets is to some extent complementary.</p><p>The generalization power of our cluster based feature-sets has both practical and theoretical con- sequences. Practically, they provide useful ab- stractions for performing NLIR over arbitrary tex- tual input. That is, they enable performing this task using any textual input during both training and testing phases. Theoretically, the effectiveness of linguistically motivated features in discerning native languages suggests that linguistic factors play an important role in the ESL reading process. The analysis presented in the following sections will further explore this hypothesis.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Analysis of Cross-Linguistic Influence in ESL Reading</head><p>As mentioned in the previous section, the ability to perform NLIR in general, and the effectiveness of linguistically motivated features in particular, sug- gest that linguistic factors in the native and sec- ond languages are pertinent to ESL reading. In this section we explore this hypothesis further, by analyzing classifier uncertainty and the features learned in the NLIR task.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">Preservation of Linguistic Similarity</head><p>Previous work in NLP suggested a link between textual patterns in ESL production and linguistic similarities of the respective native languages <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">(Nagata and Whittaker, 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b25">Nagata, 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Berzak et al., 2014</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Berzak et al., , 2015</ref>). In particular, <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Berzak et al. (2014)</ref> has demonstrated that NLI classification uncertainty correlates with similarities between languages with respect to their typological fea- tures. Here, we extend this framework and exam- ine if preservation of native language similarities in ESL production is paralleled in reading. Similarly to <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Berzak et al. (2014)</ref> we define the classification uncertainty for a pair of native lan- guages y and y in our data collection D, as the average probability assigned by the NLIR classi- fier to one language given the other being the true native language. This approach provides a robust measure of classification confusion that does not rely on the actual performance of the classifier. We interpret the classifier uncertainty as a similarity measure between the respective languages and de-note it as English Reading Similarity ERS. |D y |+|D y | (5) We compare these reading similarities to the lin- guistic similarities between our native languages. To approximate these similarities, we utilize fea- ture vectors from the URIEL Typological Com- pendium ( <ref type="bibr">Littel et al., 2016</ref>) extracted using the lang2vec tool ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Littell et al., 2017)</ref>. URIEL ag- gregates, fuses and normalizes typological, phy- logenetic and geographical information about the world's languages.</p><p>We obtain all the 103 available morpho- syntactic features in URIEL, which are derived from the World Atlas of Language Structures (WALS) <ref type="bibr">(Dryer and Haspelmath, 2013)</ref>, Syntac- tic Structures of the World's Languages (SSWL) <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Collins and Kayne, 2009</ref>) and Ethnologue ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">Lewis et al., 2015)</ref>. Missing feature values are completed with a KNN classifier. We also extract URIEL's 3,718 language family features derived from Glot- tolog ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Hammarström et al., 2015</ref>). Each of these features represents membership in a branch of Glottolog's world language tree. Truncating fea- tures with the same value for all our languages, we remain with 76 features, consisting of 49 syntactic features and 27 family tree features. The linguistic similarity LS between a pair of languages y and y is then determined by the cosine similarity of their URIEL feature vectors. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 1</ref> presents the URIEL based linguistic similarities for our set of non-native languages against the average NLIR classification uncertain- ties on the cross-validation test samples. The re- sults presented in this figure are based on the un- igram IC+SC feature-set in the individual sen- tences regime. We also provide a graphical il- lustration of the language similarities for each measure, using the Ward clustering algorithm <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">(Ward Jr, 1963)</ref>. We observe a correlation be- tween the two measures which is also reflected in similar hierarchies in the two language trees. Thus, linguistically motived features in English re- veal linguistic similarities across native languages. This outcome supports the hypothesis that English reading differences across native languages are re- lated to linguistic factors. We note that while comparable results are ob- tained for the IC and SC feature-sets, together and in separation in the shared regime, WFC features in the shared regime do not exhibit a clear un- certainty distinction when comparing across the pairs Japanese and Spanish, Japanese and Por- tuguese, Chinese and Spanish, and Chinese and Portuguese. Instead, this feature-set yields very low uncertainty, and correspondingly very high performance ranging from 90.41 to 93.15, for all four language pairs.</p><formula xml:id="formula_4">LS y,y = v y · v y v y v y (6)</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">Feature Analysis</head><p>Our framework enables not only native language classification, but also exploratory analysis of na- tive language specific reading patterns in English. The basic question that we examine in this respect is on which features do readers of different native language groups spend more versus less time. We also discuss several potential relations of the ob- served reading time differences to usage patterns and grammatical errors committed by speakers of our four native languages in production. We obtain this information by extracting grammatical error counts from the CLC FCE corpus <ref type="bibr" target="#b38">(Yannakoudakis et al., 2011)</ref>, and from the ngram frequency anal- ysis in <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">Nagata and Whittaker (2013)</ref>.</p><p>In order to obtain a common benchmark for reading time comparisons across non-native speakers, in this analysis we also consider our group of native English speakers. In this context, we train four binary classifiers that discern each of the non-native groups from native English speak- ers based on TF times over unigram PTB POS tags in the shared regime. The features with the strongest positive and negative weights learned by these classifiers are presented in table 3. These features serve as a reference point for selecting the case studies discussed below.</p><p>Interestingly, some of the reading features that are most predictive of each native language lend themselves to linguistic interpretation with respect to structural factors. For example, in Japanese and Chinese we observe shorter reading times for de- terminers (DT), which do not exist in these lan- guages. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 2a</ref> presents the mean TF times for determiners in all five native languages, suggest- ing that native speakers of Portuguese and Span- ish, which do have determiners, do not exhibit re- duced reading times on this structure compared to natives. In ESL production, missing determiner errors are the most frequent error for native speak- ers of Japanese and third most common error for native speakers of Chinese.</p><p>In <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">figure 2b</ref> we present the mean TF read- ing times for pronouns (PRP), where we also see shorter reading times by natives of Japanese and Chinese as compared to English natives. In both languages pronouns can be omitted both in object and subject positions. Portuguese and Spanish, in which pronoun omission is restricted to the subject position present similar albeit weaker tendency. <ref type="table">Table 3</ref>: PTB POS features with the strongest weights learned in non-native versus native clas- sification for each native language in the shared regime. Feature types presented in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">figure 2</ref> are highlighted in bold. In <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">figure 2c</ref> we further observe that differ- ently from natives of Chinese and Japanese, native speakers of Portuguese and Spanish spend more time on NN+POS in head final possessives such as "the public's confidence". While similar construc- tions exist in Chinese and Japanese, the NN+POS combination is expressed in Portuguese and Span- ish as a head initial NN of NN. This form exists in English (e.g. "the confidence of the public") and is preferred by speakers of these languages in ESL writing ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">Nagata and Whittaker, 2013)</ref>. As an ad- ditional baseline for this construction, we provide the TF times for NN in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">figure 2d</ref>. There, relative to English natives, we observe longer reading times for Japanese and Chinese and comparable times for Portuguese and Spanish.</p><formula xml:id="formula_5">Negative (Fast) Positive (Slow) Chinese DT JJR PRP NN Japanese DT NN CD VBD Portuguese NNS NN-POS PRP VBZ Spanish NNS MD PRP RB</formula><p>The reading times of NN in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">figure 2d</ref> also give rise to a second, potentially competing interpreta- tion of differences in ESL reading times, which highlights lexical rather than structural factors. According to this interpretation, increased read- ing times of nouns are the result of substantially smaller lexical sharing with English by Chinese and Japanese as compared to Spanish and Por- tuguese. Given the utilized speed normalization, lexical effects on nouns could in principle account for reduced reading times on determiners and pro- nouns. Conversely, structural influence leading to reduced reading times on determiners and pro- nouns could explain longer dwelling on nouns. A third possibility consistent with the observed read- ing patterns would allow for both structural and lexical effects to impact second language reading. Importantly, in each of these scenarios, ESL read- ing patterns are related to linguistic factors of the reader's native language. We note that the presented analysis is prelimi- nary in nature, and warrants further study in future research. In particular, reading times and classi- fier learned features may in some cases differ be- tween the shared and the individual regimes. In the examples presented above, similar results are ob- tained in the individual sentences regime for DT, PRP and NN. The trend for the NN+POS construc- tion, however, diminishes in that setup with simi- lar reading times for all languages. On the other hand, one of the strongest features for predicting Portuguese and Spanish in the individual regime are longer reading times for prepositions (IN), an outcome that holds in the shared regime only rel- ative to Chinese and Japanese, but not relative to native speakers of English.</p><p>Despite these caveats, our results suggest that reading patterns can potentially be related to lin- guistic factors of the reader's native language. This analysis can be extended in various ways, such as inclusion of additional feature types and fixation metrics, as well as utilization of other comparative methodologies. Combined with ev- idence from language production, this line of in- vestigation can be instrumental for informing lin- guistic theory of cross-linguistic influence.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Related Work</head><p>Eyetracking and second language reading Sec- ond language reading has been studied using eye- tracking, with much of the work focusing on processing of syntactic ambiguities and analysis of specific target word classes such as cognates <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(Dussias, 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b30">Roberts and Siyanova-Chanturia, 2013)</ref>. In contrast to our work, such studies typ- ically use controlled, rather than free-form sen- tences. Investigation of global metrics in free- form second language reading was introduced only recently by <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Cop et al. (2015)</ref>. This study compared ESL and native reading of a novel by native speakers of Dutch, observing longer sen- tence reading times, more fixations and shorter saccades in ESL reading. Differently from this study, our work focuses on comparison of reading patterns between different native languages. We also analyze a related, but different metric, namely speed normalized fixation durations on word se- quences.</p><p>Eyetracking for NLP tasks Recent work in NLP has demonstrated that reading gaze can serve as a valuable supervision signal for standard NLP tasks. Prominent examples of such work include POS tagging ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Barrett and Søgaard, 2015a;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Barrett et al., 2016)</ref>, syntactic parsing ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Barrett and Søgaard, 2015b</ref>) and sentence compression ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Klerke et al., 2016)</ref>. Our work also tackles a traditional NLP task with free-form text, but differs from this line of research in that it addresses this task only in comprehension. Furthermore, while these stud- ies use gaze recordings of native readers, our work focuses on non-native readers.</p><p>NLI in production NLI was first introduced in <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">Koppel et al. (2005)</ref> and has been drawing considerable attention in NLP, including a recent shared-task challenge with 29 participating teams <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">(Tetreault et al., 2013)</ref>. NLI has also been driving much of the work on identification of native lan- guage related features in writing <ref type="bibr" target="#b36">(Tsur and Rappoport, 2007;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Jarvis and Crossley, 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Brooke and Hirst, 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b35">Tetreault et al., 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr">Charniak, 2013, 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b21">Malmasi and Dras, 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Bykh and Meurers, 2016)</ref>. Several studies have also linked usage patterns and grammatical errors in production to linguistic properties of the writer's native language ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">Nagata and Whittaker, 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b25">Nagata, 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Berzak et al., 2014</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Berzak et al., , 2015</ref>. Our work departs from NLI in writing and intro- duces NLI and related feature analysis in reading.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Conclusion and Outlook</head><p>We present a novel framework for studying cross- linguistic influence in multilingualism by measur- ing gaze fixations during reading of free-form En-glish text. We demonstrate for the first time that this signal can be used to determine a reader's na- tive language. The effectiveness of linguistically motivated criteria for fixation clustering and our subsequent analysis suggest that the ESL reading process is affected by linguistic factors. Specifi- cally, we show that linguistic similarities between native languages are reflected in similarities in ESL reading. We also identify several key fea- tures that characterize reading in different native languages, and discuss their potential connection to structural and lexical properties of the native langauge. The presented results demonstrate that eyetracking data can be instrumental for develop- ing predictive and explanatory models of second language reading.</p><p>While this work is focused on NLIR from fix- ations, our general framework can be used to ad- dress additional aspects of reading, such as anal- ysis of saccades and gaze trajectories. In future work, we also plan to explore the role of native and second language writing system characteris- tics in second language reading. More broadly, our methodology introduces parallels with produc- tion studies in NLP, creating new opportunities for integration of data, methodologies and tasks be- tween production and comprehension. Further- more, it holds promise for formulating language learning theory that is supported by empirical find- ings in naturalistic setups across language process- ing domains. the forehead bar, and 13cm below it. The eye- tracker camera knob is 65cm away from forehead bar. Throughout the experiment participants hold a joystick with a button for indicating sentence completion, and two buttons for answering yes/no questions. We record gaze of the participant's dominant eye.</p><p>Text Parameters All the textual material in the experiment is presented using Times font, normal style, with font size 23. In our setup, this cor- responds to 0.36 degrees (11.3px) average lower case letter width, and 0.49 degrees (15.7px) av- erage upper case letter width. We chose a non- monospace font, as such fonts are generally more common in reading. They are also more com- pact compared to monospace fonts, allowing to substantially increase the upper limit for sentence length.</p><p>Calibration We use 3H line calibration with point repetition on the central horizontal line (y=384), using 16px outer circle, 6px inner circle, fixation points. At least three calibrations are per- formed during the experiment, one at the begin- ning of each experimental section. We also recali- brate upon failure to produce a 300ms fixation on any fixation trigger preceding a sentence or a ques- tion within 4 seconds after its appearance. The mean validation error for calibrations across sub- jects is 0.146 degrees (std 0.038).</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: (a) Linguistic versus English reading language similarities. The horizontal axis represents typological and phylogenetic similarity between languages, obtained by vectorizing linguistic features form URIEL, and measuring their cosine similarity. The vertical axis represents the average uncertainty of the NLIR classifier in distinguishing ESL readers of each language pair. (b) Ward hierarchical clustering of linguistic similarities between languages. (c) Ward hierarchical clustering of NLIR average pairwise classification uncertainties.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2: Mean speed-normalized Total Fixation duration for Determiners (DT), Pronouns (PRP), singular noun possessives (NN+POS), and singular nouns (NN) appearing in the shared sentences. Error bars denote standard error.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3" validated="false"><head>Table 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>sentences, while IC features exhibit weaker performance in this regime, with accura- cies of 41.38 to 46.21. Both results are well above chance, but lower than WFC fixations due to the information loss imposed by the clustering step. Crucially, both feature-sets remain effective in the individual input regime, with 43.45 to 48.97 accu- racy for SC features and 32.41 to 38.62 accuracy for IC features. The strongest result in the individ- ual regime is 51.03, obtained by concatenating IC and SC features over unigrams. We also note that using this setup in a binary classification scheme yields results ranging from chance level 49.31 for Portuguese versus Spanish, to 84.93 on Spanish versus Japanese.</figDesc><table>Native Language Identification from Reading results with 10-fold cross-validation for native 
speakers of Chinese, Japanese, Portuguese and Spanish. In the Shared regime all the participants read 
the same 78 sentences. In the Individual regime each participant reads a different set of 78 sentences. 

regime for performing reliable NLIR, and suggest 
a strong native language signal in non-native read-
ing fixation times. 
SC features yield accuracies of 45.52 to 58.62 
on the shared </table></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> The experimental data collected in this study will be made publicly available.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="2"> Note that for bigrams and trigrams, one could also measure FF and FP for interest regions spanning the sequence, instead, or in addition to summing these fixation times over individual tokens.</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgements</head><p>We thank Amelia Smith, Emily Weng, Run Chen and Lila Jansen for contributions to stimuli prepa-ration and data collection. We also thank An-drei Barbu, Guy Ben-Yosef, Yen-Ling Kuo, Roger Levy, Jonathan Malmaud, Karthik Narasimhan and the anonymous reviewers for valuable feed-back on this work. This material is based upon work supported by the Center for Brains, Minds, and Machines (CBMM), funded by NSF STC award CCF-1231216.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>A Supplemental Material</head><p>Eyetracking Setup We use a 44.5x30cm screen with 1024x768px resolution to present the read- ing materials, and a desktop mount Eyelink 1000 eyetracker (1000Hz) to record gaze. The screen, eyetracker camera and chinrest are horizontally aligned on a table surface. The screen center (x=512, y=384) is 79cm away from the center of</p></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Crosslinguistic Influence in Second Language Acquisition</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rosa Alonso</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alonso</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
			<publisher>Multilingual Matters</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="volume">95</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Weakly supervised part-ofspeech tagging using eye-tracking data</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Maria</forename><surname>Barrett</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Joachim</forename><surname>Bingel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Frank</forename><surname>Keller</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Anders</forename><surname>Søgaard</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ACL</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="579" to="584" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Reading behavior predicts syntactic categories</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Maria</forename><surname>Barrett</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Anders</forename><surname>Søgaard</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">CoNLL</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="345" to="349" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Using reading behavior to predict grammatical functions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Maria</forename><surname>Barrett</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Anders</forename><surname>Søgaard</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Sixth Workshop on Cognitive Aspects of Computational Language Learning</title>
		<meeting>the Sixth Workshop on Cognitive Aspects of Computational Language Learning</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="5" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Multilingualism: New perspectives on syntactic development. The Handbook of Bilingualism and Multilingualism</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Éva</forename><surname>Berkes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Suzanne</forename><surname>Flynn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="137" to="167" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Reconstructing native language typology from foreign language usage</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yevgeni</forename><surname>Berzak</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Roi</forename><surname>Reichart</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Boris</forename><surname>Katz</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Eighteenth Conference on Computational Natural Language Learning (CoNLL)</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Contrastive analysis with predictive power: Typology driven estimation of grammatical error distributions in esl</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yevgeni</forename><surname>Berzak</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Roi</forename><surname>Reichart</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Boris</forename><surname>Katz</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Conference on Computational Natural Language Learning (CoNLL)</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Measuring interlanguage: Native language identification with l1influence metrics</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Julian</forename><surname>Brooke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Graeme</forename><surname>Hirst</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">LREC</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="779" to="784" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Advancing linguistic features and insights by label-informed feature grouping: An exploration in the context of native language identification</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Serhiy</forename><surname>Bykh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Detmar</forename><surname>Meurers</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">COLING</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A limited memory algorithm for bound constrained optimization</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Richard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Peihuang</forename><surname>Byrd</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jorge</forename><surname>Lu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ciyou</forename><surname>Nocedal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Zhu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">SIAM Journal on Scientific Computing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">16</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1190" to="1208" />
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Syntactic Structures of the world&apos;s languages</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chris</forename><surname>Collins</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Richard</forename><surname>Kayne</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://sswl.railsplayground.net" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Eye movement patterns in natural reading: A comparison of monolingual and bilingual reading of a novel</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Uschi</forename><surname>Cop</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Denis</forename><surname>Drieghe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wouter</forename><surname>Duyck</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">PLOS ONE</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="38" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">WALS Online. Max Planck Institute for Evolutionary Anthropology</title>
		<ptr target="http://wals.info/" />
		<editor>Matthew S. Dryer and Martin Haspelmath</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<pubPlace>Leipzig</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Uses of eye-tracking data in second language sentence processing research</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Paola</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Dussias</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Annual Review of Applied Linguistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">30</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="149" to="166" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Glottolog 2.6. Leipzig: Max Planck Institute for Evolutionary Anthropology</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Harald</forename><surname>Hammarström</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Robert</forename><surname>Forkel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://glottolog.org" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Martin Haspelmath, and Sebastian Bank</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Scott</forename><surname>Jarvis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Scott</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Crossley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Approaching Language Transfer Through Text Classification: Explorations in the Detection-based Approach</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="page">64</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Multilingual Matters</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Crosslinguistic influence in language and cognition</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Scott</forename><surname>Jarvis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Aneta</forename><surname>Pavlenko</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Routledge</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Improving sentence compression by learning to predict gaze</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sigrid</forename><surname>Klerke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yoav</forename><surname>Goldberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Anders</forename><surname>Søgaard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
			<publisher>NAACL-HLT</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Determining an author&apos;s native language by mining a text for errors</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Moshe</forename><surname>Koppel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jonathan</forename><surname>Schler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kfir</forename><surname>Zigdon</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the eleventh ACM SIGKDD international conference on Knowledge discovery in data mining</title>
		<meeting>the eleventh ACM SIGKDD international conference on Knowledge discovery in data mining</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="624" to="628" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Paul</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Lewis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gary</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Simons</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Charles</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Fennig</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://www.ethnologue.com" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Ethnologue: Languages of the World. SIL International</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Uriel and lang2vec: Representing languages as typological, geographical, and phylogenetic vectors</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Patrick</forename><surname>Littell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Mortensen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ke</forename><surname>Lin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Katherine</forename><surname>Kairis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Carlisle</forename><surname>Turner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lori</forename><surname>Levin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
			<biblScope unit="page">8</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Language transfer hypotheses with linear svm weights</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Shervin</forename><surname>Malmasi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mark</forename><surname>Dras</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">EMNLP</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1385" to="1390" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Building a large annotated corpus of english: The penn treebank</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mary</forename><forename type="middle">Ann</forename><surname>Mitchell P Marcus</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Beatrice</forename><surname>Marcinkiewicz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Santorini</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Computational linguistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="313" to="330" />
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Language transfer: what do we really mean</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gita</forename><surname>Martohardjono</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Suzanne</forename><surname>Flynn</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">The current state of Interlanguage: studies in honor of William E. Rutherford, John Benjamins: The Netherlands</title>
		<editor>L. Eubank, L. Selinker, and M. Sharwood Smith, editors</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="205" to="219" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Universal dependency annotation for multilingual parsing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Joakim</forename><surname>Ryan T Mcdonald</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yvonne</forename><surname>Nivre</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yoav</forename><surname>Quirmbachbrundage</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dipanjan</forename><surname>Goldberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kuzman</forename><surname>Das</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Ganchev</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Keith</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Slav</forename><surname>Hall</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hao</forename><surname>Petrov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Oscar</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Täckström</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ACL</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="92" to="97" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Language family relationship preserved in non-native english</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ryo</forename><surname>Nagata</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">COLING</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1940" to="1949" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Reconstructing an indo-european family tree from nonnative english texts</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ryo</forename><surname>Nagata</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Edward</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Whittaker</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ACL</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1137" to="1147" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Language transfer: Crosslinguistic influence in language learning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Terence</forename><surname>Odlin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1989" />
			<publisher>Cambridge University Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A universal part-of-speech tagset</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Slav</forename><surname>Petrov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dipanjan</forename><surname>Das</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ryan</forename><surname>Mcdonald</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">LREC</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Word lengths are optimized for efficient communication</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Harry</forename><surname>Steven T Piantadosi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Edward</forename><surname>Tily</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Gibson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">108</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3526" to="3529" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Using eye-tracking to investigate topics in l2 acquisition and l2 processing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Leah</forename><surname>Roberts</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Anna</forename><surname>Siyanova-Chanturia</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Studies in Second Language Acquisition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">35</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">02</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="213" to="235" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Part-of-speech tagging guidelines for the penn treebank project (3rd revision)</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Beatrice</forename><surname>Santorini</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1990" />
			<publisher>CIS</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
<note type="report_type">Technical Reports</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Extracting the native language signal for second language acquisition</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ben</forename><surname>Swanson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Eugene</forename><surname>Charniak</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">HLT-NAACL</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="85" to="94" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Data driven language transfer hypotheses</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ben</forename><surname>Swanson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Eugene</forename><surname>Charniak</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="page">169</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A report on the first native language identification shared task</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Joel</forename><surname>Tetreault</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Daniel</forename><surname>Blanchard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Aoife</forename><surname>Cahill</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Eighth Workshop on Innovative Use of NLP for Building Educational Applications. Citeseer</title>
		<meeting>the Eighth Workshop on Innovative Use of NLP for Building Educational Applications. Citeseer</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="48" to="57" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Native tongues, lost and found: Resources and empirical evaluations in native language identification</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Daniel</forename><surname>Joel R Tetreault</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Aoife</forename><surname>Blanchard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Martin</forename><surname>Cahill</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Chodorow</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">COLING</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2585" to="2602" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Using classifier features for studying the effect of native language on the choice of written second language words</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Oren</forename><surname>Tsur</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ari</forename><surname>Rappoport</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Workshop on Cognitive Aspects of Computational Language Acquisition. Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the Workshop on Cognitive Aspects of Computational Language Acquisition. Association for Computational Linguistics</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="9" to="16" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Hierarchical grouping to optimize an objective function</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Joe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Ward</surname><genName>Jr</genName></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of the American statistical association</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">58</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">301</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="236" to="244" />
			<date type="published" when="1963" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A new dataset and method for automatically grading esol texts</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Helen</forename><surname>Yannakoudakis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ted</forename><surname>Briscoe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ben</forename><surname>Medlock</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ACL</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="180" to="189" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
