<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T10:59+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Automatic Compositor Attribution in the First Folio of Shakespeare</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
				<availability status="unknown"><p>Copyright Association for Computational Linguistics</p>
				</availability>
				<date>July 30-August 4, 2017. July 30-August 4, 2017</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Maria</forename><surname>Ryskina</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hannah</forename><surname>Alpert-Abrams</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dan</forename><surname>Garrette</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Taylor</forename><surname>Berg-Kirkpatrick</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Automatic Compositor Attribution in the First Folio of Shakespeare</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 55th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (Volume 2: Short Papers)</title>
						<meeting>the 55th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (Volume 2: Short Papers) <address><addrLine>Vancouver, Canada; Vancouver, Canada</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="411" to="416"/>
							<date type="published">July 30-August 4, 2017. July 30-August 4, 2017</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="DOI">10.18653/v1/p17-2065</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Compositor attribution, the clustering of pages in a historical printed document by the individual who set the type, is a bib-liographic task that relies on analysis of orthographic variation and inspection of visual details of the printed page. In this paper, we introduce a novel unsuper-vised model that jointly describes the tex-tual and visual features needed to distinguish compositors. Applied to images of Shakespeare&apos;s First Folio, our model predicts attributions that agree with the manual judgements of bibliographers with an accuracy of 87%, even on text that is the output of OCR.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Within literary studies, the field of bibliography has an unusually long tradition of quantitative analysis. One particularly relevant area is that of compositor attribution-the clustering of pages in a historical printed document by the individ- ual (the compositor) who set the type. Like sty- lometry, a long-standing area of NLP that has largely focused on attributing the authorship of text <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Holmes, 1994;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Hope, 1994;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Juola, 2006;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Koppel et al., 2009;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Jockers and Witten, 2010)</ref>, the analysis of orthographic patterns is fundamen- tal to compositor attribution. Additionally, com- positor attribution often makes use of visual fea- tures, such as whitespace layout, introducing new challenges. These analyses have traditionally been done by hand, but efforts are painstaking due to the difficulty of manually recording these features.</p><p>In this paper, we present an unsupervised model specifically designed for compositor attribution that incorporates both textual and visual sources of evidence traditionally used by bibliographers <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(Hinman, 1963;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Taylor, 1981;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Blayney, 1991)</ref>. Our model jointly describes the patterns of vari- ation both in orthography and in the whitespace between glyphs, allowing us to cluster pages by discovering patterns of similarity and differ- ence. When applied to digital scans of histori- cal printed documents, our approach learns ortho- graphic and whitespace preferences of individual compositors and predicts groupings of pages set by the same compositor. 1 This is, to our knowl- edge, the first attempt to perform compositor at- tribution automatically. Prior work has proposed automatic approaches to authorship attribution- which is typically viewed as the supervised prob- lem of identifying a particular author given sam- ples of their writing. In contrast, compositor attri- bution lacks supervision because compositors are unknown and, in addition, focuses on different lin- guistic patterns. We explain spellings of words conditioned on word choice, not the word choice itself. Figure 2: In our model, a compositor ci is generated for page i from a multi- nomial prior. Then, each diplomatic word, dij, is generated conditioned on ci and the corresponding modern word, mij, from a distribution parameterized by weight vector wc. Finally, each me- dial comma spacing width (measured in pixels), s ik , is generated conditioned on ci from a distribution parameterized by θc.</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">c i s ik m ij d ij dear deere K i J i I Compositor C ! ! ! ! ! ! Edit operation weights: C w c</formula><p>To evaluate our approach, we fit our model to digital scans of Shakespeare's First Folio (1623)- a document with well established manual judge- ments of compositor attribution. We find that even when relying on noisy OCR transcriptions of tex- tual content, our model predicts compositor attri- butions that agree with manual annotations 87% of the time, outperforming several simpler baselines. Our approach opens new possibilities for consid- ering patterns across a larger vocabulary of words and at a higher visual resolution than has been pos- sible historically. Such a tool may enable scalable first-pass analysis in understudied domains as a complement to humanistic studies of composition.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Background</head><p>In this paper we focus on modeling the same types of observations made by scholars and demonstrate agreement with authoritative attributions. We use compositor studies of Shakespeare's First Folio to inform our approach, drawing on the meth- ods proposed by <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Hinman (1963)</ref>, <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Howard-Hill (1973), and</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Taylor (1981)</ref>. Hinman's landmark 1963 study clustered the pages of the First Fo- lio according to five different compositors based on variations in spelling among three common words. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref>, for example, shows portions of two pages of the First Folio with different spelling variants for the words dear and do: one compos- itor used deere and doe, while the other used deare and do. Hinman relied on the assumption that each compositor was consistent in their pref- erences for the sake of convenience in the typeset- ting process <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Blayney, 1991)</ref>. Subsequent studies looked at larger sets of words and more general orthographic preferences (e.g. the preference to terminate words with -ie instead of -y), lead- ing to modifications of Hinman's original analysis <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Howard-Hill, 1973;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Taylor, 1981)</ref>. In this paper we propose a probabilistic model designed to cap- ture both word-specific preferences and general orthographic patterns. To separate the effect of the compositor from the choices made by the au- thor or editor, we condition on a modernized (col- lated) version of Shakespeare's text as was done by scholars.</p><p>Visual features, including typeface usage and whitespace layout, also inform compositor attribu- tion. For example, the highlighted spacing in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Fig- ure 1</ref> shows different choices after medial commas (commas that occur before the end of the line). Bibliographers produced new hypotheses about how many compositors were involved in produc- tion based on the analysis of the use of spaces before and after punctuation <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Howard-Hill, 1973;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Taylor, 1981)</ref>. We additionally incorporate this source of evidence into to our automatic approach by modeling pixel-level whitespace distances.</p><p>Bibliographers also use contextual information to inform their analyses, including copy text or- thography, printing house records, collation, type case usage, and the use of type with cast-on spaces. In our model, we restrict our analysis to only those features that can be derived from the OCR output and simple visual analysis.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Model</head><p>Our computational approach to compositor attri- bution operates on the sources of evidence that have been considered by bibliographers. In par- ticular, we focus on jointly modeling patterns of orthographic variation and spacing preferences across pages of a document, treating composi- tor assignments as latent variables in a generative model. We assume access to a diplomatic tran- scription of the document (a transcription faith-ful to the original orthography), which we auto- matically align with a modernized version. <ref type="bibr">2</ref> We experiment with both manually and automatically (OCR) produced transcriptions, and assume ac- cess to pixel-level spacing information on each page, which can be extracted using OCR as de- scribed in Section 4. <ref type="figure">Figure 2</ref> shows the generative process. In our model, each of I total pages is generated independently. The compositor assignment for the ith page is represented by the variable c i ∈ {1, . . . , C} and is generated from a multinomial prior. For page i, each diplomatic word, d ij , is generated conditioned on the corresponding mod- ern word, m ij , and the compositor who set the page, c i . Finally, the model produces the pixel width of the space after each medial comma, s ik , again conditioned on the compositor, c i . The joint distribution for page i, conditioned on modern text, takes the following form:</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">P ({d ij }, {s ik }, c i |{m ij }) = P (c i ) [Prior on compositors] · J i j=1 P (d ij |m ij , c i ; w c i ) [Orthographic model] · K i k=1 P (s ik |c i ; θ c i ) [Whitespace model]</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Orthographic Preference Model</head><p>We choose the parameterization of the distribu- tion of diplomatic words in order to capture two types of spelling preference: (1) general prefer- ences for certain character groups (such as -ie) and (2) preferences that only pertain to a particu- lar word and do not indicate a larger pattern. Since it is unknown which of the two behaviors is dom- inant, we let the model describe both and learn to separate their effects. Using a log-linear parame- terization,</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">P (d|m, c; w) ∝ exp(w c f (m, d))</formula><p>we introduce features to capture both effects.</p><p>Here, f (m, d) is a feature function defined on modern word m paired with diplomatic word d, while w c is a weight vector corresponding to com- positor c.</p><p>To capture word-specific preferences we add an indicator feature for each pair of modern word m and diplomatic spelling d. We refer to these as WORD features below. To capture general ortho- graphic preferences we introduce an additional set of features based on the edit operations involved in</p><note type="other">the computation of Levenshtein distance between m and d. In particular, each operation is added as a separate feature, both with and without local context (previous or next character of the modern word). We refer to this group as EDIT features. The weight vector for each compositor represents their unique biases, as shown in the depiction of these parameters in Figure 2.</note></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Whitespace Preference Model</head><p>Manual analysis of spacing has revealed differ- ences across pages. In particular, the choice of spaced or non-spaced punctuation marks is hy- pothesized by biobliographers to be indicative of compositor preference and specific typecase. We add whitespace distance to our model to capture those observations. While bibliographers only made a coarse distinction between spaced or non- spaced commas, in our model we generate medial comma spacing widths, s ik , that are measured in pixels to enable finer-grained analysis. We use a simple multinomial parameterization where each pixel width is treated as a separate outcome up to some maximum allowable width:</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">s ik |c i ∼ M ult(θ c i )</formula><p>Here, θ c represents the vector of multinomial spacing parameters corresponding to compositor c. We choose this parameterization because it can capture non-unimodal whitespace preference dis- tributions, as depicted in <ref type="figure">Figure 2</ref>, and it makes learning simple.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3">Learning and Inference</head><p>Modern and diplomatic words and spacing vari- ables are observed, while compositor assignments are latent. In order to fit the model to an input doc- ument we estimate the orthographic preference pa- rameters, w c , and spacing preference parameters, θ c , for each compositor using EM. The E-step is accomplished via a tractable sum over composi- tor assignments, while the M-step for w c is ac- complished via gradient ascent <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Berg-Kirkpatrick et al., 2010</ref>). The M-step for spacing parameters, θ c , uses the standard multinomial update. Pre- dicting compositor groups is accomplished via an Model Setup</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Bodleian Transcription Ocular OCR Transcription Hinman Attr</head><p>Blayney Attr Hinman Attr Blayney Attr 1-to-1 M-to-1 1-to-1 M-to-1 1-to-1 M-to-1 1-to-1 M-to- independent argmax over each c i . In all experi- ments we run 75 iterations of EM with 100 ran- dom restarts, choosing the learned parameters cor- responding the best model likelihood.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Experiments</head><p>Data: To evaluate our model when it has ac- cess to perfectly transcribed historical text, we use the Bodleian diplomatic transcription of the First Folio. 3 To test whether our approach can also work with untranscribed books, we ran the Ocu- lar OCR system <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Berg-Kirkpatrick et al., 2013</ref>) on the Bodleian facsimile images to create an auto- matic diplomatic transcription. In both cases, we used Ocular's estimates of glyph bounding boxes on the complete First Folio images to extract spac- ing information. The modern text was taken from MIT Complete Works of Shakespeare 4 and was aligned with diplomatic transcriptions by running a word-level edit distance calculation. The ex- tracted substitutions form the model's observed modern-diplomatic word pairs.</p><p>Evaluation: To compare the recovered attribu- tion with those proposed by bibliographers, we evaluate against an authoritative attribution com- piled by Peter Blayney (1996) which includes the work of various scholars <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(Hinman, 1963;</ref><ref type="bibr">HowardHill, 1973</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b11">, 1976</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b12">, 1980</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Taylor, 1981;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b18">O'Connor, 1975;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b21">Werstine, 1982)</ref>. We also evaluate our sys- tem against an earlier, highly influential model proposed by <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Hinman (1963)</ref>, which we approx- imate by reverting certain compositor divisions in Blayney's attribution. Hinman's attribution posited five compositors, while Blayney's posited eight. In experiments, we set the model's maxi- mum number of compositors to C = 5 when eval- uating on Hinman's attribution, and use C = 8 BASIC model variant: We evaluate a simple base- line model that uses a multinomial parameteriza- tion for generating diplomatic words and does not incorporate spacing information. We use two dif- ferent options for selection of spelling variants to be considered by the model. First, we consider only the three words selected by Hinman: do, go and here (referred to as HINMAN). Second, we use a larger, automatically selected, word list (re- ferred to as AUTO). Here, we select all modern words with frequency greater than 70 that are not names and that exhibit sufficient variance in diplo- matic spellings (most common diplomatic spelling occurs in less than 80% of aligned tokens). For our full model, described in the next section, we always use the larger AUTO word list.</p><p>FEAT model variant: We run experiments with several variants of our full model, described in Section 3 (referred to as FEAT since they use a feature-based parameterization of diplomatic word generation.) We try ablations of WORD and EDIT features, as well as model variants with and without the spacing generation component (re- ferred to as SPACE.) We refer to the full model that includes both types of features and spacing generation as ALL.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Results</head><p>Our experimental results are presented in <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>. The BASIC variant, modeled after Hinman's orig- inal procedure, substantially outperforms the ran- dom baseline, with the HINMAN word list outper- forming the larger AUTO word list. However, use <ref type="figure">Figure 3</ref>: Learned behaviors of the Fo- lio compositors. Our model only de- tected the presence of five compositors (ranked according to number of pages the compositor set in our model's pre- diction). Compositor D's habit of omit- ting u (yong vs. young) and compos- itor C's usage of spaced medial commas were also noticed in <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Taylor (1981)</ref>.</p><formula xml:id="formula_4">! ! ! ! ! ! ! ! ! u o u w ! u DEL ! B A C E D ! ! ! ! ! ! ! ! ! ! ! ! ! ! ! ! ! ! ! ! ! ! ! ! Comp B Comp A Comp C Comp E Comp D ! ! ! !</formula><p>of the larger word list with feature-based models yields large gains in all scenarios, including evalu- ation on Hinman's original attributions and while using OCR diplomatic transcriptions. The best- performing model for both manually transcribed and OCR text uses EDIT features in conjunction with spacing generation and achieves an accuracy of up to 87%. Including WORD features on top of this leads to slightly reduced performance, per- haps as a result of the substantially increased num- ber of free parameters. In the OCR scenario, the addition of WORD features on top of EDIT de- creases accuracy, unlike the same experiment with the manual transcription. This is possibly a result of the reduced reliability of full word forms due to mistakes in OCR.</p><p>Particularly interesting is the result that spac- ing, rarely a factor considered in NLP models, improves the accuracy significantly for our sys- tem when compared with EDIT features alone. Because pixel-level visual information and arbi- trary orthographic patterns are also the most diffi- cult features to measure manually, our results give strong evidence to the assertion that NLP-style models can aid bibliographers.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Discussion</head><p>The results on OCR (character error rate for most plays ≈ 10 − 15%) transcripts are only marginally worse than those on manual transcripts, which shows that our approach can be generalized for the common case where manual diplomatic transcrip- tions are not available. For our experiments, we also chose a common modern edition of Shake- speare instead of more carefully produced mod- ernized transcription of the facsimile-our goal being to again show that this approach can be generalized, perhaps to documents where careful modernizations of the facsimile are not available. Together, these results suggest that our model may be sufficiently robust to aid bibliographers in their analysis of less studied texts. <ref type="figure">Figure 3</ref> shows an example of the feature weights and spacing parameters learned by the FEAT w/ ALL model. Our statistical approach is able to successfully explain some of the observa- tions scholars made. For example, <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Taylor (1981)</ref> notices that compositors C and D prefer to omit u in young but A does not. Our model reflects this by giving u → DEL high weight for D and low weight for A. However, the weight of a single feature is difficult to interpret in isolation. This might be the reason why our model only moder- ately agrees in case of compositor C. Another ex- ample can be seen in spacing patterns: according to <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Taylor (1981)</ref>, compositor C uses spaced me- dial commas unlike A and D. Our model learns the same behavior.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7">Conclusion</head><p>Our primary goal is to scale the methods of com- positor attribution, including both textual and vi- sual modes of evidence, for use across books and corpora. By using principled statistical techniques and considering evidence at a larger scale, we of- fer a more robust approach to compositor identi- fication than has previously been possible. The fact that our system works well on OCR texts means that we are not restricted to only those documents for which we have manually produced transcriptions, opening up the possibility for bib- liographic study on a much larger class of texts.</p><p>Though we are unable to incorporate the kinds of world knowledge used by bibliographers, our ability to include more information and more fine- grained information allows us to recreate their re- sults. Having validated these techniques on the First Folio, where historical claims are well es- tablished, we hope future work can extend these methods and their application.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: The compositor of the left page tended to use the spellings doe and deere, while the compositor for the right page used spellings do and deare, indicating these pages were likely set by different people. The varying width of the medial comma whitespace also distinguishes the typesetters.</figDesc><graphic url="image-4.png" coords="1,219.39,248.79,341.68,81.62" type="bitmap" /></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> The validity of compositor attribution has sparked an ongoing and heated debate among bibliographers (McKenzie, 1969, 1984; Rizvi, 2016); while some reject parts or all of this approach, it continues to be cited in authoritative bibliographical texts (Gaskell, 2007; Blayney, 1996). Without taking a position in this debate, we seek only to automate the methods that remain in use by particular bibliographers (Blayney, 1996; Burrows, 2013).</note>

			<note place="foot" n="2"> Modern editions are common for many books that are of interest to bibliographers, though future work could consider how to cope with their absence.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="3"> http://firstfolio.bodleian.ox.ac.uk/ 4 http://shakespeare.mit.edu/ with Blayney&apos;s. We compute the one-to-one and many-to-one accuracy, mapping the recovered page groups to the gold compositors to maximize accuracy, as is standard for many unsupervised clustering tasks, e.g. POS induction (see Christodoulopoulos et al. (2010)).</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgements</head><p>We thank the three anonymous reviewers for their valuable feedback. This project is funded in part by the NSF under grant 1618044.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Painless unsupervised learning with features</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Taylor</forename><surname>Berg-Kirkpatrick</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alexandre</forename><surname>Bouchard-Côté</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">John</forename><surname>Denero</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dan</forename><surname>Klein</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics: Human Language Technologies</title>
		<meeting>the North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics: Human Language Technologies</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Unsupervised transcription of historical documents</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Taylor</forename><surname>Berg-Kirkpatrick</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Greg</forename><surname>Durrett</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dan</forename><surname>Klein</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the Association for Computational Linguistics</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The First Folio of Shakespeare: In Conjunction with the Exhibition at the Folger Shakespeare Library</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Peter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Blayney</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1991-04-01" />
			<publisher>Folger Shakespeare Library</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Washington, DC</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The First Folio of Shakespeare: The Norton Facsimile</title>
		<editor>Peter W. M. Blayney</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
			<pubPlace>Norton</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The peryod of my blisse&quot;: Commas, ends and utterance in Solyman and Perseda</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Ian</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Burrows</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Textual Cultures: Texts, Contexts, Interpretation</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="95" to="120" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Two decades of unsupervised POS induction: How far have we come?</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christos</forename><surname>Christodoulopoulos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sharon</forename><surname>Goldwater</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mark</forename><surname>Steedman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</title>
		<meeting>the Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">A New Introduction to Bibliography</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Philip</forename><surname>Gaskell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
			<publisher>Oak Knoll Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The printing and proofreading of the First Folio of Shakespeare</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Charlton</forename><surname>Hinman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1963" />
			<publisher>Clarendon Press</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<pubPlace>Oxford</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><forename type="middle">I</forename><surname>Holmes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Authorship attribution. Computers and the Humanities</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1994" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">28</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="87" to="106" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The authorship of Shakespeare&apos;s plays: A socio-linguistic study</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jonathan</forename><surname>Hope</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1994" />
			<publisher>Cambridge University Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The compositors of Shakespeare&apos;s Folio Comedies</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Trevor</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Howard-Hill</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Studies in bibliography</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="61" to="106" />
			<date type="published" when="1973" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Compositors B and E in the Shakespeare First Folio and Some Recent Studies</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Trevor</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Howard-Hill</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1976" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Self-published</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">New light on compositor E of the Shakespeare First Folio</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Trevor</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Howard-Hill</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The Library</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="156" to="178" />
			<date type="published" when="1980" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A comparative study of machine learning methods for authorship attribution</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Matthew</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Daniela</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Jockers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Witten</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Literary and Linguistic Computing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">25</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="215" to="223" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Authorship attribution. Foundations and Trends in Information Retrieval</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Patrick</forename><surname>Juola</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="233" to="334" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Computational methods in authorship attribution</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Moshe</forename><surname>Koppel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jonathan</forename><surname>Schler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Shlomo</forename><surname>Argamon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="doi">10.1002/asi.v60:1</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1002/asi.v60:1" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Am. Soc. Inf. Sci. Technol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">60</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="9" to="26" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Printers of the mind: Some notes on bibliographical theories and printing-house practices</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Mckenzie</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Studies in Bibliography</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="75" />
			<date type="published" when="1969" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Stretching a point: Or, the case of the spaced-out comps</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Mckenzie</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Studies in Bibliography</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">37</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="106" to="121" />
			<date type="published" when="1984" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Compositors D and F of the Shakespeare First Folio</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">O&amp;apos;</forename><surname>John</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Connor</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Studies in Bibliography</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">28</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="81" to="117" />
			<date type="published" when="1975" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Use of spellings for compositor attribution in the First Folio</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Pervez</forename><surname>Rizvi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The Papers of the Bibliographical Society of America</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">110</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="53" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The shrinking compositor A of the Shakespeare First Folio</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gary</forename><surname>Taylor</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Studies in Bibliography</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">34</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="96" to="117" />
			<date type="published" when="1981" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Cases and compositors in the Shakespeare First Folio Comedies</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Paul</forename><surname>Werstine</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Studies in Bibliography</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">35</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="206" to="234" />
			<date type="published" when="1982" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
