<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T10:04+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">TutorialBank: A Manually-Collected Corpus for Prerequisite Chains, Survey Extraction and Resource Recommendation</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date>July 15-20, 2018</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alexander</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Fabbri</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Yale University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Irene</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Yale University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Prawat</forename><surname>Trairatvorakul</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Yale University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yijiao</forename><surname>He</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Yale University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wei</forename><forename type="middle">Tai</forename><surname>Ting</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Yale University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Robert</forename><surname>Tung</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Yale University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Caitlin</forename><surname>Westerfield</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Yale University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dragomir</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Radev</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Yale University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">TutorialBank: A Manually-Collected Corpus for Prerequisite Chains, Survey Extraction and Resource Recommendation</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 56th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (Long Papers)</title>
						<meeting>the 56th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (Long Papers) <address><addrLine>Melbourne, Australia</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="611" to="620"/>
							<date type="published">July 15-20, 2018</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<note>611</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>The field of Natural Language Processing (NLP) is growing rapidly, with new research published daily along with an abundance of tutorials, codebases and other on-line resources. In order to learn this dynamic field or stay up-to-date on the lat-est research, students as well as educators and researchers must constantly sift through multiple sources to find valuable, relevant information. To address this situation , we introduce TutorialBank, a new, publicly available dataset which aims to facilitate NLP education and research. We have manually collected and categorized over 6,300 resources on NLP as well as the related fields of Artificial Intelligence (AI), Machine Learning (ML) and Information Retrieval (IR). Our dataset is notably the largest manually-picked corpus of resources intended for NLP education which does not include only academic papers. Additionally, we have created both a search engine 1 and a command-line tool for the resources and have annotated the corpus to include lists of research topics, relevant resources for each topic, prerequisite relations among topics, relevant sub-parts of individual resources, among other annotations. We are releasing the dataset and present several avenues for further research .</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>NLP has seen rapid growth over recent years. A Google search of "Natural Language Processing" returns over 100 million hits with papers, tutorials, 1 http://aan.how blog posts, codebases and other related online re- sources. Additionally, advances in related fields such as Artificial Intelligence and Deep Learn- ing are strongly influencing current NLP research. With these developments, an increasing number of tutorials and online references are being published daily. As a result, the task of students, educa- tors and researchers of tracking the changing land- scape in this field has become increasingly diffi- cult.</p><p>Recent work has studied the educational aspect of mining text for presenting scientific topics. One goal has been to develop concept maps of top- ics, graphs showing which topics are prerequisites for learning a given topic ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Gordon et al., 2016;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Liu et al., 2016;</ref><ref type="bibr">Pan et al., 2017a,b;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Liang et al., 2017)</ref>. Another goal has been to automatically create reading lists for a subject either by build- ing upon concept graphs (  or through an unstructured approach <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(Jardine, 2014)</ref>.</p><p>Additionally, other work has aimed to automati- cally summarize scientific topics, either by extrac- tively summarizing academic papers ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Jha et al., 2013</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Jha et al., , 2015</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Jaidka et al., 2016)</ref> or by producing Wikipedia articles on these topics from multiple sources <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">(Sauper and Barzilay, 2009;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Liu et al., 2018)</ref>. Scientific articles constitute primary texts which describe an author's work on a particular subject, while Wikipedia articles can be viewed as tertiary sources which summarize both results from primary works as well as explanations from secondary sources. <ref type="bibr">McCalla (2004, 2009)</ref> and  explore the peda- gogical function among the types of sources.</p><p>To address the problem of the scientific educa- tion of NLP more directly, we focus on the an- notation and utilization of secondary sources pre- sented in a manner immediately useful to the NLP community. We introduce the TutorialBank cor- pus, a manually-collected dataset of links to over 6,300 high-quality resources on NLP and related fields. The corpus's magnitude, manual collection and focus on annotation for education in addition to research differentiates it from other corpora. Throughout this paper we use the general term "re- source" to describe any tutorial, research survey, blog post, codebase or other online source with a focus on educating on a particular subject. We have created a search engine for these resources and have annotated them according to a taxonomy to facilitate their sharing. Additionally, we have annotated for pedagogical role, prerequisite rela- tions and relevance of resources to hand-selected topics and provide a command-line interface for our annotations.</p><p>Our main contribution is the manual collection of good quality resources related to NLP and the annotation and presentation of these resources in a manner conducive to NLP education. Addition- ally, we show initial work on topic modeling and resource recommendation. We present a variant of standard reading-list generation which recom- mends resources based on a title and abstract pair and demonstrate additional uses and research di- rections for the corpus.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Related Work</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">Pedagogical Value of Resources</head><p>Online resources are found in formats which vary in their roles in education.  identify seven types of pedagogical roles found in technical works: Tutorial, Survey, Software Man- ual, Resource, Reference Work, Empirical Re- sults, and Other. They annotate a dataset of over 1,000 resources according to these types. Beyond these types, resources differ in their pedagogical value, which they define as "the estimate of how useful a document is to an individual who seeks to learn about specific concepts described in the doc- ument". <ref type="bibr">McCalla (2004, 2009</ref>) discuss the pedagogical value of a single type, academic papers, in relation to a larger recommendation sys- tem.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">Prerequisite Chains</head><p>Prerequisite chains refer to edges in a graph de- scribing which topics are dependent on the knowl- edge of another topic. Prerequisite chains play an important role in curriculum planning and reading list generation. <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Liu et al. (2016)</ref> propose "Con- cept Graph Learning" in order to induce a graph from which they can predict prerequisite relations among university courses. Their framework con- sists of two graphs: (1) a higher-level graph which consists of university courses and (2) a lower- level graph which consists of induced concepts and pair-wise sequential preferences in learning or teaching the concept. <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Liang et al. (2017)</ref> experiment with prerequi- site chains on education data but focus on the recovery of a concept graph rather than on pre- dicting unseen course relations as in <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Liu et al. (2016)</ref>. They introduce both a synthetic dataset as well as one scraped from 11 universities which includes course prerequisites as well as concept- prerequisite labels. Concept graphs are also used in ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Gordon et al., 2016)</ref> to address the problem of developing reading lists for students. The con- cept graph in this case is a labeled graph where nodes represent both documents and concepts (de- termined using Latent Dirichlet Allocation (LDA) ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Blei et al., 2003)</ref>), and edges represent dependen- cies. They propose methods based on cross en- tropy and information flow for determining edges in the graph. Finally, finding prerequisite relation- ships has also been used in other contexts such as Massive Open Online Courses (MOOCs) (Pan et al., 2017a,b).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3">Reading List Generation</head><p>Jardine (2014) generates recommended reading lists from a corpus of technical papers in an un- structured manner in which a topic model weighs the relevant topics and relevant papers are chosen through his ThemedPageRank approach. He also provides a set of expert-generated reading lists. Conversely,  approach read- ing list generation from a structured perspective, first generating a concept graph from the corpus and then traversing the graph to select the most relevant document.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.4">Survey Extraction</head><p>Recent work on survey generation for scientific topics has focused on creating summaries from academic papers ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Jha et al., 2013</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Jha et al., , 2015</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Jaidka et al., 2016</ref>). Jha et al. (2013) present a system that generates summaries given a topic keyword. From a base corpus of papers found by query matching, they expand the corpus via a citation network us- ing a heuristic called Restricted Expansion. This process is repeated for seven standard NLP topics. In a similar manner, <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Jha et al. (2015)</ref> experiment with fifteen topics in computational linguistics and collect at least surveys written by experts on each topic, also making use of citation networks to ex- pand their corpus. They introduce a content model as well as a discourse model and perform a qual- itative comparisons of coherence with a standard summarization model. The task of creating surveys for specified top- ics has also been viewed in the multi-document summarization setting of generating Wikipedia articles <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">(Sauper and Barzilay, 2009;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Liu et al., 2018)</ref>.</p><p>Sauper and Barzilay (2009) induce domain-specific templates from Wikipedia and fill these templates with content from the Internet. More recently <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Liu et al. (2018)</ref> explore a diverse set of domains for summarization and are the first to attempt abstractive summarization of the first section of Wikipedia articles, by combining ex- tractive and abstractive summarization methods.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Dataset Collection</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">An Overview of TutorialBank</head><p>As opposed to other collections like the ACL An- thology ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Bird et al., 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b19">Radev et al., 2009</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Radev et al., , 2013</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b18">Radev et al., , 2016</ref>, which contain solely academic pa- pers, our corpus focuses mainly on resources other than academic papers. The main goal in our deci- sion process of what to include in our corpus has been the quality-control of resources which can be used for an educational purpose. Initially, the re- sources collected were conference tutorials as well as surveys, books and longer papers on broader topics, as these genres contain an inherent amount of quality-control. Later on, other online resources were added to the corpus, as explained below. Stu- dent annotators, described later on, as well as the professor examined resources which they encoun- tered in their studies. The resources were added to the corpus if deemed of good quality. Important to note is that not all resources which were found on the Internet were added to TutorialBank; one could scrape the web according to search terms, but quality control of the results would be largely missing. The quality of a resource is a somewhat subjective measure, but we aimed to find resources which would serve a pedagogical function to ei- ther students or researchers, with a professor of NLP making the final decision. This collection of resources and meta-data annotation has been done over multiple years, while this year we cre- ated the search engine and added additional anno- tations mentioned below.  <ref type="table">Table 2</ref>: Corpus count by taxonomy topic for the most frequent topics (excluding topic "Other").</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">-Introduction and Linguistics 2 -Language Modeling, Syntax and Parsing 3 -Semantics and Logic 4 -Pragmatics, Discourse, Dialogue and Applications 5 -Classification and Clustering 6 -Information Retrieval and Topic Modeling 7 -Neural Networks and Deep Learning 8 -Artificial Intelligence 9 -Other Topics</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1.1">TutorialBank Taxonomy</head><p>In order to facilitate the sharing of resources about NLP, we developed a taxonomy of 305 topics of varying granularity. The top levels of our taxon- omy tree are shown in <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table 1</ref>. The backbone of our Taxonomy corresponds to the syllabus of a university-level NLP course and was expanded to include related topics from other courses in ML, IR and AI. As a result, there is a bias in the corpus towards NLP resources and resources from other fields in so far as they are relevant to NLP. How- ever, this bias is planned, as our focus remains teaching NLP. The resource count for the most fre- quent taxonomy topics is shown in <ref type="table">Table 2</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Data Preprocessing</head><p>For each resource in the corpus, we downloaded the corresponding PDF, PowerPoint presentations and other source formats and used PDFBox to per- form OCR in translating the files to textual for- mat. For HTML pages we downloaded both the raw HTML with all images as well as a formatted text version of the pages. For copyright purposes we release only the meta data such as urls and an- notations and provide scripts for reproducing the dataset.</p><p>Resource <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Category  Count  corpus  131  lecture  126  library  1014  link set  1186  naclo  154  paper  1176  survey  390  tutorial  2079   Table 3</ref>: Corpus count by pedagogical feature.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Dataset Annotation</head><p>Annotations were performed by a group of 3 PhD students in NLP, and 6 undergraduate Computer Science students who have taken at least one course in AI or NLP.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">Pedagogical Function</head><p>When collecting resources from the Internet, each item was labeled according to the medium in which it was found, analogous to the pedagogical function of ( ). We will use this term throughout the paper to describe this catego- rization. The categories along with their counts are shown in <ref type="table">Table 3</ref>:</p><p>• Corpus: A corpus provides access to and a de- scription of a scientific dataset.</p><p>• Lecture: A lecture consists of slides/notes from a university lecture.</p><p>• Library: A library consists of github pages and other codebases which aid in the implemen- tation of algorithms.</p><p>• NACLO: NACLO problems refer to linguistics puzzles from the North American Computa- tional Linguistics Olympiad.</p><p>• Paper: A paper is a short/long conference paper taken from sites such as https://arxiv.org/ and which is not included in the ACL Anthology.</p><p>• Link set: A link set provides a collection of helpful links in one location.</p><p>• Survey: A survey is a long paper or book which describes a broader subject.</p><p>• Tutorial: A tutorial is a slide deck from a con- ference tutorial or an HTML page that de- scribes a contained topic.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">Topic to Resource Collection</head><p>We first identified by hand 200 potential topics for survey generation in the fields of NLP, ML, AI and  IR. Topics were added according to the following criteria:</p><p>1. It is conceivable that someone would write a Wikipedia page on this topic (an actual page may or may not exist).</p><p>2. The topic is not overly general (e.g., "Natu- ral Language Processing") or too obscure or narrow.</p><p>3. In order to write a survey on the topic, one would need to include information from a number of sources.</p><p>While some of the topics come from our taxon- omy, many of the taxonomy topics have a differ- ent granularity than we desired, which motivated our topic collection. Topics were added to the list along with their corresponding Wikipedia pages, if they exist. A sample of the topics selected is shown in 4. Once the list of topics was com- piled, annotators were assigned topics and asked to search that topic in the TutorialBank search en- gine and find relevant resources. In order to im- pose some uniformity on the dataset, we chose to only include resources which consisted of Power- Point slides as well as HTML pages labeled as tu- torials. We divided the topics among the annota- tors and asked them to choose five resources per topic using our search engine. The resource need not solely focus on the given topic; the resource may be on a more general topic and include a sec- tion on the given topic. As in general searching for resources, often resources include related in- formation, so we believe this setting is fitting. For some topics the annotators chose fewer than five resources (partially due to the constraint we im- pose on the form of the resources). We noted top- ics for which no resources were found, and rather than replace the topics to reflect TutorialBank cov- erage, we leave these topics in and plan to add ad- ditional resources in a future release.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3">Prerequisite Chains</head><p>Even with a collection of resources and a list of topics, a student may not know where to begin studying a topic of interest. For example, in or- der to understand sentiment analysis the student should be familiar with Bayes' Theorem, the ba- sics of ML as well as other topics. For this pur- pose, the annotators annotated which topics are prerequisites of others for the given topics from their reading lists. We expanded our list of poten- tial prerequisites to include eight additional topics which were too broad for survey generation (e.g., Linear Algebra) but which are important prerequi- sites to capture. Following the method of (Gordon et al., 2016), we define labeling a topic Y as a pre- requisite of X according to the following question:</p><p>• Would understanding Topic Y help you to un- derstand Topic X?</p><p>As in ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Gordon et al., 2016)</ref>, the annotators can an- swer this question as "no", "somewhat" or "yes."</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.4">Reading Lists</head><p>When annotators were collecting relevant re- sources for a particular topic, we asked them to order the resources they found in terms of the use- fulness of the resource for learning that particular topic. We also include the Wikipedia pages corre- sponding to the topics, when available, as an ad- ditional source of information. We do not perform additional annotation of the order of the resources or experiment in automatically reproducing these ordered lists but rather offer this annotation as a pedagogical tool for students and educators. We plan the expansion of these lists and analysis in future experiments.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.5">Survey Extraction</head><p>We frame the task of creating surveys of scien- tific topics as a document retrieval task. A student searching for resources in order to learn about a topic such as Recurrent Neural Networks (RNN's) may encounter resources 1) which solely cover RNN's as well as 2) resources which cover RNN's within the context of a larger topic (e.g., Deep Learning). Within the first type, not every piece of content (a single PowerPoint slide or section in a blog post) contributes equally well to an un- derstanding of RNN's; the content may focus on background information or may not clearly ex- plain the topic. Within the second type, larger tutorials may contain valuable information on the topic, but may also contain much information not immediately relevant to the query. Given a query topic and a set of parsed documents we want to retrieve the parts most relevant to the topic. In order to prepare the dataset for extracting surveys of topics, we first divide resources into units of content which we call "cards". Power- Point slides inherently contain a division in the form of each individual slide, so we divide Pow- erPoint presentations into individual slides/cards. For HTML pages, the division is less clear. How- ever, we convert the HTML pages to a markdown file and then automatically split the markdown file using header markers. We believe this is a reason- able heuristic as tutorials and similar content tend to be broken up into sections signalled by headers.</p><p>For each of the resources which the annotators gathered for the reading lists on a given topic, that same annotator was presented with each card from that resource and asked to rate the usefulness of the card. The annotator could rate the card from 0-2, with 0 meaning the card is not useful for learning the specified topic, 1 meaning the card is somewhat useful and 2 meaning the card is useful. We chose a 3-point scale as initial trials showed a 5-point scale to be too subjective. The annotators also had the option in our annotation interface to drop cards which were parsed incorrectly or were repeated one after the other as well as skip cards and return to score a card.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.6">Illustrations</head><p>Whether needed for understanding a subject more deeply or for preparing a blog post on a subject, images play an important role in presenting con- cepts more concretely. Simply extracting the text from HTML pages leaves behind this valuable in- formation, and OCR software often fails to parse complex graphs and images in a non-destructive fashion. To alleviate this problem and promote the sharing of images, we extracted all images from our collected HTML pages. Since many images were simply HTML icons and other extraneous images, we manually checked the images and se- lected those which are of value to the NLP stu- dent. We collected a total of 2,000 images and matched them with the taxonomy topic name of the resource it came from as well as the url of the resource. While we cannot outdo the countless im-ages from Google search, we believe illustrations can be an additional feature of our search engine, and we describe an interface for this collection be- low.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Additional Features and Analysis</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.1">Search Engine</head><p>In order to present our corpus in a user-friendly manner, we created a search engine using Apache Lucene <ref type="bibr">2</ref> . We allow the user to query key words to search our resource corpus, and the results can then be sorted based on relevance, year, topic, medium, and other meta data. In addition to searching by term, users can browse the resources by topic according to our taxonomy. For each child topic from the top-level taxonomy down- ward, we display resources according to their ped- agogical functions. In addition to searching for general resources, we also provide search func- tionality for a corpus of papers, where the user can search by keyword as well as by author and venue.</p><p>While the search engine described above pro- vides access to our base corpus and meta data, we also provide a command-line interface tool with our release so that students and researchers can easily use our annotations for prerequisite topics, illustrations and survey generation for educational purposes. The tool allows the user to input a topic from the taxonomy and retrieve all images related to that topic according to our meta data. Addi- tionally, the user can input a topic from our list of 200 topics, and our tool outputs the prerequisites of that topic according to our annotation as well as the cards labelled as relevant for that topic.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.2">Resource Recommendation from Title and Abstract Pairs</head><p>In addition to needing to search for a general term, often a researcher begins with an idea for a project which is already focused on a nuanced sub-task. An employee at an engineering company may be starting a project on image captioning. Ideas about the potential direction of this project may be clear, but what resources may be helpful or what papers have already been published on the subject may not be immediately obvious. To this end we pro- pose the task of recommending resources from ti- tle and abstract pairs. The employee will input the title and abstract of the project and obtain a list of resources which can help complete the project.</p><p>This task is analogous to reproducing the reference section of a paper, however, with a focus on tu- torials and other resources rather than solely on papers. As an addition to our search engine, we allow a user to input a title and an abstract of vari- able length. We then propose taxonomy topics based on string matches with the query as well as a list of resources and papers and their scores as determined by the search engine. We later explore two baseline models for recommending resources based on document and topic modeling.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.3">Dataset and Annotation Statistics</head><p>We created reading lists for 182 of the 200 top- ics we identify in Section 4.2. Resources were not found for 18 topics due to the granularity of the topic (e.g., Radial Basis Function Networks) as well as our intended restriction of the chosen resources to PowerPoint presentations and HTML pages. The average number of resources per read- ing list for the 182 topics is 3.94. As an extension to the reading lists we collected Wikipedia pages for 184 of the topics and present these urls as part of the dataset. We annotated prerequisite relations for the 200 topics described above. We present a subset of our annotations in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref>, which shows the net- work of topic relations (nodes without incoming edges were not annotated for their prerequisites as part of this shown inter-annotation round). Our network consists of 794 unidirectional edges and 33 bidirectional edges. The presence of bidirec- tional edges stems from our definition of a pre- requisite, which does not preclude bidirectional- ity (one topic can help explain another and vice- versa) as well as the similarity of the topics. The set of bidirectional edges consists of topic pairs (BLEU -ROUGE; Word Embedding -Distribu- tional Semantics; Backpropagation -Gradient de- scent) which could be collapsed into one topic to create a directed acyclic graph in the future.</p><p>For survey extraction, we automatically split 313 resources into content cards which we anno- tated for usefulness in survey extraction. These resources are a subset of the reading lists limited in number due to constraints in downloading urls and parsing to our annotation interface. The to- tal number of cards which were not marked as repeats/mis-parsed totals 17,088, with 54.59 per resource. 6,099 cards were labeled as somewhat relevant or relevant for the target topic. The re- sources marked as non-relevant may be poorly  presented or may not pertain fully to the topic of that survey. These numbers confirm the appropri- ateness of this survey corpus as a non-trivial infor- mation retrieval task.</p><p>To better understand the difficulty of our anno- tation tasks, we performed inter-annotator agree- ment experiments for each of our annotations. We randomly sampled twenty-five resources and had annotators label for pedagogical function. Addi- tionally, we sampled twenty-five topics for pre- requisite annotations and five topics with reading list lengths of five for survey annotation. We used Fleiss's Kappa ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Fleiss et al., 2004</ref>), a variant of Cohen's Kappa <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Cohen, 1960</ref>) designed to mea- sure annotator agreement for more than two anno- tators. The results are shown in <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">Table 5</ref>. Using the scale as defined in <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Landis and Koch (1977)</ref>, pedagogical function annotation exhibits substan- tial agreement while prerequisite annotation and survey extraction annotation show fair agreement. The Kappa score for pedagogical function is com- parable to that of <ref type="bibr">Sheng et al. (2017) (0.68)</ref> while the prerequisite annotation is slightly lower than the agreement metric used in <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Gordon et al. (2016)</ref> (0.36) although they measure agreement through Pearson correlation. We believe that the sparsity of the labels plays a role in these scores.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.4">Comparison to Similar Datasets</head><p>Our corpus distinguishes itself in its magnitude, manual collection and focus on annotation for ed- ucational purposes in addition to research tasks. We use similar categories for classifying pedagog- ical function as , but our corpus is hand-picked and over four-times larger, while exhibiting similar annotation agreement. <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Gordon et al. (2016)</ref> present a corpus for pre- requisite relations among topics, but this corpus differs in coverage. They used LDA topic model- ing to generate a list of 300 topics, while we man- ually create a list of 200 topics based on criteria described above. Although their topics are gener- ated from the ACL Anthology and related to NLP, we find less than a 40% overlap in topics. Ad- ditionally, they only annotate a subset of the top- ics for prerequisite annotations while we focus on broad coverage, annotating two orders of magni- tude larger in terms of prerequisite edges while ex- hibiting fair inter-annotator agreement.</p><p>Previous work and datasets on generating sur- veys for scientific topics have focused on scien- tific articles ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Jha et al., 2013</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Jha et al., , 2015</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Jaidka et al., 2016)</ref> and Wikipedia pages <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">(Sauper and Barzilay, 2009;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Liu et al., 2018)</ref> as a summarization task. We, on the other hand, view this problem as an information retrieval task and focus on extract- ing content from manually-collected PowerPoint slides and online tutorials. <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">Sauper and Barzilay (2009)</ref> differ in their domain coverage, and while the surveys of <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Jha et al. (2013</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Jha et al. ( , 2015</ref>) focus on NLP, we collect resources for an order of magni- tude larger set of topics. Finally, our focus here in creating surveys, as well as the other annotations, is first and foremost to create a useful tool for stu- dents and researchers. Websites such as the ACL Anthology <ref type="bibr">3</ref> and arXiv 4 provide an abundance of resources, but do not focus on the pedagogical as- pect of their content. Meanwhile, websites such as Wikipedia which aim to create a survey of a topic may not reflect the latest trends in rapidly chang- ing fields.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Topic Modeling and Resource Recommendation</head><p>As an example usage of our corpus, we experi- mented with topic modeling and its extension to resource recommendation. We restricted our cor- pus for this study to non-HTML files to exam- ine the single domain of PDF's and PowerPoint presentations. This set consists of about 1,480 files with a vocabulary size 191,446 and a to- ken count of 9,134,452. For each file, the to- kens were processed, stop tokens were stripped, and then each token was stemmed. Words with counts less than five across the entire corpus were dropped. We experimented with two models: LDA, a generative probabilistic model mentioned earlier, and Doc2Vec ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Le and Mikolov, 2014)</ref>, an extension of Word2Vec ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Mikolov et al., 2013)</ref> which creates representations of arbitrarily-sized documents. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 2</ref> shows the document repre- sentations obtained with Doc2Vec as well as the topic clusters created with LDA. The grouping of related resources around a point demonstrates the clustering abilities of these models. We applied LDA in an unsupervised way, using 60 topics over 300 iterations as obtained through experimenta- tion, and then colored each document dot with its category to observe the distribution. Our Doc2Vec model used hidden dimension 300, a window size of 10 and a constant learning rate of 0.025. Then, the model was trained for 10 epochs.</p><p>We tested these models for the task of resource recommendation from title+abstract pairs. We col- lected 10 random papers from ACL 2017. For LDA, the document was classified to a topic, and then the top resources from that topic were cho- sen, while Doc2Vec computed the similarity be- tween the query document and the training set and chose the most similar documents. We concate- nated the title and abstract as input and had our models predict the top 20 documents. We then had five annotators rate the recommendations for helpfulness as 0 (not helpful) or 1 (helpful). Rec- ommended resources were rated according to the criterion of whether reading this resource would be useful in doing a project as described in the ti- tle and abstract. The results are found in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure  3</ref>. Averaging the performance over each test case, the LDA model performed better than Doc2Vec (0.45 to 0.34), although both leave large room for improvements. LDA recommended resources no- tably better for cases 5 and 6, which correspond to papers with very well defined topics areas (Ques- tion Answering and Machine Translation) while Doc2Vec was able to find similar documents for cases 2 and 8 which are a mixture of topics, yet are well-represented in our corpus (Reinforcement Learning with dialog agents and emotion (senti- ment) detection with classification). The low per- formance for both models also corresponds to dif- ferences in corpus coverage, and we plan to ex- plore this bias in the future. We believe that this variant of reading list generation as well as the re- lationship between titles and abstracts is an unex- plored and exciting area for future research.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7">Conclusion and Future Work</head><p>In this paper we introduce the TutorialBank Cor- pus, a collection of over 6,300 hand-collected re- sources on NLP and related fields. Our corpus is notably larger than similar datasets which deal with pedagogical resources and topic dependen- cies and unique in use as an educational tool. To this point, we believe that this dataset, with its multiple layers of annotation and usable interface, will be an invaluable tool to the students, edu- cators and researchers of NLP. Additionally, the corpus promotes research on tasks not limited to pedagogical function classification, topic model- ing and prerequisite relation labelling. Finally, we formulate the problem of recommending resources for a given title and abstract pair as a new way to approach reading list generation and propose two baseline models. For future work we plan to con- tinue the collection and annotation of resources and to separately explore each of the above re- search tasks.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: Subset of prerequisite annotations taken from inter-annotator agreement round.</figDesc><graphic url="image-1.png" coords="7,72.00,62.81,431.98,78.73" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2: Plot showing a query document with title "Statistical language models for IR" and its neighbour document clusters as obtained through tSNE dimension reduction for Doc2Vec (left) and LDA topic modeling (right). Nearest neighbor documents titles are shown to the right of each plot.</figDesc><graphic url="image-2.png" coords="8,70.64,62.81,453.54,135.45" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Figure 3: Relevance accuracies of the Doc2Vec and LDA resource recommendation models.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" validated="true"><head>Table 1 : Top-level Taxonomy Topics</head><label>1</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Topic Category 
Count 
Introduction to Neural Networks and 
Deep Learning 
635 

Tools for Deep Learning 
475 
Miscellaneous Deep Learning 
287 
Machine Learning 
225 
Word Embeddings 
139 
Recurrent Neural Networks 
134 
Python Basics 
133 
Reinforcement learning 
132 
Convolutional Neural Networks 
129 
Introduction to AI 
89 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" validated="false"><head>Table 4 :</head><label>4</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Random sample of the list of 200 top-
ics used for prerequisite chains, readling lists and 
survey extraction. 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3" validated="false"><head>Table 5 : Inter-annotator agreement.</head><label>5</label><figDesc></figDesc><table></table></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="2"> http://lucene.apache.org/</note>

			<note place="foot" n="3"> http://aclweb.org/anthology/ 4 https://arxiv.org/</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>We would like to thank all those who worked on the development of the search engine and website as well as those whose discussion and annotated greatly helped this work, especially Jungo Kasai, Alexander Strzalkowski, Michihiro Yasunaga and Rui Zhang.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The ACL Anthology Reference Corpus: A Reference Dataset for Bibliographic Research in Computational Linguistics</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Steven</forename><surname>Bird</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Robert</forename><surname>Dale</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bonnie</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Dorr</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bryan</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Gibson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mark</forename><forename type="middle">Thomas</forename><surname>Joseph</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Min-Yen</forename><surname>Kan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dongwon</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Brett</forename><surname>Powley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Dragomir</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yee Fan</forename><surname>Radev</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Tan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">LREC. European Language Resources Association</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Latent Dirichlet Allocation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Blei</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Andrew</forename><forename type="middle">Y</forename><surname>Ng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michael</forename><forename type="middle">I</forename><surname>Jordan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Machine Learning Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="993" to="1022" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A Coefficient of Agreement for Nominal Scales</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jacob</forename><surname>Cohen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Educational and psychological measurement</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="37" to="46" />
			<date type="published" when="1960" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The Measurement of Interrater Agreement</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Joseph</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Fleiss</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bruce</forename><surname>Levin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Myunghee Cho</forename><surname>Paik</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
			<publisher>John Wiley &amp; Sons, Inc</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Structured Generation of Technical Reading Lists</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jonathan</forename><surname>Gordon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Stephen</forename><surname>Aguilar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Emily</forename><surname>Sheng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gully</forename><surname>Burns</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">BEA@EMNLP</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="261" to="270" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Modeling Concept Dependencies in a Scientific Corpus</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jonathan</forename><surname>Gordon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Linhong</forename><surname>Zhu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Aram</forename><surname>Galstyan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Prem</forename><surname>Natarajan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gully</forename><surname>Burns</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>Au- gust 7-12</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 54th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics, ACL 2016</title>
		<meeting>the 54th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics, ACL 2016<address><addrLine>Berlin, Germany</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Long Papers</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Overview of the Cl-SciSumm 2016 Shared Task</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kokil</forename><surname>Jaidka</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Muthu</forename><surname>Kumar Chandrasekaran</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sajal</forename><surname>Rustagi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Min-Yen</forename><surname>Kan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">BIRNDL@JCDL, volume 1610 of CEUR Workshop Proceedings</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="93" to="102" />
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>CEUR-WS.org</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Automatically Generating Reading Lists</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">James</forename><surname>Gregory</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jardine</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<pubPlace>UK</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>University of Cambridge</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
<note type="report_type">Ph.D. thesis</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A System for Summarizing Scientific Topics Starting from Keywords</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rahul</forename><surname>Jha</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Amjad</forename><surname>Abu-Jbara</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dragomir</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Radev</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 51st Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics, ACL</title>
		<meeting>the 51st Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics, ACL<address><addrLine>Sofia, Bulgaria</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Short Papers</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2013-08-09" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="572" to="577" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Surveyor: A System for Generating Coherent Survey Articles for Scientific Topics</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rahul</forename><surname>Jha</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Reed</forename><surname>Coke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Dragomir</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Radev</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Twenty-Ninth AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence</title>
		<meeting>the Twenty-Ninth AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence<address><addrLine>Austin, Texas, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015-01-25" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2167" to="2173" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Measurement of Observer Agreement for Categorical Data</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Richard</forename><surname>Landis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gary G</forename><surname>Koch</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Biometrics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="159" to="174" />
			<date type="published" when="1977" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Distributed Representations of Sentences and Documents</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Quoc</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tomas</forename><surname>Le</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Mikolov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>abs/1405.4053</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<publisher>CoRR</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Recovering Concept Prerequisite Relations from University Course Dependencies</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chen</forename><surname>Liang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jianbo</forename><surname>Ye</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Zhaohui</forename><surname>Wu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bart</forename><surname>Pursel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">Lee</forename><surname>Giles</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Thirty-First AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence</title>
		<meeting>the Thirty-First AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence<address><addrLine>San Francisco, California, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017-02-04" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="4786" to="4791" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Learning Concept Graphs from Online Educational Data</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hanxiao</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wanli</forename><surname>Ma</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yiming</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jaime</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Carbonell</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Artif. Intell. Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">55</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1059" to="1090" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Peter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mohammad</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Etienne</forename><surname>Saleh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ben</forename><surname>Pot</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ryan</forename><surname>Goodrich</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lukasz</forename><surname>Sepassi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Noam</forename><surname>Kaiser</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Shazeer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Generating Wikipedia by Summarizing Long Sequences. International Conference on Learning Representations</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Efficient Estimation of Word Representations in Vector Space</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tomas</forename><surname>Mikolov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kai</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Greg</forename><surname>Corrado</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jeffrey</forename><surname>Dean</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>abs/1301.3781</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<publisher>CoRR</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Prerequisite Relation Learning for Concepts in MOOCs</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Liangming</forename><surname>Pan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chengjiang</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Juanzi</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jie</forename><surname>Tang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 55th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the 55th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics<address><addrLine>Vancouver, Canada</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Long Papers</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="0304" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1447" to="1456" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Course Concept Extraction in MOOCs via Embedding-Based Graph Propagation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Liangming</forename><surname>Pan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xiaochen</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chengjiang</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Juanzi</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jie</forename><surname>Tang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Asian Federation of Natural Language Processing</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="875" to="884" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>IJCNLP(1)</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A Bibliometric and Network Analysis of the Field of Computational Linguistics</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Dragomir</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mark</forename><forename type="middle">Thomas</forename><surname>Radev</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bryan</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Joseph</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Pradeep</forename><surname>Gibson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Muthukrishnan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">JASIST</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">67</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="683" to="706" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The ACL Anthology Network Corpus</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Dragomir</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Pradeep</forename><surname>Radev</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Vahed</forename><surname>Muthukrishnan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Qazvinian</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings, ACL Workshop on Natural Language Processing and Information Retrieval for Digital Libraries</title>
		<meeting>ACL Workshop on Natural Language Processing and Information Retrieval for Digital Libraries<address><addrLine>Singapore</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Dragomir</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Pradeep</forename><surname>Radev</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Muthukrishnan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Vahed Qazvinian, and Amjad Abu-Jbara. 2013. The ACL Anthology Network Corpus. Language Resources and Evaluation</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">47</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="919" to="944" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Automatically Generating Wikipedia Articles: A StructureAware Approach</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christina</forename><surname>Sauper</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Regina</forename><surname>Barzilay</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ACL 2009, Proceedings of the 47th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics and the 4th International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing of the AFNLP</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Singapore</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009-02-07" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="208" to="216" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">An Investigation into the Pedagogical Features of Documents</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Emily</forename><surname>Sheng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Prem</forename><surname>Natarajan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jonathan</forename><surname>Gordon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gully</forename><surname>Burns</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="109" to="120" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>BEA@EMNLP</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">On the Pedagogically Guided Paper Recommendation for an Evolving Web-Based Learning System</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tiffany</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ya</forename><surname>Tang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gordon</forename><forename type="middle">I</forename><surname>Mccalla</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">FLAIRS Conference</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>AAAI Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="86" to="92" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Pedagogical Value of Papers: a CollaborativeFiltering based Paper recommender</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tiffany</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ya</forename><surname>Tang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gordon</forename><forename type="middle">I</forename><surname>Mccalla</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Digit. Inf</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
