<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T12:10+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Simplified Abugidas</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date>July 15-20, 2018</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chenchen</forename><surname>Ding</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Advanced Speech Translation Research and Development Promotion Center</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">Advanced Translation Technology Laboratory</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">National Institute of Information and Communications Technology</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>3-5 Hikaridai, Seika-cho, Soraku-gun</addrLine>
									<postCode>619-0289</postCode>
									<settlement>Kyoto</settlement>
									<country key="JP">Japan</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Masao</forename><surname>Utiyama</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Advanced Speech Translation Research and Development Promotion Center</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">Advanced Translation Technology Laboratory</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">National Institute of Information and Communications Technology</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>3-5 Hikaridai, Seika-cho, Soraku-gun</addrLine>
									<postCode>619-0289</postCode>
									<settlement>Kyoto</settlement>
									<country key="JP">Japan</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Eiichiro</forename><surname>Sumita</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Advanced Speech Translation Research and Development Promotion Center</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">Advanced Translation Technology Laboratory</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">National Institute of Information and Communications Technology</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>3-5 Hikaridai, Seika-cho, Soraku-gun</addrLine>
									<postCode>619-0289</postCode>
									<settlement>Kyoto</settlement>
									<country key="JP">Japan</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Simplified Abugidas</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 56th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (Short Papers)</title>
						<meeting>the 56th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (Short Papers) <address><addrLine>Melbourne, Australia</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="491" to="495"/>
							<date type="published">July 15-20, 2018</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<note>491</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>An abugida is a writing system where the consonant letters represent syllables with a default vowel and other vowels are denoted by diacritics. We investigate the feasibility of recovering the original text written in an abugida after omitting subordinate diacritics and merging consonant letters with similar phonetic values. This is crucial for developing more efficient input methods by reducing the complexity in abugidas. Four abugidas in the southern Brahmic family, i.e., Thai, Burmese, Khmer, and Lao, were studied using a newswire 20, 000-sentence dataset. We compared the recovery performance of a support vector machine and an LSTM-based recurrent neural network, finding that the abugida graphemes could be recovered with 94%-97% accuracy at the top-1 level and 98%-99% at the top-4 level, even after omitting most diacritics (10-30 types) and merging the remaining 30-50 characters into 21 graphemes.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Writing systems are used to record utterances in a wide range of languages and can be organized into the hierarchy shown in <ref type="figure">Fig. 1</ref>. The sym- bols in a writing system generally represent either speech sounds (phonograms) or semantic units (logograms). Phonograms can be either segmen- tal or syllabic, with segmental systems being more phonetic because they use separate symbols (i.e., letters) to represent consonants and vowels. Seg- mental systems can be further subdivided depend- ing on their representation of vowels. Alphabets (e.g., the Latin, Cyrillic, and Greek scripts) are the most common and treat vowel and consonant let- ters equally. In contrast, abjads (e.g., the Arabic and Hebrew scripts) do not write most vowels ex- plicitly. The third type, abugidas, also called al- phasyllabary, includes features from both segmen- tal and syllabic systems. In abugidas, consonant letters represent syllables with a default vowel, and other vowels are denoted by diacritics. Abugi- das thus denote vowels less explicitly than alpha- bets but more explicitly than abjads, while being less phonetic than alphabets, but more phonetic than syllabaries. Since abugidas combine segmen- tal and syllabic systems, they typically have more symbols than conventional alphabets. In this study, we investigate how to simplify and recover abugidas, with the aim of developing a more efficient method of encoding abugidas for in- put. Alphabets generally do not have a large set of symbols, making them easy to map to a traditional keyboard, and logogram and syllabic systems need specially designed input methods because of their large variety of symbols. Traditional input meth- ods for abugidas are similar to those for alphabets, mapping two or three different symbols onto each key and requiring users to type each character and diacritic exactly. In contrast, we are able to sub- stantially simplify inputting abugidas by encoding them in a lossy (or "fuzzy") way.</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">TH ะ ั ั ั ั ั ั ั ั ั ั ั ั ั ั ั ั ั MY ိ ိ ိ ိ ေိ ိ ိ ိ ိ KM ិ ិ ិ ិ ិ ិ ិ ើិ ើិ ើិ ើិ ែិ ៃិ ើិ ើិ ិ ិ ិ ិ ិ ិ ិ ិ ិ ិ ិ ិ LO ະ ិ ិ ិ ិ ិ ិ ិ ិ ិ ិ ຽ ិ ិ ិ ិ ិ ិ OMITTED I II I II I II I II MN K G U C J I Y T D N L P B M W R S H Q A E TH กขฃ คฅฆ ง จฉ ชซฌ ญ ย ฎฏฐดตถ ฑฒทธ ณน ลฦฬ บปผฝ พฟภ ม ว รฤ ศษส หฬ อ ๅ เ แ โ ใ ไ MY ကခ ဂဃ င စဆ ဇဈ ဉ ည ယ ိ ဋဌတထ ဍဎဒဓ ဏန လဠ ပဖ ဗဘ မ ဝ ိ ရ ြိ သဿ ဟ ိ အ ိ ိ ိ ိ KM កខ គឃ ង ចឆ ជឈ ញ យ ដឋតថ ឌឍទធ ណន លឡ បផ ពភ ម វ រ ឝឞស ហ អ ិ ្ LO ກຂ ຄ ງ ຈ ຊ ຍ ຢ ດຕຖ ທ ນ ລ ບປຜຝ ພຟ ມ ວ ຣ ສ ຫຮ ອ ເ ແ ໂ ໃ ໄ APP. DENTAL PALATE PRE-V. DE-V. PLOSIVE NAS. MERGED R-LIKE S-LIKE H-LIKE LONG-A ZERO-C. LABIAL PLOSIVE NAS. APP. PLOSIVE NAS. GUTTURAL PLOSIVE NAS. APP.</formula><p>Figure 3: Merging and omission for Thai (TH), Burmese (MY), Khmer (KM), and Lao (LO) scripts. The MN row lists the mnemonics assigned to graphemes in our experiment. In this study, the mnemonics can be assigned arbitrarily, and we selected Latin letters related to the real pronunciation wherever possible. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Fig. 2</ref> gives an overview of this study, show- ing examples in Khmer. We simplify abugidas by omitting vowel diacritics and merging consonant letters with identical or similar phonetic values, as shown in (a). This simplification is intuitive, both orthographically and phonetically. To resolve the ambiguities introduced by the simplification, we use data-driven methods to recover the origi- nal texts, as shown in (b). We conducted experi- ments on four southern Brahmic scripts, i.e., Thai, Burmese, Khmer, and Lao scripts, with a unified framework, using data from the Asian Language Treebank (ALT) ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Riza et al., 2016)</ref>. The exper- iments show that the abugidas can be recovered satisfactorily by a recurrent neural network (RNN) using long short-term memory (LSTM) units, even when nearly all of the diacritics (10 -30 types) have been omitted and the remaining 30 -50 char- acters have been merged into 21 graphemes. Thai gave the best performance, with 97% top-1 ac- curacy for graphemes and over 99% top-4 accu- racy. Lao, which gave the worst performance, still achieved the top-1 and top-4 accuracies of around 94% and 98%, respectively. The Burmese and Khmer results, which lay in-between the other two, were also investigated by manual evaluation.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Related Work</head><p>Some optimized keyboard layout have been pro- posed for specific abugidas <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Ouk et al., 2008</ref>). Most studies on input methods have focused on Chinese and Japanese characters, where thousands of symbols need to be encoded and recovered. For Chinese characters, <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Chen and Lee (2000)</ref> made an early attempt to apply statistical methods to sentence-level processing, using a hidden Markov model. Others have examined max-entropy mod- els, support vector machines (SVMs), conditional random fields (CRFs), and machine translation techniques ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Wang et al., 2006;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Jiang et al., 2007;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Li et al., 2009;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Yang et al., 2012</ref>). Similar meth- ods have also been developed for character con- version in Japanese ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Tokunaga et al., 2011</ref>). This study takes a similar approach to the research on Chinese and Japanese, transforming a less infor- mative encoding into strings in a natural and re- dundant writing system. Furthermore, our study can be considered as a specific lossy compression scheme on abugida textual data. Unlike images or audio, the lossy text compression has received lit- tle attention as it may cause difficulties with read- ing ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Witten et al., 1994)</ref>. However, we handle this issue within an input method framework, where the simplified encoding is not read directly.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Simplified Abugidas</head><p>We designed simplification schemes for several different scripts within a unified framework based on phonetics and conventional usages, without considering many language specific features. Our primary aim was to investigate the feasibility of re- ducing the complexity of abugidas and to establish methods of recovering the texts. We will consider language-specific optimization in a future work, via both data-and user-driven studies.</p><p>The simplification scheme is shown in <ref type="figure">Fig. 3</ref>. 1 Generally, the merges are based on the common distribution of consonant phonemes in most natu- ral languages, as well as the etymology of the char- acters in each abugida. Specifically, three or four graphemes are preserved for the different articu- lation locations (i.e., guttural, palate, dental, and labial), that two for plosives, one for nasal (NAS.), and one for approximant (APP.) if present. Addi- tional consonants such as trills (R-LIKE), frica- tives (S-/H-LIKE), and empty (ZERO-C.) are also assigned their own graphemes. Although the simplification omits most diacritics, three types are retained, i.e., one basic mark common to nearly all Brahmic abugidas (LONG-A), the pre- posed vowels in Thai and Lao (PRE-V.), and the vowel-depressors (and/or consonant-stackers) in Burmese and Khmer (DE-V.). We assigned graphemes to these because we found they in- formed the spelling and were intuitive when typ- ing. The net result was the omission of 18 types of diacritics in <ref type="bibr">Thai, 9 in Burmese, 27 in Khmer, and 18</ref> in Lao, and the merging of the remaining 53 types of characters in <ref type="bibr">Thai, 43 in Burmese, 37 in Khmer, and 33</ref> in Lao, into a unified set of 21 graphemes. The simplification thus substantially reduces the number of graphemes, and represents a straightforward benchmark for further language- specific refinement to build on.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Recovery Methods</head><p>The recovery process can be formalized as a se- quential labeling task, that takes the simplified encoding as input, and outputs the writing units, composed of merged and omitted character(s) in the original abugidas, corresponding to each sim- plified grapheme. Although structured learning methods such as CRF ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Lafferty et al., 2001</ref>) have been widely used, we found that searching for the label sequences in the output space was too costly, because of the number of labels to be recovered. <ref type="bibr">2</ref> Instead, we adopted non-structured point-wise prediction methods using a linear SVM ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Cortes and Vapnik, 1995)</ref> and an LSTM-based RNN <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Hochreiter and Schmidhuber, 1997)</ref>. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Fig. 4</ref> shows the overall structure of the RNN. After many experimentations, a general "shallow and broad" configuration was adopted. Specifi- cally, simplified grapheme bi-grams are first em- bedded into 128-dimensional vectors <ref type="bibr">3</ref>  resulting in a final representation consisting of a 512-dimensional vector that concatenates two 256-dimensional vectors from the two directions. The number of dimensions used here is large be- cause we found that higher-dimensional vectors were more effective than the deeper structures for this task, as memory capacity was more important than classification ability. For the same reason, the representations obtained from the LSTM layer are transformed linearly before the softmax function is applied, as we found that non-linear transfor- mations, which are commonly used for final clas- sification, did not help for this task.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Experiments and Evaluation</head><p>We used raw textual data from the ALT, 4 compris- ing around 20, 000 sentences translated from En- glish. The data were divided into training, devel- opment, and test sets as specified by the project. <ref type="bibr">5</ref> For the SVM experiments, we used the off- the-shelf LIBLINEAR library ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Fan et al., 2008)</ref> wrapped by the KyTea toolkit. <ref type="bibr">6</ref>  <ref type="table">Table 1</ref> gives the recovery accuracies, demonstrating that recov- ery is not a difficult classification task, given well represented contextual features. In general, us- ing up to 5-gram features before/after the sim- plified grapheme yielded the best results for the baseline, except with Burmese, where 7-gram fea- tures brought a small additional improvement. Be- cause Burmese texts use relatively more spaces than the other three scripts, longer contexts help more. Meanwhile, Lao produced the worst results, possibly because the omission and merging pro- cess was harsh: Lao is the most phonetic of the four scripts, with the least redundant spellings.</p><p>The LSTM-based RNN was implemented using DyNet ( <ref type="bibr">Neubig et al., 2017)</ref>, and it was trained using Adam ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Kingma and Ba, 2014</ref>) with an initial learning rate of 10 −3 . If the accuracy decreased on the development set, the learning rate was halved, and learning was terminated when there was no improvement on the development set for three it- erations. We did not use dropout ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Srivastava et al., 2014</ref>) but instead a voting ensemble over a set of differently initialized models trained in parallel, which is both more effective and faster.</p><p>As shown in <ref type="table">Table 2</ref>, the RNN outperformed SVM on all scripts in terms of top-1 accuracy. A more lenient evaluation, i.e., top-n accuracy, showed a satisfactory coverage of around 98% (Khmer and Lao) to 99% (Thai and Burmese) con- sidering only the top four results. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Fig. 5</ref> shows the effect of changing the size of the training dataset by repeatedly halving it until it was one-eighth of its original size, demonstrating that the RNN out- performed SVM regardless of training data size. The LSTM-based RNN should thus be a substan- tially better solution than the SVM for this task.</p><p>We also investigated Burmese and Khmer fur- ther using manual evaluation. The results of RNN @1 ⊕16 in <ref type="table">Table 2</ref> were evaluated by native speakers, who examined the output writing units corresponding to each input simplified grapheme and classified the errors using four levels: 0) ac- ceptable, i.e., alternative spelling, 1) clear and easy to identify the correct result, 2) confusing but possible to identify the correct result, and 3) in- comprehensible. <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">Table 3</ref> shows the error distribu- tion. For Burmese, most of the errors are at lev- els 1 and 2, and Khmer has a wider distribution. For both scripts, around 50% of the errors are se- rious (level 2 or 3), but the distributions suggest that they have different characteristics. We are cur- rently conducting a case study on these errors for further language-specific improvements.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Conclusion and Future Work</head><p>In this study, a scheme was used to substantially simplify four abugidas, omitting most diacritics and merging the remaining characters. An SVM and an LSTM-based RNN were then used to re- cover the original texts, showing that the simpli- fied abugidas could be recovered well. This illus- trates the feasibility of encoding abugidas less re- dundantly, which could help with the development of more efficient input methods.</p><p>As for the future work, we are planning to in- clude language-specific optimizations in the de- sign of the simplification scheme and to improve  <ref type="table">Table 2</ref>: Top-n accuracy on the test set for the LSTM-based RNN with an m-model ensemble (RNN @n ⊕m ). Here, † and ‡ mean the RNN outper- formed the SVM with statistical significance at p &lt; 10 −2 and p &lt; 10 −3 level, respectively, mea- sured by bootstrap re-sampling.   </p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 1: Hierarchy of writing systems.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 4 :</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Figure 4: Structure of the RNN used in this study.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 5 :</head><label>5</label><figDesc>Figure 5: Top-1 accuracy on the test set (y-axis) for different training data sizes (x-axis, number of graphemes after simplification, logarithmic).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" validated="false"><head>Table 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Recovery error distribution. 

the LSTM-based RNN by integrating dictionaries 
and increasing the amount of training data. </table></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> Each script also includes native punctuation marks, digit notes, and standalone vowel characters that are not represented by diacritics. These characters were kept in the experimental texts but not evaluated in the final results, as the usage of these characters is trivial. In addition, white spaces, Latin letters, Arabic digits, and non-native punctuation marks were normalized into placeholders in the experiments, and were also excluded from evaluation.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="2"> One consonant character can be modified by multiple diacritics. In the ALT data used in this study, there are around 600-900 types of writing units in each script, and there could be over 1, 000 on larger textual data. 3 Directly embedding uni-grams (single graphemes) did not give good performance in our preliminary experiments.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="4"> http://www2.nict.go.jp/astrec-att/ member/mutiyama/ALT/ 5 Around 18, 000, 1, 000, and 1, 000 sentences, resp. 6 http://www.phontron.com/kytea/</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>The experimental results of Burmese were evalu-ated by Dr. Win Pa Pa and Ms. Aye Myat Mon from University of Computer Studies, Yangon, Myanmar. The experimental resutls of Khmer were evaluated by Mr. Vichet Chea, Mr. Hour Kaing, Mr. Kamthong Ley, Mr. Vanna Chuon, and Mr. Saly Keo from National Institute of Posts, Telecommunications and ICT, Cambodia. We are grateful for their collaboration. We would like to thank Dr. Atsushi Fujita for his helpful comments.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A new statistical approach to Chinese pinyin input</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Zheng</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kai-Fu</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of ACL</title>
		<meeting>of ACL</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="241" to="247" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Supportvector networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Corinna</forename><surname>Cortes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Vladimir</forename><surname>Vapnik</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Machine learning</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="273" to="297" />
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">LIBLINEAR: A library for large linear classification</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kai-Wei</forename><surname>Rong-En Fan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Cho-Jui</forename><surname>Chang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xiangrui</forename><surname>Hsieh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chih-Jen</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Lin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of machine learning research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1871" to="1874" />
			<date type="published" when="2008-08" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Long short-term memory</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sepp</forename><surname>Hochreiter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jürgen</forename><surname>Schmidhuber</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Neural computation</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1735" to="1780" />
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Pinyin-to-character conversion model based on support vector machines</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wei</forename><surname>Jiang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yi</forename><surname>Guan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xiaolong</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bingquan</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Chinese information processing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">21</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="100" to="105" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Adam: A method for stochastic optimization</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Diederik</forename><surname>Kingma</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jimmy</forename><surname>Ba</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
<note type="report_type">arXiv preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Conditional random fields: Probabilistic models for segmenting and labeling sequence data</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">John</forename><surname>Lafferty</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Andrew</forename><surname>Mccallum</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Fernando</forename><forename type="middle">C N</forename><surname>Pereira</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of ICML</title>
		<meeting>of ICML</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="282" to="289" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A conditional random fields approach to Chinese pinyin-to-character conversion</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lu</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xuan</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xiaolong</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yanbing</forename><surname>Yu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Communication and Computer</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="25" to="31" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Graham</forename><surname>Neubig</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chris</forename><surname>Dyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yoav</forename><surname>Goldberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Austin</forename><surname>Matthews</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Waleed</forename><surname>Ammar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Antonios</forename><surname>Anastasopoulos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Miguel</forename><surname>Ballesteros</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Chiang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Daniel</forename><surname>Clothiaux</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Trevor</forename><surname>Cohn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kevin</forename><surname>Duh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Manaal</forename><surname>Faruqui</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Cynthia</forename><surname>Gan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dan</forename><surname>Garrette</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yangfeng</forename><surname>Ji</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lingpeng</forename><surname>Kong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Adhiguna</forename><surname>Kuncoro</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gaurav</forename><surname>Kumar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chaitanya</forename><surname>Malaviya</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Paul</forename><surname>Michel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Swabha Swayamdipta, and Pengcheng Yin. 2017. DyNet: The dynamic neural network toolkit</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Yusuke Oda, Matthew Richardson, Naomi Saphra</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
<note type="report_type">arXiv preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The design of Khmer wordbased predictive non-QWERTY soft keyboard for stylus-based devices</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Phavy</forename><surname>Ouk</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ye</forename><forename type="middle">Kyaw</forename><surname>Thu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mitsuji</forename><surname>Matsumoto</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yoshiyori</forename><surname>Urano</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of VL/HCC</title>
		<meeting>of VL/HCC</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="225" to="232" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Introduction of the Asian language treebank</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hammam</forename><surname>Riza</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Purwoadi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Teduh</forename><surname>Gunarso</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Uliniansyah</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Khin Mar Soe, Khin Thandar Nwet, Masao Utiyama, and Chenchen Ding</title>
		<editor>Aw Ai Ti, Sharifah Mahani Aljunied, Luong Chi Mai, Vu Tat Thang, Nguyen Phuong Thai, Rapid Sun, Vichet Chea</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="6" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Proc. of O-COCOSDA</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dropout: A simple way to prevent neural networks from overfitting</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nitish</forename><surname>Srivastava</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Geoffrey</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Hinton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alex</forename><surname>Krizhevsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ilya</forename><surname>Sutskever</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ruslan</forename><surname>Salakhutdinov</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of machine learning research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1929" to="1958" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Discriminative method for Japanese kana-kanji input method</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hiroyuki</forename><surname>Tokunaga</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Daisuke</forename><surname>Okanohara</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Shinsuke</forename><surname>Mori</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of WTIM</title>
		<meeting>of WTIM</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="10" to="18" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A maximum entropy approach to Chinese pinyin-tocharacter conversion</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xuan</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lu</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lin</forename><surname>Yao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Waqas</forename><surname>Anwar</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of SMC</title>
		<meeting>of SMC</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2956" to="2959" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Semantic and generative models for lossy text compression</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Ian</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Timothy</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Witten</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alistair</forename><surname>Bell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Craig</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Moffat</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tony</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Nevill-Manning</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Harold</forename><surname>Smith</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Thimbleby</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The Computer Journal</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">37</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="83" to="87" />
			<date type="published" when="1994" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A machine translation approach for Chinese wholesentence pinyin-to-character conversion</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Shaohua</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hai</forename><surname>Zhao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Baoliang</forename><surname>Lu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of PACLIC</title>
		<meeting>of PACLIC</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="333" to="342" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
