<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T12:59+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Improved Evaluation Framework for Complex Plagiarism Detection</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date>July 15-20, 2018</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Anton</forename><surname>Belyy</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory">International laboratory &quot;Computer Technologies&quot;</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">ITMO University</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="RU">Russia</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marina</forename><surname>Dubova</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">Saint Petersburg State University</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="RU">Russia</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dmitry</forename><surname>Nekrasov</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory">International laboratory &quot;Computer Technologies&quot;</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">ITMO University</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="RU">Russia</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Improved Evaluation Framework for Complex Plagiarism Detection</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 56th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (Short Papers)</title>
						<meeting>the 56th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (Short Papers) <address><addrLine>Melbourne, Australia</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="157" to="162"/>
							<date type="published">July 15-20, 2018</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<note>157</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Plagiarism is a major issue in science and education. It appears in various forms, starting from simple copying and ending with intelligent paraphrasing and summarization. Complex plagiarism, such as plagiarism of ideas, is hard to detect, and therefore it is especially important to track improvement of methods correctly and not to overfit to the structure of particular datasets. In this paper, we study the performance of plagdet, the main measure for Plagiarism Detection Systems evaluation, on manually paraphrased plagiarism datasets (such as PAN Summary). We reveal its fallibility under certain conditions and propose an evaluation framework with normalization of inner terms, which is resilient to the dataset imbalance. We conclude with the experimental justification of the proposed measure. The implementation of the new framework is made publicly available as a Github repository.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Plagiarism is a problem of primary concern among publishers, scientists, teachers <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(Maurer et al., 2006</ref>). It is not only about text copying with minor revisions but also borrowing of ideas. Plagiarism appears in substantially paraphrased forms and presents conscious and unconscious appropriation of others' thoughts ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Gingerich and Sullivan, 2013)</ref>. This kind of borrowing has very serious consequences and can not be detected with common Plagiarism Detection Systems (PDS). That is why detection of complex plagiarism cases comes to the fore and becomes a central challenge in the field.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Plagiarism Detection</head><p>Most of the contributions to the plagiarism text alignment were made during the PAN annual track for plagiarism detection held from 2009 to 2015. The latest winning approach ( <ref type="bibr">SanchezPerez et al., 2014</ref>) achieved good performance on all the plagiarism types except the Summary part. Moreover, this type of plagiarism turned out to be the hardest for all the competitors.</p><p>In a brief review, Kraus emphasized (2016) that the main weakness of modern PDS is imprecision in manually paraphrased plagiarism and, as a consequence, the weak ability to deal with real-world problems. Thus, the detection of manually paraphrased plagiarism cases is a focus of recently proposed methods for plagiarism text alignment. In the most successful contributions, scientists applied genetic algorithms ( <ref type="bibr">SanchezPerez et al., 2018;</ref><ref type="bibr">Vani and Gupta, 2017)</ref>, topic modeling methods ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Le et al., 2016)</ref>, and word embedding models <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Brlek et al., 2016</ref>) to manually paraphrased plagiarism text alignment. In all of these works, authors used PAN Summary datasets to develop and evaluate their methods.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Task, Dataset, and Evaluation Metrics</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Text Alignment</head><p>In this work we deal with an extrinsic text alignment problem. Thus, we are given pairs of suspicious documents and source candidates and try to detect all contiguous passages of borrowed information. For a review of plagiarism detection tasks, see Alzahrani et al. 2012.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Datasets</head><p>PAN corpora of datasets for plagiarism text alignment is the main resource for PDS evaluation. This collection consists of slightly or substantially different datasets used at the PAN competitions since 2009 to 2015. We used the most recent 2013 ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Potthast et al., 2013</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Potthast et al., 2014</ref>) English datasets to develop and evaluate our models and metrics. They consist of copy&amp;paste, random, translation, and summary plagiarism types. We consider only the last part, as it exhibits the problems of plagdet framework to the greatest extent.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3">Evaluation Metrics</head><p>Standard evaluation framework for text alignment task is plagdet ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Potthast et al., 2010)</ref>, which consists of macro-and micro-averaged precision, recall, granularity and the overall plagdet score. In this work, we consider only the macro-averaged metrics, where recall can be defined as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">rec macro (S, R) = 1 |S| s∈S rec single macro (s, R s ),<label>(1)</label></formula><p>and precision can be defined through recall as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">prec macro (S, R) = rec macro (R, S),<label>(2)</label></formula><p>where S and R are true plagiarism cases and system's detections, respectively.</p><p>Single case recall rec single macro (s, R s ) is defined as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">|s plg ∩ (R s ) plg | + |s src ∩ (R s ) src | |s plg | + |s src | ,</formula><p>where R s is the union of all detections of a given case s.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Problem Statement</head><p>In this section, we explore problems representative to several manual plagiarism datasets (mainly, Summary part of PAN corpora), and show that the plagdet framework can fail to correctly estimate PDS quality on these datasets.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">Dataset Imbalance</head><p>The PAN Summary datasets turn out to be highly imbalanced.</p><p>• Source part of each plagiarism case takes up the whole source document:  <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref>: Single case recall computation for text alignment task. Note the imbalance in this case: plagiarism part s plg is much shorter than source part s src .</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">∀s ∈ S ∃d src ∈ D src : s src = d src . (3)</formula><p>• For any given case, its plagiarism part is much shorter than its source part 1 :</p><formula xml:id="formula_4">∀s ∈ S : |s plg | &lt;&lt; |s src |.<label>(4)</label></formula><p>As these datasets are publicly available, anyone can figure out these details and, therefore, construct an algorithm where statements 3 and 4 are true for detections R as well.</p><p>Let us now consider a true case s, its detections R s and its source document d src . Then single case recall for PAN Summary document will be equal to:</p><formula xml:id="formula_5">|s plg ∩ (R s ) plg | + |d src | |s plg | + |d src |<label>(5)</label></formula><p>(here we used that and s src = (R s ) src = d src ). Since plagiarism part s plg of the case s is much shorter than source document d src , the term |d src | dominates numerator and denominator in eq. 5, which results in inadequately high document- level precision and recall on PAN Summary datasets.</p><p>Other datasets for manual plagiarism detection display the similar properties, however, not to the PAN Summary extent. Examples include: Palkovskii15, <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Mashhadirajab et al. 2016, and</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Sochenkov et al. 2017</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Discussion</head><p>The important question is whether such dataset imbalance reflects the real-world plagiarizers' behavior.</p><p>There is an evidence that performing length unrestricted plagiarism task people tend to make texts shorter, however, not to the PAN Summary extent <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Barrón-Cedeño et al., 2013</ref>). Moreover, we can find some supporting theoretical reasons. Firstly, summarization and paraphrasing are the only techniques students are taught to use for the transformation of texts. Hence, they can use summarization to plagiarize intellectually. Secondly, in the cases of inadvertent plagiarism and the plagiarism of ideas details of source texts are usually omitted or forgotten. This should also lead to smaller plagiarized texts. Though we can find some reasons, such huge imbalance does not seem to be supported enough and may be considered as a bias.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">Degenerate Intersection</head><p>Lemma 4.1. For any sets e 1 ⊆ d and e 2 ⊆ d, their intersection length |e 1 ∩ e 2 | is bounded by:</p><formula xml:id="formula_6">a(e 1 , e 2 , d) |e 1 ∩ e 2 | b(e 1 , e 2 ),</formula><p>where: </p><formula xml:id="formula_7">a(e 1 , e 2 , d) = max(0, |e 1 | + |e 2 | − |d|), b(e 1 , e 2 ) = min(|e 1 |, |e 2 |).</formula><formula xml:id="formula_8">0 |s src ∩ (R s ) src | |s src |.</formula><p>But, according to lemma 4.1, we see that:</p><formula xml:id="formula_9">0 a src |s src ∩ (R s ) src | b src |s src |,</formula><p>where:</p><formula xml:id="formula_10">a src = a(s src , (R s ) src , d src ), b src = b(s src , (R s ) src ). . d e 1 e 2 e 1 ∩ e 2 a(e 1 ,e 2 , d) d e 2 e 1 = e 1 ∩ e 2 b(e 1 ,e 2 )</formula><p>Figure 2:</p><p>Degenerate intersection lemma. Intuitively, lower bound (a) is achieved when e 1 and e 2 are "farthest" away from each other in d, and upper bound (b) is achieved when e 1 ⊆ e 2 (or e 2 ⊆ e 1 ). This results in a smaller possible value range of intersection length and, therefore, range of precision and recall values. Because of (3), on PAN Summary this leads to the extreme case of a src = b src = |d src |, which causes precision and recall to take constant values on the source part of the dataset.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Proposed Metrics</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.1">Normalized Single Case Recall</head><p>To address issues of dataset imbalance (section 4.1) and degenerate intersection (section 4.2), we propose the following normalized version of single case recall nrec single macro (s, R s ) for macro- averaged case:</p><formula xml:id="formula_11">w plg (|s plg ∩ (R s ) plg |) + w src (|s src ∩ (R s ) src |) w plg (|s plg |) + w src (|s src |) ,</formula><p>where:</p><formula xml:id="formula_12">w i (x) = (x − a i )(b i − a i ) |d i | , a i = a(s i , (R s ) i , d i ), b i = b(s i , (R s ) i ),</formula><p>i ∈ {plg, src}.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.2">Normalized recall, precision and plagdet</head><p>The result of <ref type="formula" target="#formula_0">(1)</ref>  normalized recall nrec macro (S, R). Normalized precision nprec macro (S, R) can be obtained from normalized recall using eq. 2. Normalized macro-averaged plagdet, or normplagdet, is defined as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_13">normplagdet(S, R) = F α (S, R) log 2 (1 + gran(S, R)) ,</formula><p>where F α is the weighted harmonic mean of nprec macro (S, R) and nrec macro (S, R), i.e. the F α -measure, and gran(S, R) is defined as in <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Potthast et al. 2010</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Adversarial models</head><p>To justify the proposed evaluation metrics, we construct two models, M1 and M2, which achieve inadequately high macro-averaged precision and recall.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.1">Preprocessing</head><p>We represent each plagiarism document d plg as a sequence of sentences, where each sentence sent d plg ,i ∈ d plg is a set of tokens. Each source document d src will be represented as a set of its tokens.</p><p>For each sentence sent d plg ,i we also define a measure of similarity sim d plg ,dsrc,i with respect to the source document as:</p><formula xml:id="formula_14">sim d plg ,dsrc,i = |sent d plg ,i ∩ d src | |sent d plg ,i | .</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.2">Models</head><p>Our models are rule-based classifiers, which proceed in three steps for each pair of documents d plg , d src :</p><p>1. Form a candidate set according to similarity score:</p><formula xml:id="formula_15">cand = i|sim d plg ,dsrc,i &gt; 3 4 .</formula><p>2. Find the candidate with highest similarity score (if it exists): best = arg max</p><formula xml:id="formula_16">i sim d plg ,dsrc,i |i ∈ cand .</formula><p>3. (M1) Output sentence best as a detection (if it exists). (M2) Output sentences i|i = best as a detection (or all sentences if best does not exist).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7">Results and Discussion</head><p>We evaluated our adversarial models as well as several state-of-the-art algorithms, whose source code was available to us, using plagdet and normplagdet scores on all PAN Summary datasets available to date.</p><p>In plagdet score comparison <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">(Table 1)</ref> we included additional state-of-the-art algorithms' results (marked by * ), borrowed from respective papers. Proposed models M1 and M2 outperform all algorithms by macro-averaged plagdet and recall measures on almost every dataset. Despite their simplicity, they show rather good results.</p><p>On the contrary, while measuring normplagdet score <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">(Table 2</ref>), M1 and M2 exhibit poor results, while tested state-of-the-art systems evenly achieve better recall and normplagdet scores. These experimental results back up our claim that normplagdet is more resilient to dataset imbalance and degenerate intersection attacks and show that tested state-of-the-art algorithms do not exploit these properties of PAN Summary datasets.</p><p>The code for calculating normplagdet metrics, both macro-and micro-averaged, is made available as a Github repository 2 . We preserved the command line interface of plagdet framework to allow easy adaptation for existing systems.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="8">Conclusion</head><p>Our paper shows that the standard evaluation framework with plagdet measure can be misused to achieve high scores on datasets for manual plagiarism detection.</p><p>We constructed two primitive models that achieve state-of-the-art results for detecting plagiarism of ideas by exploiting flaws of standard plagdet. Finally, we proposed a new framework, normplagdet, that normalizes single case scores to prevent misuse of datasets such as PAN Summary, and proved its correctness experimentally. The proposed evaluation framework seems beneficial not only for plagiarism detection but for any other text alignment task with imbalance or degenerate intersection dataset properties.   </p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Let us take a fresh look at a source part of rec single macro . We assume that |ssrc∩(Rs)src| |ssrc| ∈ [0; 1], and this is actually the case if:</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" validated="false"><head>where every rec single macro (s, R s ) term is replaced for nrec single macro (s, R s ) is defined as</head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><table></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" validated="true"><head>Table 1 : Results of Summary Plagiarism Detection using Plagdet</head><label>1</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Dataset 
Model 
Year 
Precision Recall 
Plagdet 

PAN 2013 Train 

Sanchez-Perez et al. 
2014 
0.9942 
0.4235 
0.5761 
Brlek et al. 
2016 
0.9154 
0.6033 
0.7046 
Le et al.  *  
2016 
0.8015 
0.7722 
0.7866 
Sanchez-Perez et al. 
2018 
0.9662 
0.7407 
0.8386 
Adversarial M1 
2018 
0.9676 
0.7892 
0.8693 
Adversarial M2 
2018 
0.5247 
0.8704 
0.4816 

PAN 2013 Test-1 

Sanchez-Perez et al. 
2014 
1.0000 
0.5317 
0.6703 
Brlek et al. 
2016 
0.9832 
0.7003 
0.8180 
Vani and Gupta  *  
2017 
0.9998 
0.7622 
0.8149 
Sanchez-Perez et al. 
2018 
0.9742 
0.8093 
0.8841 
Adversarial M1 
2018 
0.9130 
0.7641 
0.8320 
Adversarial M2 
2018 
0.4678 
0.8925 
0.4739 

PAN 2013 Test-2 

Sanchez-Perez et al. 
2014 
0.9991 
0.4158 
0.5638 
Brlek et al. 
2016 
0.9055 
0.6144 
0.7072 
Le et al.  *  
2016 
0.8344 
0.7701 
0.8010 
Vani and Gupta  *  
2017 
0.9987 
0.7212 
0.8081 
Sanchez-Perez et al. 
2018 
0.9417 
0.7226 
0.8125 
Adversarial M1 
2018 
0.9594 
0.8109 
0.8789 
Adversarial M2 
2018 
0.5184 
0.8938 
0.4848 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3" validated="false"><head>Table 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Results of Summary Plagiarism Detection using NormPlagdet 
Dataset 
Model 
Year 
Precision Recall 
Plagdet 

PAN 2013 Train 
Sanchez-Perez et al. 
2014 
0.9917 
0.6408 
0.7551 
Brlek et al. 
2016 
0.8807 
0.7889 
0.8064 
Sanchez-Perez et al. 
2018 
0.8929 
0.9238 
0.9081 
Adversarial M1 
2018 
0.9673 
0.1617 
0.2770 
Adversarial M2 
2018 
0.1769 
0.2984 
0.1634 

PAN 2013 Test-1 
Sanchez-Perez et al. 
2014 
0.9997 
0.7020 
0.7965 
Brlek et al. 
2016 
0.9384 
0.8254 
0.8783 
Sanchez-Perez et al. 
2018 
0.9180 
0.9463 
0.9319 
Adversarial M1 
2018 
0.9130 
0.1525 
0.2614 
Adversarial M2 
2018 
0.1488 
0.4237 
0.1700 

PAN 2013 Test-2 
Sanchez-Perez et al. 
2014 
0.9977 
0.6377 
0.7470 
Brlek et al. 
2016 
0.8701 
0.8104 
0.8107 
Sanchez-Perez et al. 
2018 
0.8771 
0.9067 
0.8859 
Adversarial M1 
2018 
0.9585 
0.1687 
0.2869 
Adversarial M2 
2018 
0.1552 
0.3299 
0.1559 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4" validated="false"><head>Table 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Average Length of Plagiarism and Source Cases in Summary Datasets 
Dataset 
Plagiarism (plg) 
Source (src) 
PAN 2013 Train 
626 ± 45 
5109 ± 2431 
PAN 2013 Test-1 
639 ± 40 
3874 ± 1427 
PAN 2013 Test-2 
627 ± 42 
5318 ± 3310 </table></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> For exact lengths, see table 3</note>

			<note place="foot" n="2"> https://github.com/AVBelyy/ normplagdet</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>This work was financially supported by Government of Russian Federation (Grant 08-08).</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Understanding plagiarism linguistic patterns, textual features, and detection methods</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Naomie</forename><surname>Salha M Alzahrani</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ajith</forename><surname>Salim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Abraham</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE Transactions on Systems, Man, and Cybernetics, Part C (Applications and Reviews)</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">42</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="133" to="149" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Plagiarism meets paraphrasing: Insights for the next generation in automatic plagiarism detection</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alberto</forename><surname>Barrón-Cedeño</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marta</forename><surname>Vila</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Antònia</forename><surname>Martí</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Paolo</forename><surname>Rosso</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Computational Linguistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">39</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="917" to="947" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Plagiarism detection using word2vec model. Text Analysis and Retrieval</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Arijana</forename><surname>Brlek</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Petra</forename><surname>Franjic</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nino</forename><surname>Uzelac</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Course Project Reports</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="4" to="7" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Claiming hidden memories as one&apos;s own: a review of inadvertent plagiarism</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Amanda</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Meaghan C</forename><surname>Gingerich</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Sullivan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Cognitive Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">25</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="903" to="916" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Plagiarism detection-stateof-the-art systems (2016) and evaluation methods</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christina</forename><surname>Kraus</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:1603.03014</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
<note type="report_type">arXiv preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Semantic text alignment based on topic modeling</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Huong T Le</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Lam</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Pham</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Duy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Son</forename><forename type="middle">V</forename><surname>Nguyen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">An</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Nguyen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Nguyen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Computing &amp; Communication Technologies, Research, Innovation, and Vision for the Future (RIVF)</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>IEEE</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="67" to="72" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>IEEE RIVF International Conference on</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A text alignment corpus for persian plagiarism detection</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Fatemeh</forename><surname>Mashhadirajab</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mehrnoush</forename><surname>Shamsfard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Razieh</forename><surname>Adelkhah</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Fatemeh</forename><surname>Shafiee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chakaveh</forename><surname>Saedi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">FIRE (Working Notes)</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="184" to="189" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Plagiarism-a survey</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Hermann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Frank</forename><surname>Maurer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bilal</forename><surname>Kappe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Zaka</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. UCS</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1050" to="1084" />
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Overview of the 6th international competition on plagiarism detection</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Martin</forename><surname>Potthast</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Matthias</forename><surname>Hagen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Anna</forename><surname>Beyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Matthias</forename><surname>Busse</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Martin</forename><surname>Tippmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Paolo</forename><surname>Rosso</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Benno</forename><surname>Stein</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">CEUR Workshop Proceedings</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">1180</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="845" to="876" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>CEUR Workshop Proceedings</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Overview of the 5th international competition on plagiarism detection</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Martin</forename><surname>Potthast</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Matthias</forename><surname>Hagen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tim</forename><surname>Gollub</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Martin</forename><surname>Tippmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Johannes</forename><surname>Kiesel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Paolo</forename><surname>Rosso</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Efstathios</forename><surname>Stamatatos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Benno</forename><surname>Stein</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">CLEF Conference on Multilingual and Multimodal Information Access Evaluation</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>CELCT</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="301" to="331" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">An evaluation framework for plagiarism detection</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Martin</forename><surname>Potthast</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Benno</forename><surname>Stein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alberto</forename><surname>Barrón-Cedeño</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Paolo</forename><surname>Rosso</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 23rd international conference on computational linguistics: Posters</title>
		<meeting>the 23rd international conference on computational linguistics: Posters</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="997" to="1005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Plagiarism detection with genetic-based parameter tuning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Miguel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alexander</forename><surname>Sanchez-Perez</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Grigori</forename><surname>Gelbukh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Helena</forename><surname>Sidorov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Gómez-Adorno</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">International Journal</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Pattern Recognition and Artificial Intelligence</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">32</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">01</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1860006</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A winning approach to text alignment for text reuse detection at pan</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Miguel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Grigori</forename><surname>Sanchez-Perez</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alexander F</forename><surname>Sidorov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Gelbukh</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">CLEF (Working Notes)</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1004" to="1011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The paraplag: russian dataset for paraphrased plagiarism detection</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ilya</forename><surname>Sochenkov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Denis</forename><surname>Zubarev</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ivan</forename><surname>Smirnov</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Annual International Conference &quot;Dialogue&quot; 2017 (1)</title>
		<meeting>the Annual International Conference &quot;Dialogue&quot; 2017 (1)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="284" to="297" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
