<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T12:17+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">00 Things You Always Wanted to Know about Semantics &amp; Pragmatics But Were Afraid to Ask *</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date>July 15-20, 2018</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Emily</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Bender</surname></persName>
							<email>ebender@uw.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Linguistics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Washington</orgName>
								<address>
									<postBox>Box 3542425</postBox>
									<postCode>98195-2425</postCode>
									<settlement>Seattle</settlement>
									<region>WA</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">00 Things You Always Wanted to Know about Semantics &amp; Pragmatics But Were Afraid to Ask *</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 56th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics-Tutorial Abstracts</title>
						<meeting>the 56th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics-Tutorial Abstracts <address><addrLine>page 1 Melbourne, Australia</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<date type="published">July 15-20, 2018</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<note>1</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract/>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Tutorial overview</head><p>Meaning is a fundamental concept in Natural Lan- guage Processing (NLP), given its aim to build systems that mean what they say to you, and un- derstand what you say to them. In order for NLP to scale beyond partial, task-specific solutions, it must be informed by what is known about how humans use language to express and understand communicative intents. The purpose of this tuto- rial is to present a selection of useful information about semantics and pragmatics, as understood in linguistics, in a way that's accessible to and useful for NLP practitioners with minimal (or even no) prior training in linguistics.</p><p>The tutorial will look at both aspects of meaning tied to the linguistic signal (sentence meaning), in- cluding how it is tied to syntactic structure, and as- pects of meaning in situated language use (speaker meaning). For the most part, the points will be illustrated with English examples, but to the ex- tent possible I will bring in a typological perspec- tive to foster an understanding of to what extent phenomena are crosslinguistically variable and to highlight semantic phenomena that are not present in English.</p><p>The tutorial will briefly cover the following six topics: </p><formula xml:id="formula_0">1. Introduction:</formula></div>		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Instructor</head><p>Emily M. Bender is a Professor in the Department of Linguistics and Adjunct Professor in the Paul G. Allen School of Computer Science &amp; Engi-neering at the University of Washington. She is also the past chair <ref type="bibr">(2016)</ref><ref type="bibr">(2017)</ref> of NAACL. Her research interests lie in multilingual grammar en-gineering, computational semantics, and the incor-poration of linguistic knowledge in natural lan-guage processing. She is the PI of the Grammar Matrix grammar customization system, which is developed in the context of the DELPH-IN Con-sortium (Deep Linguistic Processing with HPSG Initiative). More generally, she is interested in the intersection of linguistics and computational lin-guistics, from both directions: bringing computa-tional methodologies to linguistic science and lin-guistic science to natural language processing.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl/>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
