<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T12:13+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Out-of-the-box Universal Romanization Tool uroman</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date>July 15-20, 2018</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ulf</forename><surname>Hermjakob</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Information Sciences Institute</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Southern California</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jonathan</forename><surname>May</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Information Sciences Institute</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Southern California</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kevin</forename><surname>Knight</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Information Sciences Institute</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Southern California</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Out-of-the-box Universal Romanization Tool uroman</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 56th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics-System Demonstrations</title>
						<meeting>the 56th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics-System Demonstrations <address><addrLine>Melbourne, Australia</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="13" to="18"/>
							<date type="published">July 15-20, 2018</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<note>13</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>We present uroman, a tool for converting text in myriads of languages and scripts such as Chinese, Arabic and Cyrillic into a common Latin-script representation. The tool relies on Unicode data and other tables , and handles nearly all character sets, including some that are quite obscure such as Tibetan and Tifinagh. uroman converts digital numbers in various scripts to Western Arabic numerals. Romanization enables the application of string-similarity metrics to texts from different scripts without the need and complexity of an intermediate phonetic representation. The tool is freely and publicly available as a Perl script suitable for inclusion in data processing pipelines and as an interactive demo web page.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>String similarity is a useful feature in many natural language processing tasks. In machine translation, it can be used to improve the alignment of bitexts, and for low-resource languages with a related lan- guage of larger resources, it can help to decode out-of-vocabulary words. For example, suppose we have to translate degustazione del vino with- out any occurrence of degustazione in any train- ing corpora, but we do know that in a related lan- guage dégustation de vin means wine tasting, we can use string similarity to infer the meaning of degustazione.</p><p>String similarity metrics typically assume that the strings are in the same script, but many cross- lingual tasks such as machine translation often in- volve multiple scripts. If we can romanize text from a non-Latin script to Latin, standard string similarity metrics can be applied, including edit distance-based metrics <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Levenshtein, 1966;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Winkler, 1990</ref>) and phonetic-based metrics such as Metaphone <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Philips, 2000)</ref>.</p><p>Hindi, for example, is written in the Devanagari script and Urdu in the Arabic script, so any words between those two languages will superficially appear to be very different, even though the two languages are closely related. After romanization, however, the similarities become apparent, as can be seen in <ref type="table">Table 1:   Table 1: Example of Hindi and Urdu romanization</ref> Foreign scripts also present a massive cognitive barrier to humans who are not familiar with them. We devised a utility that allows people to trans- late text from languages they don't know, using the same information available to a machine trans- lation system <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Hermjakob et al., 2018)</ref>. We found that when we asked native English speakers to use this utility to translate text from languages such as Uyghur or Bengali to English, they strongly pre- ferred working on the romanized version of the source language compared to its original form and indeed found using the native, unfamiliar script to be a nearly impossible task.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.1">Scope of Romanization</head><p>Romanization maps characters or groups of char- acters in one script to a character or group of char- acters in the Latin script (ASCII) with the goal to approximate the pronunciation of the original text and to map cognates in various languages to simi- lar words in the Latin script, typically without the <ref type="table">Table 2</ref>: Romanization examples for 10 scripts use of any large-scale lexical resources. As a sec- ondary goal, romanization standards tend to pre- fer reversible mappings. For example, as stand- alone vowels, the Greek letters ι (iota) and υ (up- silon) are romanized to i and y respectively, even though they have the same pronunciation in Mod- ern Greek.</p><p>uroman generally follows such preference, but uroman is not always fully reversible. For exam- ple, since uroman maps letters to ASCII charac- ters, the romanized text does not contain any dia- critics, so the French word ou ("or") and its homo- phone o` u ("where") both map to romanized ou.</p><p>uroman provides the option to map to a plain string or to a lattice of romanized text, which al- lows the system to output alternative romaniza- tions. This is particularly useful for source lan- guages that use the same character for significantly different sounds. The Hebrew letter Pe for exam- ple can stand for both p and f. Lattices are output in JSON format.</p><p>Note that romanization does not necessarily capture the exact pronunciation, which varies across time and space (due to language change and dialects) and can be subject to a number of processes of phonetic assimilation. It also is not a translation of names and cognates to English (or any other target language). See <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Table 3</ref>    Romanization tools have long existed for spe- cific individual languages such as the Kakasi 2 kanji-to-kana/romaji converter for Japanese, but to the best of our knowledge, we present the first pub- licly available (near) universal romanizer that han- dles n-to-m character mappings. Many romaniza- tion examples are shown in <ref type="table">Table 2</ref> and examples of n-to-m character mapping rules are shown in <ref type="table">Table 7</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">System Description</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">Unicode Data</head><p>As its basis, uroman uses the character descrip- tions of the Unicode table. <ref type="bibr">3</ref> For the characters of most scripts, the Unicode table contains descrip- tions such as CYRILLIC SMALL LETTER SHORT U or CYRILLIC CAPITAL LETTER TE WITH MIDDLE HOOK. Using a few heuristics, uroman identifies the phonetic token in that description, i.e. U and TE for the examples above. The heuris- tics use a list of anchor keywords such as letter and syllable as well as a number of modifier pat- terns that can be discarded. Given the phonetic token of the Unicode description, uroman then uses a second set of heuristics to predict the ro- manization for these phonetic tokens, i.e. u and t. For example, if the phonetic token is one of more consonants followed by one or more vowels, the predicted romanization is the leading sequence of consonants, e.g. SHA → sh.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">Additional Tables</head><p>However, these heuristics often fail. An exam- ple of a particularly spectacular failure is SCHWA → schw instead of the desired e. Addition- ally, there are sequences of characters with non- compositional romanization. For example, the standard romanization for the Greek sequence omikron+upsilon, (ου) is the Latin ou rather than the character-by-character romanization oy.</p><p>As a remedy, we manually created additional correction tables that map sequences of one or more characters to the desired romanization, with currently 1,088 entries. The entries in these tables can be restricted by conditions, for example to spe- cific languages or to the beginning of a word, and can express alternative romanizations. This data table is a core contribution of the tool.</p><p>uroman additionally includes a few special heuristics cast in code, such as for the voweliza- tions of a number of Indian languages and Ti- betan, dealing with diacritics, and a few language- specific idiosyncrasies such as the Japanese sokuon and Thai consonant-vowel swaps.</p><p>Building these uroman resources has been greatly facilitated by information drawn from Wikipedia, 4 Richard Ishida's script notes, <ref type="bibr">5</ref> and ALA-LC Romanization Tables. <ref type="bibr">6</ref> </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3">Characters without Unicode Description</head><p>The Unicode table does not include character de- scriptions for all scripts.</p><p>For Chinese characters, we use a Mandarin pinyin table for romanization.</p><p>For Korean, we use a short standard Hangul ro- manization algorithm. <ref type="bibr">7</ref> For Egyptian hieroglyphs, we added single- sound phonetic characters and numbers to uro- man's additional tables.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.4">Numbers</head><p>uroman also romanizes numbers in digital form.</p><p>For some scripts, number characters map one- to-one to Western Arabic numerals 0-9, e.g. for Bengali, Eastern Arabic and Hindi.</p><p>For other scripts, such as Amharic, Chinese, and Egyptian hieroglyphics, written numbers are structurally different, e.g. the Amharic num- ber character sequence 10·9·100·90·8 = 1998 and the Chinese number character sequence 2·10·5·10000·6·1000 = 256000. uroman includes a special number module to accomplish this latter type of mapping. Examples are shown in <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">Table 5</ref>.</p><p>Note that for phonetically spelled-out numbers such as Greek οκτώ, uroman romanizes to the spelled-out Latin okto rather than the digital 8.  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.5">Romanization of Latin Text</head><p>Some Latin script-based languages have words for which spelling and pronunciation differ substan- tially, e.g. the English name Knight (IPA: /naIt/) and French Bordeaux (/bOK.do/), which compli- cates string similarity matching if the correspond- ing spelling of the word in the non-Latin script is based on pronunciation.</p><p>uroman therefore offers alternative romaniza- tions for words such as <ref type="bibr">Knight and Bordeaux (see</ref>  <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">Table 6</ref> for an example of the former), but, as a policy uroman always preserves the original Latin spelling, minus any diacritics, as the top romanization alternative.  <ref type="table">Table 7</ref> includes examples of the Romanization rules in uroman, including n-to-m mappings.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.6">Caching</head><p>uroman caches token romanizations for speed. <ref type="table">Table 7</ref>: Romanization rules with two examples each for Greek, Uyghur, Japanese, and English, with a variety of n-to-m mappings. (::s = source; ::t = target; ::lcode = language code)</p><p>3 Download and Demo Sites uroman v1.2 is publicly available for download at bit.ly/isi-nlp-software. The fully self-sufficient software package includes the implementation of uroman in Perl with all necessary data tables. The software is easy to install (gunzip and tar), with- out any need for compilation or any other software (other than Perl). Typical call (for plain text output):</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">uroman.pl --lc uig &lt; STDIN &gt; STDOUT</formula><p>where -lc uig specifies the (optional) language code (e.g. Uyghur).</p><p>There is also an interactive demo site at bit.ly/uroman. Users may enter text in the lan- guage and script of their choice, optionally specify a language code, and then have uroman romanize the text.</p><p>Additionally, the demo page includes sample texts in 290 languages in a wide variety of scripts. Texts in 21 sample languages are available on the demo start page and more are accessible as ran-dom texts. After picking the first random text, additional random texts will be available from three corpora to choose from (small, large, and Wikipedia articles about the US). Users can then restrict the randomness in a special option field. For example, --l will exclude texts in Latin+ scripts. For further information about possible re- strictions, hover over the word restriction (a dot- ted underline indicates that additional info will be shown when a user hovers over it).</p><p>The romanization of the output at the demo site is mouse sensitive. Hovering over characters of either the original or romanized text, the page will highlight corresponding characters. See <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref> for an example. Hovering over the original text will also display additional information such as the Unicode name and any numeric value. To sup- port this interactive demo site, the uroman package also includes fonts for Burmese, Tifinagh, Klin- gon, and Egyptian hieroglyphs, as they are some- times missing from standard browser font pack- ages.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Limitations and Future Work</head><p>The current version of uroman has a few limita- tions, some of which we plan to address in fu- ture versions. For Japanese, uroman currently ro- manizes hiragana and katakana as expected, but kanji are interpreted as Chinese characters and ro- manized as such. For Egyptian hieroglyphs, only single-sound phonetic characters and numbers are currently romanized. For Linear B, only phonetic syllabic characters are romanized. For some other extinct scripts such as cuneiform, no romanization is provided.</p><p>uroman allows the user to specify an ISO-639-3 source language code, e.g. uig for Uyghur. This invokes any language-specific romanization rules for languages that share a script with other lan- guages. Without source language code specifi- cation, uroman assumes a default language, e.g. Arabic for text in Arabic script. We are consid- ering adding a source language detection com- ponent that will automatically determine whether an Arabic-script source text is Arabic, Farsi, or Uyghur etc.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Romanization Applications</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.1">Related Work</head><p>Gey (2009) reports that romanization based on ALA-LC romanization tables (see Section 2.2) is useful in cross-lingual information retrieval.</p><p>There is a body of work mapping text to pho- netic representations. <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Deri and Knight (2016)</ref> use Wiktionary and Wikipedia resources to learn text-to-phoneme mappings. Phonetic representa- tions are used in a number of end-to-end translit- eration systems <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Knight and Graehl, 1998;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Yoon et al., 2007)</ref>. <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Qian et al. (2010)</ref> describe the toolkit ScriptTranscriber, which extracts cross- lingual transliteration pairs from comparable cor- pora. A core component of ScriptTranscriber maps text to an ASCII variant of the International Phonetic Alphabet (IPA). Andy Hu's transliterator 8 is a fairly universal romanizer in JavaScript, limited to romanizing one Unicode character at a time, without context. uroman has also been used in our aforemen- tioned translation utility ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Hermjakob et al., 2018)</ref>, where humans translate text to another language, with computer support, with high fluency in the target language (English), but no prior knowledge of the source language.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.2">Applications Using uroman</head><p>uroman has been partially ported by third par- ties to Python and Java. <ref type="bibr">9</ref> </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Conclusion</head><p>Romanization tools have long existed for specific individual languages, but to the best of our knowl- edge, we present the first publicly available (near) universal romanizer that handles n-to-m character mappings. The tool offers both simple plain text as well as lattice output with alternatives, and in- cludes romanization of numbers in digital form. It has been successfully deployed in a number of multi-lingual natural language systems.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: Screenshot of Uyghur romanization on demo site at bit.ly/uroman</figDesc><graphic url="image-4.png" coords="4,72.00,62.81,453.54,174.83" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Ji et al. (2017) and Mayfield et al. (2017) use uroman for named entity recognition. Mayhew et al. (2016) use uroman for (end-to-end) translit- eration. Cheung et al. (2017) use uroman for ma- chine translation of low-resource languages.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" validated="false"><head>Table 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Examples of Greek romanization 

occurring text in Arabic and Hebrew (i.e., without 
diacritics/points); see Table 4. 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" validated="false"><head>Table 4 :</head><label>4</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Romanization with and without diacritics 

1.2 Features 

uroman has the following features: 
1. Input: UTF8-encoded text and an optional 
ISO-639-3 language code 

2. Output: Romanized text (default) or lattice of 
romanization alternatives in JSON format 

3. Nearly universal romanization 1 

4. N-to-m mapping for groups of characters that 
are non-decomposable with respect to roman-
ization 

5. Context-sensitive and source language-
specific romanization rules </table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3" validated="false"><head>Table 5 : Romanization/Arabization of numbers</head><label>5</label><figDesc></figDesc><table></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4" validated="false"><head>Table 6 : Romanization with alternatives</head><label>6</label><figDesc></figDesc><table></table></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> See Section 4 for a few limitations.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="2"> http://kakasi.namazu.org 3 ftp://ftp.unicode.org/Public/UNIDATA/UnicodeData.txt</note>

			<note place="foot" n="4"> https://en.wikipedia.org 5 https://r12a.github.io/scripts/featurelist 6 https://www.loc.gov/catdir/cpso/roman.html 7 http://gernot-katzers-spice-pages.com/var/ korean hangul unicode.html</note>

			<note place="foot" n="8"> https://github.com/andyhu/transliteration 9 https://github.com/BBN-E/bbn-transliterator</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgment</head><p>This work is supported by DARPA (HR0011-15-C-0115).</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Leon</forename><surname>Cheung</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Thamme</forename><surname>Gowda</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ulf</forename><surname>Hermjakob</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nelson</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jonathan</forename><surname>May</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alexandra</forename><surname>Mayn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nima</forename><surname>Pourdamghani</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Pust</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Elisa system description for LoReHLT</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Kevin Knight, Nikolaos Malandrakis</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Grapheme-tophoneme models for (almost) any language</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Aliya</forename><surname>Deri</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kevin</forename><surname>Knight</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 54th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the 54th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="399" to="408" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Romanization-an untapped resource for out-of-vocabulary machine translation for CLIR</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Fredric</forename><surname>Gey</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">SIGIR Workshop on Information Access in a Multilingual World</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="49" to="51" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Translating a language you don&apos;t know in the Chinese Room</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ulf</forename><surname>Hermjakob</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jonathan</forename><surname>May</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Pust</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kevin</forename><surname>Knight</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 56th Annual Meeting of Association for Computational Linguistics, Demo Track</title>
		<meeting>the 56th Annual Meeting of Association for Computational Linguistics, Demo Track</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Overview of TAC-KBP2017 13 languages entity discovery and linking</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Heng</forename><surname>Ji</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xiaoman</forename><surname>Pan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Boliang</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Joel</forename><surname>Nothman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">James</forename><surname>Mayfield</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Paul</forename><surname>Mcnamee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Cash</forename><surname>Costello</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Text Analysis Conference-Knowledge Base Population track</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Machine transliteration</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kevin</forename><surname>Knight</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jonathan</forename><surname>Graehl</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Computational Linguistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="599" to="612" />
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Binary codes capable of correcting deletions, insertions, and reversals</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Vladimir I Levenshtein</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Soviet physics doklady</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1966" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="707" to="710" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Language-independent named entity analysis using parallel projection and rule-based disambiguation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">James</forename><surname>Mayfield</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Paul</forename><surname>Mcnamee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Cash</forename><surname>Costello</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 6th Workshop on BaltoSlavic Natural Language Processing</title>
		<meeting>the 6th Workshop on BaltoSlavic Natural Language Processing</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="92" to="96" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Stephen</forename><surname>Mayhew</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christos</forename><surname>Christodoulopoulos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dan</forename><surname>Roth</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:1609.04325</idno>
		<title level="m">Transliteration in any language with surrogate languages</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
<note type="report_type">arXiv preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The double Metaphone search algorithm. C</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lawrence</forename><surname>Philips</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">C++ Users J</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">18</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="38" to="43" />
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A Python toolkit for universal transliteration</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kristy</forename><surname>Ting Qian</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Hollingshead</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kyoung-Young</forename><surname>Su-Youn Yoon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Richard</forename><surname>Kim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Sproat</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">LREC</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">String comparator metrics and enhanced decision rules in the Fellegi-Sunter model of record linkage</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">William</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Winkler</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Section on Survey Research Methods</title>
		<meeting>the Section on Survey Research Methods</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ERIC</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1990" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="354" to="359" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Multilingual transliteration using feature based phonetic method</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kyoung-Young</forename><surname>Su-Youn Yoon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Richard</forename><surname>Kim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Sproat</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 45th annual meeting of the Association of Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the 45th annual meeting of the Association of Computational Linguistics</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="112" to="119" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
