<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T10:01+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main"></title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract/>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Introduction</head><p>Welcome to the ACL 2018 Student Research Workshop! The ACL 2018 Student Research Workshop (SRW) is a forum for student researchers in computational linguistics and natural language processing. The workshop provides a unique opportunity for student participants to present their work and receive valuable feedback from the international research community as well as from selected mentors.</p><p>Following the tradition of the previous years' student research workshops, we have two tracks: research papers and research proposals. The research paper track is a venue for Ph.D. students, Masters students, and advanced undergraduates to describe completed work or work-in-progress along with preliminary results. The research proposal track is offered for advanced Masters and Ph.D. students who have decided on a thesis topic and are interested in feedback on their proposal and ideas about future directions for their work.</p><p>We received 66 submissions in total: 12 research proposals and 54 research papers. We accepted 26 papers, for an acceptance rate of 39%. After withdrawals, 22 papers are appearing in these proceedings, including 6 research proposals and 16 research papers. All of the accepted papers will be presented as posters in lunchtime sessions as a part of the main conference, split across two days (July 17th and 18th).</p><p>Mentoring is at the heart of the SRW. In keeping with previous years, students had the opportunity to participate in a pre-submission mentoring program prior to the submission deadline. This program offered students a chance to receive comments from an experienced researcher, in order to improve the quality of the writing and presentation before making their submission. Eleven authors participated in the pre-submission mentoring. In addition, authors of accepted SRW papers are matched with mentors who will meet with the students in person during the workshop. Each mentor prepares in-depth comments and questions prior to the student's presentation, and provides discussion and feedback during the workshop.</p><p>We are deeply grateful to our sponsors whose support will enable a number of students to attend the conference, including the Don and Betty Walker Scholarship Fund, Roam Analytics, Google, and the National Science Foundation under award No. 1827830. We would also like to thank our program committee members for their careful reviews of each paper, and all of our mentors for donating their time to provide feedback to our student authors.</p><p>Thank you to our faculty advisors Marie-Catherine de Marneffe, Wanxiang Che, and Malvina Nissim for their essential advice and guidance, and to the members of the ACL 2018 organizing committee, in particular Claire Cardie, Yusuke Miyao, and Priscilla Rasmussen for their helpful support. Finally, thank you to our student participants!  </p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" validated="false"><head>iii Organizers :, University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign Wuwei Lan, The Ohio State University Eric Laporte, Université Paris-Est Marne-la-Vallée Haixia Liu, The University of Nottingham Haijing Liu, Institute of Software, Chinese Academy of Sciences &amp; University of Chinese</head><label>Organizers</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Vered Shwartz, Bar-Ilan University 
Jeniya Tabassum, Ohio State University 
Rob Voigt, Stanford University 

Faculty Advisors: 

Wanxiang Che, Harbin Institute of Technology 
Marie-Catherine de Marneffe, Ohio State University 
Malvina Nissim, University of Groningen 

Program Committee: 

Roee Aharoni, Bar Ilan University 
Fernando Alva-Manchego, University of Sheffield 
Bharat Ram Ambati, Apple Inc. 
Jacob Andreas, University of California, Berkeley 
Isabelle Augenstein, Department of Computer Science, University of Copenhagen 
Petr Babkin, Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute 
Fan Bai, The Ohio State University 
Kalika Bali, Microsoft Research Labs 
Miguel Ballesteros, IBM Research AI 
David Bamman, University of California, Berkeley 
Yonatan Belinkov, MIT CSAIL 
Yonatan Bisk, University of Washington 
Facundo Carrillo, Buenos Aires University 
Arun Chaganty, Stanford University 
Kuan-Yu Chen, NTUST 
Tanmay Chinchore, M S Ramaiah Institute of Technology 
Grzegorz Chrupała, Tilburg University 
Daria Dzendzik, ADAPT Centre Dublin City University 
Kurt Junshean Espinosa, University of the Manchester 
Tina Fang, University of Waterloo 
Silvia García Méndez, AtlantTIC Center -University of Vigo 
Matt Gardner, Allen Institute for Artificial Intelligence 
Marjan Ghazvininejad, University of Southern California 
Hila Gonen, Bar-Ilan University 
Alvin Grissom II, Ursinus College 
Vivek Gupta, Microsoft Research 
He He, Stanford University 
Mohit Iyyer, Allen Institute for Artificial Intelligence 
Ganesh Jawahar, IIIT Hyderabad 
Vasu Jindal, University of Texas at Dallas 
Sudipta Kar, University of Houston 
Alina Karakanta, Saarland Univesity 
Eliyahu Kiperwasser, Bar-Ilan University 
Thomas Kober, University of Edinburgh 
Alexandar Konovalov, The Ohio State University 
v 

Alice LaiAcademy 
of Sciences 
Edison Marrese-Taylor, The University of Tokyo 
Prashant Mathur, eBay 
Brian McMahan, Rutgers University 
Paul Michel, Carnegie Mellon University 
Saif Mohammad, National Research Council Canada 
Taesun Moon, IBM Research 
Maria Moritz, University of Goettingen 
Nihal V. Nayak, Stride.AI 
Denis Newman-Griffis, The Ohio State University 
Dat Quoc Nguyen, The University of Melbourne 
Vlad Niculae, Cornell University 
Suraj Pandey, The Open University 
Mohammad Taher Pilehvar, University of Cambridge 
Daniel Preo¸tiucPreo¸tiuc-Pietro, University of Pennsylvania 
Emily Prud'hommeaux, Boston College 
Avinesh PVS, UKP Lab, Technische Universität Darmstadt 
Sudha Rao, University Of Maryland, College Park 
Will Roberts, Humboldt-Universität zu Berlin 
Stephen Roller, Facebook 
Julia Romberg, Heinrich Heine University Düsseldorf 
Farig Sadeque, University of Arizona 
Enrico Santus, MIT 
Shoetsu Sato, Graduate School of Information Science and Technology, The University of Tokyo 
Sabine Schulte im Walde, University of Stuttgart 
Sebastian Schuster, Stanford University 
Vasu Sharma, Carnegie Mellon University 
Sunayana Sitaram, Microsoft Research India 
Kevin Small, Amazon 
Katira Soleymanzadeh, Ege University 
R.Sudhesh Solomon, Indian Institute of Information Technology 
Richard Sproat, Google 
Gabriel Stanovsky, University of Washington, Allen Institute for Artificial Intelligence 
Shang-Yu Su, National Taiwan University 
Sandesh Swamy, The Ohio State University 
Ivan Vuli´cVuli´c, University of Cambridge 
Olivia Winn, Columbia University 
Zhou Yu, University of California, Davis 
Omnia Zayed, Insight Centre for Data Analytics, National University of Ireland Galway 
Meishan Zhang, Heilongjiang University, China 
Yuan Zhang, Google 

vi 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" validated="false"><head>Table of Contents</head><label>of</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Towards Opinion Summarization of Customer Reviews 
Samuel Pecar . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . 1 

Sampling Informative Training Data for RNN Language Models 
Jared Fernandez and Doug Downey . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . 9 

Learning-based Composite Metrics for Improved Caption Evaluation 
Naeha Sharif, Lyndon White, Mohammed Bennamoun and Syed Afaq Ali Shah . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . 14 </table></figure>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl/>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
