<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T12:50+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Constraining MGbank: Agreement, L-Selection and Supertagging in Minimalist Grammars</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date>July 15-20, 2018</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">John</forename><surname>Torr</surname></persName>
							<email>john.torr@cantab.net</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">School of Informatics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Edinburgh</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>11 Crichton Street</addrLine>
									<settlement>Edinburgh</settlement>
									<country key="GB">UK</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Constraining MGbank: Agreement, L-Selection and Supertagging in Minimalist Grammars</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 56th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (Long Papers)</title>
						<meeting>the 56th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (Long Papers) <address><addrLine>Melbourne, Australia</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="590" to="600"/>
							<date type="published">July 15-20, 2018</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<note>590</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>This paper reports on two strategies that have been implemented for improving the efficiency and precision of wide-coverage Minimalist Grammar (MG) parsing. The first extends the formalism presented in Torr and Stabler (2016) with a mechanism for enforcing fine-grained selectional restrictions and agreements. The second is a method for factoring computation-ally costly null heads out from bottom-up MG parsing; this has the additional benefit of rendering the formalism fully compatible for the first time with highly efficient Markovian supertaggers. These techniques aided in the task of generating MG-bank, the first wide-coverage corpus of Minimalist Grammar derivation trees.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Parsers based on deep grammatical formalisms, such as CCG ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b36">Steedman and Baldridge, 2011</ref>) and HPSG <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">(Pollard and Sag, 1994)</ref>, exhibit superior performance on certain semantically crucial (un- bounded) dependency types when compared to those with relatively shallow context free gram- mars (in the spirit of <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Collins (1997)</ref> and <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Charniak (2000)</ref>) or, in the case of modern dependency parsers ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">McDonald and Pereira (2006)</ref>, <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">Nivre et al. (2006)</ref>), no explicit formal grammar at all ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">Rimell et al. (2009)</ref>, <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">Nivre et al. (2010)</ref>). As parsing technology advances, the importance of correctly analysing these more complex construc- tion types will also inevitably increase, making re- search into deep parsing technology an important goal within NLP.</p><p>One deep grammatical framework that has not so far been applied to NLP tasks is the Minimalist Grammar (MG) formalism <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">(Stabler, 1997)</ref>. Lin- guistically, MG is a computationally-oriented for- malization of many aspects of Chomsky's (1995) Minimalist Program, arguably still the dominant framework in theoretical syntax, but so far con- spicuously absent from NLP conferences. Part of the reason for this has been that until now no Min- imalist treebank existed on which to train efficient statistical Minimalist parsers.</p><p>The Autobank (Torr, 2017) system was de- signed to address this issue. It provides a GUI for creating a wide-coverage MG together with a module for automatically generating MG trees for the sentences of the Wall Street Journal section of the Penn Treebank (PTB) <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">(Marcus et al., 1993)</ref>, which it does using an exhaustive bottom-up MG chart parser <ref type="bibr">1</ref> . This system has been used to cre- ate MGbank, the first wide coverage (precision- oriented) Minimalist Grammar and MG treebank of English, which consists of 1078 hand-crafted MG lexical categories (355 of which are phoneti- cally null) and currently covers approximately half of the WSJ PTB sentences. A problem which arose during its construction was that without any statistical model to constrain the derivation, MG parsing had to be exhaustive, and this presented some significant efficiency challenges once the grammar grew beyond a certain size 2 , mainly be- cause of the problem of identifying the location and category of phonetically silent heads (equiva- lent to type-changing unary rules) allowed by the theory. This problem was particularly acute for the MGbank grammar, which makes extensive use of such heads to multiply out the lexicon during pars-ing. This approach reduces the amount of time needed for manual annotation, and also enables the parser to better generalise to unseen construc- tions, but it can quickly lead to an explosion in the search space if left unconstrained.</p><p>This paper provides details on two strategies that were developed for constraining the hypoth- esis space for wide-coverage MG parsing. The first of these is an implementation of the sorts of selectional restrictions 3 standardly used by other formalisms, which allow a head to spec- ify certain fine-grained properties about its argu- ments. <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">Pesetsky (1991)</ref> refers to this type of fine- grained selection as l(exical)-selection, in con- trast to coarser-grained c(ategory)-selection and semantic s-selection. The same system is also used here to enforce morphosyntactic agreements, such as subject-verb agreement <ref type="bibr">4</ref> and case 'assign- ment'. It is simpler and flatter than the structured feature value matrices one finds in formalisms such as HPSG and LFG, which arguably makes it less linguistically plausible. However, it is also considerably easier to read and to annotate, which greatly facilitated the manual treebanking task.</p><p>The second technique to be presented is a method for extracting a set of complex overt cate- gories from a corpus of MG derivation trees which has the dual effect of factoring computationally costly null heads out from parsing (but not from the resulting parse trees) and rendering MGs fully compatible for the first time with existing su- pertagging techniques. Supertagging was origi- nally introduced in <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Bangalore and Joshi (1999)</ref> for the Lexicalised Tree Adjoining Grammar (LTAG) formalism ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">Schabes et al., 1988)</ref>, and involves applying Markovian part-of-speech tagging tech- niques to strongly lexicalised tag sets that are much larger and richer than the 45 tags used by the PTB. Because each supertag contains a great deal of information about the syntactic environ- ment of the word it labels, such as its subcatego- rization frame, supertagging is sometimes referred to as 'almost parsing'. It has proven highly ef- fective at making CCG <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Clark and Curran, 2007;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Lewis et al., 2016;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b41">Xu, 2016;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b40">Wu et al., 2017</ref>) pars- ing in particular efficient enough to support large- scale NLP tasks, making it desirable to apply this technique to MGs. However, existing supertag- gers can only tag what they can see, presenting a problem for MGs, which include phonetically un- pronounced heads. Our extraction algorithm ad- dresses this by anchoring null heads to overt ones within complex LTAG-like supertag categories.</p><p>The paper is arranged as follows: section 2 gives an informal overview of MGs; section 3 in- troduces the selectional mechanisms and shows how these are used in MGbank to enforce case 'assignment' (3.1), l-selection (3.2) and subject- verb agreement (3.3); section 4 presents the al- gorithm for extracting supertags from a corpus of MG derivation trees (4.1), gives details of how a standard CKY MG parser can straightforwardly be adapted to make use of these complex tags (4.2), and presents some preliminary supertagging re- sults (4.3) and a discussion of these (4.4); section 5 concludes the paper.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Minimalist Grammars</head><p>For a more detailed and formal account of the MG formalism assumed in this paper, see Torr and Sta- bler (2016) (henceforth T&amp;S); here we give only an informal overview. MG is introduced in <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">Stabler (1997)</ref>; it is a strongly lexicalised formalism in which categories are comprised of lists of struc- ture building features ordered from left to right. These features must be checked against each other and deleted during the derivation, except for a sin- gle c feature on the complementizer (C) heading the sentence, which survives intact (equivalent to reaching the S root in classical CFG parsing). Fea- tures are checked and deleted via the application of a small set of abstract Merge and Move rules. Two simple MG lexical entries are given below (The :: is a type identifier 5 ):</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">him :: d helps :: d= v</formula><p>The structure building features themselves can be categorized into four classes: selector =x/x= features, selectee x features, licensor +y features, and licensee -y features. In a directional MG, such as that presented in T&amp;S, the = symbol on the se- lector can appear on either side of the x category symbol, and this indicates whether selection is to the left or to the right. For instance, in our toy lexi- con helps's first feature is a d= selector, indicating that it is looking for a DP on its right. Since the first feature of him is a d selectee, we can merge these two words to obtain the following VP cate- gory, where ✏ is the empty string (The reason for the commas separating the left and right depen- dent string components from the head string com- ponent is to allow for subsequent head movement of the latter (see <ref type="bibr" target="#b35">Stabler (2001)</ref>):</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">✏, helps, him : v</formula><p>The strings of the two merged elements have been here been concatenated, but this will not al- ways be the case. In particular, if the selected item has additional features behind its selectee, then it will need to check these in subsequent derivational steps via applications of Move. In that case the two constituents must be kept separate within a single expression following Merge. To illustrate this, we will update the lexicon as follows:</p><p>him :: d -case helps :: d= +CASE v Merging these two items results in the following expression:</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">✏, helps, ✏ : +CASE v, him : -case</formula><p>The two subconstituents, separated above by the rightmost comma, are referred to as chains; the leftmost chain in any expression is the head of the expression; all other chains are movers. The +CASE licensor on the head chain must now at- tract a chain within the expression with a matching -case licensee as its first feature to move overtly to its left dependent (specifier) position <ref type="bibr">6</ref> . Exactly one moving chain must satisfy this condition, or this expression will be unable to enter into any further operations (if more than one chain has the same licensee feature, it will violate a con- straint on MG derivations known as the Shortest Move Constraint (SMC) and automatically be dis- carded). As this condition is satisfied by just him's 6 Uppercase licensors specify overt movement; lowercase licensors, by contrast, trigger covert movement, where only the features move, not the string (see T&amp;S). Note that the MGbank grammar follows <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Chomsky's (2008)</ref> suggestion that it is the lexical verb V, rather than the null 'little v' head gov- erning it, which checks the object's features, having inherited the relevant licensors (offline we assume) from v. This uni- fies the analysis of standard transitives with ECM construc- tions (Jack expected Mary to help), which in MGbank involve overt raising of the subject of the embedded infinitival clause to spec-VP to check accusative case (object control Jack per- suaded Mary to help involves two such movements, the first for theta and the second for case).</p><p>-case feature, we can perform the unary operation Move on this expression, resulting in the following new, single-chained expression:</p><p>him, helps, ✏ : v We can represent these binary Merge and unary Move operations using the MG derivation tree in fig 1a. Derivation trees such as this are used fre- quently in work on Stablerian Minimalist Gram- mars, but they can be deterministically mapped into phrase structure trees like <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">fig 1b 7</ref> . To continue this derivation and derive the transi- tive sentence he helps him, we will expand our lex- icon with the following categories, where square brackets indicate a null head and a &gt; diacritic on a selector feature indicates that a variant of Merge is triggered in which the head string of the selected constituent undergoes head movement to the left of the selecting constituent's head string:  Notice that at present both the nominative and ac- cusative forms of the masculine personal pronoun <ref type="bibr">[pres]</ref> helps <ref type="bibr">[trans]</ref> him : c he, <ref type="bibr">[pres]</ref>, helps in our lexicon have the same feature sequence. This means that as well as correctly generating he helps him, our grammar also overgenerates him helps he. One way to solve this would be to split +/-case features into +/-nom and +/-acc. However, many items of category d in English (e.g. the, a, you, there, it) are syncretised (i.e. have the same phonetic form) for nominative vs. accusative case. This solution therefore lacks elegance as it ex- pands the lexicon with duplicate homophonic en- tries differing in just a single (semantically mean- ingless) feature. Furthermore, increasing the size of the set k of licensees could adversely impact parsing efficiency, given that the worst case the- oretical time complexity of MG chart parsing is known to be n 2k+3 <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Fowlie and Koller, 2017)</ref>, where k is the number of moving chains allowed in any single expression by the grammar.</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">✏, [decl], he</formula><p>Instead, we will retain the single -case licensee feature and introduce NOM and ACC as subcat- egories, or selectional properties, of this feature. We will also subcategorize licensor features using selectional requirements of the form +X and -X, where X is some selectional property. Positive +X features require the presence of the specified prop- erty on the licensee feature being checked, while -X features require its absence. For example, con- sider the following updated lexical entries, where individual selectional features are separated by the . symbol: The +ACC selectional requirement on the V head's +CASE licensor specifies that the object's licensee feature must bear an ACC selectional property, while +NOM on the T(ense) head indi- cates that the subject's licensee must have a NOM property. For SMC purposes, however, these two different subcategories of -case will still block one another, meaning that k remains unaffected. The reader should satisfy themselves that our grammar now correctly blocks the ungrammatical him helps he.</p><p>We can now also address the aforementioned syncretism issue without increasing the size of the grammar. To do this, we simply allow features to bear multiple selectional properties from the same paradigm. For example, representing the pronoun it as follows will allow it to appear in either a nom- inative or an accusative case licensing position:</p><formula xml:id="formula_4">it :: d -case{ACC.NOM}</formula><p>As well as constraining Move, selectional restric- tions can also constrain Merge. For instance, we can ensure that a subject control verb like want subcategorizes for a to-infinitival CP complement, and thereby avoid overgenerating Jack wants that she help(s), simply by using the following cate- gories for want and that:</p><p>want :: c{+INF}= v{TRANS} that :: t{+FIN}= c{DECL.FIN} Because that lacks the INF feature required by want, the ungrammatical derivation is blocked. We also need to block *Jack wants she help(s), where the overt C head is omitted. Minimalists assume that finite embedded declaratives lacking an overt C are nevertheless headed by a null C - a silent counterpart of that. A complicating fac- tor is that a null complementizer is also assumed to head certain types of embedded infinitivals, in- cluding the embedded help clause in Jack wants [ CP to help]. Given that these null C heads are (trivially) homophones and that they arguably ex- ist to encode the same illocutionary force <ref type="bibr">9</ref> , an el- egant approach would be to minimize the size of the lexicon -and hence the grammar -by treat- ing them as one and the same item. On the other hand, using a single null C head syncretised with both FIN and INF will fail to block *Jack wants she help(s).</p><p>At present both C and T are specified as FIN, suggesting a redundancy. Instead, therefore, we will assume that T, being the locus of tense, is also the sole locus of inherent finiteness, but that C's selectee may inherit FIN or INF from its TP com- plement as the derivation proceeds <ref type="bibr">10</ref> . Only a null C which inherits INF from a to-TP complement will be selectable by a verb like want, blocking the 9 Infinitival complementizers are sometimes assumed to encode irrealis force (see e.g. <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">Radford (2004)</ref>) in contrast to that and its null counterpart which encode declarative force. However, the fact that Jack expects her to help is (on one reading) virtually synonymous with Jack expects that she will help suggests that in both cases the C head is encoding the same semantic property, with any subtle difference in mean- ing attributable to the contents of the Tense (T) head (i.e. to vs. will). Consider also Mary wondered whether to help vs. Mary wondered whether she should help, where the embed- ded infinitival and finite clauses are both clearly interrogative. <ref type="bibr">10</ref> If <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Grimshaw (1991)</ref> is correct that functional projections like DP, TP and CP are part of extended projections of the N and V heads they most closely c-command, then we should not be surprised to find instances where fine-grained syntactic properties are projected up through these functional layers. ungrammatical *Jack wants she help(s). However, although lacking inherent tense properties, certain C heads continue to bear inherent tense require- ments <ref type="bibr">11</ref> ; for instance, that's selector will retain its inherent +FIN, identifying it as a finite comple- mentizer.</p><p>To The <ref type="bibr">[pres]</ref> T head has an x variable on its lv= selector feature and this same variable also ap- pears to the right on its +CASE licensor and t se- lectee; any selectional properties or requirements contained on the lv selectee of its vP complement will thus percolate onto these two features (see <ref type="figure">fig 4)</ref>. The x's on the two C heads will percolate the FIN property from the t selectee of <ref type="bibr">[pres]</ref> to the c selectee of <ref type="bibr">[decl]</ref>, where it can be selected for by a verb like say, but not want, which requires INF (contained on the to T head); this will correctly block *Jack wants (that) she help(s).</p><note type="other">implement this percolation 12 mechanism, we now introduce selectional variables, which we write as x, y, z etc. A variable on a selector or licensor feature will cause all the selectional prop- erties and requirements (but not other variables) contained on the selectee or licensee feature that it checks to be copied onto all other instances of that variable on the selecting or licensing category's remaining unchecked feature sequence. Consider the following:</note><p>Although we will not discuss the details here, it is worth noting that the MGbank grammar also uses this same percolation mechanism to capture long distance subcategorization in English sub- junctives, thereby allowing Jack demanded that she be there on time while also blocking *Jack de- manded that she is there on time.</p><note type="other">✏, [pres], helps [trans] him : +CASE{+NOM.PRES.TRANS.+3SG} t{FIN.PRES.TRANS.+3SG}, he : -case{NOM.3SG} ✏, helps [</note><p>trans], him : lv{PRES.TRANS.+3SG}, he : -case{NOM.3SG} ✏, <ref type="bibr">[pres]</ref>, ✏ :: lv{+PRES.x}= +CASE{+NOM.x} t{FIN.x} <ref type="figure">Figure 4</ref>: Merge of T with vP with percolation of selectional properties and requirements.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3">Subject-Verb Agreement</head><p>The percolation mechanism introduced above can also be used to capture agreement between the subject and the inflected verb. In Minimalist the- ory, this agreement is only indirect: the subject actually agrees directly with T when it moves to become the latter's specifier, having been initially selected for either by V (in the case of non-agent arguments) or by v (in the case of agent subjects - see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">fig 3)</ref>  <ref type="bibr">13</ref> . There is also assumed to be some sort of syntactic agreement (Roberts (2010)) and/or phonetic (Chomsky (2001)) process operating be- tween T and the inflected verb, resulting in any tense/agreement inflectional material generated in T(ense) being suffixed onto the finite verb.</p><p>In MGbank, tense agreement is enforced be- tween T and the finite verb by percolating a PRES or PAST selectional property from the se- lectee of the latter up through the tree so that it can be selected for by the <ref type="bibr">[pres]</ref> or <ref type="bibr">[past]</ref> T head. Subject-verb agreement, meanwhile, is en- forced by also placing an agreement selectional <ref type="bibr">13</ref> A reviewer asks why all subjects are not directly se- lected for by V, suggesting that this appears to be a deviation from semantics, and more generally calls for some explana- tion of the underlying modelling decisions adopted here (e.g. head movements, case movements, null heads etc) which clearly deviate from the more surface oriented analyses of other formalisms used in NLP. In many cases these decisions rest on decades of research which we cannot hope to sum- marise here; for good introductions to Minimalism, see Rad- ford (2004) and <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Hornstein et al. (2005)</ref>. It is worth noting, however, that the null v head in fig 3 is essentially a valency increasing causative morpheme which ends up suffixed to the main verb (via head movement of the latter), effectively en- abling it to take an additional 'external' argument. We can therefore view the V-v complex as a single synthetic verbal head, so that just as in a language like Turkish the verbölverb¨verböl meaning 'to die' can be transformed from an intransitive to a transitive (meaning 'to kill') by appending to it the causative suffix dür, in English a verb like break can be transformed from an intransitive (the window broke) to a transitive (he broke the window) by applying a null version of this mor- pheme. This cross-linguistic perspective (which makes this formalism potentially very relevant for machine translation) reflects a central goal of Minimalism, which is to show that at a relevant level of abstract representation, all languages share a common syntax (making them easier for children to learn). Most of the analyses adopted here are standard ones from the literature (see e.g. <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">Larson's (1988)</ref>  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">MG Supertagging</head><p>The above selectional system restricts the parser's search space sufficiently well that it is feasible to generate an initial MG treebank for many of the sentences in the PTB, particularly the shorter ones and those longer ones which do not require the full range of null heads to be allowed into the chart <ref type="bibr">16</ref> . However, for longer sentences requiring null heads such as extraposers, topicalizers or fo- calizers, parsing remains impractically slow. In this section we show how computationally costly null heads can be factored out from MG parsing al- <ref type="bibr">14</ref> Note that selectional requirements are entirely inert on selectee and licensee features while, conversely, selectional properties are inert on selectors and licensors. <ref type="bibr">15</ref> For non-3SG present tense verbs, MGbank uses a -3SG negative selectional requirement; for verbs with more com- plex paradigms, however, the grammar allows for inclusive disjunctive selectional requirements. For example, the se- lectee feature of the was form of the verb be bears the fea- ture <ref type="bibr">[+1SG|+3SG]</ref>, allowing it to take either a first or third singular subject. <ref type="bibr">16</ref> The Autobank parser holds certain costly null heads back from the chart and only introduces these incrementally if it fails to parse the sentence without them. The advantage of this strategy is that it improves efficiency for many sentences, but the disadvantage is that it can also result in correct analy- ses being bled by incorrect ones. The supertagging approach introduced in this section eliminates this problem, since null heads are now anchored to overt ones as part of complex cat- egories, any of which may freely be assigned by the supertag- ger.</p><p>together by anchoring them to overt heads within complex overt categories extracted from this ini- tial treebank. This allows much more of the dis- ambiguation work to be undertaken by a statisti- cal Markovian supertagger 17 , a strategy which has proven highly effective at rendering CCG parsing in particular efficient enough for large-scale NLP tasks. We also show how a standard CKY MG parser can be adapted to make use of these com- plex categories, and present some preliminary su- pertagging results.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">Factoring null heads out from MG parsing</head><p>Consider again the lexical items which appear along the spine of the clause in <ref type="figure">fig 2.</ref> [decl] :: t= c If we view each of these head- complement merge operations as a link in a chain, then all of these null heads are either directly (in the case of v) or indirectly (in the case of T and C) linked to the overt verb. All of the information represented on V, v, T and C heads in Minimalism is in LTAG represented on a single overt lexical category (known as an initial tree). We can adopt this perspective for Minimalist parsing if we view chains of merges that start with some null head and end with some overt head as constituting com- plex overt categories. Given a corpus of deriva- tion trees, it is possible to extract all such chains appearing in the corpus, essentially precompiling all of the attested combinations of null heads with their overt anchors into the lexicon. A very simple algorithm for doing this is given below.</p><p>for each derivation tree ⌧ :</p><p>for each null head ⌘ in ⌧ : if ⌘ is a proform: linkWithGovernor(⌘); else: linkWithHeadOfComplement(⌘); groupLinksIntoSupertags() <ref type="bibr">17</ref> During treebank generation we used the C&amp;C <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Clark and Curran, 2007</ref>) supertagger retrained to take gold CCGbank categories and words as input and output MGbank supertags.</p><p>For each derivation tree, we first anchor all null heads either directly or indirectly to some overt head; this is achieved by extracting a set of links, each of which represents one merge operation in the tree. Each link is comprised of the two atomic MG lexical categories that are the arguments to the merge operation along with matching indices indicating which features are checked by the op- eration. Applying the algorithm to our example sentence would result in the following 3 links: The majority of null heads are simply linked with the head of their complement, the only ex- ception being that null proforms, such as PRO in arbitrary control constructions 18 (named <ref type="bibr">[pro-d]</ref> in MGbank) and the null verbal heads used for VP ellipsis ( <ref type="bibr">[pro-v]</ref> in MGbank), are linked to whichever head selects for them (i.e. their gov- ernor). Assuming that null proforms are the only null heads appearing at the bottom of any extended projection (ep) <ref type="bibr">19</ref> in the corpus, this ensures that all of the lexical items inside a given supertag are part of the same ep, except for PRO, which is trivially an ep in its own right and must therefore be an- chored to the verb that selects it. Note that some atomic overt heads (such as he and him in our ex- ample sentence) will not be involved in any links and will therefore form simplex supertags.</p><p>Once the merge links and unattached overt heads are extracted, the algorithm then groups them together in such a way that any lexical items which are chained together either directly or indi- rectly by merge links are contained in the same group. Because links are only formed between null heads and their complements (except in the case of the null proform heads), and not between heads and specifiers or adjuncts, each chain ends with the first overt head encountered, so that every (null or overt) head is guaranteed to appear in just one group and each group is guaranteed to contain at most one overt lexical item.</p><p>The above merge links would form one group, or supertag, represented compactly as follows:</p><p>[decl] :: t= 1 c [pres] :: lv= 2 +CASE t 1 [trans] :: v= 3 =d lv 2 helps :: d= +CASE v 3</p><p>All of the subcategorization information of the main verb is contained within this supertag, but unlike in the case of LTAG categories, this is not always the case: if an auxiliary verb were present between little vP and TP, for instance, then only little v would be anchored to the main verb, while T and C would be anchored to the structurally higher auxiliary. C is the head triggering A'- movements, such as wh-movement and topical- ization. A consequence of this is that, although like LTAG (but unlike CCG) A'-movement is lex- icalised onto an overt category here, that overt category is often structurally and linearly much closer to the A'-moved element than in LTAG. For instance, in the sentence what did she say that Pete eats for breakfast?, an LTAG would precom- pile the wh-movement onto the supertag for eats, whereas here the [int] C head licensing this move- ment would be precompiled onto did.</p><p>As noted in <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Kasai et al. (2017)</ref>, LTAG's lexical- isation of unbounded A'-movement is one reason why supertagging has proven more difficult to ap- ply successfully to TAG than to CCG, Markovian supertaggers being inherently better at identifying local dependencies. We hope that lexicalising A'- movement into a supertag that is linearly closer to the moved item will therefore ultimately prove ad- vantageous.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">Adapting an existing CKY MG parser to use MG supertags</head><p>The MG supertags can be integrated into an ex- isting CKY MG parser quite straight forwardly as follows: first, for each supertag token assigned to each word in the sentence, we map the indices that indicate which features check each other into glob- ally unique identifiers. This is necessary to ensure that different supertags and different instances of the same supertag assigned to different words are differentiated by the system. Then, whenever one of the constrained features is encountered, the parser ensures that it is only checked against the feature with the matching identifier. The parser otherwise operates as usual except that thousands of potential merge operations are now disallowed, with the result that the search space is drastically reduced (though this of course depends on the number of supertags assigned to each word). One complication concerns the dynamic pro- gramming of the chart. In standard CKY MG parsing, as with classical CFG CKY, items with the same category spanning the same substring are combined into a single chart entry during parsing. This prevents the system having to create identical tree fragments multiple times. But the current ap- proach complicates this because many items now have different predetermined futures (i.e. their unchecked features are differentially constrained), and when the system later attempts to reconstruct the trees by following the backpointers, things can become very complicated. We can avoid this is- sue, however, simply by treating the unique identi- fiers that were assigned to certain selector features as part of the category. This has the effect of split- ting the categories and will, for instance, prevent two single chain categories =d 1 d= v and =d 2 d= v from being treated as a single chart entry until their =d features have been checked.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3">Preliminary Results</head><p>An LSTM supertagger similar to that in ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Lewis et al., 2016</ref>) was trained on 13,000 sentences ran- domly chosen from MGbank, extracting various types of (super)tag from the derivation trees. A further 742 sentences were used for development, and 753 for testing, again randomly chosen. We tried training on just the automatically generated corpus and testing on the hand-crafted trees, but this hurt 1-best performances by 2-4%, no doubt owing to the fact that this hand-crafted set delib- erately contains many of the rarer constructions in the Zipfian tail which didn't make it into the au- tomatically generated corpus <ref type="bibr">20</ref> . With more data this effect should lessen. The results for n-best su- pertagging accuracies are given in table 1.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.4">Discussion</head><p>Unsurprisingly, the accuracies improve as the number of tags decreases. The CCGbank data contains by far the least tag types and has the highest performance. However, it is worth not- ing that the MG supertags contain a lot more in- formation than their CCGbank counterparts, even once A'-movement and selectional restrictions are removed. For example, MGbank encodes all predicate-argument relations directly in the syn- tax, distinguishing for instance between subject rei ab rei-A' ab-A' ov ccg |tags| <ref type="formula">3087 2087 1883 1181 717 342  1</ref> raising and subject control verbs, and between object raising (ECM) and object control verbs, whereas CCGbank itself does not. For a fairer comparison, therefore, we would need to com- bine CCGbank syntactic types with the seman- tic types of Bos ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Bos et al., 2004</ref>). There are also many types of dependencies, such as those for rightward movement and correlative focus (either..or, neither..nor, both..and), which could be delixicalised to reduce the size of the supertag sets further. Of course, the more null heads that are allowed freely into the chart, the stronger the sta- tistical model of the derivation itself must be. Fi- nally, the MGbank grammar (particularly in its rei- fied versions) is precision-oriented, in the sense that it blocks many ungrammatical sentence types (agreement/l-selection violations, binding theory violations, (anti)that-trace violations, wh-island violations etc). The extra information needed to attain this precision expands the tag set but should also ultimately help in pruning the search space, enabling the parser to try more tags. The CCG- bank grammar, meanwhile, is much more flexi- ble (making it very robust), and therefore leaves a much greater proportion of the task of constrain- ing the search space to the probability model. The 1-best accuracies are clearly not high enough to be practical for wide-coverage MG parsing at present. By the time the 3-best su- pertags per word are considered, however, the ac- curacies are in all cases quite high, and by the 25- best they are very high, although it is difficult to say at this point what level will be sufficient for wide-coverage parsing. The overt atomic tagging is much better, achieving high accuracy by the 3- best, but these tags contain the least information and therefore leave much more disambiguation to the parsing model. Clearly, using MG supertags will require an algorithm that navigates the search space as efficiently as possible and allows the su- pertagger to try as many tags for each word as pos- sible. We are in the process of re-implementing the A* search algorithm of ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">Lewis and Steedman, 2014</ref>), which allows their CCG parser to consider the complete distribution of 425 supertags for each word.</p><p>The potential efficiency advantages of parsing with MG supertags are considerable: reparsing the seed set of 960 trees (which includes 207 sen- tences which were added to cover some construc- tions not found in the Penn Treebank) takes over 8 hours on a 1.4GHz Intel Core i5 Macbook Air with a perfect oracle providing the 1-best overt atomic tag, but just over 6 minutes using reified supertags.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Conclusion</head><p>We presented two methods for constraining the parser's search space and improving efficiency during wide-coverage MG parsing. The first ex- tends the formalism with mechanisms for enforc- ing morphosyntactic agreements and selectional restrictions. The second anchors computationally costly null heads to overt heads inside complex overt categories, rendering the formalism fully compatible with Markovian supertagging tech- niques. Both techniques have proven useful for the generation of MGbank. We are now working on an A* MG parser which can consider the full distribution of supertags for each word and exploit the potential of these rich lexical categories.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>A big thank you is due to Mark Steedman, as well as to the four anonymous reviewers for all their helpful comments and suggestions. Most espe- cially, I would like to thank Miloš Stanojevi´cStanojevi´c, who coded up the LSTM supertagger, ran the experi- ments reported in this paper and made some very helpful suggestions regarding the supertagging method described above. This project was sup- ported by the Engineering and Physical Sciences Research Council (EPSRC) and an ERC H2020 Advanced Fellowship GA 742137 SEMANTAX and a Google Faculty Award.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: An MG Derivation tree for the VP him, helps (a); and its corresponding Xbar phrase structure tree (b). At this stage in the derivation the verb and its object are incorrectly ordered. This will be rectified by subsequent V-to-v head movement placing the verb to the left of its object.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>he</head><label></label><figDesc>:: d -case [trans] :: &gt;v= =d lv 8 [pres] :: lv= +CASE t [decl] :: t= c The full derivation tree and corresponding Xbar phrase structure tree for the sentence are given in fig 2 and fig 3 respectively.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>Figure 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Figure 2: MG derivation tree for the sentence he helps him.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head>him</head><label></label><figDesc>:: d -case{ACC} he :: d -case{NOM} helps :: d= +CASE{+ACC} v{PRES.TRANS} [pres] :: lv{+PRES}= +CASE{+NOM} t{FIN.PRES} [trans] :: &gt;v{+TRANS}= =d lv</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><head>[</head><label></label><figDesc>trans] :: &gt;v{+TRANS.x}= =d lv{x} [pres] :: lv{+PRES.x}= +CASE{+NOM.x} t{FIN.x} to :: lv{+BARE.x}= t{INF.x} [decl] :: t{x}= c{DECL.x} that :: t{+FIN.x}= c{DECL.x}</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_6"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>VP Shell Hypothe- sis, Baker's (1988) Uniform Theta Assignment Hypothesis, Koopman and Sportiche's (1991) Verb Phrase Internal Sub- ject Hypothesis, and Chomsky (1995; 2008) on little v). restriction (+3SG, +1PL, -3SG etc) on the finite verb's selectee, and then percolating this up to the +CASE licensor of the T head. We thus have the following updated entries: him :: d -case{ACC.3SG} he :: d -case{NOM.3SG} helps :: d= +CASE{+ACC} v{+3SG.PRES} The percolation step from little v (lv) to T is shown in fig 4; lv has already inherited PRES and +3SG from V (helps) at this point, and these fea- tures now percolate to T's licensor and selectee 14 owing to the x variables; the PRES feature inher- ited from V by v is selected for by T, enforcing non-local tense agreement between T and V, while the +3SG enforces subject verb agreement 15 .</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_7"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>[pres] :: lv= +CASE t [trans] :: &gt;v= =d lv helps :: d= +CASE v Recall that the null [trans] little v merges with the VP headed by overt helps, while the null [pres] T head merges with the vP, and the null [decl] C with TP.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_8"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>link1: [decl] :: t= 1 c, [pres] :: lv= +CASE t 1 link2: [pres] :: lv= 2 +CASE t, [trans] :: v= =d lv 2 link3: [trans] :: v= 3 =d lv, helps :: d= +CASE v 3</figDesc></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> The parser is based on Harkema&apos;s (2001) CKY variant. 2 As Cramer and Zhang (2010) (who pursue a similar treebanking strategy for HPSG) observe, there is very often considerable tension between the competing goals of efficiency and coverage for deep, hand-written and precision-oriented parsers, which aim not only to provide detailed linguistic analyses for grammatical sentences, but also to reject ungrammatical ones wherever possible.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="3"> These were briefly introduced in Torr (2017), but are expounded here in much greater depth. 4 The approach to agreement adopted here differs in various respects from the operation Agree (Chomsky (2000) (2001)) assumed in current mainstream Minimalism.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="5"> :: indicates a non-derived item and : a derived one.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="7"> MGbank includes MG derivation tree, MG derived (bare phrase structure) tree, and Xbar tree formats. 8 Note that little v is written as lv in MGbank derivation trees because upper vs lowercase letters are used to trigger different rules. In the corresponding MGbank Xbar trees, however, v has been converted to V and lv to v, to make these trees more familiar.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="11"> The property vs. requirement distinction mirrors Chomsky&apos;s (1995) interpretable vs. uninterpretable one. 12 Note that because we are only allowing selectional properties and requirements to percolate, rather than the structure building feature themselves, this system is fundamentally different from that described in Kobele (2005), where it was shown that allowing licensee features to be percolated leads to type 0 MGs. Furthermore, by unifying any multiple instances of the same selectional property or requirement that arise on a structure building feature owing to percolation, we can ensure that the set of MG terminals and non-terminals remains finite and thus that the weak equivalence to MCFG (Michaelis, 1998; Harkema, 2001) is maintained.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="18"> Other instances of control are treated as cases of Amovement following Boeckx et al. (2010). 19 Here, we define the clausal extended projection as running from V up to the closest CP (or TP if CP is absent, as in ECM constructions), and for nominals from N up to the closest PP (or DP if PP is absent).</note>

			<note place="foot" n="20"> There are 831 category types in the automatically generated corpus from a total of 1078 for the entire treebank.</note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Incorporation: A theory of grammatical function changing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Mark</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Baker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1988" />
			<publisher>University of Chicago Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Supertagging: An approach to almost parsing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Srinivas</forename><surname>Bangalore</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Aravind</forename><surname>Joshi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Computational Linguistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">25</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="237" to="265" />
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Cedric</forename><surname>Boeckx</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Norbert</forename><surname>Hornstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jairo</forename><surname>Nunes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Control as Movement</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Cambridge, UK</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Cambridge University Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Widecoverage semantic representations from a ccg parser</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Johan</forename><surname>Bos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Stephen</forename><surname>Clark</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mark</forename><surname>Steedman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Julia</forename><surname>James R Curran</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Hockenmaier</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 20th international conference on Computational Linguistics, page 1240. Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the 20th international conference on Computational Linguistics, page 1240. Association for Computational Linguistics</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A maximum-entropy-inspired parser</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Eugene</forename><surname>Charniak</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 1st Meeting of the North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the 1st Meeting of the North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics<address><addrLine>Seattle, WA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="132" to="139" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The Minimalist Program</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Noam</forename><surname>Chomsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
			<publisher>MIT Press</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Cambridge, Massachusetts</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Minimalist inquiries: The framework</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Noam</forename><surname>Chomsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Step by Step: Essays in Minimalist Syntax in Honor of Howard Lasnik</title>
		<editor>Roger Martin, David Michaels, and Juan Uriagereka</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Cambridge, MA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>MIT Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="89" to="155" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Derivation by phase. Ken Hale: A life in language</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Noam</forename><surname>Chomsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="52" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">In Robert Freidin, Carlos Peregrin Otero, and Maria Zubizarreta, editors, Foundational Issues in Linguistic Theory: Essays in Honor of Jean-Roger Vergnaud</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Noam</forename><surname>Chomsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
			<publisher>MIT Press</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="133" to="166" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>On phases</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Widecoverage efficient statistical parsing with ccg and log-linear models</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Stephen</forename><surname>Clark</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>James R Curran</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Computational Linguistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">33</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="493" to="552" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Three generative lexicalized models for statistical parsing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Collins</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 35th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the 35th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Madrid. ACL</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="16" to="23" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Constraining robust constructions for broad-coverage parsing with precision grammars</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Cramer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 23rd International Conference on Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the 23rd International Conference on Computational Linguistics<address><addrLine>Beijing</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="223" to="231" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Parsing minimalist languages with interpreted regular tree grammars</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Meaghan</forename><surname>Fowlie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alexander</forename><surname>Koller</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Thirteenth International Workshop on Tree Adjoining Grammar and Related Formalisms (TAG+13)</title>
		<meeting>the Thirteenth International Workshop on Tree Adjoining Grammar and Related Formalisms (TAG+13)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="11" to="20" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Unpublished manuscript</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jane</forename><surname>Grimshaw</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Words and Structure</title>
		<editor>J. Grimshaw</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Waltham, Mass; Stanford</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1991" />
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>Brandeis University</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
	<note>: CSLI)</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Parsing Minimalist Languages</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hendrik</forename><surname>Harkema</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
			<pubPlace>UCLA, Los Angeles, California</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
<note type="report_type">Ph.D. thesis</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Understanding Minimalism</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Norbert</forename><surname>Hornstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jairo</forename><surname>Nunes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kleanthes</forename><surname>Grohmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Tag parsing with neural networks and vector representations of supertags</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jungo</forename><surname>Kasai</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bob</forename><surname>Frank</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tom</forename><surname>Mccoy</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2017 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</title>
		<meeting>the 2017 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1712" to="1722" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Owen Rambow, and Alexis Nasr</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Features moving madly: A formal perspective on feature percolation in the minimalist program</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gregory</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Kobele</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Research on Language and Computation</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="391" to="410" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The position of subjects</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hilda</forename><surname>Koopman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dominique</forename><surname>Sportiche</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Lingua</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">85</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2-3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="211" to="258" />
			<date type="published" when="1991" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">On the double object construction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Richard</forename><surname>Larson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Linguistic Inquiry</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="335" to="392" />
			<date type="published" when="1988" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Lstm ccg parsing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mike</forename><surname>Lewis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kenton</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Luke</forename><surname>Zettlemoyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2016 Conference of the North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics: Human Language Technologies</title>
		<meeting>the 2016 Conference of the North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics: Human Language Technologies</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="221" to="231" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A* ccg parsing with a supertag-factored model</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mike</forename><surname>Lewis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mark</forename><surname>Steedman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2014 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP)</title>
		<meeting>the 2014 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="990" to="1000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Building a large annotated corpus of english: The penn treebank</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mary</forename><forename type="middle">Ann</forename><surname>Mitchell P Marcus</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Beatrice</forename><surname>Marcinkiewicz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Santorini</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Computational linguistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="313" to="330" />
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Discriminative learning and spanning tree algorithms for dependency parsing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ryan</forename><surname>Mcdonald</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Fernando</forename><surname>Pereira</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>University of Pennsylvania</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Derivational minimalism is mildly context-sensitive</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jens</forename><surname>Michaelis</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">International Conference on Logical Aspects of Computational Linguistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="179" to="198" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Maltparser: A data-driven parser-generator for dependency parsing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Joakim</forename><surname>Nivre</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Johan</forename><surname>Hall</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jens</forename><surname>Nilsson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of LREC</title>
		<meeting>LREC</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2216" to="2219" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Evaluation of dependency parsers on unbounded dependencies</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Joakim</forename><surname>Nivre</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Laura</forename><surname>Rimell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ryan</forename><surname>Mcdonald</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Carlos</forename><surname>Gomez-Rodriguez</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 23rd International Conference on Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the 23rd International Conference on Computational Linguistics</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="833" to="841" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Pesetsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Zero syntax</title>
		<editor>Infinitives. Unpublished MS., MIT</editor>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1991" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Head Driven Phrase Structure Grammar</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Carl</forename><surname>Pollard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ivan</forename><surname>Sag</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1994" />
			<publisher>CSLI Publications</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Stanford, CA</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Andrew</forename><surname>Radford</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Minimalist Syntax: Exploring the Structure of English</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Cambridge University Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Unbounded dependency recovery for parser evaluation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Laura</forename><surname>Rimell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Stephen</forename><surname>Clark</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mark</forename><surname>Steedman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</title>
		<meeting>the Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing<address><addrLine>Singapore. ACL</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="813" to="821" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Agreement and head movement: Clitics, incorporation, and defective goals</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Ian G Roberts</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Linguistic Inquiry Monograph</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">59</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<publisher>MIT Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Parsing strategies with &apos;lexicalized&apos; grammars: application to tree adjoining grammars</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yves</forename><surname>Schabes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Anne</forename><surname>Abeille</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Aravind K</forename><surname>Joshi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 12th conference on Computational linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the 12th conference on Computational linguistics</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1988" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="578" to="583" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Derivational minimalism</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Edward</forename><surname>Stabler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<analytic>
			</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Logical Aspects of Computational Linguistics (LACL&apos;96)</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>New York</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1328</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="68" to="95" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Recognizing head movement</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Edward</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Stabler</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Logical Aspects of Computational Linguistics: 4th International Conference</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Le Croisic, France</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2001-06-27" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="245" to="260" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Combinatory categorial grammar</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mark</forename><surname>Steedman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jason</forename><surname>Baldridge</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Non-Transformational Syntax: A Guide to Current Models</title>
		<editor>Robert Borsley and Kirsti Börjars</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Blackwell, Oxford</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="181" to="224" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Autobank: a semi-automatic annotation tool for developing deep minimalist grammar treebanks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">John</forename><surname>Torr</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the EACL 2017</title>
		<meeting>the EACL 2017</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<monogr>
				<title level="m">Software Demonstrations</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Valencia, Spain</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017-04-37" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="81" to="86" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Coordination in minimalist grammars: Excorporation and across the board (head) movement</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">John</forename><surname>Torr</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Edward</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Stabler</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Twelfth International Workshop on Tree Adjoining Grammar and Related Formalisms (TAG+12)</title>
		<meeting>the Twelfth International Workshop on Tree Adjoining Grammar and Related Formalisms (TAG+12)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="17" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b40">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A dynamic window neural network for ccg supertagging</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Huijia</forename><surname>Wu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jiajun</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chengqing</forename><surname>Zong</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Thirty-First AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence (AAAI-17)</title>
		<meeting>the Thirty-First AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence (AAAI-17)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3337" to="3343" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b41">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Lstm shift-reduce ccg parsing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wenduan</forename><surname>Xu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2016 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</title>
		<meeting>the 2016 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1754" to="1764" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
