<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T11:02+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Sentence Suggestion of Japanese Functional Expressions for Chinese-speaking Learners</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date>July 15-20, 2018</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jun</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Nara Institute of Science and Technology</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hiroyuki</forename><surname>Shindo</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Nara Institute of Science and Technology</orgName>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">RIKEN Center for Advanced Intelligence Project (AIP)</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yuji</forename><surname>Matsumoto</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Nara Institute of Science and Technology</orgName>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">RIKEN Center for Advanced Intelligence Project (AIP)</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Sentence Suggestion of Japanese Functional Expressions for Chinese-speaking Learners</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 56th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics-System Demonstrations</title>
						<meeting>the 56th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics-System Demonstrations <address><addrLine>Melbourne, Australia</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="56" to="61"/>
							<date type="published">July 15-20, 2018</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<note>56</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>We present a computer-assisted learning system, Jastudy 1 , which is particularly designed for Chinese-speaking learners of Japanese as a second language (JSL) to learn Japanese functional expressions with suggestion of appropriate example sentences. The system automatically recognizes Japanese functional expressions using a free Japanese morphological analyz-er MeCab, which is retrained on a Conditional Random Fields (CRF) model. In order to select appropriate example sentences , we apply Support Vector Machines for Ranking (SVMrank) to estimate the complexity of the example sentences using Japanese-Chinese homographs as an important feature. In addition, we cluster the example sentences that contain Japanese functional expressions to discriminate different meanings and usages, based on part-of-speech, conjugation forms and semantic attributes, using the k-means clustering algorithm. Experimental results demonstrate the effectiveness of our approach.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>In the process of Japanese learning, learners must study many vocabulary words as well as various functional expressions. Since a large number of Chinese characters (Kanji characters in Japanese) are commonly used both in Chinese and Japa- nese, one of the most difficult and challenging problem for Chinese-speaking learners of Japa- nese as a second language (JSL) is the acquisition of Japanese functional expressions <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Dongli Han, and Xin Song. 2011</ref>). Japanese has various types of compound functional expressions that consist of more than one word including both content words and functional words, such as "ざるをえ 1 http://jastudy.net/jastudy.php ない (have to)", "ことができる (be able to)". Due to various meanings and usages of Japanese functional expressions, it is fairly difficult for JSL learners to learn them.</p><p>In recent years, certain online Japanese learn- ing systems are developed to support JSL learn- ers, such as Reading Tutor 2 , Asunaro 3 , Rikai <ref type="bibr">4</ref> , and WWWJDIC 5 . Some of these systems are particu- larly designed to enable JSL learners to read and write Japanese texts by offering the word infor- mation with their corresponding difficulty infor- mation or translation information ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Ohno et al., 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Toyoda 2016)</ref>. However, learners' native language background has not been taken into ac- count in these systems. Moreover, these systems provide learners with limited information about the various types of Japanese functional expres- sions, which learners actually intend to learn as a part of the procedure for learning Japanese. Therefore, developing a learning system that can assist JSL learners to learn Japanese functional expressions is crucial in Japanese education.</p><p>In this paper, we present Jastudy, a computer- assisted learning system, aiming at helping Chi- nese-speaking JSL learners with their study of Japanese functional expressions. We train a CRF model and use a Japanese morphological analyzer MeCab 6 to detect Japanese functional expres- sions. To select the appropriate example sentenc- es, we take Japanese-Chinese homographs as an important feature to estimate the complexity of example sentences using SVMrank <ref type="bibr">7</ref> . In addition, in order to suggest example sentences that con- tain the target Japanese functional expression with the same meaning and usage, we cluster the example sentences, based on part-of-speech, con- jugation forms and semantic attributes of the neighboring words, using the k-means clustering algorithm in Scikit-learn 8 .</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">General Method</head><p>As shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref>, our proposed system is mainly composed of three processes: automatic detection of Japanese functional expressions, sen- tence complexity estimation and sentence cluster- ing. In this section, we explain them in detail. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">Detection of Functional Expressions</head><p>Several previous researches have been especially paid attention on automatic detection of Japanese functional expressions ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Tsuchiya et al., 2006;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Shime et al., 2007;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Suzuki et al., 2012</ref>). However, recognition of Japanese functional expressions is still a difficult problem. For automatic detection of Japanese functional expressions, we apply a Japa- nese morphological analyzer Mecab, which em- ploys CRF algorithm to build the feature-based statistical model for morphological analysis.</p><p>While MeCab provides a pre-trained model us- ing RWCP Text Corpus as well as Kyoto Univer- sity Corpus (KC), we train a new CRF model us- ing our training corpus, hoping MeCab can detect more Japanese functional expressions. To prepare the training corpus, we firstly referenced certain Japanese grammar dictionaries (Xiaoming Xu and Reika, 2013; Estuko Tomomastu, Jun Miyamoto and Masako <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Wakuki, 2016)</ref> to construct a list of Japanese functional expressions. As a result, we collected approximately 4,600 types of various surface forms in our list. Then we gathered 21,435 sentences from Tatoeba 9 corpus, HiraganaTime 10 corpus, BCCWJ <ref type="bibr">11</ref> and some grammar dictionaries <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Jamashi and Xu, 2001;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Xu and Reika, 2013)</ref> and segmented each sentence into word level using MeCab. Finally, we manually annotated part-of- speech information for each Japanese functional expression in our training corpus. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 2</ref> shows an example sentence after pre-processing. after I take a bath.) after pre-processing. In the sentence, the Japanese functional expression and its part-of-speech information are in bold.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">Sentence Complexity Estimation</head><p>There are a large number of Japanese words writ- ten with Chinese characters. Most of the words share identical or similar meaning with the Chi- nese words. We define these words as Japanese- Chinese homographs in our study. For Chinese- speaking learners, it is easy to understand their meanings even though they have never learned Japanese. Therefore, Japanese-Chinese homo- graphs should be considered as an important fea- ture in estimating sentence complexity. In order to construct a list of Japanese-Chinese homographs, we firstly extracted Japanese words written only with Chinese characters from two Japanese dictionaries: IPA (mecab-ipadic-2.7.0- 20070801) <ref type="bibr">12</ref> and UniDic (unidic-mecab 2.1.2) <ref type="bibr">13</ref> . These two dictionaries are used as the standard dictionaries for the Japanese morphological ana- lyzer MeCab, with appropriate part-of-speech in- formation for each expression. We then extracted the Chinese translations of these Japanese words from two online dictionary websites: and Weblio <ref type="bibr">15</ref> . We compared the character forms of Japanese words with their Chinese translations to identify whether the Japanese word is a Japanese- Chinese homograph or not. Since Japanese words use both the simplified Chinese characters and the traditional Chinese characters, we first replaced all the traditional Chinese characters with the corre- sponding simplified Chinese characters. If the character form of a Japanese word is the same as the character form of the Chinese translation, the Japanese word is recognized as a Japanese- Chinese homograph, as illustrated in <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>. Considering unknown words in the above online dictionaries, we also referenced an online Chinese encyclopedia: Baike Baidu <ref type="bibr">16</ref> and a Japa- nese dictionary: Kojien fifth Edition <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Shinmura, 1998)</ref>. If a Japanese word and its corresponding Chinese translation share an identical or a similar meaning, the Japanese word is also identified as a Japanese-Chinese homograph. Ultimately, we cre- ated a list of Japanese-Chinese homographs that consists of approximately 14,000 words.  <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>: Examples of Identification of Japanese- Chinese homographs</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Original</head><p>To estimate sentence complexity, we follow the standard of the JLPT (Japanese Language Profi- ciency Test). The JLPT consists of five levels, ranging from N5 (the least difficult level) to N1 (the most difficult level) <ref type="bibr">17</ref> . We employ the follow- ing 12 features as the baseline feature set: Different from the standard of the JLPT, the words in the list of Japanese-Chinese homographs (JCHs) were categorized separately as a new fea- ture. Ultimately, we combine the following new features with the baseline features (all 17 fea- tures), forming our feature set. The last three features are to measure syntactic complexity of a sentence. We used a well-known Japanese dependency structure analyzer Cabo- Cha <ref type="bibr">18</ref> to divide an example sentence into base phrases (called bunsetsu) and to obtain its syntac- tic dependency structure. For example, the exam- ple sentence "彼は人生に満足して死んだ。 (He died content with his life.)" is divided into four phrases: "彼は", "人生に", "満足して", "死 んだ". In this sentence, the first, and the third phrases depend on the fourth, and the second phrase depends on the third. The numbers of syn- tactic dependencies in this sentence is 3. The length of syntactic dependencies is the numbers of phrases between arbitrary phrase and its depend- ent. In this sentence, the average length of syntac- tic dependencies is 1.7 (the length of syntactic de- pendency between the first and the fourth is 3, the length of syntactic dependency between the se- cond and the third is 1, and the length of syntactic dependency between the third and the fourth is 1). The fourth phrase has two child's phrases while the third has only one child phrase, so the maxi- mum number of child phrases in this sentence is 2.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3">Sentence Clustering</head><p>Some Japanese functional expressions have two or more meanings and usages. For example, the following two example sentences contain the identical Japanese functional expression "そ う だ", but have different meanings. However, we can distinguish the meaning of "そうだ" through part-of-speech and conjugation forms of the words that appear just before "そうだ".</p><p>雨が降りそうだ。 (It looks like it will rain.) 雨が降るそうだ。 (It's heard that it will rain.)</p><p>To obtain example sentences for each of dis- tinct usages of a functional expression, we apply a clustering algorithm with a small number of known examples (those appear in dictionaries) and a large number of untagged example sentenc- es. For the features of sentence clustering, we uti- lize the following features: part-of-speech, conju- gation form, and semantic attribute of the word that appear just before or after the target Japanese functional expression.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Experiments and Results</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Automatically Detecting Japanese Func- tional Expressions</head><p>This experiment evaluates automatic detection of Japanese functional expressions. We apply CRF++ <ref type="bibr">19</ref> , which is an open source implementation of CRF for segmenting sequential data. We utilized nine features including surface forms and their part-of-speech in our training. The training corpus mentioned in Section 2.1 was used in the CRF++. The CRF++ learned the training corpus and outputted a model file as the learning result. We then applied MeCab, trained on our training corpus, to automatically recognize the Japanese functional expressions.</p><p>For the test data, we randomly extracted 200 example sentences from Tatoeba, HiraganaTimes and BCCWJ. <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">Table 2</ref> shows some examples of de- tected Japanese functional expressions by our sys- tem. The final evaluation results are shown in Ta- ble 3. We obtained 86.5% accuracy, indicating our approach has certain validity.   </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Estimating Sentence Complexity</head><p>This experiment evaluates sentence complexity estimation, using an online machine learning tool SVMrank.</p><p>We first collected 5,000 example sentences from Tatoeba, HiraganaTimes, BCCWJ and ran- domly paired them and constructed 2,500 sen- tence pairs. Then 15 native Chinese-speaking JSL learners, all of whom have been learning Japanese for about one year, were invited to read the pairs of example sentences and asked to choose the one which is easier to understand. We asked three learners to compare each pair and the final deci- sion was made by majority voting. We finally ap- plied a set of five-fold cross-validations with each combination of 4,000 sentences as the training da- ta and 1,000 sentences as the test data.</p><p>The experimental results using baseline features and our method using all of the proposed features are presented in <ref type="table" target="#tab_5">Tables 4 and 5</ref>. Compared with the results using the baseline features, our method enhances the average accuracy by 3.3%, partially demonstrating the effectiveness of our features.    <ref type="table">Table 5</ref>: Experimental results using our proposed features</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3">Clustering Example Sentences</head><p>This experiment evaluates the performance of sen- tence clustering, using the k-means clustering al- gorithm in Scikit-learn. Here in our study, we took five different types of Japanese functional expressions as the exam- ples. For the test data, we collected 10 example sentences, which were used for the reference, from Japanese functional expression dictionaries and 20 example sentences from Tatoeba, Hiraga- naTimes, and BCCWJ for each type of Japanese functional expressions, respectively. We conduct- ed our experiments with the number of clusters ranging from four to six. The clustering result was evaluated based on whether the test data that was clustered into one cluster share the same usage of a Japanese functional expression. The experi- mental results are shown in <ref type="table" target="#tab_7">Table 6</ref>. The average results of accuracies for the number of clusters ranging from four to six are 89%, 93%, 92%, in- dicating the usefulness of the sentence clustering method for classifying sentences in the same us- age.  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Featured functions of the Demo</head><p>In our proposed demo, we have implemented the following main functions.</p><p>1. The function to detect Japanese functional expressions. Given a sentence, Jastudy automati- cally segments the input sentence into individual words using MeCab. Difficult Japanese functional expressions (N2 and above) in the input sentence are simplified with easier Japanese functional ex- pressions (N3 and below) or with phrases and shown in the output sentence, using a "Simple Japanese Replacement List" (Jun <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Liu and Yuji Matsumoto, 2016)</ref>. An example is shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">Fig- ure 3</ref>. Moreover, Jastudy represents detailed in- formation about the surface-form, part-of-speech of each word in the input sentence and the output sentence, respectively. 2. The function to provide JSL learners with the detail information about the meaning, usage and example sentences of the Japanese functional ex- pression which appears in the input sentence and the output sentence, respectively. An example is shown in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_7">Figure 4</ref>. Learners can also choose the Japanese functional expressions they want to learn, based on their Japanese abilities. 3. The function to suggest comprehensive ex- ample sentences. The JSL learners can search more example sentences through the following three aspects: 1) only keyword, 2) only usage, 3) both keyword and usage. For example, the learner inputs the Japanese functional expression "そう だ" as a keyword and selects its meaning and us- age "it looks like" from drop-down list, a list of example sentences that contain the functional ex- pression sharing the same meaning are retrieved to form the corpus, as shown in <ref type="figure">Figure 5</ref>. The only sentences whose complexity is equal to or below the learner's level are retrieved.</p><p>Figure 5: Example sentences suggested by the system, given "そうだ" with its meaning as "様 態(it looks like)"</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Conclusion and Future Work</head><p>In this paper, we presented a computer-assisted leaning system of Japanese language for Chinese- speaking learners with their study of Japanese functional expressions. The system detects Japa- nese functional expressions using MeCab that employs the CRF model we trained. We apply SVMrank to estimate sentence complexity using the Japanese-Chinese homographs as an important feature to suggest example sentences that are easy to understand for Chinese-speaking JSL learners. Moreover, we cluster example sentences contain- ing the Japanese functional expressions with the same meanings and usages. The experimental re- sults indicate effectiveness of our method. We plan to examine the run-time effectiveness of the system for JSL learners. This will be our fu- ture task for improving the performance of our system.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: The processing stages of the system</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2: An example sentence (I will go to sleep after I take a bath.) after pre-processing. In the sentence, the Japanese functional expression and its part-of-speech information are in bold.</figDesc><graphic url="image-10.png" coords="2,306.82,234.45,226.80,69.36" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>l</head><label></label><figDesc>Numbers of N0-N5 Japanese words in a sentence (Here, N0 implies unknown words in the vocabulary list of JLPT.) l Numbers of N1-N5 Japanese functional expressions in a sentence l Length of a sentence</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>l</head><label></label><figDesc>Numbers of JCHs in a sentence l Numbers of verbs in a sentence l Numbers of syntactic dependencies in a sentence l Average length of syntactic dependencies l Maximum number of child phrases</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head>Correctly</head><label></label><figDesc>detected Japanese functional expressions Input: 今、雪が降っている。 (It is snowing now.) Output: 今 、 雪 が 降っ ている 。 Input: この箱を開けてください。 (Please open this box.) Output: この 箱 を 開け てください 。 Incorrectly detected Japanese functional expressions Input: 彼女は火にあたってからだを暖めた。 (She warmed herself by the fire.) Output: 彼女 は 火 にあたって からだ を 暖め た 。</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><head>Features</head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_6"><head>Figure 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Figure 3: "投資しようにも金がない。(I have no money to invest.)" is typed in the system.</figDesc><graphic url="image-11.png" coords="5,333.70,84.45,163.92,187.20" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_7"><head>Figure 4 :</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Figure 4: Detailed information of Japanese functional expressions appeared in the input sentence (a) and the output sentence (b).</figDesc><graphic url="image-13.png" coords="5,416.98,432.69,107.76,157.52" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" validated="false"><head>Table 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Detection of Japanese functional expres-
sions. In the sentences, Japanese functional ex-
pressions are in bold and underlined. 

Correctly recognized 
173 (86.5%) 
Incorrectly recognized 
27(13.5%) 
Total 
200 (100%) 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3" validated="false"><head>Table 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Experimental results on detection of Jap-
anese functional expressions 

19 https://taku910.github.io/crfpp/ 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_5" validated="false"><head>Table 4 :</head><label>4</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Experimental results using baseline 
features. 

Features 
Cross-validations 
Accuracy 

Proposed Features 

1 
87.6% 
2 
86.4% 
3 
84.6% 
4 
83.8% 
5 
85.4% 
Average 
85.6% 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_7" validated="false"><head>Table 6 :</head><label>6</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Experimental results of sentence 
clustering 

</table></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="2"> http://language.tiu.ac.jp/ 3 https://hinoki-project.org/asunaro/ 4 http://www.rikai.com/perl/Home.pl 5 http://nihongo.monash.edu/cgi-bin/wwwjdic?9T 6 http://taku910.github.io/mecab/ 7 https://www.cs.cornell.edu/people/tj/svm_light/ svm_rank.html</note>

			<note place="foot" n="8"> http://scikitlearn.org/stable/modules/ clustering.html#clustering</note>

			<note place="foot" n="15"> http://cjjc.weblio.jp 16 https://baike.baidu.com 17 http://jlpt.jp/e/about/levelsummary.html</note>

			<note place="foot" n="18"> https://taku910.github/cabocha/</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>We would like to thank anonymous reviewers for their detailed comments and advice.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Japanese Sentence Pattern Learning with the Use of Illustrative Examples Extracted from the Web</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dongli</forename><surname>Han</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xin</forename><surname>Song</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEJ Transactions on Electrical and Electronic Engineering</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="490" to="496" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Chubunban Nihongo Kukei Jiten-Nihongo Bunkei Jiten</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Group</forename><surname>Jamashi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yiping</forename><surname>Xu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Chinese and Japanese)</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Tokyo</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Kurosio Publishers</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Simplification of Example Sentences for Learners of Japanese Functional Expressions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jun</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yuji</forename><surname>Matsumoto</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 3rd Workshop on Natural Language Processing Techniques for Educational Applications</title>
		<meeting>the 3rd Workshop on Natural Language Processing Techniques for Educational Applications</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="5" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A Japanese Learning Support System Matching Individual Abilities</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Takahiro</forename><surname>Ohno</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Zyunitiro</forename><surname>Edani</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ayato</forename><surname>Inoue</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dongli</forename><surname>Han</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceeding of the PACLIC 27 Workshop on ComputerAssisted Language Learning</title>
		<meeting>eeding of the PACLIC 27 Workshop on ComputerAssisted Language Learning</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="556" to="562" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Automatic Detection of Japanese Compound Functional Expressions and its Application to Statistical Dependency Analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Takao</forename><surname>Shime</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Masatoshi</forename><surname>Tsuchiya</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Suguru</forename><surname>Matsuyoshi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Takehito</forename><surname>Utsuro</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Satoshi</forename><surname>Sato</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Natural Language Processing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="issue">14</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="167" to="196" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Kojien 5th Editon</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Izuru</forename><surname>Shinmura</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
			<publisher>Iwanani Press</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Tokyo</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>in Japanese</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Detecting Japanese Compound Functional Expressions using Canonical/Derivational Relation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Takafumi</forename><surname>Suzuki</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yusuke</forename><surname>Abe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Itsuki</forename><surname>Toyota</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Takehito</forename><surname>Utsuro</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Suguru</forename><surname>Matsuyoshi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Masatoshi</forename><surname>Tsuchiya</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Eighth International Conference on Language Resources and Evaluation</title>
		<meeting>the Eighth International Conference on Language Resources and Evaluation</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="page">2012</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Estuko</forename><surname>Tomomastu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jun</forename><surname>Miyamoto</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Masako</forename><surname>Wakuki</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Japanese Expressions Dictionary</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Aruku Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Evaluation of computerized reading-assistance systems for reading Japanese texts-from a linguistic point of view</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Etsuko</forename><surname>Toyoda</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Australasian Journal of Educational Technology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">32</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="94" to="97" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Chunking Japanese compound functional expressions by machine learning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Masatoshi</forename><surname>Tsuchiya</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Takao</forename><surname>Shime</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Toshihiro</forename><surname>Takagi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Takehito</forename><surname>Utsuro</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kiyotaka</forename><surname>Uchimoto</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Suguru</forename><surname>Matsuyoshi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Satoshi</forename><surname>Sato</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Seiichi</forename><surname>Nakagawa</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Workshop on Multi-word-expressions in a Multilingual Context</title>
		<meeting>the Workshop on Multi-word-expressions in a Multilingual Context</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="25" to="32" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Detailed introduction of the New JLPT N1-N5 grammar</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xiaoming</forename><surname>Xu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Reika</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>East China University of Science and Technology Press</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
