<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T11:33+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">The SUMMA Platform: A Scalable Infrastructure for Multi-lingual Multi-media Monitoring Ren¯ ars Liepin , š LETA</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date>July 15-20, 2018</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ulrich</forename><surname>Germann</surname></persName>
							<email>ugermann@ed.ac.uk</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory" key="lab1">Priberam Labs</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory" key="lab2">Priberam Labs</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">University of Edinburgh</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">University of Latvia</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Guntis</forename><surname>Barzdins</surname></persName>
							<email>guntis.barzdins@lu.lv</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory" key="lab1">Priberam Labs</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory" key="lab2">Priberam Labs</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">University of Edinburgh</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">University of Latvia</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sebastião</forename><surname>Miranda</surname></persName>
							<email>Sebastiao.Miranda@priberam.pt</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory" key="lab1">Priberam Labs</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory" key="lab2">Priberam Labs</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">University of Edinburgh</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">University of Latvia</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Nogueira</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory" key="lab1">Priberam Labs</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory" key="lab2">Priberam Labs</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">University of Edinburgh</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">University of Latvia</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Nogueira@priberam</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory" key="lab1">Priberam Labs</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory" key="lab2">Priberam Labs</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">University of Edinburgh</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">University of Latvia</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Pt</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory" key="lab1">Priberam Labs</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory" key="lab2">Priberam Labs</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">University of Edinburgh</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">University of Latvia</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">The SUMMA Platform: A Scalable Infrastructure for Multi-lingual Multi-media Monitoring Ren¯ ars Liepin , š LETA</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 56th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics-System Demonstrations</title>
						<meeting>the 56th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics-System Demonstrations <address><addrLine>Melbourne, Australia</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="99" to="104"/>
							<date type="published">July 15-20, 2018</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<note>99</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>The open-source SUMMA Platform is a highly scalable distributed architecture for monitoring a large number of media broadcasts in parallel, with a lag behind actual broadcast time of at most a few minutes. The Platform offers a fully automated media ingestion pipeline capable of recording live broadcasts, detection and transcription of spoken content, translation of all text (original or transcribed) into English, recognition and linking of Named Entities , topic detection, clustering and cross-lingual multi-document summarization of related media items, and last but not least, extraction and storage of factual claims in these news items. Browser-based graphical user interfaces provide humans with aggre-gated information as well as structured access to individual news items stored in the Platform&apos;s database. This paper describes the intended use cases and provides an overview over the system&apos;s implementation.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>SUMMA ("Scalable Understanding of Multilingual Media") is an EU-funded Research and Innova- tion Action that aims to assemble state-of-the-art NLP technologies into a functional media process- ing pipeline to support large news organizations in their daily work. The project consortium consists of the University of Edinburgh, the Lativan Infor- mation Agency (LETA), Idiap Research Institute, Priberam Labs, Qatar Computing Research Insti- tute, University College London, and Sheffield Uni- versity as technical partners, and BBC Monitoring and Deutsche Welle as use case partners.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.1">Use Cases</head><p>Three use cases drive the technology integration efforts.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.1.1">External Media Monitoring</head><p>BBC Monitoring 1 is a business unit within the British Broadcasting Corporation (BBC). In op- eration since 1939 and with a staff of currently ca. 300 regional expert journalists, it provides media monitoring and analysis services to the BBC's own news rooms, the British government, and other subscribers.</p><p>Each staff journalist monitors up to four live broadcasts in parallel, plus several other informa- tion sources such as social media feeds. Assuming work distributed around the clock in three shifts, <ref type="bibr">2</ref> BBC Monitoring currently has, on average, the ca- pacity to actively monitor about 400 live broad- casts at any given time. At the same time, it has access to over 1,500 TV stations and ca. 1,350 ra- dio stations world-wide via broadcast reception, as well as a myriad of information sources on the in- ternet. The main limiting factor in maintaining (or even extending) monitoring coverage is the cost and availability of the staff required to do so.</p><p>Continuous live monitoring of broadcast chan- nels by humans is not the most effective use of their time. Entertainment programming such as movies and sitcoms, commercial breaks, and repetitions of content (e.g., on 24/7 news channels), for example, are of limited interest to monitoring operations. What is of interest are emerging stories, new devel- opments, and shifts in reporting. By automatically recording, monitoring, and indexing media content from a large number of media streams, and storing it in a database within a very short period of time after it has been published, the Platform allows an- alysts to focus on media content that is most rel- evant to their work and alleviates them from the tedious task of just monitoring broadcast streams in search of such relevant content.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.1.2">Internal Monitoring</head><p>Deutsche Welle, 3 headquartered in Germany, is an international public broadcaster covering world-  wide news in 30 different languages. Regional news rooms produce and broadcast content indepen- dently; journalistic and programming decisions are not made by a central authority within Deutsche Welle. This means that it is difficult for the organi- zation at large, from regional managers in charge of several news rooms to top management, to main- tain an accurate and up-to-date overview of what is being broadcast, what stories have been covered, and where there is potential for synergies, for ex- ample by using journalistic background work that was performed for one story to produce similar con- tent for a different audience in a different broadcast region and language. The SUMMA Platform's cross-lingual story clus- tering and summarization module with the corre- sponding online visualization tool addresses this need. It provides an aggregate view of recent cap- tured broadcasts, with easy access to individual broadcast segments in each cluster.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.1.3">Data Journalism</head><p>The third use case is the use of the platform (or more specifically, it's database API) by journalists and researchers (e.g., political scientists) who want to perform data analyses based on large amounts of news reports. Potential uses are the plotting of events or time series of events on maps, analysis of bias or political slant in news reporting, etc. This use case is the most open-ended and, unlike the other two, has not been a major driving force in the actual design and implementation of the Platform so far. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref> shows a schematic overview over the Platform's workflow. The Platform comprises three major parts: a data ingestion pipeline build mostly upon existing state-of-the-art NLP technol- ogy; a web-based user front-end specifically devel- oped with the intended use cases in mind, and a database at the center that is continuously updated by the data ingestion pipeline and accessed by end users through the web-based GUI, or through a REST API by downstream applications.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">System Architecture</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">Design</head><p>Services within the Platform -technical such as the database server or the message queue, and services performing natural language processing tasks -run independently in individual Docker4 application containers. This encapsulation allows for mostly independent development of the com- ponents by the consortium partners responsible for them.</p><p>Each NLP service augments incoming media items (represented as json structures) with addi- tional information: automatic speech recognition (ASR) services add transcriptions, machine trans- lation (MT) engines add translations, and so forth.</p><p>The flow of information within the Platform is realized via a message queues5. Each type of task (e.g., speech recognition in a specific language, ma- chine translation from a specific language into En- glish, etc.) has a queue for pending tasks and another queue for completed tasks; task workers pop a message off the input queue, acknowledge it upon successful completion, and push the output of the completed task onto the output queue. A task scheduler (the only component that needs to "know" about the overall structure of the process- ing pipeline) orchestrates the communication.</p><p>The use of a message queues allows for easy scal- ability of the Platform -if we need more through- put, we add more workers, which all share the same queues.</p><p>The central database for orchestration of media item processing is an instance of RethinkDB,6 a document-oriented database that allows clients to subscribe to a continuous stream of notifications about changes in the database. Each document consists of several fields, such as the URL of the original news item, a transcript for audio sources, or the original text, a translation into English if applicable, entities such as persons, organisations or locations mentioned in the news items, etc.</p><p>For the user-facing front end, we use an in- stance of PostgreSQL7 that pulls in new arrivals periodically from the RethinkDB. The PostgreSQL database was not part of the original platform de- sign. It was introduced out out of performance con- cerns, when we noticed at at some point that Re- thinkDB's reponsiveness was deteriorating rapidly as the database grew. We ultimately determined that this was due to an error in our set-up of the database -we had failed to set up indexing for certain fields in the database, resulting in linear searches through the database that grew longer and longer as the number of items in the database increased. However, we did not realise this until af- ter we had migrated the user front-ends to interact with a PostgreSQL database. The Platform also provides an export mechanism into ElasticSearch 8 databases.</p><p>The web-based graphical user front-end was de- veloped specifically for SUMMA, based on wire- frame designs from our use case partners. It is im- plemented in the Aurelia JavaScript Client Frame- work 9 .</p><p>In the following section, we briefly present the in- dividual components of the data ingestion pipeline.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Data Ingestion Pipeline Components</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Live Stream Recorder and Chunker</head><p>The recorder and chunker monitors one or more live streams via their respective URLs. Broad- cast signals received via satellite are converted into transport streams suitable for streaming via the in- ternet and provided via a web interface. All data received by the Recorder is recorded to disk und chunked into 5-minutes segments for further pro- cessing. Within the Platform infrastructure, the recorder and chunker also serves as the internal video server for recorded transitory material. Once downloaded and chunked, a document stub with the internal video URL is entered into the database, which then schedules them for down- stream processing.</p><p>Video and audio files that are not transitory but provided by the original sources in more persistent forms (i.e., served from a permanent location), are currently not recorded but retrieved from the orig- inal source when needed.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Other Data Feeds</head><p>Text-based data is retrieved by data feed modules that poll the providing source at regular intervals for new data. The data is downloaded and entered into the database, which then schedules the new arrivals for downstream processing.</p><p>In addition to a generic RSS feed monitor, we use custom data monitors that are tailored to spe- cific data sources, e.g. the specific APIs that broadcaster-specific news apps use for updates. The main task of these specialized modules is to map between data fields of the source API's spe- cific (json) response and the data fields used within the Platform.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3">Automatic Speech Recognition</head><p>The ASR modules within the Platform are built on top of CloudASR ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Klejch et al., 2015)</ref>; the underly- ing speech recognition models are trained with the Kaldi toolkit <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Povey et al., 2011</ref>). Punctuation is added using a neural MT engine that was trained to translate from un-punctuated text to punctua- tion. The training data for the punctuation module is created by stripping punctuation from an exist- ing corpus of news texts. The MT engine used for punctuation insertion uses the same software components as the MT engines used for language translation. Currently, the Platform supports ASR of English, German, Arabic, Russian, Spanish, and Latvian; systems for Farsi, Portuguese and Ukra- nian are planned.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.4">Machine Translation</head><p>The machine translation engines for language translation use the Marian decoder (Junczys- Dowmunt et al., 2016) for translation, with neu- ral models trained with the Nematus toolkit <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(Sennrich et al., 2017</ref>). In the near future, we plan to switch to Marian entirely for training and trans- lation. Currently supported translation directions are from German, Arabic, Russian, Spanish, and Latvian into English. Systems for translation from Farsi, Portuguese and Ukranian into English are planned.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.5">Topic Classification</head><p>The topic classifier uses a hierarchical attention model for document classification ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Yang et al., 2016</ref>) trained on nearly 600K manually annotated documents in 8 languages. <ref type="bibr">10</ref> </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.6">Storyline Clustering and Cluster Summarization</head><p>Incoming stories are clustered into storylines with the online clustering algorithm by <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Aggarwal and Yu (2006)</ref>. The resulting storylines are summa- rized with the extractive summarization algorithm by <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Almeida and Martins (2013)</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.7">Named Entity Recognition and Linking</head><p>For Named Entity Recognition, we use TurboEnti- tyRecognizer, a component within TurboParser <ref type="bibr">11 (Martins et al., 2009)</ref>. Recognized entities and re- lations between them (or propositions about them) are linked to a knowledge base of facts using AMR techniques developed by <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Paikens et al. (2016)</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.8">Trained systems and their performance</head><p>Space contraints prevent us from discussing the NLP components in more detail here. Detailed in- formation about the various components can be found in the project deliverables 3.1, 4.1, and 5.1, </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">User Interfaces</head><p>The platform provides several user interfaces <ref type="bibr">("views")</ref>, to accommodate different user's needs. The trending media item views <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">(Fig 2)</ref> rely on recognised Named Entities. For each entity rec- ognized by the Named Entity recognizer, the his- togram view (top) shows a bar chart with the num- ber of media items that mention said entity within each hour for the past n hours. The order of the list of histograms corresponds to the recent promi- nence of the respective entity. In the list view (bot- tom), recent arrivals for a specific Named Entity are sorted most-recent-first. The screenshot shows the result of a full text search. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 3</ref> shows the view of a recorded video seg- ment. The video player panel is on the left. On the right, we see topic labels (top), a summary of the transcript (middle), and the original tran- script. The transcript is synchronized with the video, so that recognized speech is automatically highlighted in the transcript as the video is played, and a click into the transcript takes the user to the corresponding position in the video.</p><p>The document cluster view <ref type="figure">(Fig. 4)</ref> gives a bird eye's view of the clustered media items; the area 12 www.summa-project.eu/deliverables occupied by each cluster corresponding to the num- ber of items within the cluster. A click on the re- spective tile shows a multi-document summary of the cluster and a list of related media items.</p><p>The trending media item views correspond most to our first use case: journalists keeping track of specific stories linked to specific entities and iden- tifying emerging topics.</p><p>The document cluster ciew corresponds best to the needs of our second use case: internal monitor- ing of a media organisation's output.</p><p>In addition to these visual user interfaces, the platform can also expose a database API, so that users wishing to access the database directly with their own analysis or visualisation tools can do so. A number of ideas for such tools were explored recently at BBC's SUMMA-related #NewsHack event in London in November 2017. 13 They in- clude a slackbot that allows journalists to query the database in natural language via a chat inter- face, automatic generation of short videos captur- ing and summarizing the news of the days in a series of captioned images, or contrasting the cov- erage by a specific media outlet against a larger pool of information sources.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Hardware Requirements and Performance Analysis</head><p>When designing the system, we made a deliberate decision to avoid reliance on GPUs for processing, due to the high cost of the hardware, especially when rented from cloud computing services. This constraint does not apply to the training of the underlying models, which we assume to be done offline. For most components, pre-trained models are available for download.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.1">Disk Space</head><p>A basic installation of the platform with models for 6 languages / 5 translation directions currently requires about 150GB of disk space. Recording of live video streams requires approximately 10-25 GB per stream per day, depending on the resolu- tion of the underlying video. We do not transcode incoming videos to a lower resolution, due to the high processing cost of transcoding. <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">Table 1</ref> shows a snapshot of performance moni- toring on a singe-host deployment of the Platform that we use for user interface testing and user expe- rience evaluation, measured over a period of about 20 minutes. The deployment's host is a large server with 32 CPU cores and 287 GB of memory, of which ca. 120GB are currently used by the Plat- form, supporting transcription in 6 languages and translation from 5 into English. Not shown in the table are the ASR, Punctuation and MT compo- nents for Latvian and German, as they were idle at the time.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.2">CPU Usage and Memory Requirements</head><p>Notice that except for the Named Entity recog- nizer, no component has a peak memory use of more than 4 GB, so that individual components can be run on much smaller machines in a dis- tributed set-up.</p><p>Speech recognition is clearly the bottleneck and resource hog in the pipeline. The ASR engine cur- rently is a single-threaded process that can tran- scribe speech at about half the "natural" speaking rate. 14 Each segment is transcribed in one chunk; we use multiple workers (2-3) per channel to keep up with the speed of data arrival.</p><p>The multi-threaded MT engines use all avail- able cores to translate in parallel and are able to translate some 500 words per minute per thread.  In a successful scalability test with docker swarm in January 2018 we were able to ingest 400 TV streams simultaneously on Amazon's AWS EC2 service, allocating 2 t2.2xlarge virtual machines (8 CPUs, 32GB RAM) per stream, although 1 ma- chine per stream probably would have be sufficient. For this test, we deployed several clones of the en- tire platform for data ingestion, all feeding into a single user-facing PostgreSQL database instance.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Conclusion</head><p>The SUMMA Platform successfully integrates a multitude of state-of-the-art NLP components to provide an integrated platform for multi-lingual media monitoring and analysis. The Platform de- sign provides for easy scalability and facilitates the integration of additional NLP analysis mod- ules that augment existing data.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Availability</head><p>The Platform infrastructure and most of its com- ponents are currently scheduled to be released as open-source software in late August 2018 and will available through the project home page at http://www.summa-project.eu</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: Overview of the SUMMA architecture.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2: Trending media item views: histogram (top), and list (bottom)</figDesc><graphic url="image-89.png" coords="4,77.98,203.80,218.25,136.41" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Figure 3: Single media item view</figDesc><graphic url="image-90.png" coords="5,140.03,62.81,317.45,198.41" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" validated="true"><head>Table 1 : Relative use of CPU time and peak mem- ory use (per container) for various tasks in the NLP processing pipeline.</head><label>1</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Task 
CPU 
RAM 
ASR (ar) 
27.26% 
1359 MiB 
ASR (en) 
26.53% 
2594 MiB 
ASR (ru) 
22.40% 
2044 MiB 
ASR (es) 
13.44% 
2800 MiB 
MT (ar) 
3.34% 
926 MiB 
MT (ru) 
3.14% 
1242 MiB 
Summarization 
1.21% 
3609 MiB 
Semantic parsing 
0.97% 
3290 MiB 
MT (es) 
0.34% 
1801 MiB 
Job queue 
0.30% 
326 MiB 
Topic identification 
0.27% 
1418 MiB 
Named entity recognition 
0.18% 12625 MiB 
Punctuation (en) 
0.16% 
362 MiB 
Database 
0.16% 
3021 MiB 
Recording and chunking 
0.15% 
337 MiB 
Punctuation (ru) 
0.04% 
285 MiB 
Punctuation (ar) 
0.03% 
276 MiB 
DB REST interface 
0.02% 
153 MiB 
Clustering 
0.01% 
1262 MiB 
Data feed (not streamed) 
0.01% 
141 MiB 
Punctuation (es) 
0.01% 
240 MiB 
Task creation 
0.01% 
1076 MiB 
Result writer 
0.01% 
1003 MiB 
(msg. queue to DB) 

</table></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> https://monitoring.bbc.co.uk/ 2 Actual staff allocation and thus the amount of media monitoring may vary over the course of the day. 3 http://www.dw.com</note>

			<note place="foot" n="4"> www.docker.com 5 www.rabbitmq.com 6 www.rethinkdb.com 7 www.postgresql.org</note>

			<note place="foot" n="8"> www.elastic.co 9 aurelia.io</note>

			<note place="foot" n="10"> The Platform currently is designed to handle 9 languages: English, Arabic, Farsi, German, Latvian, Portuguese, Russian, Spanish, and Ukrainian. 11 https://github.com/andre-martins/TurboParser</note>

			<note place="foot" n="13"> http://bbcnewslabs.co.uk/2017/11/24/ summa-roundup. The event attracted 63 registrations; subtracting no-shows, the event had ca. 50 attendees.</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgements</head><p>This work was conducted within the scope of the Research and Innovation Action SUMMA, which has received funding from the Eu-ropean Union's Horizon 2020 research and innova-tion programme under grant agreement No 688139.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A framework for clustering massive text and categorical data streams</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Charu</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Aggarwal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Philip S</forename><surname>Yu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">SIAM Int&apos;l. Conf. on Data Mining</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Boston, MA, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="479" to="483" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Fast and robust compressive summarization with dual decomposition and multi-task learning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Miguel</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Almeida</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Andre</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Martins</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">ACL</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="196" to="206" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Is neural machine translation ready for deployment? A case study on 30 translation directions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Junczys-Dowmunt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tomasz</forename><surname>Marcin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hieu</forename><surname>Dwojak</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Hoang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">International Workshop on Spoken Language Translation</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">CloudASR: platform and service</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ondřej</forename><surname>Klejch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ondřej</forename><surname>Plátek</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lukáš</forename><surname>Žilka</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Filip</forename><surname>Jurčíček</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Int&apos;l. Conf. on Text, Speech, and Dialogue</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Pilsen, Czech Republic</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="334" to="341" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Concise integer linear programming formulations for dependency parsing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">André</forename><surname>Martins</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Ft</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Noah</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Eric</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Smith</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Xing</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">ACLIJCNLP</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="342" to="350" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">SUMMA at TAC knowledge base population task 2016</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Peteris</forename><surname>Paikens</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Guntis</forename><surname>Barzdins</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Afonso</forename><surname>Mendes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Daniel</forename><surname>Ferreira</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Samuel</forename><surname>Broscheit</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mariana</forename><forename type="middle">S C</forename><surname>Almeida</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sebastião</forename><surname>Miranda</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Nogueira</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Pedro</forename><surname>Balage</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">André</forename><forename type="middle">F T</forename><surname>Martins</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">TAC</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Kaldi speech recognition toolkit</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Daniel</forename><surname>Povey</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Arnab</forename><surname>Ghoshal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gilles</forename><surname>Boulianne</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lukáš</forename><surname>Burget</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nagendra</forename><surname>Ond˘ Rej Glembek</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mirko</forename><surname>Goel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Petr</forename><surname>Hannemann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yanmin</forename><surname>Motlíček</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Petr</forename><surname>Qian</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Schwarz</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">ASRU</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Georg Stemmer, and Karel Veselý</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Nematus: a toolkit for neural machine translation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rico</forename><surname>Sennrich</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Orhan</forename><surname>Firat</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kyunghyun</forename><surname>Cho</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alexandra</forename><surname>Birch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Barry</forename><surname>Haddow</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Julian</forename><surname>Hitschler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marcin</forename><surname>Junczys-Dowmunt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Samuel</forename><surname>Läubli</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Antonio</forename><surname>Valerio Miceli</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jozef</forename><surname>Barone</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Maria</forename><surname>Mokry</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Nadejde</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">EACL Demonstration Session</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Hierarchical attention networks for document classification</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Zichao</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Diyi</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chris</forename><surname>Dyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xiaodong</forename><surname>He</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alexander</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Smola</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Eduard</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Hovy</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">NAACL</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
