<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T12:16+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Not that much power: Linguistic alignment is influenced more by low-level linguistic features rather than social power</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date>July 15-20, 2018</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yang</forename><surname>Xu</surname></persName>
							<email>yang.xu@psu.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">College of Information Sciences and Technology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">The Pennsylvania State University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jeremy</forename><surname>Cole</surname></persName>
							<email>jrcole@psu.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">College of Information Sciences and Technology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">The Pennsylvania State University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Reitter</surname></persName>
							<email>reitter@psu.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">College of Information Sciences and Technology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">The Pennsylvania State University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Not that much power: Linguistic alignment is influenced more by low-level linguistic features rather than social power</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 56th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (Long Papers)</title>
						<meeting>the 56th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (Long Papers) <address><addrLine>Melbourne, Australia</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="601" to="610"/>
							<date type="published">July 15-20, 2018</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<note>601</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Linguistic alignment between dialogue partners has been claimed to be affected by their relative social power. A common finding has been that interlocutors of higher power tend to receive more alignment than those of lower power. However, these studies overlook some low-level linguistic features that can also affect alignment , which casts doubts on these findings. This work characterizes the effect of power on alignment with logistic regression models in two datasets, finding that the effect vanishes or is reversed after controlling for low-level features such as utterance length. Thus, linguistic alignment is explained better by low-level features than by social power. We argue that a wider range of factors, especially cog-nitive factors, need to be taken into account for future studies on observational data when social factors of language use are in question.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>The effect of social power on language use in con- versations has been widely studied. The Com- munication Accommodation Theory <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Giles, 2008)</ref> states that the social power of speakers influence the extent to which conversation partners accom- modate (or align, coordinate) their communicat- ing styles towards them. This theory is supported by findings from qualitative studies on employ- ment interviews ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">Willemyns et al., 1997</ref>), class- room talks ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Jones et al., 1999)</ref>, and the more re- cent data-driven studies on large online communi- ties and court conversations (Danescu-Niculescu- <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Mizil et al., 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Jones et al., 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b18">Noble and Fernández, 2015)</ref>. In particular, Danescu- Niculescu-Mizil et al. (2012) uses a probability- based measure of linguistic alignment to demon- strate that people align more towards conversa- tion partners of higher power, i.e., the admin users in Wikipedia talk-page, and the justices in U.S. supreme court conversations, than those of lower power, i.e., the non-admin users and the lawyers.</p><p>However, while these results find sound expla- nations from socio-linguistic theories, they are still somewhat surprising from the perspective of cog- nitive mechanisms of language production, be- cause the mutual alignment between interlocutors of in natural dialogue can be explained by an au- tomatic and low-level priming process ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">Pickering and Garrod, 2004</ref>). It is known that the strength of alignment is sensitive to low-level linguistic features (e.g., words, syntactic structures etc.), such as temporal clustering properties <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(Myslín and Levy, 2016</ref>), syntactic surprisal measured by pre- diction error <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(Jaeger and Snider, 2013)</ref>, and lexical information density ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">Xu and Reitter, 2018)</ref>.</p><p>Then why, or under what mechanisms, can alignment be affected by the relatively high-level social perceptions of power as reported? Could it be the case that the effect of power on alignment is actually due to the other low level features in lan- guage, such as the ones mentioned above? Is the effect of power still observable, if we control for other factors? How large is the effect? Is it sig- nificant enough to be captured by computational measures of alignment? Answering these ques- tions will help clarify the role of social factors in linguistic alignment, and improve our understand- ing of language production in general.</p><p>In this study, we conduct a two-step model anal- ysis. First, we use a basic model that has two predictors, count (number of a certain linguis- tic marker in the preceding utterance) and power (power status of the preceding speaker), to predict the occurrence of the same marker in the follow-ing utterance. Here, the linguistic markers are de- rived from 11 Linguistic Inquiry and Word Count (LIWC; <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Pennebaker et al., 2001</ref>) categories <ref type="bibr">(e.g., article, adverb, etc.)</ref>. With the basic model, the main effect of count characterizes the strength of alignment, and the interaction between count and power characterizes the effect of power on align- ment (Section 3). Second, we use an extended model that includes a third predictor, utterance length (It is chosen as a typical low-level linguis- tic feature, discussed in Section 2.3), on top of the basic model. With the extended model, we aim to examine whether the inclusion of utterance length will influence the interaction between count and power (Section 4). Therefore, we can examine the extent to which the effect of power on alignment is confounded by low-level linguistic features.</p><p>To clarify, our goal is not to disprove the existence of social accommodation in dialogue. Nonetheless, it is important to distinguish between what is caused by automatic priming-based align- ment and what is caused by high-level, inten- tional accommodation. As we will discuss, these are different processes with different predictions. Throughout this paper we use the term alignment to refer to the priming-based process, and accom- modation to refer to the intentional process.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Related Work</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">Social power and linguistic alignment</head><p>The social factors of language use have been widely studied. Communication Accommoda- tion Theory <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Giles, 2008)</ref> posits that individuals adapt their communication styles to increase or de- crease the social distance from their interlocutors. One factor that affects the adaptation of linguistic styles is social power. Typically, people of lower power converge their linguistic styles to those of higher power; for example, interviewees towards interviewers ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">Willemyns et al., 1997</ref>), or students towards teachers ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Jones et al., 1999</ref>).</p><p>More recently, sensitive quantitative meth- ods have been applied to this line of inquiry. Danescu-Niculescu-Mizil et al. (2012) computed the probability-based linguistic coordination mea- sure among Wikipedia editors and participants of the US supreme court, and they showed that peo- ple with low power (e.g., lawyers, non-admins) ex- hibit greater coordination than people with high power (Justices, admins). Using the same data, <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">Noble and Fernández (2015)</ref> found that linguis- tic coordination is positively correlated with social network centrality, and this effect is even greater than the effect of power status distinction.</p><p>The aforementioned studies do not include low- level language features in their analysis and thus overlook the possibility that cognitive mechanisms may be able to more readily explain the data. Im- portantly, as we will later discuss, these studies use a measurement of alignment that we believe is more appropriately measuring the automatic pro- cess, rather than the intentional one.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">Quantifying linguistic alignment</head><p>A variety of computational measures of linguistic alignment have been developed. Some quantify the increase in conditional probability of certain elements (words or word types) given that they have appeared earlier <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Church, 2000;</ref><ref type="bibr">DanescuNiculescu-Mizil et al., 2012)</ref>. Some compute the proportion of repeated lexical entries or syn- tactic rules between two pieces of text ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Fusaroli et al., 2012;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b25">Wang et al., 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b27">Xu and Reitter, 2015)</ref>. Some use the coefficients returned by gen- eralized linear models <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">(McCullagh, 1984;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Breslow and Clayton, 1993;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Lindstrom and Bates, 1990)</ref> as an index of alignment <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">(Reitter and Moore, 2014)</ref>. A large body of the existing computational mea- sures intensively use LIWC ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Pennebaker et al., 2001</ref>) to construct representations of language users' styles, which can be used to measure align- ment with distance-like metrics <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">(Niederhoffer and Pennebaker, 2002;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Jones et al., 2014</ref>). Many of these approaches do not distinguish between dif- ferent levels of linguistic analysis and different psycholinguistic processes (phonological, lexical, syntactic, etc.), and neither do we. Alignment is consistently present across these levels and pro- cesses, although it is not as clear in naturalis- tic language as it is in the constrained utterances of experiments, particularly at the syntactic level ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Healey et al., 2014</ref>). We are concerned with the question of whether alignment is a socially linked, intentional adaptation process, as opposed to ad- dressing any particular cognitive model. More recently,  pointed out that most existing measures are difficult to com- pare, and emphasized the need for a universal measure. The Hierarchical Alignment Model (HAM;  and Word-Based HAM (WHAM; ) use statisti- cal inference techniques, which out-perform other measures in terms of robustness of capturing lin- guistic alignment in social media conversations.</p><p>In this study, we choose to use generalized lin- ear models to quantify linguistic alignment, avoid- ing issues with more complex, and less inspectable models. For instance, the commonly used prob- ability based methods and their more advanced variants (HAM and WHAM) lack the flexibility to jointly examine multiple factors (e.g., speaker groups, utterance length etc.) that influence align- ment. Another issue is that they do not take into account the number of occurrences of linguistic markers, which is known to affect alignment (see Section 2.3). Conversely, though linear models do not give an accurate per-speaker estimate of align- ment (which we do not need for the purpose of this study), they do provide the ability to examine multiple factors that influence alignment by sim- ply including multiple predictors in the model. As should be clear, a generalized linear model also al- ready takes into account baseline usage with a fit- ted intercept. Given these considerations, we use generalized linear models for quantitative analy- sis. The formulation of our models is described in Sections 3.2 and 4.1.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3">Cognitive constraints on linguistic alignment: why utterance length matters</head><p>There are many, at times competing, cognitive ex- planations of linguistic alignment in both compre- hension and production. Jaeger and Snider (2013) explained alignment as a consequence of expec- tation adaptation, and they found that stronger alignment is associated with syntactic structures that have higher surprisal (roughly speaking, less common). Alignment in language production can also be modeled as a general memory phe- nomenon (Reitter et al., 2011), which explains a number of known interaction effects. <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Myslín and Levy (2016)</ref> found that sentence comprehension is faster when the same syntactic structure clus- ters in time in prior experience than when it is evenly spaced in time. <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Myslín and Levy (2016)</ref> cast comprehension priming as the rational ex- pectation for repetition of stimuli. Though this result is not directly related to comprehension- to-production priming, it makes sense to antici- pate that production could also be sensitive to the clustering patterns of linguistic elements, because comprehension and production are closely cou- pled processes <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">(Pickering and Garrod, 2007)</ref>.</p><p>Utterance length, i.e., the number of words in utterance, is a feature that closely relates to both surprisal and clustering properties. Longer utter- ances tend to have higher syntactic surprisal ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">Xu and Reitter, 2016a)</ref>, and it is reasonable to assume they tend to contain more evenly distributed stim- uli. Thus, utterance length is a low-level linguistic feature that correlates with many of the causes of alignment. In this way, we use utterance length as a stand-in for low-level linguistic features as a whole when comparing it with social power, a much higher-level feature. Examining alignment (in social science research and elsewhere) there- fore calls for controlling sentence length.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Experiment 1: Basic model</head><p>In Experiment 1, we justify the practice of us- ing generalized linear models to quantify linguis- tic alignment. We compare two ways of charac- terizing the occurrence of LIWC-derived markers in a preceding utterance, binary presence and nu- meric count, to determine which results in better model. We use an interaction term in the model to quantify the effect of the power status of speakers on linguistic alignment, which serves as the basis for the following sections.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Corpus data</head><p>We use two datasets compiled by Danescu- Niculescu-Mizil et al. <ref type="formula">(2012)</ref> A conversation consists of a sequence of utter- ances, {u i }(i = 1, 2, . . . , N ), where N is the to- tal number of utterances in the conversation. Be- cause people take turns to talk in conversation, u i and u i+1 are always from different speakers. Since our interest here is the alignment between different speakers (as opposed to within the same speaker), we use a sliding window of size 2 to go through the whole conversation, generating a sequence of adjacent utterance pairs, {{prime i , target i }(i = 1, 2 . . . N − 1).</p><p>Next, we process each utterance u i by count- ing the number of occurrences of 14 linguistic markers that are derived from LIWC categories, resulting in 14 counts for each utterance. These 14 linguistic markers are: high frequency adverbs (adv), articles (art), auxiliary verbs (auxv), cer- tainty (certain), conjunctions (conj), discrepancy (discrep), exclusion (excl), inclusion (incl), imper- sonal pronouns (ipron), negations (negate), per- sonal pronouns (ppron), prepositions (prep), quan- tifiers (quant), and tentativeness (tentat). These fourteen markers come from taking the union of the 8 markers used by Danescu-Niculescu-Mizil et al. <ref type="formula">(2012)</ref> and the 11 markers used by , which are the main studies we wanted to compare with.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Statistical models</head><p>We formulate alignment as the impact of using certain linguistic elements in the preceding utter- ance on their chance to appear again in the fol- lowing utterance. In the language of generalized linear models, we use the occurrence of linguistic markers in target as the response variable and the predictor is their occurrence in prime. These oc- currences can be represented as either a boolean or a count. Thus alignment is characterized by the β coefficient of the predictor, which allows the model to distinguish the prevalence of Occurrence or another feature in primed situations as com- pared to its prior in the corpus. Factors that may influence alignment (e.g., social power) can then be examined by adding a corresponding interac- tion term to the model. Our first step, then, is to replicate the previ- ous studies' findings of the effect of social power on alignment. Two models were fitted, predict- ing the presence of the linguistic marker m in target utterance over its absence. We fit models both corresponding to a binary predictor (C presence ) and a count-based one (C count ). Both models in- clude a second binary predictor, C power , indicat- ing the power status of the prime speaker (high vs. low), and its interaction with C presence and C count , respectively. Additionally, random inter- cepts on linguistic marker and target speaker are fitted, based on the consideration that individuals might have different levels of alignment towards different markers. C count is log-transformed to maximize model fit according to <ref type="bibr">Bayesian Information Criterion;</ref> this is commensurate with stan- dard psycholinguistic practice and known cumu- lative priming and memory effects. Equation <ref type="formula">(1)</ref> shows the count-based model. To reiterate, the in- teraction term C count * C power characterizes the ef- fect of power on alignment.</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">logit(m) = ln p(m in target) p(m not in target) = β 0 + β 1 C count + β 2 C power + β 3 C count * C power (1)</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3">Model coefficients</head><p>The main effects of C presence and C count are sig- nificant (p &lt; 0.001) and positive in both corpora (SC: β presence = 0.439, β count = 0.291; Wiki: β presence = 0.440, β count = 0.395), which cap- tures the linguistic alignment from prime to target. However, there is difference in how alignment is influenced by power between the two corpora: In SC, C count * C power is significant (β = 0.078, p &lt; 0.001), but C presence * C power is non-significant; In Wiki, on the contrary, C presence * C power is marginally significant (β = 0.014, p = .055), but C count * C power in not significant. No collinearity is found between C count (or C presence ) and C power (Pearson correlation r &lt; 0.2).</p><p>To explore why using C presence vs. C count results in different significance levels for SC and Wiki, we fit a individual linear model for each linguistic marker, using 14 disjoint subsets of each corpus. We present the z scores and significance levels of the two interaction terms are reported in <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>. First, in SC the interaction term C presence * C power is significant for 9 out of 14 markers. In Wiki, C count * C power is significant for 5 out of 14 mark- ers. This suggests that the interaction between the occurrence of linguistic markers and the power status of speakers exists within a subset of the linguistic categories, but not across all of them. Thus, we consider this first experiment a replica- tion of past findings of the effect of social power on alignment: social power has a significant ef- fect across certain markers, but its overall effect is neutralized in the full model since some markers at not significant. This analysis also revealed that C count * C power is more reliable in capturing this effect, which is what we will use in the following experiment. <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>: Summary of the 14 models that fit in- dividual markers on disjoint data subsets. Wald's z-score and significance level ( * * * for p &lt; 0.001, * * for p &lt; 0.01, * for p &lt; 0.05, and † for 0.05 &lt; p &lt; 0.1) of the interaction terms (C presence * C power or C count * C power ) are reported. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.4">Visualizing the effect of power</head><p>To better understand the interaction term C count * C power , we divide the data into two groups by whether C power is high or low, and fit a model on each of the groups. In the models we include only one predictor C count (see Equation <ref type="formula">(2)</ref>). Then we compare the main effects (β 1 coefficients) from the two groups.</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">logit(m) = β 0 + β 1 C count (2)</formula><p>Unsurprisingly, the main effects of C count are significant for both groups (p &lt; 0.001). But more importantly, the β 1 coefficients of the high power group are larger than those of the low power group. For SC, the difference is very salient: β . This is in line with the non- significant coefficient of C count * C power in Wiki. In fact, the models of Wiki are fitted on a subset of data that contain the 5 (out of 14) markers that have significant coefficients of C count * C power in the individual models shown in <ref type="table">Table 1</ref> (certain, excl, incl, ipron, negate), so that the difference in slopes is presented at maximal degree.</p><p>In <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref> we illustrate the β high and β low coef- ficients of C count by plotting the predicted proba- bility (the reversed logit transformation of the left- hand side term of Equation <ref type="formula">(2)</ref>) against C count (log- transformed). It is obvious that the slope of β high is larger than that of β low (more salient in SC), in- dicating the significant interaction between C count and C power . (b) Wikipedia <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref>: The predicted probability of marker ap- pearing in target (the reverse logit transform of the left hand side of Equation <ref type="formula">(2)</ref>) against the number of markers in prime, i.e., C count (log-transformed), grouped by the power of prime speaker, i.e., high vs. low. Divergent slopes indicate significant in- teractions. Colored hexagons indicate the number of data points within that region.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.5">Discussion</head><p>The occurrence of linguistic markers in prime is a strong predictor of whether the same marker will appear again in target. The coefficients of C count can be viewed as indicators of the linguis- tic alignment between interlocutors: larger posi- tive βs indicate stronger alignment, while smaller or even negative βs indicate weaker and reverse alignment, respectively (not found in our data).</p><p>Our results confirm the previously reported ef- fect of power on linguistic alignment. The signifi- cant β ′ coefficient of C count * C power means that the β of C count is dependent on C power . In other words, the strength of alignment varies significantly de- pending on different power levels (i.e., high vs. low) of the prime speaker (reflected by the differ- ent slopes in <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref>). However, we need to keep in mind that this affirmative finding is not safe, be- cause it based on a simple model that has only one key predictor, C power . According to our hypothe- sis, the strength of alignment can be influenced by a lot of low-level linguistic features, and we are not sure yet if the effect of power will still be visi- ble after we includes more predictors representing those features. This will be the next step experi- ment.</p><p>Additionally, the results also suggest that the in- fluence of power on linguistic alignment is better characterized by the more fine-grained cumulative effect of linguistic markers than when it is simply explained by the mere difference between their ab- sence or presence. Thus, we will discard C presence and proceed with C count .</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Experiment 2: Extended model</head><p>In our first experiment, we replicated the effect of prime speakers' power status on the linguis- tic alignment from target speakers, from the sig- nificant interaction term C count * C power . Now, we want to determine if the effect of power re- mains significant after taking into account utter- ance length. As discussed, our hypothesis is that alignment (as measured by changes in probabil- ity of using LIWC categories) is best explained by low-level linguistic features that would be taken into account by an automatic priming process.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">Statistical models</head><p>We add a new predictor to Equation (1), C pLen , which is the number of words in prime, result- ing in an extended model shown in Equation (3). We are interested to see if β 4 remains significant when the other interaction terms (with correspond- ing coefficients β 5 , β 6 and β 7 ) are added.</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">logit(m) = ln p(m in target) p(m not in target) = β 0 + β 1 C count + β 2 C power + β 3 C pLen + β 4 C count * C power + β 5 C count * C pLen + β 6 C power * C pLen + β 7 C count * C power * C pLen</formula><p>(3) Note that we used the same subset of Wiki as used in Section 3.4 (using the five most significant LIWC categories), so that the strongest effect of C count * C power is considered.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">Model coefficients</head><p>The coefficients of the full model are in <ref type="table">Table 2</ref>. Surprisingly, the coefficient of C count * C power is significantly negative in SC, and non-significant in Wiki (see highlighted rows), which are in con- trast to the positive coefficients of the same term <ref type="table">Table 2</ref>: Summary of the model described in Equation <ref type="formula">(3)</ref>: β coefficients, Wald's z-score and significance level ( * * * for p &lt; 0.001, * * for p &lt; 0.01, * for p &lt; 0.05) for all predictors and inter- actions. in <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>. It indicates that the observed effect of power on alignment depends on the presence of C pLen in the model. No collinearity is found be- tween C power and other predictors: Pearson corre- lation r &lt; 0.2; Variance inflation factor (VIF) is low (&lt; 2.0) <ref type="bibr">(O'brien, 2007)</ref>.</p><p>To further demonstrate how the coefficient of C power * C count is dependent on C pLen , we remove C count * C pLen , C power * C pLen and C count * C power * C pLen from Equation (3) stepwisely, and exam- ine C count * C power in the corresponding remain- ing models. z-scores, significance levels, and the Akaike information criterion (AIC) score <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Akaike, 1998)</ref> of the remainder models are reported in <ref type="table">Ta- ble 3</ref>. In the full model, and when C count * C power * C pLen or C count * C pLen is removed from the model, the coefficients of C power * C count are significantly negative in SC and non-significant in Wiki. Only when C power * C pLen is removed, the coefficients of C count * C power become significantly positive (the last two rows in <ref type="table">Table 3</ref>). However, the models that have negative or non-significant coefficient for C power * C count have lower AIC scores than those that have positive coefficient (The full model has the lowest AIC score), which indicates that the former ones have higher quality. Altogether, the stepwise analysis not only indicates that the pos- itive interaction between C power and C count shown in our basic model (Section 3) is unreliable, but also suggests that a negative interaction (SC) or non-significant interaction is more preferable.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3">Visualizing interaction effect</head><p>To illustrate how the interaction C power * C count diminishes after adding C pLen into the extended model, we cluster different ranges of C pLen and de- termine how the amount of priming changes with C count w.r.t. different combinations of C power and C pLen . This is a common practice to interpret lin- ear models with three-way interactions <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Houslay, 2014)</ref>.</p><p>To cluster, we first compute the mean of C pLen (i.e., the average utterance length), M pLen . Then we divide the data by whether C pLen is above or below M pLen . Then we compute the mean of C pLen for the upper and lower parts of data, resulting in M L pLen and M S pLen respectively (L for long and S for short). Now, we can replace the continuous variable C pLen to a categorical and ordinal one that has two values, {M S pLen , M L pLen }, which represent the length of relatively short and long utterances respectively. Together with the other categorical variable, C power , which has two values, high and low, we have four combinations: C pLen = M S pLen and C power = high (SH), C pLen = M L pLen and C power = high (LH), C pLen = M S pLen and C power = low (SL), C pLen = M L pLen and C power = low (LL). In <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 2</ref> we plot the smoothed regression lines of predicted probability against C count , w.r.t. the above four groups of C pLen and C power combina- tions. Here C count is not log-transformed, because it better demonstrates the trend of the fitted regres- sion lines. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 2</ref> intuitively shows that C pLen is a more determinant predictor than C power . Division by power, i.e., high (SH and LH groups) vs. low (SL and LL groups), does not result in a salient dif- ference in slopes, as it can be seen that the slopes of high (solid) and low (dashed) power lines do not differ much from each other within the same prime utterance length group (indicated by color). However, division by prime utterance length, i.e. short (SH and SL) vs. long (LH and LL), results in very significant differences in slopes: in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 2a</ref>, short C pLen group (orange) has larger slopes than long C pLen group (blue), while in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">Figure 2b</ref>, short group has smaller slopes than long group.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.4">Discussion</head><p>Adding C pLen to the model has strong impact on the previous conclusion about the effect of power on alignment. First of all, we find a negative inter- action between C count and C power in SC and a non- significant effect in Wiki, which is contrary to the previous findings reported by Danescu-Niculescu- <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Mizil et al. (2012)</ref>. Moreover, we doubt the relia- bility of a positive interaction because the valence of its β varies when other interaction terms (as- sociated with C pLen ) are removed or added, and a negative or non-significant interaction is preferred <ref type="table">Table 3</ref>: Wald's z-score and significance level ( * * * for p &lt; 0.001) of the C count * C power term, and the AIC scores of the remainder models after removing other interaction terms from the full model stepwisely. The full model is described in Equation (3).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Remainder model SC Wiki</head><p>z-score AIC z-score AIC Full -9.95*** 697588 0.14 890685</p><p>Full − C count * C power * C pLen -8.75*** 697609 -0.62 890686</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">Full − C count * C power * C pLen − C count * C pLen -5.61*** 697838.9 -0.74 890723.5 Full − C count * C power * C pLen − C power * C pLen 10.90*** 698254.7 3.85*** 890726.7 Full − C count * C power * C pLen − C count * C pLen − C power * C pLen</formula><p>15.02*** 698461.8 3.72*** 890763.8 by a simple model selection criterion.</p><p>Second, there is a significant interaction be- tween C count and C pLen , though it is in different directions for the two corpora: negative β in SC and positive β in Wiki. Both observations have some theoretical justification from previous stud- ies. <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Myslín and Levy (2016)</ref>'s work is in favor of the negative β: language comprehension is facili- tated by the clustering of linguistic stimuli in time. In our case, the linguistic markers in the utterance of speaker A function as stimuli to speaker B. A longer utterance means that all the stimuli span wider in time, and thus demonstrate less cluster- ing, which make the stimuli less salient features for speaker B to adapt to. This in turn causes speaker B to be less likely reuse those stimuli in the near future. Meanwhile, evidence from the line of works on surprisal and syntactic priming sup- ports the positive β. In syntactic alignment, struc- tures with higher surprisal (less common) are asso- ciated with stronger alignment <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(Jaeger and Snider, 2013;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Reitter and Moore, 2014)</ref>. Since surprisal has been found to be closely related with utterance length in dialogue <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(Genzel and Charniak, 2003;</ref><ref type="bibr">Xu and Reitter, 2016b,a)</ref>, it is reasonable to expect that longer utterances receive stronger alignment because they contain content of higher surprisal.</p><p>The discrepancy between Wiki and SC in terms of the direction of C count * C pLen is an interest- ing phenomenon to explore, because it can tell us something about how the form of dialogue (Wiki consists of online conversations and SC consists of face-to-face ones) affects the underlying cognitive mechanism of language production.</p><p>Regardless, our main finding is that low-level linguistic features, such as utterance length, have a strong effect on linguistic alignment. These ef- fects are an important confound to take into ac- count when examining higher-level features, such as social power. In particular, the effect of social power cannot be reliably detected by linear models once introducing utterance length.</p><p>Another interesting piece of result is the signif- icant interaction term C power * C pLen , which im- plies that the power status of speaker and how long he/she tends to speak are not totally unre- lated. Significant but weak correlation are found between C power and C pLen (using Pearson's corre- lation score): r = −0.059 in SC; r = −0.018 in Wiki. This correlation may show some kind of a linguistic manifestation of social power, but since it is not directly related to the alignment process, we do not further discuss it in this paper.</p><p>In summary of the results, we conjecture that the previously reported effect of power (Danescu- Niculescu- <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Mizil et al., 2012</ref>) is likely to be caused by the correlation between power status and utter- ance length, though further investigation is needed to confirm this. Moreover, utterance length is just one simple factor, and there are many more other linguistic features that can correlate with social power: e.g., the surprisal based measure of lexi-cal information etc.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Conclusion</head><p>To sum up, our findings suggest that the previously reported effect of power on linguistic alignment is not reliable. Instead, we consistently align towards language that shares certain low-level features. We call for the inclusion of a wider range of factors in future studies of social influences on language use, especially low-level but interpretable cogni- tive factors. Perhaps in most scenarios, alignment is primarily influenced by linguistic features them- selves, rather than social power.</p><p>We are not denying the existence of accommo- dation caused by the social distance between in- terlocutors. However, we want to stress the dif- ference between the priming-induced alignment at lower linguistic levels and the intentional accom- modation that is caused by higher-level percep- tion of social power. The latter should be a rela- tively stable effect that is independent on the low- level linguistic features. In particular, our findings suggest that the probability change of LIWC cat- egories is more likely to be a case of automatic alignment, rather than an intentional accommo- dation, because it is better explained by lower- level linguistic features (utterance length). There- fore, we suggest that future work on social power and language use should consider other (maybe higher-level) linguistic elements.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2: The predicted probability of marker appearing in target against C count , grouped by the four combinations of C pLen (long vs. short, indicated by color) and C power (high vs. low, indicated by line type): LH, LL, SH, and SL. Colored hexagon indicates the number of data points.</figDesc></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/ Wikipedia:Talk_page_guidelines 2 http://www.supremecourt.gov/oral_ arguments/</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgement</head><p>We sincerely thank Lizhao Ge for her useful ad-vice on the statistical methods used. The work leading to this paper was funded by the Na-tional Science Foundation (IIS-1459300 and BCS-1457992).</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Information theory and an extension of the maximum likelihood principle</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Hirotogu Akaike</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Selected Papers of Hirotugu Akaike</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="199" to="213" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Approximate inference in generalized linear mixed models</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Norman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David G</forename><surname>Breslow</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Clayton</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of the American Statistical Association</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">88</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">421</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="9" to="25" />
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Empirical estimates of adaptation: the chance of two Noriega&apos;s is closer to p/2 than p 2</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Kenneth W Church</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 18th Conference on Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the 18th Conference on Computational Linguistics<address><addrLine>Saarbrücken, Germany</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="180" to="186" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Echoes of power: Language effects and power differences in social interaction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Cristian</forename><surname>Danescu-Niculescu-Mizil</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lillian</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bo</forename><surname>Pang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jon</forename><surname>Kleinberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 21st International Conference on World Wide Web</title>
		<meeting>the 21st International Conference on World Wide Web<address><addrLine>Lyon, France</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="699" to="708" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Investigating the sources of linguistic alignment in conversation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gabriel</forename><surname>Doyle</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Michael</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Frank</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 54th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the 54th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics<address><addrLine>Berlin, Germany</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="526" to="536" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A robust framework for estimating linguistic alignment in Twitter conversations</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gabriel</forename><surname>Doyle</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dan</forename><surname>Yurovsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michael C</forename><surname>Frank</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 25th International Conference on World Wide Web</title>
		<meeting>the 25th International Conference on World Wide Web<address><addrLine>Montreal, Canada</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="637" to="648" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Coming to terms quantifying the benefits of linguistic coordination</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Riccardo</forename><surname>Fusaroli</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bahador</forename><surname>Bahrami</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Karsten</forename><surname>Olsen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Andreas</forename><surname>Roepstorff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Geraint</forename><surname>Rees</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chris</forename><surname>Frith</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kristian</forename><surname>Tylén</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">23</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="931" to="939" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Variation of entropy and parse trees of sentences as a function of the sentence number</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dmitriy</forename><surname>Genzel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Eugene</forename><surname>Charniak</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2003 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</title>
		<meeting>the 2003 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="65" to="72" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Communication accommodation theory</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Howard</forename><surname>Giles</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Engaging theories in interpersonal communication: Multiple perspectives</title>
		<editor>L. A. Baxter and D. O. Braithewaite</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Sage, Thousand Oaks, CA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="161" to="173" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Divergence in dialogue</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Patrick</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Matthew</forename><surname>Healey</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christine</forename><surname>Purver</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Howes</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">PLOS ONE</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="6" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Understanding 3way interactions between continuous variables</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Thomas</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Houslay</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://tomhouslay.com/2014/03/21/understanding-3-way-interactions-between-continuous-variables/" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Alignment as a consequence of expectation adaptation: Syntactic priming is affected by the prime&apos;s prediction error given both prior and recent experience</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Florian</forename><surname>Jaeger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Neal</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Snider</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">127</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="57" to="83" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Strategies of accommodation: Development of a coding system for conversational interaction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Elizabeth</forename><surname>Jones</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Cynthia</forename><surname>Gallois</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Victor</forename><surname>Callan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michelle</forename><surname>Barker</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Language and Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">18</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="123" to="151" />
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Finding zelig in text: A measure for normalizing linguistic accommodation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Simon</forename><surname>Jones</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rachel</forename><surname>Cotterill</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nigel</forename><surname>Dewdney</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kate</forename><surname>Muir</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Adam</forename><surname>Joinson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">25th International Conference on Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Bath, UK</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Nonlinear mixed effects models for repeated measures data</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Mary</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Douglas M</forename><surname>Lindstrom</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Bates</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Biometrics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="673" to="687" />
			<date type="published" when="1990" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Generalized linear models</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Peter</forename><surname>Mccullagh</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">European Journal of Operational Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">16</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="285" to="292" />
			<date type="published" when="1984" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Comprehension priming as rational expectation for repetition: Evidence from syntactic processing</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mark</forename><surname>Myslín</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Roger</forename><surname>Levy</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">147</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="29" to="56" />
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Linguistic style matching in social interaction</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Kate</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">James</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Niederhoffer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Pennebaker</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Language and Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">21</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="337" to="360" />
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Centre stage: How social network position shapes linguistic coordination</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bill</forename><surname>Noble</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Raquel</forename><surname>Fernández</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of CMCL 2015</title>
		<meeting>CMCL 2015<address><addrLine>Denver, CO</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="29" to="38" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A caution regarding rules of thumb for variance inflation factors</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Robert M O&amp;apos;brien</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Quality &amp; Quantity</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">41</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="673" to="690" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Linguistic inquiry and word count: LIWC</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Martha</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>James W Pennebaker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Roger J</forename><surname>Francis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Booth</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Mahway: Lawrence Erlbaum Associates</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">71</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2001" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Toward a mechanistic psychology of dialogue</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Martin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Simon</forename><surname>Pickering</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Garrod</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Behavioral and Brain Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">27</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">02</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="169" to="190" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Do people use language production to make predictions during comprehension?</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Martin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Simon</forename><surname>Pickering</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Garrod</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Trends in cognitive sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="105" to="110" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A computational cognitive model of syntactic priming</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Reitter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Frank</forename><surname>Keller</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Johanna D</forename><surname>Moore</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognitive Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">35</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="587" to="637" />
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Alignment and task success in spoken dialogue</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Reitter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Johanna D</forename><surname>Moore</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Memory and Language</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">76</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="29" to="46" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Linguistic adaptation in conversation threads: Analyzing alignment in online health communities</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yafei</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Reitter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">John</forename><surname>Yen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of Cognitive Modeling and Computational Linguistics. Workshop at the Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>Cognitive Modeling and Computational Linguistics. Workshop at the Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Accent accommodation in the employment interview</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Willemyns</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Cynthia</forename><surname>Gallois</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Victor</forename><surname>Callan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Pittam</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Language and Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3" to="22" />
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">An evaluation and comparison of linguistic alignment measures</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yang</forename><surname>Xu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Reitter</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of Cognitive Modeling and Computational Linguistics (CMCL)</title>
		<meeting>Cognitive Modeling and Computational Linguistics (CMCL)<address><addrLine>Denver, DO</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="58" to="67" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Convergence of syntactic complexity in conversation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yang</forename><surname>Xu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Reitter</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 54th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the 54th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics<address><addrLine>Berlin, Germany</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="443" to="448" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Short Papers)</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Entropy converges between dialogue participants: Explanations from an information-theoretic perspective</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yang</forename><surname>Xu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Reitter</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 54th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the 54th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics<address><addrLine>Berlin, Germany</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="537" to="546" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Long Papers)</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Information density converges in dialogue: Towards an informationtheoretic model</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yang</forename><surname>Xu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Reitter</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">170</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="147" to="163" />
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
