<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T10:26+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Translating a Language You Don&apos;t Know in the Chinese Room</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
				<availability status="unknown"><p>Copyright Association for Computational Linguistics</p>
				</availability>
				<date>July 15-20, 2018. 2018</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ulf</forename><surname>Hermjakob</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Information Sciences Institute</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Department of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Southern California</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jonathan</forename><surname>May</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Information Sciences Institute</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Department of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Southern California</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Pust</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Information Sciences Institute</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Department of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Southern California</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kevin</forename><surname>Knight</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Information Sciences Institute</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Department of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Southern California</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Translating a Language You Don&apos;t Know in the Chinese Room</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 56th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics-System Demonstrations</title>
						<meeting>the 56th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics-System Demonstrations <address><addrLine>Melbourne, Australia</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="62" to="67"/>
							<date type="published">July 15-20, 2018. 2018</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<note>62</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>In a corruption of John Searle&apos;s famous AI thought experiment, the Chinese Room (Searle, 1980), we twist its original intent by enabling humans to translate text, e.g. from Uyghur to English, even if they don&apos;t have any prior knowledge of the source language. Our enabling tool, which we call the Chinese Room, is equipped with the same resources made available to a machine translation engine. We find that our superior language model and world knowledge allows us to create perfectly fluent and nearly adequate translations, with human expertise required only for the target language. The Chinese Room tool can be used to rapidly create small corpora of parallel data when bilingual translators are not readily available, in particular for low-resource languages.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Domain adaptation for machine translation is a well-studied problem. 1 Most works assume a system-builder has an adequate amount of out- of-domain or 'general' domain parallel sentence training data and some smaller corpus of in- domain data that can be used, depending on the size of the in-domain corpus, for additional train- ing, for parameter estimation, or, if the in-domain corpus is very small, simply for system evaluation. Very little, however, is said of the scenario where there is no in-domain parallel data available, and yet an in-domain system must be built.</p><p>In such scenarios one may try to mine paral- lel data from comparable corpora ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Munteanu and Marcu, 2005</ref>), but in cases where even scant (but <ref type="bibr">1</ref> See http://www.statmt.org/survey/Topic/ DomainAdaptation for a survey of methodologies.</p><p>not zero) in-domain monolingual resources are available this is not a feasible strategy and the only way to obtain any reliably measure of quality is to solicit human translations. However, it may be difficult to recruit translators to prepare such data, if the language is underrepresented or politically sensitive.</p><p>Al- <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Onaizan et al. (2002)</ref> describe an experiment where individual humans translated 10 sentences from Tetun to English, without any prior knowl- edge of Tetun, based solely on an in-domain bi- text of 1,102 sentences. Without any prior tools, translation was very tedious, inefficient, and im- practical for the 10 sentences, taking about one sentence per hour. But the experiment success- fully showed in principle the feasibility of human translation without prior knowledge of the source language.</p><p>We introduce a tool, the Chinese Room, to fa- cilitate efficient human translation without prior knowledge of a source language. The name is in- spired from Searle (1980) who envisioned a mono- lingual English-speaking human equipped with in- structions for answering Chinese questions by ma- nipulating symbols of a Chinese information cor- pus and the question text to form answers. While Searle used this idea to argue against 'strong' AI, we thought the setup, i.e. giving a human the tools an NLP model is given (in this case, a machine translation model), was a good one for rapidly generating useful translation data.</p><p>Apart from generating human translation data, an additional use of the Chinese Room is to support computational linguists in identifying the challenges of machine translation for a specific language pair and language resources. By plac- ing humans in the role of the MT, we may bet- ter understand the nature and magnitude of out-of- vocabulary gaps, and whether they might be due to morphological complexity, compounding, assimi-lation, spelling variations, insufficient or out-of- domain parallel corpora or dictionaries, etc. We found that the Chinese Room can be a useful tool to help generate new ideas for machine translation research.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.1">Features</head><p>Our Chinese Room tool has the following features: The principal glossing resources are dictionaries and translation probability tables (t-tables) that are automatically computed from parallel corpora ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Brown et al., 1993</ref>). The Chinese Room tool will present the top 10 t-table entries and all dictionary entries, including multi-word entries.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">Out-of-Vocabulary Words</head><p>However, particularly for low-resource languages, words will frequently not be found that easily. Due to morphological inflection, affixes, compound- ing, assimilation, and typos, a source word might not occur in a dictionary or t-table.</p><p>Low-resource languages often lack consistent spelling due to dialects, lack of spelling standards, or lack of education. For example, even a small Uyghur corpus included six different spellings for the Uyghur word for kilometer: kilometer, kilome- tir, kilomitir, kilometr, kilomitr, klometir.</p><p>It is therefore critical to be able to identify dictionary and t-table entries that approximately match a word or a part hereof. We address this challenge with a combination of multiple indexes and a weighted string similarity metric.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3">Multiple Indexes For String Matching</head><p>We currently use the following indexing heuris- tics: (1) stemming, (2) hashing, (3) drop-letter, and (4) long substring. Inspired by phonetic matching <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Philips, 2000)</ref>, our current hash func- tion first removes duplicate letters and then re- moves vowels, except for any leading vowels that get mapped to a canonical e. For example, both break and broke are hashed to brk.</p><p>The drop-letter heuristic allows to find entries for words with typos due to letter deletion, addi- tion, substitution and juxtaposition. For example, "crocodile" and "cocodrile" share the drop-letter sequence "cocodile".</p><p>The long (7+ letters) substring heuristic finds dictionary entries that contain additional content.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.4">Weighted String Distance Metric</head><p>Traditional edit distance metrics <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Levenshtein, 1966)</ref> do not consider the particular characters being added, subtracted, or substituted, and will therefore typically assign a higher cost to (gram, gramme) than to (gram, tram). Such uniform edit distance costs are linguistically implausible.</p><p>The Chinese Room Editor therefore uses a mod- ified metric that leverages a resource of edit dis- tance costs. In particular, costs for vowels and du- plicate letters are cheap. <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table 1</ref>: String similarity rule examples. ::s1 = string 1; ::left1 = left context of string 1; ::lc1 = language code of string 1.</p><p>The first rule in <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table 1</ref> assigns a cost of 0.1 for o/u substitution, well below the default cost of 1. The second and third rule reduce the string dis- tance cost of (gram, gramme) to 0.12. Cost en- tries for pairs of substrings can be restricted to specific left and right contexts or to specific lan- guages. The last rule in <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table 1</ref> assigns a low cost to word-initial silent k in English. The manually created resource currently has 590 entries, includ- ing a core set of 252 language-independent cost entries that are widely applicable.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.5">Romanization</head><p>For a similarity metric to be widely practical, the strings need to be in the same script. We therefore romanize before computing string similarity.</p><p>An additional motivation for romanization in the Chinese Room is based on the observation that foreign scripts present a massive cognitive barrier to humans who are not familiar with them. See <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Table 2</ref> for examples. We found that when we asked native English speakers to use the Chinese Room to translate text from languages such as Uyghur or Bengali to En- glish, they strongly preferred working on a roman- ized version of the source language compared to its original form and indeed found using the native, unfamiliar script to be a nearly impossible task.</p><p>By default, we therefore romanize non-Latin- script text, using the universal romanizer uroman 2 ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Hermjakob et al., 2018</ref>). The Chinese Room Editor includes the option to display the original text or both the original and romanized source text. The Uyghur text in <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Table 2</ref> is romanized as yaponie fukushima 1-yadro elektir istansisining toet genratorlar guruppisi which facilitates the recognition of cognates. <ref type="bibr">2</ref> bit.ly/uroman</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.6">Grammar Resource Files</head><p>An additional optional resource is a set of gram- mar entries for affixes and function words that dic- tionaries and t-tables do not cover very well. Ta- ble 3 shows examples for five Hungarian affixes and two Tagalog function words. The grammar files have been built manually, typically drawing on external resources such as Wiktionary. <ref type="bibr">3</ref> The size is language specific, rang- ing from a few dozen entries to several hundred entries for extremely suffix-rich Hungarian.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.7">Process</head><p>Figure 1 provides an overview of the Chinese Room process. Given a set of NLP resources and a workset of source language sentences, the Chinese Room Glosser builds a Chinese Room File, which can be edited in the Chinese Room Editor. The resulting Chinese Room Corpus can be used for machine translation and other NLP applications.  <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 2</ref> shows an example from a Uyghur article about an earthquake. For the (romanized) Uyghur word asaslanghanda, the tool shows several rele- vant entries that guide the translator to the correct gloss based (on). Note the information regarding the suffixes -maq, -ghan, and -da.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.8">Chinese Room Example</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.9">Gloss Propagation</head><p>Words and expressions often occur multiple times in a document. When a translator edits a gloss, the edited gloss is propagated to other yet unedited glosses of the same word(s) in a document. The propagated glosses can be overwritten, but that is rarely necessary.</p><p>Additionally, the edited glosses are collected as an additional translation resource, which can be compiled and propagated to other documents. This allows the sharing of newly discovered trans- lations between translators.</p><p>At times, some sentences will be difficult to fully translate, particularly if there are multiple unknown words. The meaning of some of those words will become apparent in other sentences with a stronger context, which in turn will help comprehension of the original difficult sentence.</p><p>The discovery of morphological bridge forms is one such case. In (romanized) Uyghur, for exam- ple, a translator might struggle with the meaning of panahliniwetiptu, but later in the text find a re- lated word panahlinish, which in turn is similar enough to the dictionary entry panalinish = shelter to be found by the tool. With additional grammar guidance for the suffixes -wet, -ip, -tu, and -sh, the originally hard word can now be glossed and the sentence translated.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Chinese Room Editor User Interface 4</head><p>The Chinese Room URL is bit.ly/chinese-room. Temporary visitors are invited to login as guest.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Loading a Workset</head><p>To get started, click the load button, wait a mo- ment, select a source language (e.g. Uyghur), and a workset (e.g. earthquake-jp-2011-wo-cr-corpus).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Exploring and Editing Glosses</head><p>The initial gloss will often provide a good first idea of what the sentence is about. To explore alterna- tives to the glosses provided, hover the mouse over a gloss that you want to explore. A blue info box will appear in the lower part of the screen, provid- ing you with a range of entries related to the word. To edit a gloss, or just to fix an info box for subse- quent scrolling, click on a gloss, and the gloss be- comes editable. To move on to another gloss, click that gloss. To exit gloss editing mode, press Enter (while the cursor is in a gloss box). Alternatively, you can click on a translation in the info box to select that translation as a gloss. Double-clicking on a source word will copy it to the gloss; this is useful for words that don't need translations, such as names.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3">Editing Sentence Translations</head><p>To edit the translation of the full sentence, click on the current translation (in green), initially empty. Type text, or adopt a gloss by clicking on it. Press Enter to exit sentence editing.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.4">Grouping, Ungrouping, Confidence</head><p>In the Special ops section, click on group to com- bine words to a multi-word expression, or ungroup to undo. You may optionally assign a confidence level to glosses and sentence translations, which allows you flag uncertainty, for later review by you or somebody else, or to inform a subsequent user (such as a learning algorithm). For more info, hover over a special-op name.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Experiments</head><p>We have built Chinese Rooms for Bengali, Hungarian, Oromo, Somali, Swahili, Tagalog, Tigrinya, and Uyghur.</p><p>For Bengali, two of the authors of this paper translated an article of 10 Bengali sentences to En- glish, without any prior knowledge of Bengali, us- ing the Chinese Room. To evaluate the results, we asked a native speaker from Bangladesh, a grad- uate student living in the US who is not a pro- fessional translator, to first translate the same 10 sentences independently and then to evaluate our translations. According to the native speaker our translations were better; we only missed one Ben- gali word in translation, and were actually aware of it, but were unable to decode it with the re- sources at hand.</p><p>We used the Chinese Room to create small cor- pora of parallel data in a time-constrained MT system-building scenario. In this scenario we were required to translate documents from Uyghur to English describing earthquakes and disaster relief efforts. However, we had no parallel data dealing with this topic, and our use of an unrelated test set (see <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Figure 3)</ref> to estimate overall task performance was not reliable. We thus wanted to construct an in-domain Uyghur-English parallel corpus.</p><p>In the scenario we were given a small number of one-hour sessions with a native informant (NI), a Uyghur native who spoke English and was not a linguistics or computer science expert. We ini- tially asked the NI use the time to translate docu- ments, one sentence at a time. This was accom- plished at a rate of 360 words per hour, but re- quired another 30-60 minutes of post-editing to ensure fluency. We next tried typing for the NI (and ensured fluency); this yielded 320 words/hr but did not require post-editing. Finally we used the Chinese Room to translate and asked the NI to point out any errors. This hour yielded 480 words. Machine translation quality on the resulting in- domain set tracked much better with performance on the evaluation set. Later on we built a second in-domain set but did not have any further access to the NI. Using this set of approximate translation to tune parameters yielded a 0.3 BLEU increase in system performance.</p><p>We have trained more than 20 people to use the Chinese Room with very good results for the training test case, Somali. We are similarly confident in our translations for Hungarian and Uyghur. Tagalog and Swahili are recent builds, and translations look very promising.</p><p>However, we found the dictionary and bitext resources for Tigrinya (to a lesser degree) and Oromo (to a larger degree) to be too small to con- fidently translate most sentences. We were able to translate some sentences completely, and many others partially, but had to rely on the support of non-professional native speakers to complete the translations. The Chinese Room nevertheless proved to be very useful in this very-low-resource scenario. We could already build glosses for many words and provide a partial translations, so that the native speaker could finish a sentence faster than starting from scratch. The Chinese Room also helped the native speaker to more easily find the English words he/she was looking for, and al- lowed us to make sure that the translation covered all essential parts of the original text.  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Related Work</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Future Work</head><p>We have observed that by using the Chinese Room, human translators start to learn some of the vocabulary and grammar of the source language. It might therefore be worthwhile to explore how the Chinese Room tool, with a few modifications, could be used in foreign language learning.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7">Conclusion</head><p>We have established the feasibility of a practical system that enables human translation from an un- familiar language, supporting even low-resource languages. We found that we were able to create perfectly fluent and nearly adequate translations, far exceeding the quality of a state-of-the-art ma- chine translation system ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Cheung et al., 2017</ref>) us- ing the same resources as the Chinese Room, by exploiting the human translators' target language model and their world knowledge, both of which are still far superior to those of a computer.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: Chinese Room process. Blue rectangles represent data, pink ovals programs and processes.</figDesc><graphic url="image-2.png" coords="3,72.00,62.81,453.55,223.27" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2: Screenshot of Chinese Room Editor with Uyghur example. Demo site: bit.ly/chinese-room</figDesc><graphic url="image-5.png" coords="4,72.00,62.80,453.54,224.28" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Callison-Burch (2005); Albrecht et al. (2009); Koehn (2010) and Trados 5 have built computer- aided translation systems for high-resource lan- guages, with an emphasis on post-editing. Hu et al. (2011) describe a monolingual trans- lation protocol that combines MT with not only monolingual target language speakers, but, unlike the Chinese Room, also monolingual source lan- guage speakers.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>Figure 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Figure 3: MT performance on an out-of-domain corpus ('test') does not predict performance on the evaluation ('eval') set but performance on our 'domain' data set which comprises NI translations and Chinese Room post-edits, is predictive.</figDesc><graphic url="image-7.png" coords="6,298.77,62.98,216.00,129.83" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" validated="false"><head>1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Glosser accommodates a variety of NLP and 
source language resources 

2. User can explore alternative translations 

3. Grammar support (such as prefixes, suffixes, 
function words) 

4. Optional romanization of source text 

5. Robust to spelling variations 

6. Optional confidence levels 

7. Propagation of user translations 

8. Dictionary search function (allowing regular 
expressions) 

9. User accounts with login, password, work-
sets, separate workspaces 

10. Web-based 

2 System Description 

2.1 Dictionary and T-table Lookup 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" validated="false"><head>Table 2 : Texts in Uyghur, Amharic and Tibetan.</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" validated="false"><head>Table 3 : Grammar entries for Hungarian, Tagalog.</head><label>3</label><figDesc></figDesc><table></table></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="3"> https://en.wiktionary.org, e.g. https://en.wiktionary.org/ wiki/Appendix:Hungarian suffixes</note>

			<note place="foot" n="4"> For more details, please consult the Chinese Room Editor manual at bit.ly/chinese-room-manual.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="5"> https://www.sdltrados.com</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>This work was sponsored by DARPA (HR0011-15-C-0115).</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Translation with scarce bilingual resources. Machine translation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yaser</forename><surname>Al-Onaizan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ulrich</forename><surname>Germann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ulf</forename><surname>Hermjakob</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kevin</forename><surname>Knight</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Philipp</forename><surname>Koehn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Daniel</forename><surname>Marcu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kenji</forename><surname>Yamada</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="17" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Correcting automatic translations through collaborations between MT and monolingual target-language users</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rebecca</forename><surname>Joshua S Albrecht</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Hwa</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Marai</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">EACL</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="60" to="68" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The mathematics of statistical machine translation: Parameter estimation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Vincent J Della</forename><surname>Peter F Brown</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Stephen A Della</forename><surname>Pietra</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Robert L</forename><surname>Pietra</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Mercer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Computational linguistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="263" to="311" />
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Linear B system description for the 2005 NIST MT evaluation exercise</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chris</forename><surname>Callison-Burch</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the NIST 2005 Machine Translation Evaluation Workshop</title>
		<meeting>the NIST 2005 Machine Translation Evaluation Workshop</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Leon</forename><surname>Cheung</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ulf</forename><surname>Hermjakob</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jonathan</forename><surname>May</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nima</forename><surname>Pourdamghani</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Pust</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kevin</forename><surname>Knight</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Elisa system description for LoReHLT</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Out-of-the-box universal romanization tool uroman</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ulf</forename><surname>Hermjakob</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jonathan</forename><surname>May</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kevin</forename><surname>Knight</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 56th Annual Meeting of Association for Computational Linguistics, Demo Track</title>
		<meeting>the 56th Annual Meeting of Association for Computational Linguistics, Demo Track</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Monotrans2: A new human computation system to support monolingual translation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chang</forename><surname>Hu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Benjamin</forename><surname>Bederson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Philip</forename><surname>Resnik</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yakov</forename><surname>Kronrod</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">SIGCHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1133" to="1136" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Enabling monolingual translators: Post-editing vs. options</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Philipp</forename><surname>Koehn</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">NAACL Human Language Technologies</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="537" to="545" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Binary codes capable of correcting deletions, insertions, and reversals</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Vladimir I Levenshtein</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Soviet physics doklady</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1966" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="707" to="710" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Improving machine translation performance by exploiting non-parallel corpora</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Stefan</forename><surname>Dragos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Daniel</forename><surname>Munteanu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Marcu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Computational Linguistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">31</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="477" to="504" />
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The double Metaphone search algorithm. C</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lawrence</forename><surname>Philips</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">C++ Users J</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">18</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="38" to="43" />
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">John</forename><surname>Searle</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Minds, brains, and programs. Behavioral and Brain Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1980" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="417" to="442" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
