<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T10:42+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Alignment Analysis of Sequential Segmentation of Lexicons to Improve Automatic Cognate Detection</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date>July 15-20, 2018</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Pranav</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename></persName>
							<email>cs.pranav.a@gmail.com</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Big Data Institute Hong Kong University of Science and Technology Hong Kong</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Alignment Analysis of Sequential Segmentation of Lexicons to Improve Automatic Cognate Detection</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of ACL 2018, Student Research Workshop</title>
						<meeting>ACL 2018, Student Research Workshop <address><addrLine>Melbourne, Australia</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="134" to="140"/>
							<date type="published">July 15-20, 2018</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<note>134</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Ranking functions in information retrieval are often used in search engines to recommend the relevant answers to the query. This paper makes use of this notion of information retrieval and applies onto the problem domain of cognate detection. The main contributions of this paper are: (1) positional segmentation, which incorporates the sequential notion; (2) graphical error modelling, which deduces the transformations. The current research work focuses on classification problem; which is distinguishing whether a pair of words are cognates. This paper focuses on a harder problem, whether we could predict a possible cognate from the given input. Our study shows that when language modelling smoothing methods are applied as the retrieval functions and used in conjunction with positional segmentation and error modelling gives better results than competing baselines, in both classification and prediction of cognates.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Cognates are a collection of words in different lan- guages deriving from the same origin. The study of cognates plays a crucial role in applying com- parative approaches for historical linguistics, in particular, solving language relatedness and track- ing the interaction and evolvement of multiple lan- guages over time. A cognate instance in Indo- European languages is given as the word group: night (English), nuit (French), noche (Spanish) and nacht (German).</p><p>The existing studies on cognate detection in- volve experiments which distinguish between a pair of words whether they are cognates or non- cognates ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Ciobanu and Dinu, 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">List, 2012a</ref>). These studies do not approach the problem of pre- dicting the possible cognate of the target language, if the cognate of the source language is given. For example, given the word nuit, could the algorithm predict the appropriate German cognate within the huge German wordlist? This paper tackles this problem by incorporating heuristics of the prob- abilistic ranking functions from information re- trieval. Information retrieval addresses the prob- lem of scoring a document with a given query, which is used in every search engine. One can view the above problem as the construction of a suitable search engine, through which we want to find the cognate counterpart of a word (query) in a lexicon of another language (documents).</p><p>This paper deals with the intersection between the areas of information retrieval and approximate string similarity (like the cognate detection prob- lem), which is largely under-explored in the liter- ature. Retrieval methods also provide a variety of alternative heuristics which can be chosen for the desired application areas <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Fang et al., 2011</ref>). Tak- ing such advantage of the flexibility of these mod- els, the combination of approximate string simi- larity operations with an information retrieval sys- tem could be beneficial in many cases. We demon- strate how the notion of information retrieval can be incorporated into the approximate string sim- ilarity problem by breaking a word into smaller units. Regarding this, <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Nguyen et al. (2016)</ref> has argued that segmented words are a more practi- cal way to query large databases of sequences, in comparison with conventional query methods. This further encourages the heuristic attempt at imposing an information retrieval model on the cognate detection problem in this paper.</p><p>Our main contribution is to design an informa- tion retrieval based scoring function (see section 4) which can capture the complex morphological shifts between the cognates. We tackled this by proposing a shingling (chunking) scheme which incorporates positional information (see section 2) and a graph-based error modelling scheme to un- derstand the transformations (see section 3). Our test harness focuses not only on distinguishing be- tween a pair of cognates, but also the ability to pre- dict the cognate for a target language (see section 5).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Positional Character-based Shingling</head><p>This section examines on converting a string into a shingle-set which includes the encodings of the positional information. In this paper, we notify, S as the shingle-set of cognate from the source language and T as the shingle-set of cognate for the target language. The similarity between these split-sets is denoted by S ∩ T . An example of cognate from the source language, S (Romanian) could be shingle set of the word rosmarin and T (Italian) could be romarin.</p><p>K-gram shingling: Usually, set based string similarity measures are based on comparing over- lap between the shingles of two strings. Shingling is a way of viewing a string as a document by con- sidering k characters at a time. For example, the shingle of the word rosmarin is created with k = 2 as: S = {{sr, ro, os, sm, ma, ar, ri, in, n/s}. Here, s is the start sentinel token and /s is the stop sentinel token. For the sake of simplic- ity, we have ignored sentinel tokens; which trans- forms into: S = {r, ro, os, sm, ma, ar, ri, in, n}. This method splits the strings into smaller k-grams without any positional information.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">Positional Shingling from 1 End</head><p>We argue that the unordered k-grams splitting could lead to an inefficient matching of strings since a shingle set is visualized as the bag-of- words method. Given this, we propose a po- sitional k-gram shingling technique, which in- troduces position number in the splits to incor- porate the notion of the sequence of the to- kens. For example, the word rosmarin could be position-wise split with k = 2 as: S = {1r, 2ro, 3os, 4sm, 5ma, 6ar, 7ri, 8in, 9n}.</p><p>Thus, the member 4sm means that it is the fourth member of the set. The motivation behind this modification is that it retains the positional in- formation which is useful in probabilistic retrieval ranking functions.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">Positional Shingling from 2 Ends</head><p>The main disadvantage of the positional shin- gling from single end is that any mismatch can completely disturb the order of the rest, leading to low similarity.</p><p>For example, if the query is rosmarin with cognate ro- marin, the corresponding split sets would be {1r, 2ro, 3os, 4sm, 5ma, 6ar, 7ri, 8in, 9n} and {1r, 2ro, 3om, 4ma, 5ar, 6ri, 7in, 8n}. The order of the members after 2ro is misplaced, thus this will lead to low similarity between two cognates. Only {1r, 2ro} is common between the cognates. Considering this, we propose positional shingling from both ends, which is robust against such displacements.</p><p>We attach a position number to the left if the numbering begins from the start, and to the right if the numbering begins from the end. Then the smallest position number is selected between the two position numbers. If the position numbers are equal, then we select the left position number as a convention. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref> gives an exemplification of this algorithm illustrated with splits of romarin and rosmarin.  On the left, algo- rithm segments the Romanian word romarin into the split-set {1r, 2ro, 3om, 4ma, ar4, ri3, in2, n1}. On the right, the algorithm segments rosmarin into {1r, 2ro, 3os, 4sm, 5ma, ar4, ri3, in2, n1}.</p><p>In <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref>, split sets of rosmarin and romarin are shown. After taking intersection of them, we get {1r, 2ro, ar4, ri3, in2, n1}, indicating a higher similarity.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Graphical Error Modelling</head><p>Once shingle sets are created, common overlap set measures like set intersection, Jaccard <ref type="bibr">(Järvelin et al., 2007</ref>), XDice ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Brew et al., 1996)</ref> or TF-IDF ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Wu et al., 2008)</ref> could be used to measure simi- larities between two sets. However, these methods only focus on similarity of the two strings. For cognate detection, it is crucial to understand how substrings are transformed from source language to target language. This section discusses on how to view this "dissimilarity" by creating a graphical error model. Algorithm 1 explicates the process of graphical error modelling. For illustration purposes, we vi- sualize the procedure via a Romanian-Italian cog- nate pair (mesia, messia). If the source language is Romanian, then S = {1m, 2me, 3es, si3, ia2, a1}, which is the split-set of mesia. Let the tar- get language by Italian. Then the split-set of the Italian word messia, denoted as T , will be {1m, 2me, 3es, 4ss, si3, ia2, a1}. Thus |S ∩ T | is the number of common terms. Thus the term matches are, S∩T = {1m, 2me, 3es, si3, ia2, a1}. We are interested in examining the "dissimilar- ity", which are the leftover terms in the sets. That means, we need to infer a certain pattern from left- over sets, which are S −{S ∩T } and T −{S ∩T }. Thus we can draw mappings to gather informa- tion of the corrections. Let top and bottom be the ordered sets referring to S − {S ∩ T } and T − {S ∩ T } respectively. Referring to the exam- ple, T − S ∩ T = {4ss}, a bottom set. Similarly, S − S ∩ T = {}, a top set. Then we follow in- structions given in algorithm 1.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Algorithm 1: Graphical Error Model</head><p>Graphical Error Model takes two split sets generated by the shingling variants, namely top and bottom. The objective is to output a graphical structure showing connections between members of the top and the bottom sets.</p><p>1. Initialization of the top and bottom: If the given sets top and bottom are empty, we ini- tialize them by inserting an empty token (φ) into those sets.</p><p>Running example: This step transforms top set as {φ} and bottom as {4ss}. 2. Equalization of the set cardinalities: The cardinalities of the sets top and bottom made equal by inserting empty tokens (φ) into the middle of the sets.</p><p>Running example: The set cardinalities of top and bottom were already equal. Thus the output of this step are top set as {φ} and bot- tom as {4ss}.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.">Inserting the mappings of the set members</head><p>into the graph: The empty graph is initial- ized as graph = {}. The directed edges are generated, originating from every set member of top to every set member of bottom. This results in a complete directed bipartite graph between top and bottom sets. Each edge is as- signed a probability P (e) which is discussed in a later section.</p><p>Running example: The output of this step would be complete directed bipartite graph between top and bottom sets which is {φ → 4ss} One more example is provided in <ref type="figure">figure 2</ref>.</p><p>Intuition: The edges created as the result of this graph could be used for probabilistic calcula- tions which are detailed more in section 4.2. Intu- itively, φ → 4ss means that if the letter s is added at position 4 of the word of the source mesia, then one could get the target word messia.</p><p>{po3, ϕ, or2} {pe4, eu3, ur2}</p><p>Figure 2: The figure shows the bipartite graph out- put of the algorithm when the source cognate is stupor and the target cognate is stupeur.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Evaluation Function</head><p>The design of our evaluation function focuses on two main properties: set based similarity (see section 4.1) and probabilistic calculation through graphical model (see section 4.2)</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">Similarity Function</head><p>Usually, the computation of similarity between two sets is done by metrics like Jaccard, Dice and XDice ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Brew et al., 1996)</ref>. Dynamic pro- gramming based methods like edit distance and LCSR (Longest Common Subsequence Ratio, <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(Melamed, 1999)</ref>) are also often used to calculate similarity between two strings. Ranking functions incorporate more complex but necessary features which are needed to distinguish between the doc- uments.</p><p>In this paper, we use BM25 and a Dirichlet smoothing based ranking function to compute the similarity. BM25 considers term-frequency, in- verse document frequency and length normaliza- tion based penalization features for similarity cal- culations. Dirichlet smoothing function <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(Robertson and Zaragoza, 2009</ref>) makes use of language modelling features and tunable parameter which aids in Bayesian smoothing of unseen shingles in the split sets ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Blei et al., 2003</ref>).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">Error Modelling Function</head><p>The information of the common morphological transformations for cognates between two differ- ent languages helps in determining if a pair of words could be cognates. Based on the graphs of cognate pairs between Italian and Romanian (sec- tion 3), which models the morphological shifts be- tween the cognates in the two languages, we define an error modelling function on any pair of words from the two languages. The split set from the source language is denoted by S and target lan- guage by T , then probabilistic function would be:</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">π(S, T) = 1 |G(S, T )| e∈G(S,T ) P(e) q</formula><p>where G(S, T ) is the constructed graph of S and T , the strength parameter is called q here with the range of (0, ∞), and P (e) is the probability of edge e to occur in between two cognates, which is estimated by its frequency of being observed in the graphs of cognate pairs in the training set. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">Figure 3</ref> illustrates the aggregation of edges in the graph and <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">figure 4</ref> shows the final output of the error modelling function after normalizing.</p><p>π(S, T) is called the error modelling function defined for the word pair, which is an intuitive calculation of probabilty between a pair of cog- nates through estimating their transformations. q is a tunable parameter that controls the effect of the probabilistic frequencies P (e) observed in the training set, often useful in avoiding overfitting.  </p><note type="other">po3 po3 ϕ ϕ ϕ or2 or2 or2 pe4 eu3 ur2 pe4 eu3 ur2 pe4 eu3 ur2</note><p>aggregate the edge probabilities   </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3">Combining Error Modelling and Similarity Function metrics</head><p>In this subsection, we merge the notion of sim- ilarity and dissimilarity together. We combine a set-based similarity function (discussed in section 4.1) and the error modelling function (discussed in section 4.2) into a score function by a weighted sum of them, which is,</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">score(S, T ) = λ × sim(S, T) + (1 − λ) × π(S, T)</formula><p>where λ ∈ [0, 1] is a weight based hyperparameter, sim(S, T ) is a set-based similarity between S and T , and π(S, T ) is the graphical error modelling function defined above. <ref type="table">Table 1</ref> summarizes the results of the experimental setup. The elements of test harness are mentioned as following:</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Test Harness</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.1">Setup Description</head><p>Dataset: The experiments in this paper are per- formed on the dataset used by <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Ciobanu et al (2014)</ref>. The dataset consists 400 pairs of cognates and non-cognates for Romanian-French (Ro -Fr), Romanian-Italian (Ro -It), Romanian-Spanish (Ro -Es) and Romanian-Portuguese (Ro -Pt). The dataset is divided into a 3:1 ratio for training and testing purposes. Using cross-validation, hyperpa- rameters and thresholds for all the algorithms and baselines were tuned accordingly in a fair manner. Experiments: Two experiments are included in test harness.</p><p>1. We provide a pair of words and the algo- rithms would aim to detect whether they are cognates. Accuracy on the test set is used as a metric for evaluation. 2. We provide a source cognate as the input and the algorithm would return a ranked list as the output. The efficiency of the algorithm would depend on the rank of the desired target cog- nate. This is measured by MRR (Mean Re- ciprocal Rank), which is defined as,</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">M RR = |dataset| i=1 1 rank i</formula><p>, where rank i is the rank of the true cognate in the ranked list returned to the i th query.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.2">Baselines</head><p>String Similarity Baselines: It is intuitive to compare our methods with the prevalent string similarity baselines since the notions behind cog- nate detection and string similarity are almost sim- ilar. Edit Distance is often used as the baseline in the cognate detection papers <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(Melamed, 1999)</ref>. This computes the number of operations required to transform from source to target cognate. We have also incorporated XDice ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Brew et al., 1996)</ref>, which is a set based similarity measure that oper- ates between shingle set between two strings. Hid- den alignment conditional random fields (CRF) are often used in transliteration which serves as the generative sequential model to compute the prob- abilities between the cognates, which is analogous to learnable edit distance <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(McCallum et al., 2012</ref>). Among these baselines, CRF performs the best in accuracy and MRR. Orthographic Cognate Detection: Papers re- lated to this notion usually take alignment of sub- strings which in classifier like support vector ma- chines ( <ref type="bibr">Dinu, 2015, 2014)</ref> or hidden markov models <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Bhargava and Kondrak, 2009</ref>). We included Alina et al as the baseline <ref type="formula">(2014)</ref>, which employs the dynamic programming based methods for sequence alignment following which features were extracted from the mismatches in the word alignments. These features are plugged into the classifier like SVM which results in decent per- formance on accuracy with an average of 84%, but only 16% on MRR. This result is due to the fact that a large number of features leads to overfitting and scoring function is not able to distinguish the appropriate cognate. Phonetic Cognate Detection: Research in au- tomatic cognate identification using phonetic as- pects involve computation of similarity by de- composing phonetically transcribed words <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(Kondrak, 2000</ref>), acoustic models <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Mielke, 2012)</ref>, pho- netic encodings <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">(Rama, 2015)</ref>, aligned segments of transcribed phonemes <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(List, 2012b)</ref>. We im- plemented Rama's research (2015), which em- ploys a Siamese convolutional neural network to learn the phonetic features jointly with language relatedness for cognate identification, which was achieved through phoneme encodings. Although it performs well on accuracy, it shows poor results with MRR, possibly the reason as same as SVM performance.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.3">Ablation experiments</head><p>We experiment with the variables like length of substrings, ranking functions, shingling tech- niques, and graphical error model, which are de- tailed in the Table 1. Amongst the shingling tech- niques, we found that character bigrams with 2- ended positioning give better results. Adding tri- grams to the database does not give major effect on the results. The results clearly indicate that adding graphical error model features greatly im- prove the test results. Amongst the ranking func- tions, Dirichlet smoothing tends to give better re- sults, possibly due to the fact that it requires fewer parameters to tune and is able to capture the se- quential data (like substrings) better than other ranking functions <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Fang et al., 2011</ref>). The hy-</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: The process of positional tokenisation from both ends. On the left, algorithm segments the Romanian word romarin into the split-set {1r, 2ro, 3om, 4ma, ar4, ri3, in2, n1}. On the right, the algorithm segments rosmarin into {1r, 2ro, 3os, 4sm, 5ma, ar4, ri3, in2, n1}.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>1</head><label></label><figDesc>|G(S,T )| is the normalization factor to allow us to compare the quantity across different word pairs.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>Figure 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Figure 3: From the graph created in figure 2, we calculate the probabilities of each edge (by computing frequencies and smoothing) and then aggregate all the probabilities of edges in the graph.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><head>Figure 4 :</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Figure 4: After aggregating, we normalize the sum and the graph conversion score is outputted.</figDesc></figure>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgements</head><p>This work would not be possible without the sup-port from my parents. I would like to thank the NLP community for providing me open-sourced resources to help an underprivileged and naive stu-dent like me. Finally, I would like to thank the re-viewers, mentors, and organizers for ACL-SRW for supporting student research. Special thanks to my classmate Chun Sik Chan and SRW men-tor Sam Bowman for providing excellent critiques for this paper, and Alina Ciobanu for providing the dataset.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Conclusions</head><p>We approach towards the harder problem where the algorithm aims to find a target cognate when a source cognate is given. Positional shingling out- performed non-positional shingling based meth- ods, which demonstrates that inclusion of posi- tional information of substrings is rather impor- tant. Addition of graphical error model boosted the test results which shows that it is crucial to add dissimilarity information in order to capture the transformations of the substrings. Methods whose scoring functions rely only on complex machine learning algorithms like CNN or SVM tend to give worse results when searching for a cognate.</p></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Multiple word alignment with profile hidden markov models</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Aditya</forename><surname>Bhargava</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Grzegorz</forename><surname>Kondrak</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of Human Language Technologies: The 2009 Annual Conference of the North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics, Companion Volume: Student Research Workshop and Doctoral Consortium</title>
		<meeting>Human Language Technologies: The 2009 Annual Conference of the North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics, Companion Volume: Student Research Workshop and Doctoral Consortium</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="43" to="48" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Latent dirichlet allocation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Blei</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Andrew</forename><forename type="middle">Y</forename><surname>Ng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michael</forename><forename type="middle">I</forename><surname>Jordan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Mach. Learn. Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="993" to="1022" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Word-pair extraction for lexicography</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chris</forename><surname>Brew</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Mckelvie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Buccleuch</forename><surname>Place</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1996" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Automatic detection of cognates using orthographic alignment</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alina</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Maria</forename><surname>Ciobanu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Liviu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Dinu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ACL (2)</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="99" to="105" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Automatic discrimination between cognates and borrowings</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alina</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Maria</forename><surname>Ciobanu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Liviu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Dinu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 53rd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics and the 7th International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing</title>
		<meeting>the 53rd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics and the 7th International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="431" to="437" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Short Papers</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Diagnostic evaluation of information retrieval models</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hui</forename><surname>Fang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tao</forename><surname>Tao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chengxiang</forename><surname>Zhai</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">ACM Trans. Inf. Syst</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">29</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">42</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">s-grams: Defining generalized n-grams for information retrieval</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Anni</forename><surname>Järvelin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Antti</forename><surname>Järvelin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kalervo</forename><surname>Järvelin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Information Processing &amp; Management</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">43</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1005" to="1019" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A new algorithm for the alignment of phonetic sequences</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Grzegorz</forename><surname>Kondrak</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 1st North American chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics conference</title>
		<meeting>the 1st North American chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics conference</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="288" to="295" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Association for Computational Linguistics</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Lexstat: Automatic detection of cognates in multilingual wordlists</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Johann-Mattis</forename><surname>List</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the EACL 2012 Joint Workshop of LINGVIS &amp; UNCLH, EACL 2012</title>
		<meeting>the EACL 2012 Joint Workshop of LINGVIS &amp; UNCLH, EACL 2012<address><addrLine>Stroudsburg, PA, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="117" to="125" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Association for Computational Linguistics</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Lexstat: Automatic detection of cognates in multilingual wordlists</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Johann-Mattis</forename><surname>List</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the EACL 2012 Joint Workshop of LINGVIS &amp; UNCLH</title>
		<meeting>the EACL 2012 Joint Workshop of LINGVIS &amp; UNCLH</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="117" to="125" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">A conditional random field for discriminatively-trained finite-state string edit distance</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Andrew</forename><surname>Mccallum</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kedar</forename><surname>Bellare</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Fernando</forename><surname>Pereira</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:1207.1406</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
<note type="report_type">arXiv preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Bitext maps and alignment via pattern recognition</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dan</forename><surname>Melamed</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Comput. Linguist</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">25</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="107" to="130" />
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A phonetically based metric of sound similarity</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jeff</forename><surname>Mielke</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Lingua</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">122</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="145" to="163" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Multiple Biological Sequence Alignment: Scoring Functions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ken</forename><surname>Nguyen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Xuan</forename><surname>Guo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Pan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Algorithms and Applications</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Automatic cognate identification with gap-weighted string subsequences</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Taraka</forename><surname>Rama</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2015 Conference of the North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics: Human Language Technologies</title>
		<meeting>the 2015 Conference of the North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics: Human Language Technologies</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1227" to="1231" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Siamese convolutional networks based on phonetic features for cognate identification</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Taraka</forename><surname>Rama</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>abs/1605.05172</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
			<publisher>CoRR</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The probabilistic relevance framework: Bm25 and beyond</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Stephen</forename><surname>Robertson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hugo</forename><surname>Zaragoza</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Found. Trends Inf. Retr</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="333" to="389" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Interpreting tf-idf term weights as making relevance decisions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chung</forename><surname>Ho</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Robert</forename><surname>Wu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Wing Pong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kam</forename><forename type="middle">Fai</forename><surname>Luk</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kui Lam</forename><surname>Wong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Kwok</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">ACM Trans. Inf. Syst</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">37</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
