<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T10:19+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Retrieval of the Best Counterargument without Prior Topic Knowledge</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date>July 15-20, 2018</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Henning</forename><surname>Wachsmuth</surname></persName>
							<email>henningw@upb.de</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory">Bauhaus-Universität Weimar Faculty of Media, Webis Group</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Paderborn University Computational Social Science Group</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Shahbaz</forename><surname>Syed</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory">Bauhaus-Universität Weimar Faculty of Media, Webis Group</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Paderborn University Computational Social Science Group</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Benno</forename><surname>Stein</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory">Bauhaus-Universität Weimar Faculty of Media, Webis Group</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Paderborn University Computational Social Science Group</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Retrieval of the Best Counterargument without Prior Topic Knowledge</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 56th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (Long Papers)</title>
						<meeting>the 56th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (Long Papers) <address><addrLine>Melbourne, Australia</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="241" to="251"/>
							<date type="published">July 15-20, 2018</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<note>241</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Given any argument on any controversial topic, how to counter it? This question implies the challenging retrieval task of finding the best counterargument. Since prior knowledge of a topic cannot be expected in general, we hypothesize the best counterar-gument to invoke the same aspects as the argument while having the opposite stance. To operationalize our hypothesis, we simultaneously model the similarity and dissim-ilarity of pairs of arguments, based on the words and embeddings of the arguments&apos; premises and conclusions. A salient property of our model is its independence from the topic at hand, i.e., it applies to arbitrary arguments. We evaluate different model variations on millions of argument pairs derived from the web portal idebate.org. Systematic ranking experiments suggest that our hypothesis is true for many arguments: For 7.6 candidates with opposing stance on average, we rank the best counterargument highest with 60% accuracy. Even among all 2801 test set pairs as candidates, we still find the best one about every third time.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Many controversial topics in real life divide us into opposing camps, such as whether to ban guns, who should become president, or what phone to buy. When being confronted with arguments against our stance, but also when forming own arguments, we need to think about how they could best be coun- tered. Argumentation theory tells us that -aside from ad-hominem attacks -a counterargument denies either an argument's premises, its conclu- sion, or the reasoning between them ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">Walton, 2009)</ref>. Take the following argument in favor of the right to bear arms from the web portal idebate.org:</p><p>Argument "Gun ownership is an integral aspect of the right to self defence. (conclusion) Law-abiding citizens deserve the right to protect their families in their own homes, especially if the police are judged incapable of dealing with the threat of attack. <ref type="bibr">[...]</ref>" (premise) While the conclusion seems well-reasoned, the web portal directly provides a counter to the argument:</p><p>Counterargument "Burglary should not be pun- ished by vigilante killings of the offender. No amount of property is worth a human life. Per- versely, the danger of attack by homeowners may make it more likely that criminals will carry their own weapons. If a right to self-defence is granted in this way, many accidental deaths are bound to result. [...]"</p><p>As in this example, we observe that a counterargu- ment often takes on the aspects of the topic invoked by the argument, while adding a new perspective to its conclusion and/or premises, conveying the opposite stance. Research has tackled the stance of argument units <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Bar-Haim et al., 2017)</ref> as well as the attack relations between arguments <ref type="bibr">(Cabrio and Villata, 2012)</ref>. However, existing approaches learn the interplay of aspects and topics on training data or infer it from external knowledge bases (details in Section 2). This does not work for topics unseen before. Moreover, to our knowledge, no work so far aims at actual counterarguments. This paper studies the task of automatically find- ing the best counterargument to any argument. In the general case, we cannot expect prior knowledge of an argument's topic. Following the observation above, we thus just hypothesize the best counterar- gument to invoke the same aspects as the argument while having the opposite stance. <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref> sketches how we operationalize the hypothesis. In particular, we simultaneously model the topic similarity and stance dissimilarity of a candidate counterargument ~ argument counterargument simultaneous similarity and dissimilarity similarity to conclusion similarity to premises topic similarity stance similarity (e.g., max) (e.g., sum)</p><p>Figure 1: Modeling the simultaneous similarity and dissimilarity of a counterargument to an argument.</p><p>to the argument. Both are inferred -in different ways -from the similarities to the argument's con- clusion and premises, since it is unclear in advance, whether either of these units or the reasoning be- tween them is countered. Thereby, we find the most dissimilar among the most similar arguments.</p><p>To study counteraguments, we provide a new corpus with 6753 argument-counterargument pairs, taken from 1069 debates on idebate.org, as well as millions of false pairs derived from them. Given the corpus, we define eight retrieval tasks that differ in the types of candidate counterarguments. Based on the words and embeddings of the arguments, we de- velop similarity functions that realize the outlined model as a ranking approach. In systematic experi- ments, we evaluate the different building blocks of our model on all defined tasks.</p><p>The results suggest that our hypothesis is true for many arguments. The best model configuration improves common word and embedding similarity measures by eight to ten points accuracy in all tasks. Inter alia, we rank 60.3% of the best counterargu- ments highest when given all arguments with op- posite stance (7.6 on average). Even with all 2801 test arguments as candidates, we still achieve 32.4% (and a mean rank of 15), fitting the intuition that off- topic arguments are easier to discard. Our analysis reveals notable gaps across topical themes though.</p><p>Contributions We believe that our findings will be important for applications such as automatic debating technologies ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Rinott et al., 2015</ref>) and ar- gument search ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Wachsmuth et al., 2017b</ref>). To sum- marize, our main contributions are:</p><p>• A large corpus for studying multiple counter- argument retrieval tasks (Sections 3 and 4).</p><p>• A topic-independent approach to find the best counterargument to any argument (Section 5).</p><p>• Evidence that many counterarguments can be found without topic knowledge (Section 6).</p><p>The corpus as well as the Java source code for reproducing the experiments are available at http: //www.arguana.com.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Related Work</head><p>Counterarguments rebut arguments. In the theoreti- cal model of <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">Toulmin (1958)</ref>, a rebuttal in fact does not attack the argument, but it merely shows excep- tions to the argument's reasoning. <ref type="bibr">Govier (2010)</ref> suggests to rather speak of counterconsiderations in such cases. Unlike <ref type="bibr">Damer (2009)</ref>, who investi- gates how to attack several kinds of fallacies, we are interested in how to identify attacks. We focus on those that target arguments, excluding personal (ad-hominem) attacks ( <ref type="bibr">Habernal et al., 2018)</ref>.</p><p>Following <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Walton (2006)</ref>, an argument can be attacked in two ways: one is to question its validity -not meaning that its conclusion must be wrong. The other is to rebut it with a counterargument that entails the opposite conclusion, often by revisiting aspects or introducing new ones. This is the type of attack we study. As Walton (2009) details, rebuttals may target an argument's premises or conclusion, or they may undercut the reasoning between them.</p><p>Recently, the computational analysis of natural language argumentation is receiving much atten- tion. Most research focuses on argument mining, ranging from segmenting a text into argument units <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Ajjour et al., 2017)</ref>, over identifying unit types ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Rinott et al., 2015</ref>) and roles ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Niculae et al., 2017)</ref>, to classifying argument schemes <ref type="bibr">(Feng and Hirst, 2011</ref>) and relations <ref type="bibr">(Lawrence and Reed, 2017)</ref>. Some works detect counterconsiderations in a text ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Peldszus and Stede, 2015)</ref> or their absence <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(Stab and Gurevych, 2016)</ref>. Such considerations make arguments more balanced (see above). In contrast, we seek for arguments that defeat others.</p><p>Many approaches mine attack relations between arguments. Some use deep learning to find attacks in discussions ( <ref type="bibr">Cocarascu and Toni, 2017</ref>). Closer to this paper, others determine them in a given set of arguments, using textual entailment <ref type="bibr">(Cabrio and Villata, 2012</ref>) or a combination of markov logic and stance classification ( <ref type="bibr">Hou and Jochim, 2017)</ref>. In principle, any attacking argument denotes a coun- terargument. Unlike previous work, however, we aim for the best counterargument to an argument.</p><p>Classifying the stance of a text towards a topic (pro or con) generally defines an alternative way of addressing counterarguments. <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Sobhani et al. (2015)</ref> specifically classify health-related arguments using supervised learning, while we do not expect to have prior topic knowledge. <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Bar-Haim et al. (2017)</ref> ap- proach the stance of claims towards open-domain topics. Their approach combines aspect-based sen- timent with external relations between aspects and topics from Wikipedia. As such, it is in fact limited to the topics covered there. Our model applies to arbitrary arguments and counterarguments.</p><p>We need to identify only whether arguments op- pose each other, not their actual stance. Similarly, <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Menini et al. (2017)</ref> classify only the disagreement of political texts. Part of their approach is to de- tect topical key aspects in an unsupervised manner, which seems useful for our purposes. Analogously, Beigman <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Klebanov et al. (2010)</ref> study differences in vocabulary choice for the related task of per- spective classification, and <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Tan et al. (2016)</ref> find that the best way to persuade opinion holders in the Change my view forum on reddit.com is to use dissimilar words. As we report later, however, our experiments did not show such results for the argument-counterargument pairs we deal with.</p><p>The goal of persuasion reveals the association of counterarguments to argumentation quality. Many quality criteria have been assessed for arguments, surveyed in ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">Wachsmuth et al., 2017a</ref>). In the study of <ref type="bibr">Habernal and Gurevych (2016)</ref>, one reason an- notators gave for why an argument was more con- vincing than another was that it tackled flaws in the opposing view. <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Zhang et al. (2016)</ref> even found that debate winners tend to counter opposing arguments rather than focusing on their own arguments.</p><p>Argument quality assessment is particularly im- portant in retrieval scenarios. Existing approaches aim to retrieve documents that contain many claims <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(Roitman et al., 2016)</ref> or that provide most sup- port for their claims <ref type="bibr">(Braunstain et al., 2016)</ref>. In <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">Wachsmuth et al. (2017c)</ref>, we adapt PageRank to ar- gumentative relations, in order to assess argument relevance objectively. While our search engine args for arguments on the web still uses content-based relevance measures in its first version ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Wachsmuth et al., 2017b</ref>), its long-term idea is to rank the best arguments highest. <ref type="bibr">1</ref> The model present in this work finds the best counterarguments, but it is meant to be integrated into args at some point.</p><p>Like here, args uses idebate.org arguments. Oth- ers take data from that portal for studying support <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Boltuži´cBoltuži´c and Šnajder, 2014</ref>) or for the distant su- pervision of argument mining (Al-Khatib et al.,</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">The ArguAna Counterargs Corpus</head><p>This section introduces our ArguAna Counterargs corpus with argument-counterargument pairs, cre- ated automatically from the structure of idebate.org. The corpus is freely available at http://www. arguana.com/data. We also provide the code to replicate the construction process.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">The Web Portal idebate.org</head><p>On the portal idebate.org, diverse controversial top- ics of usually rather general interest are discussed in debates, subsumed under 15 themes, such as "economy" and "health". Each debate has a title capturing a thesis on a topic, such as "This House would limit the right to bear arms", followed by an introductory text, a set of mostly elaborated and well-written points that have a pro or a con stance towards the thesis, and a bibliography.</p><p>A specific feature of idebate.org is that virtually every point comes along with a counter that imme- diately attacks the point and its stance. Both points and counters can be seen as arguments. While a point consists of a one-sentence claim (the argu- ment's conclusion) and a few sentences justifying the claim (the premise(s)), the counter's (opposite) conclusion remains implicit.</p><p>All arguments on the portal are established by a community with the goal of showing both sides of a topic in a balanced manner. We therefore as- sume each counter to be the best counterargument available for the respective point, and we use all resulting true argument pairs as the basis of our corpus. <ref type="figure">Figure 2</ref> illustrates the italicized concepts, showing the structure of idebate.org. An example argument pair has been discussed in Section 1.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Corpus Construction</head><p>We crawled all debates from idebate.org that fol- low the portal's theme-guided folder structure (last access: January 30, 2018). From each debate, we extracted the thesis, the introductory text, all points and counters, the bibliography, and some metadata. Each was stored separately in one plain text file, and we also created a file with the entire debate in its original order. Only points and counters are used in our experiments in Section 6. The underlying experiment settings are described in Section 4.  </p><formula xml:id="formula_0">(conclusion implicit) (a) (b) (c) (e) (d) (f) (h) (g) (i) true argument pair ... ... ... ...</formula><p>Figure 2: Structure of idebate.org for one true argument pair in our corpus. Colors denote matching stance; we assume arguments from other debates to have no stance towards a point. Points have a conclusion and premises, counters only premises. (a)-(i) are used in Section 4 to specify the candidates in different tasks.  <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>: Distribution of debates, points, and coun- ters over the themes in the counterargs-18 corpus. The bottom rows show the size of the datasets. <ref type="table">Table 1</ref> lists the number of debates crawled for each theme, along with the numbers of points and coun- ters in the debates. The 26 found points without a counter are included in the corpus, but we do not use them in our experiments. In total, the ArguAna Counterargs corpus con- sists of 1069 debates with 6753 points that have a counter. The mean length of points is 196.3 words, whereas counters span only 129.6 words, largely due to the missing explicit conclusion. To avoid exploiting this corpus bias, no approach in our ex- periments captures length differences.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3">Corpus Statistics</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.4">Datasets</head><p>We split the corpus into a training set, consisting of the first 60% of all debates of each theme (ordered by alphabet), as well as a validation set and a test set, each covering 20%. The dataset sizes are found at the bottom of <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>. By putting all arguments from a debate into a single dataset, no specific topic knowledge can be gained from the training or validation set. We include all themes in all datasets, because we expect the set of themes to be stable.</p><p>We checked for duplicates. Among the 13 532 point and counters, 3407 appear twice, 723 three times, 36 four times, and 1 five times. We ensure that no true pair is used as a false pair in our tasks.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Counterargument Retrieval Tasks</head><p>Based on the new corpus, we define the following eight counterargument retrieval tasks of different complexity. All tasks consider all true argument- counterargument pairs, while differing in terms of what arguments (points and/or counters) from which context (same debate, same theme, or entire portal) are candidates for a given argument.</p><p>Same Debate: Opposing Counters All coun- ters in the same debate with stance opposite to the given argument are candidates <ref type="figure">(Figure 2: a, b)</ref>. The task is to find the best counterargument among all counters to the argument's stance.</p><p>Same Debate: Counters All counters in the same debate irrespective of their stance are can- didates <ref type="figure">(Figure 2</ref>: a-c). The task is to find the best counterargument among all on-topic arguments phrased as counters.  <ref type="table">Table 2</ref>: Number of true and false argument-counterargument pairs as well as their ratio for each evaluated context and type of candidate counterarguments in the three datasets. Each line defines one retrieval task.</p><p>Same Debate: Opposing Arguments All argu- ments in the same debate with opposite stance are candidates <ref type="figure">(Figure 2: a, b, d</ref>). The task is to find the best among all on-topic counterarguments.</p><p>Same Debate: Arguments All arguments in the same debate irrespective of their stance are candi- dates ( <ref type="figure">Figure 2</ref>: a-e). The task is to find the best counterargument among all on-topic arguments.</p><p>Same Theme: Counters All counters from the same theme are candidates <ref type="figure">(Figure 2</ref>: a-c, f). The task is to find the best counterargument among all on-theme arguments phrased as counters.</p><p>Same Theme: Arguments All arguments from the same theme are candidates <ref type="figure">(Figure 2</ref>: a-g). The task is to find the best counterargument among all on-theme arguments.</p><p>Entire Portal: Counters All counters are candi- dates <ref type="figure">(Figure 2</ref>: a-c, f, h). The task is to find the best counterargument among all arguments phrased as counters.</p><p>Entire Portal: Arguments All arguments are candidates <ref type="figure">(Figure 2</ref>: a-i). The task is to find the best counterargument among all arguments. <ref type="table">Table 2</ref> lists the numbers of true and false pairs for each task. Experiment files containing the file paths of all candidate pairs are provided in our corpus.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Retrieval of the Best Counterargument without Prior Topic Knowledge</head><p>The eight defined tasks indicate the subproblems of retrieving the best counterargument to a given argument: Finding all arguments that address the same topic, filtering those arguments with an oppo- site stance towards the topic, and identifying the best counter among these arguments. This section presents our approach to solving these problems computationally without prior knowledge of the argument's topic, based on the simultaneous simi- larity and dissimilarity of arguments. <ref type="bibr">2</ref> </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.1">Topic as Word and Embedding Similarity</head><p>We do not reinvent the wheel to assess topical rel- evance, but rather follow common practice. Con- cretely, we hypothesize a candidate counterargu- ment to be on-topic if it is similar to the argument in terms of its words and its embedding. We capture these two types of similarity as follows.</p><p>Word Argument Similarity To best represent the words in arguments, we did initial counterargu- ment retrieval tests with token, stem, and lemma n-grams, n ∈ {1, 2, 3}. While the differences were not large, stems worked best and stem 1-grams suf- ficed. Both might be a consequence of the limited data size. In our experiments in Section 6, we de- termine the stem 1-grams to be considered on the training set of each task. For word similarity computation, we tested four inverse vector-based distance measures: Cosine, Euclidean, Manhattan, and, Jaccard similarity <ref type="bibr">(Cha, 2007)</ref>. On the validation sets, the Manhattan sim- ilarity performed best, closely followed by the Jaccard similarity. Both clearly outperformed Eu- clidean and especially Cosine similarity. This sug- gests that the presence and absence of words are equally important and that outliers should not be punished more. For brevity, we report only results for the Manhattan similarity below.</p><p>Embedding Argument Similarity We evalu- ated five pretrained word embedding models for representing arguments in first tests: GoogleNews- vectors ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">Mikolov et al., 2013)</ref>, ConceptNet Num- berbatch ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Speer et al., 2017)</ref>, wiki-news-300d-1M, wiki-news-300d-1M-subword, and crawl-300d-2M ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Mikolov et al., 2017</ref>). The former two were com- petitive, the others performed notably worse. Since ConceptNet Numberbatch is smaller and supposed to have less bias, we used it in all experiments.</p><p>To capture argument-level embedding similar- ity, we compared the four inverse vector-based dis- tance measures above on average word embeddings against the inverse Word Mover's distance, which quantifies the optimum alignment of two word em- bedding sequences ( <ref type="bibr">Kusner et al., 2015)</ref>. This Word Mover's similarity consistently beat the others, so we decided to restrict our view to it.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.2">Stance as Topic Dissimilarity</head><p>Stance classification without prior topic knowledge is challenging: While we can compare the topics of any two arguments, it is impossible in general to infer the stance of the specific aspects invoked by one argument to those of the other. As sketched in Section 2, related work employs external knowl- edge to infer stance relations of aspects and topics ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Bar-Haim et al., 2017</ref>) or trains classifying attack relations <ref type="bibr">(Cabrio and Villata, 2012)</ref>. Unfortunately, both does not apply to topics unseen before.</p><p>For argument pairs invoking similar aspects, a way to go is in principle to assess sentiment polar- ity; intuitively, two arguments with the same topic but opposite sentiment have opposing stance. How- ever, we tested topic-agnostic sentiment lexicons ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Baccianella et al., 2010)</ref> and state-of-the-art sen- timent classifiers, trained on large-scale multiple- domain review data <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(Prettenhofer and Stein, 2010;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Joulin et al., 2017</ref>). The correlation between senti- ment and stance differences of training arguments was close to zero. A possible explanation is the lim- ited explicitness of sentiment on idebate.org, mak- ing the lexicons and classifiers fail there.</p><p>Other related work suggests that the vocabulary of opposing sides differs <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Beigman Klebanov et al., 2010</ref>). We thus checked on the training set whether counterarguments are similar in their embeddings but dissimilar in their words. The measures above did not support this hypothesis, i.e., both embed- ding and word similarity increased the likelihood of a candidate counterargument being the best. Still, there must be a difference between an argument and its counterargument by concept. As a solution, we capture dissimilarity with the same similarity functions as above, but we change the granularity level on which we measure similarity.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.3">Simultaneous Similarity and Dissimilarity</head><p>The arising question is how to assess similarity and dissimilarity at the same time. We hypothesize the best counterargument to be very similar in overall terms, but very dissimilar in certain respects. To capture this intuition, we rely on expert knowledge from argumentation theory (see Section 2).</p><p>Word and Embedding Unit Similarities In par- ticular, we follow the notion that a counterargument attacks either the conclusion of an argument, the ar- gument's premises, or both. As a consequence, we compute two word and two embedding similarities as specified above for each candidate counterargu- ment; once to the argument's conclusion (called w c and e c for words and embeddings respectively) and once to the argument's premises (w p and e p ). Now, to capture similarity and dissimilarity si- multaneously, we need multiple ways to aggregate conclusion and premise similarities. As we do not generally know which argument unit is attacked, we resort to four standard aggregation functions that generalize over the unit similarities. For words, these are the following word unit similarities:</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">w ↓ := min{w c , w p } w × := w c · w p w ↑ := max{w c , w p } w + := w c + w p</formula><p>Accordingly, we define four respective embedding unit similarities, e ↓ , e ↑ , e × , and e + . As mentioned above, both word similarity and embedding similarity positively affect the likeli- hood that a candidate is the best counterargument. Therefore, we combine each pair of similarities as w ↓ + e ↓ , w ↑ + e ↑ , w × + e × , and w + + e + , but we also evaluate their impact in isolation below. <ref type="bibr">3</ref> Counterargument Scoring Model Based on the unit similarities, we finally define a scoring model for a given pair of argument and candidate counterargument. The model includes two unit similarity values, sim and dissim, but dissim is subtracted from sim, such that it actually favors dissimilarity. Thereby, we realize the topic and stance similarity sketched in <ref type="figure">Figure 1</ref>. We weight the two values with a damping factor α:</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">α · sim − (1 − α) · dissim</formula><p>where sim, dissim ∈ {w ↓ +e ↓ , w ↑ +e ↑ , w × +e × , w + + e + } and sim = dissim.</p><p>The general idea of the scoring model is that sim rewards one type of similarity, whereas sub- tracting dissim punishes another type. We seek to thereby find the most dissimilar candidate among the similar candidates. The model is meant to give a higher score to a pair the more likely the candi- date is the best counterargument to the argument, so the scores can be used for ranking.</p><p>What combination of sim and dissim turns out best, is hard to foresee and may depend on the retrieval task at hand. We hence evaluate different combinations empirically below. The same holds for the damping factor α ∈ <ref type="bibr">[0,</ref><ref type="bibr">1]</ref>. If our hypothesis on similarity and dissimilarity is true, then the best α should be close to but lower than 1. Conversely, if α = 1.0 achieves the best performance, then only similarity would be captured by our model.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Evaluation</head><p>We now report on systematic ranking experiments with our counterargument scoring model. The goal is to evaluate on all eight retrieval tasks from Sec- tion 4 to what extent our hypothesis holds that the best counterargument to an argument invokes the same aspects while having opposing stance. The Java source code of the experiments is available at: http://www.arguana.com/software</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.1">Experimental Set-up</head><p>We evaluated the following set-up of tasks, data, measures, baselines, and approaches.</p><p>Tasks We tackled each of the eight retrieval tasks as a ranking problem, i.e., we aimed to rank the best counterargument to each argument highest, given all candidates. Accordingly, only one candidate counterargument per argument is correct. 4 <ref type="bibr">4</ref> One alternative would be to see each argument pair as one instance of a classification problem. However, our pre- liminary tests confirmed the intuition that identifying the best counterargument is hard without knowing the other candidates, i.e., there is no general (dis)similarity threshold that makes an argument the best counterargument. Rather, how similar or dissimilar a counterargument needs to be depends on the topic and on the other candidates. Another alternative would be to treat all candidates for an argument as one instance, but this makes the experimental set-up very intricated. <ref type="table">Table 2</ref> has shown the true and false argu- ment pairs in all datasets. We undersampled each training set, resulting in 4065 true and 4065 false training pairs in all tasks. <ref type="bibr">5</ref> Our model does not do any learning-to-rank on these pairs, but we derived lexicons for the word similarities from them (all stems included in at least 1% of all pairs). As de- tailed below, we then determined the best model configurations on the validation sets and evaluated these configurations on the test sets.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Data</head><p>Measures As only one candidate is true per argu- ment, we report the accuracy@1 of each approach, i.e., the percentage of arguments for which the true counterargument was ranked highest. Besides, we compute the rounded mean rank of the best coun- terargument in all rankings, reflecting the average performance of an approach. Exemplarily, we also mention the mean reciprocal rank (MRR), which is more sensitive to outliers.</p><p>Baselines A trivial way to address the given tasks is to pick any candidate by chance for each argu- ment. This random baseline allows quantifying the impact of other approaches. As counterargument retrieval has not been tackled yet, we do not use any existing baseline. <ref type="bibr">6</ref> Instead, we evaluate the ef- fects of the different building blocks of our scoring model. On one hand, we check the need for distin- guishing conclusions and premises by comparing to the word argument similarity (w) and the embed- ding argument similarity (e). On the other hand, we consider all eight word and embedding unit sim- ilarities (w ↓ , w ↑ , . . . , e + ) as baselines, in order to see whether and how to best aggregate them.</p><p>Approaches After initial tests, we reduced the set of tested values of the damping factor α in our scoring model to {0.8, 0.9, 1.0}. On the validation sets of the first six tasks, <ref type="bibr">7</ref> we then analyzed all possible combinations of w ↓ +e ↓ , w ↑ +e ↑ , w × +e × , w + + e + , as well as w + e for sim and dissim. Three configurations of the model turned out best:</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">we := 1.0 · (w × + e × ) we ↓ := 0.9 · (w × + e × ) − 0.1 · (w ↓ + e ↓ ) we ↑ := 0.9 · (w + + e + ) − 0.1 · (w ↑ + e ↑ ) Same</formula><note type="other">Debate Same Theme Entire Portal</note></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Opp. Ctr.'s Counters Opposing Arguments Counters Arguments Counters Arguments</head><p># Baseline / Approach @1 R @1 R @1 R @1 R @1 R @1 R @1 R @1 R   <ref type="table">Table 3</ref>: Test set accuracy of ranking the best counterargument highest (@1) and mean rank (R) for 14 baselines and approaches (w, e, w ↓ , . . . , r) in all eight tasks (given by Context and Candidates). Each best accuracy value (bold) significantly outperforms the best baseline with 99% ( †) or 99.9% ( ‡) confidence.</p><p>we was best on the validation set of Same Debate: Opposing Arguments (accuracy@1: 62.1) and we ↓ on the one of Same Debate: Arguments (49.0). All other tasks were dominated by we ↑ . Especially, we ↑ was better than 1.0 · (w + + e + ) in all of them with clear leads of up to 2.2 points. This underlines the importance of modeling dissimilarity for coun- terargument retrieval. We took we, we ↓ , and we ↑ as our approaches for the test set. 8 <ref type="table">Table 3</ref> shows the accuracy@1 and the mean rank of all baselines and approaches on each of the eight given retrieval tasks. Overall, the counter-only tasks seem slightly harder within the same debate (comparing Coun- ters to Opposing), i.e., stance is harder to assess than topical relevance. Conversely, the other Coun- ters tasks seem easier, suggesting that topically close but false candidate counterarguments with the same stance as the argument (which are not in- cluded in any Counters task) are classified wrongly most often. Besides, these results support that po- tential differences in the phrasing of counters are not exploited, as desired.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.2">Results</head><p>The accuracy of the standard similarity measures, w and e, goes from 65.9 and 62.9 respectively in the smallest task down to 21.8 and 23.9 in the largest.</p><p>w is stronger when only counters are candidates, e otherwise. This implies that words capture differ- ences between the best and other counters, whereas embeddings rather help discard false candidates with the same stance as the argument.</p><p>From the eight unit similarity baselines, w + per- forms best on five tasks (e × twice, w × once). w + finds 71.5% true counterarguments among all op- posing counters in a debate, and 28.6% among all test arguments from the entire portal. In that task, however, the mean ranks of w + (33) and particu- larly of w × (354) are much worse than for e × (21), meaning that words are insufficient to robustly find counterarguments.</p><p>we, we ↓ , and we ↑ outperform all baselines in all tasks, improving the accuracy by 8.1 (Same Theme: Arguments) to 10.3 points (Entire Portal: Counters) over w and e, and at least 3.0 over the best baseline in each task. Among all opposing arguments from the same debate (true-to-false ratio 1:6.6), we finds 60.3% of the best counterarguments, 44.9% when all arguments are given (1:13.3).</p><p>The winner in our evaluation is we ↑ , though, being best in five of the eight tasks. It found the true among all opposing counters in 74.5% of all cases, and about every third time (32.4) among all 2801 test set arguments; a setting where the random baseline has virtually no chance. Given all arguments from the same theme, we ↑ puts the best counterargument at a mean rank of 5 (MRR 0.58), and for the entire portal still at 15 (MRR 0.5).  Although our scoring model thus does not solve the retrieval tasks, we conclude that it serves as a robust approach to rank the best counterargument high.</p><p>To test significance, we separately computed the accuracy@1 for the arguments from each theme. The differences between the 15 values of the best approach on each task and those of the best baseline (w + , w × , or e × ) were normally distributed. Since the baselines and approaches are dependent, we used a one-tailed dependent t-test with paired sam- ples. As <ref type="table">Table 3</ref> specifies, our approaches are con- sistently better, partly with at least 99% confidence, partly even with 99.9% confidence.</p><p>In <ref type="table" target="#tab_5">Table 4</ref>, we exemplarily detail the compari- son of the best approach (we ↑ ) to the best baseline (w + ) on Entire Portal: Arguments. The mean ranks across themes underline the robustness of we ↑ , be- ing in the top 10 for 7 and in the top 20 even for 13 themes. Still, the accuracy@1 of both w + and we ↑ varies notably, in case of we ↑ from 12.1 for free speech debate to 46.7 for sport. For free speech debates (e.g., "This House would criminalise blas- phemy"), we observed that their arguments tend to be overproportionally long, which might lead to deviating similarities. In case of sports, the topical specificity (e.g., "This House would ban boxing") reduces the probability of mistakenly choosing can- didates from other themes.</p><p>Free speech debate turned out the hardest theme in seven tasks, health in the remaining one. Besides sports, in some tasks the best results were obtained for religion and science, both of which share the characteristic of dealing with very specific topics. <ref type="bibr">9</ref> </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7">Conclusion</head><p>This paper has asked how to find the best counterar- gument to any argument without prior knowledge of the argument's topic. We did not aim to engineer the best approach to this retrieval task, but to study whether we can model the simultaneous similarity and dissimilarity of a counterargument to an argu- ment computationally. For the restricted domain of debate portal arguments, our main result is quite intriguing: The best model (we ↑ ) rewards a high overall similarity to the argument's conclusion and premises while punishing a too high similarity to either of them. Despite its simplicity, we ↑ found the best counterargument among 2801 candidates in almost a third of all cases, and ranked it into the top 15 on average. This speaks for our hypothesis that the best counterargument often just addresses the same topical aspects with opposite stance.</p><p>Of course, our hypothesis is simplifying, i.e., there are counterarguments that will not be found based on aspect and stance similarity only. Apart from some hyperparameters, however, our model is unsupervised and it does not make any assump- tion about an argument's topic. Hence, it applies to any argument, given a pool of candidate coun- terarguments. While the model can be considered open-topic, a next step will be to study counterar- gument retrieval open-source.</p><p>We are confident that the modeled intuition gen- eralizes beyond idebate.org. To obtain further in- sights into the nature of counterarguments, deeper linguistic analysis along with supervised learning may be needed, though. We provide a corpus to train respective approaches, but leave the according research to future work.</p><p>The intended practical application of our model is to retrieve counterarguments in automatic debat- ing technologies ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Rinott et al., 2015</ref>) and argument search ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Wachsmuth et al., 2017b</ref>). While debate portal arguments are often suitable in this regard, in general not always a real counterargument exists to an argument. Still, returning one that addresses similar aspects with opposite stance makes sense then. An alternative would be to generate counter- arguments, but we believe that humans are better than machines in writing them -currently. </p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>↓ 0 .</head><label>0</label><figDesc>9·(w× +e×) −0.1·(w ↓ +e ↓ ) 72.0 1 55.5 2 59.5 2 44.1 3 51.3 4 †41.0 7 46.3 19 31.7 35 we ↑ 0.9·(w+ +e+) −0.1·(w ↑ +e ↑ ) †74.5 1 †57.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4" validated="false"><head>Entire Portal: Arguments Accuracy@1 Mean Rank</head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Theme 
Arguments 
w+ we ↑ 
w+ we ↑ 

Culture 
69 
31.9 36.2 
12 
9 
Digital freedoms 
61 
37.7 44.3 
58 
20 
Economy 
125 
27.2 25.6 
21 
10 
Education 
81 
38.3 39.5 
36 
17 
Environment 
46 
17.4 21.7 
22 
7 

Free speech debate 
58 
10.3 12.1 
130 
55 
Health 
77 
28.6 36.4 
26 
14 
International 
271 
25.8 31.4 
31 
19 
Law 
134 
38.8 38.1 
16 
8 
Philosophy 
85 
34.1 38.8 
29 
14 

Politics 
202 
28.7 33.2 
28 
11 
Religion 
45 
24.4 33.3 
58 
8 
Science 
57 
19.3 28.1 
6 
5 
Society 
60 
16.7 20.0 
45 
22 
Sport 
30 
43.3 46.7 
35 
9 

All themes 
1401 
28.6 32.4 
33 
15 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_5" validated="false"><head>Table 4 :</head><label>4</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Accuracy@1 and mean rank of the best 
baseline (w + ) and approach (we ↑ ) on each theme 
when all 2801 test set arguments are candidates. 

</table></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> Argument search engine args: http://args.me 2016). Our corpus is not only larger, though, but it is the first to utilize a unique feature of idebate.org: the explicit specification of counterarguments.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="2"> As indicated above, counters on idebate.org (including all true counterarguments) may also differ linguistically from points (all of which are false). However, we assume this to be a specific corpus bias and hence do not explicitly account for it. Section 6 will show whether having both points and counters as candidates makes counterargument retrieval harder.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="3"> In principle, other unit similarities could be used for words than for embeddings. However, we decided to couple them to maintain interpretability of our experiment results.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="5"> Undersampling was done stratified, such that the same number of false counterarguments was taken from each type, b-i, in Figure 2 that is relevant in the respective task. 6 Notice, though, that we tested a number of approaches to identify opposing stance, as discussed in Section 5. 7 We did not expect &quot;game-changing&quot; validation set results for the last two tasks and, so, left them out for time reasons.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="8"> All validation set results are found in the supplementary material, which we provide at http://www.arguana. com/publications</note>

			<note place="foot" n="9"> The individual results of the best approach and baseline on each theme are also found in the supplementary material.</note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Unit segmentation of argumentative texts</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yamen</forename><surname>Ajjour</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wei-Fan</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Johannes</forename><surname>Kiesel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Henning</forename><surname>Wachsmuth</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Benno</forename><surname>Stein</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 4th Workshop on Argument Mining</title>
		<meeting>the 4th Workshop on Argument Mining</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="118" to="128" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Crossdomain mining of argumentative text through distant supervision</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Khalid</forename><surname>Al-Khatib</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Henning</forename><surname>Wachsmuth</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Matthias</forename><surname>Hagen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jonas</forename><surname>Köhler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Benno</forename><surname>Stein</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2016 Conference of the North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics: Human Language Technologies</title>
		<meeting>the 2016 Conference of the North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics: Human Language Technologies</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1395" to="1404" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">SentiWordNet 3.0: An enhanced lexical resource for sentiment analysis and opinion mining</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Stefano</forename><surname>Baccianella</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Andrea</forename><surname>Esuli</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Fabrizio</forename><surname>Sebastiani</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Seventh conference on International Language Resources and Evaluation (LREC&apos;10). European Languages Resources Association (ELRA)</title>
		<meeting>the Seventh conference on International Language Resources and Evaluation (LREC&apos;10). European Languages Resources Association (ELRA)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Stance classification of context-dependent claims</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Roy</forename><surname>Bar-Haim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Indrajit</forename><surname>Bhattacharya</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Francesco</forename><surname>Dinuzzo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Amrita</forename><surname>Saha</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Noam</forename><surname>Slonim</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 15th Conference of the European Chapter</title>
		<meeting>the 15th Conference of the European Chapter</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="251" to="261" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Long Papers</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Vocabulary choice as an indicator of perspective</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Eyal</forename><surname>Beata Beigman Klebanov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Daniel</forename><surname>Beigman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Diermeier</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the ACL 2010 Conference Short Papers</title>
		<meeting>the ACL 2010 Conference Short Papers</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="253" to="257" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Association for Computational Linguistics</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Back up your stance: Recognizing arguments in online discussions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Filip</forename><surname>Boltuži´cboltuži´c</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jan</forename><surname>Šnajder</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the First Workshop on Argumentation Mining</title>
		<meeting>the First Workshop on Argumentation Mining</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="49" to="58" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Topic-based agreement and disagreement in us electoral manifestos</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Stefano</forename><surname>Menini</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Federico</forename><surname>Nanni</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Simone</forename><forename type="middle">Paolo</forename><surname>Ponzetto</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sara</forename><surname>Tonelli</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2017 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</title>
		<meeting>the 2017 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2938" to="2944" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Association for Computational Linguistics</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Advances in pre-training distributed word representations</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tomas</forename><surname>Mikolov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Edouard</forename><surname>Grave</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Piotr</forename><surname>Bojanowski</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christian</forename><surname>Puhrsch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Armand</forename><surname>Joulin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
			<publisher>CoRR</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Distributed representations of words and phrases and their compositionality</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tomas</forename><surname>Mikolov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ilya</forename><surname>Sutskever</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kai</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Greg</forename><surname>Corrado</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jeffrey</forename><surname>Dean</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 26th International Conference on Neural Information Processing Systems</title>
		<meeting>the 26th International Conference on Neural Information Processing Systems</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3111" to="3119" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Argument mining with structured SVMs and RNNs</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Vlad</forename><surname>Niculae</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Joonsuk</forename><surname>Park</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Claire</forename><surname>Cardie</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 55th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the 55th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="985" to="995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Long Papers). Association for Computational Linguistics</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Towards detecting counter-considerations in text</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Andreas</forename><surname>Peldszus</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Manfred</forename><surname>Stede</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2nd Workshop on Argumentation Mining</title>
		<meeting>the 2nd Workshop on Argumentation Mining</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="104" to="109" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Association for Computational Linguistics</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Crosslanguage text classification using structural correspondence learning</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Peter</forename><surname>Prettenhofer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Benno</forename><surname>Stein</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 48th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the 48th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1118" to="1127" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Association for Computational Linguistics</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Show me your evidence-An automatic method for context dependent evidence detection</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ruty</forename><surname>Rinott</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lena</forename><surname>Dankin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Carlos</forename><forename type="middle">Alzate</forename><surname>Perez</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">Mitesh</forename><surname>Khapra</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ehud</forename><surname>Aharoni</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Noam</forename><surname>Slonim</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2015 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</title>
		<meeting>the 2015 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="440" to="450" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Association for Computational Linguistics</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">On the retrieval of wikipedia articles containing claims on controversial topics</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Shay</forename><surname>Haggai Roitman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ella</forename><surname>Hummel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Benjamin</forename><surname>Rabinovich</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Noam</forename><surname>Sznajder</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ehud</forename><surname>Slonim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Aharoni</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 25th International Conference on World Wide Web, Companion Volume</title>
		<meeting>the 25th International Conference on World Wide Web, Companion Volume</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="991" to="996" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">From argumentation mining to stance classification</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Parinaz</forename><surname>Sobhani</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Diana</forename><surname>Inkpen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Stan</forename><surname>Matwin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2nd Workshop on Argumentation Mining</title>
		<meeting>the 2nd Workshop on Argumentation Mining</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="67" to="77" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Conceptnet 5.5: An open multilingual graph of general knowledge</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Robert</forename><surname>Speer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Joshua</forename><surname>Chin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Catherine</forename><surname>Havasi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Thirty-First AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence</title>
		<meeting>the Thirty-First AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="4444" to="4451" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Recognizing the absence of opposing arguments in persuasive essays</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christian</forename><surname>Stab</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Iryna</forename><surname>Gurevych</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Third Workshop on Argument Mining (ArgMining2016)</title>
		<meeting>the Third Workshop on Argument Mining (ArgMining2016)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="113" to="118" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Winning arguments: Interaction dynamics and persuasion strategies in good-faith online discussions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chenhao</forename><surname>Tan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Vlad</forename><surname>Niculae</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Cristian</forename><surname>Danescuniculescu-Mizil</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lillian</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 25th International World Wide Web Conference</title>
		<meeting>the 25th International World Wide Web Conference</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="613" to="624" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The Uses of Argument</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Stephen</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Toulmin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1958" />
			<publisher>Cambridge University Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Computational argumentation quality assessment in natural language</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Henning</forename><surname>Wachsmuth</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nona</forename><surname>Naderi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yufang</forename><surname>Hou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yonatan</forename><surname>Bilu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Vinodkumar</forename><surname>Prabhakaran</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tim</forename><forename type="middle">Alberdingk</forename><surname>Thijm</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Graeme</forename><surname>Hirst</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Benno</forename><surname>Stein</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 15th Conference of the European Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the 15th Conference of the European Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="176" to="187" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Association for Computational Linguistics</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Building an argument search engine for the web</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Henning</forename><surname>Wachsmuth</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Martin</forename><surname>Potthast</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Khalid</forename><forename type="middle">Al</forename><surname>Khatib</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yamen</forename><surname>Ajjour</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jana</forename><surname>Puschmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jiani</forename><surname>Qu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jonas</forename><surname>Dorsch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Viorel</forename><surname>Morari</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Janek</forename><surname>Bevendorff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Benno</forename><surname>Stein</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 4th Workshop on Argument Mining</title>
		<meeting>the 4th Workshop on Argument Mining</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="49" to="59" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">PageRank&quot; for Argument Relevance</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Henning</forename><surname>Wachsmuth</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Benno</forename><surname>Stein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yamen</forename><surname>Ajjour</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 15th Conference of the European Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the 15th Conference of the European Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1117" to="1127" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Douglas</forename><surname>Walton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Fundamentals of Critical Argumentation</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Cambridge University Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Douglas</forename><surname>Walton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Objections, rebuttals and refutations</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="10" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Conversational flow in Oxford-style debates</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Justine</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ravi</forename><surname>Kumar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sujith</forename><surname>Ravi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Cristian</forename><surname>Danescu-Niculescu-Mizil</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2016 Conference of the North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics: Human Language Technologies</title>
		<meeting>the 2016 Conference of the North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics: Human Language Technologies</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="136" to="141" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
