<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T11:52+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Eyes are the Windows to the Soul: Predicting the Rating of Text Quality Using Gaze Behaviour</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
				<availability status="unknown"><p>Copyright Association for Computational Linguistics</p>
				</availability>
				<date>July 15-20, 2018. 2018. 2352</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sandeep</forename><surname>Mathias</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">♣</forename></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Diptesh</forename><surname>Kanojia</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kevin</forename><surname>Patel</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Samarth</forename><surname>Agrawal</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">IBM Research</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="IN">India</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Abhijit</forename><surname>Mishra</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Pushpak</forename><surname>Bhattacharyya</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">CSE Department</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">IIT Bombay ♣ IITB-Monash Research Academy ♦ Monash University</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="AU">Australia</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Eyes are the Windows to the Soul: Predicting the Rating of Text Quality Using Gaze Behaviour</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 56th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (Long Papers)</title>
						<meeting>the 56th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (Long Papers) <address><addrLine>Melbourne, Australia</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="2352" to="2362"/>
							<date type="published">July 15-20, 2018. 2018. 2352</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Predicting a reader&apos;s rating of text quality is a challenging task that involves estimating different subjective aspects of the text, like structure, clarity, etc. Such subjective aspects are better handled using cogni-tive information. One such source of cog-nitive information is gaze behaviour. In this paper, we show that gaze behaviour does indeed help in effectively predicting the rating of text quality. To do this, we first model text quality as a function of three properties-organization, coherence and cohesion. Then, we demonstrate how capturing gaze behaviour helps in predicting each of these properties, and hence the overall quality, by reporting improvements obtained by adding gaze features to traditional textual features for score prediction. We also hypothesize that if a reader has fully understood the text, the corresponding gaze behaviour would give a better indication of the assigned rating, as opposed to partial understanding. Our experiments validate this hypothesis by showing greater agreement between the given rating and the predicted rating when the reader has a full understanding of the text.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Automatically rating the quality of a text is an interesting challenge in NLP. It has been stud- ied since Page's seminal work on automatic es- say grading in the mid-1960s <ref type="bibr">(Page, 1966)</ref>. This is due to the dependence of quality on different aspects such as the overall structure of the text, clarity, etc. that are highly qualitative in nature, and whose scoring can vary from person to person <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">(Person, 2013)</ref>.</p><p>Scores for such qualitative aspects cannot be inferred solely from the text and would benefit from psycholinguistic information, such as gaze behaviour. Gaze based features have been used for co-reference resolution ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">Ross et al., 2016)</ref>, sentiment analysis ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Joshi et al., 2014</ref>) and trans- lation annotation complexity estimation ( <ref type="bibr">Mishra et al., 2013</ref>). They could also be very useful for education applications, like evaluating readability ( <ref type="bibr">Mishra et al., 2017)</ref> and in automatic essay grad- ing.</p><p>In this paper, we consider the following quali- tative properties of text: Organization, Coherence and Cohesion. A text is well-organized if it begins with an introduction, has a body and ends with a conclusion. One of the other aspects of organiza- tion is the fact that it takes into account how the content of the text is split into paragraphs, with each paragraph denoting a single idea. If the text is too long, and not split into paragraphs, one could consider the text to be badly organized <ref type="bibr">1</ref> .</p><p>A text is coherent if it makes sense to a reader. A text is cohesive if it is well connected. Coher- ence and cohesion are two qualities that are closely related. A piece of text that is well-connected usu- ally makes sense. Conversely, a piece of text that makes sense is usually well-connected. However, it is possible for texts to be coherent but lack co- hesion. <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table 1</ref> provides some examples for texts that are coherent and cohesive, as well as those that lack one of those qualities.</p><p>There are different ways to model coherence and cohesion. Since coherence is a measure of how much sense the text makes, it is a semantic property of the text. It requires sentences within the text to be interpreted, by themselves, as well as with other sentences in the text <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">(Van Dijk, 1980</ref>). On the other hand, cohesion makes use of Example Comments My favourite colour is blue. I like it because it is calming and it relaxes me. I often go outside in the summer and lie on the grass and look into the clear sky when I am stressed. For this reason, I'd have to say my favourite colour is blue.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Coherent and cohesive.</head><p>My favourite colour is blue. I'm calm and relaxed. In the sum- mer I lie on the grass and look up.</p><p>Coherent but not cohesive. There is no link between the sen- tences. However, the text makes sense due to a lot of implicit clues (blue, favourite, relaxing, look up (and see the blue sky)). My favourite colour is blue. Blue sports cars go very fast. Driv- ing in this way is dangerous and can cause many car crashes. I had a car accident once and broke my leg. I was very sad be- cause I had to miss a holiday in Europe because of the injury.</p><p>Cohesive but not coherent. The sentences are linked by words (that are in italics or in bold) between adjacent sentences. As we can see, every pair of adjacent sentences are connected by words / phrases, but the text does not make sense, since it first starts with blue, and describes missing a holiday due to injury. linguistic cues, such as references (demonstra- tives, pronouns, etc.), ellipsis (leaving out implicit words -Eg. Sam can type and I can <ref type="bibr">[type]</ref> too), substitution (use of a word or phrase to replace something mentioned earlier -Eg. How's the croissant? I'd like to have one too.), conjunction (and, but, therefore, etc.), cohesive nouns (prob- lem, issue, investment, etc.) and lexis (linking dif- ferent pieces of text by synonyms, hyponyms, lex- ical chains, etc.) <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Halliday and Hasan, 1976)</ref>.</p><p>Using these properties, we model the overall text quality rating. We make use of a Likert scale <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">(Likert, 1932</ref>) with a range of 1 to 4, for measur- ing each of these properties; the higher the score, the better is the text in terms of that property. We model the text quality rating on a scale of 1 to 10, using the three scores as input. In other words,</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">Quality(T ) = Org(T ) + Chr(T ) + Chs(T ) − 2,</formula><p>where Quality(T ) is the text quality rating of the text T . Org(T ), Chr(T ), and Chs(T ) cor- respond to the Organization, Coherence, and Cohesion scores respectively, for the text T , that are given by a reader. We subtract 2 to scale the scores from a range of 3 -12, to a range of 1 -10 for quality.</p><p>Texts with poor organization and/or cohesion can force readers to regress i.e. go to previous sen- tences or paragraphs. Texts with poor coherence may lead readers to fixate more on different por- tions of text to understand them. In other words, such gaze behaviour indirectly captures the effort needed by human readers to comprehend the text <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(Just and Carpenter, 1980)</ref>, which, in turn, may influence the ratings given by them. Hence, these <ref type="bibr">2</ref> We took the examples from this site for explaining coherence and cohesion: http: //gordonscruton.blogspot.in/2011/08/ what-is-cohesion-coherence-cambridge. html properties seem to be a good indicators for overall quality of texts.</p><p>In this paper, we address the following ques- tion: Can information obtained from gaze be- haviour help predict reader's rating of quality of text by estimating text's organization, coherence, and cohesion? Our work answers that question in the affirmative. We found that using gaze fea- tures does contribute in improving the prediction of qualitative ratings of text by users.</p><p>Our work has the following contributions. Firstly, we propose a novel way to predict read- ers' rating of text by recording their eye move- ments as they read the texts. Secondly, we show that if a reader has understood the text com- pletely, their gaze behaviour is more reliable. Thirdly, we also release our dataset 3 to help in further research in using gaze features in other tasks involving predicting the quality of texts.</p><p>In this paper, we use the following terms related to eye tracking. The interest area (IA) is an area of the screen that is under interest. We mainly look at words as interest areas. A fixation takes place when the gaze is focused on a point of the screen. A saccade is the movement of gaze between two fixations. A regression is a special type of saccade in which the reader refers back to something that they had read earlier.</p><p>The rest of the paper is organized as follows. Section 2 describes the motivation behind our work. Section 3 describes related work in this field. Section 4 describes the different features that we used. Sections 5 and 6 describes our experi- ments and results. Section 6 also contains analysis of our experiments. Section 7 concludes our paper and mentions future work. Radius of the circles denote the duration of the fixation (in milliseconds), which is centred at the centre of the circle. This is the output from SR Research Data Viewer software.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Motivation</head><p>Reader's perception of text quality is subjective and varies from person to person. Using cognitive information from the reader can help in predicting the score he / she will assign to the text. A well- written text would not have people fixate too long on certain words, or regress a lot to understand, while a badly written text would do so. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref> shows the gaze behaviour for a sample text. The circles denote fixations, and the arrows denote saccades. If we capture the gaze behaviour, as well as see how well the reader has understood the text, we believe that we can get a clearer pic- ture of the quality rating of the text.</p><p>One of the major concerns is How are we go- ing to get the gaze data? This is because capa- bility to gather eye-tracking data is not available to the masses. However, top mobile device man- ufacturers, like Samsung, have started integrat- ing basic eye-tracking software into their smart- phones (Samsung Smart Scroll) that are able to detect where the eye is fixated, and can be used in applications like scrolling through a web page. Start-ups, like Cogisen 4 , have started using gaze features in their applications, such as using gaze information to improve input to image processing systems. Recently, SR Research has come up with a portable eye-tracking system 5 .</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Related Work</head><p>A number of studies have been done showing how eye tracking can model aspects of text. Word length has been shown to be positively correlated with fixation count <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">(Rayner, 1998)</ref> and fixation duration <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Henderson and Ferreira, 1993)</ref>. Word predictability (i.e. how well the reader can predict the next word in a sentence) was also studied by <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">Rayner (1998)</ref>, where he found that unpredictable words are less likely to be skipped than predictable words. <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">Shermis and Burstein (2013)</ref> gives a brief overview of how text-based features are used in multiple aspects of essay grading, including gram- matical error detection, sentiment analysis, short- answer scoring, etc. Their work also describes a number of current essay grading systems that are available in the market like E-rater R ( <ref type="bibr">Attali and Burstein, 2004</ref>). In recent years, there has been a lot of work done on evaluating the holistic scores of essays, using deep learning techniques <ref type="bibr">(Alikaniotis et al., 2016;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b29">Taghipour and Ng, 2016;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Dong and Zhang, 2016)</ref>.</p><p>There has been little work done to model text organization, such as <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">Persing et al. (2010)</ref> (us- ing machine learning) and Taghipour (2017) (us- ing neural networks). However, there has been a lot of work done to model coherence and cohesion, using methods like lexical chains ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">Somasundaran et al., 2014</ref>), an entity grid ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Barzilay and Lapata, 2005</ref>), etc. An interesting piece of work to model coherence was done by <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">Soricut and Marcu (2006)</ref> where they used a machine translation-based ap- proach to model coherence. <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">Zesch et al. (2015)</ref> use topical overlap to model coherence for essay grad- ing. Discourse connectors are used as a heuristic to model cohesion by <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">Zesch et al. (2015)</ref> and <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Persing and Ng (2015)</ref>. Our work is novel because it makes use of gaze behaviour to model and predict coherence and cohesion in text.</p><p>In recent years, there has been some work in using eye-tracking to evaluate certain aspects of the text, like readability ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Gonzalez-Garduño and Søgaard, 2017;</ref><ref type="bibr">Mishra et al., 2017)</ref>, grammatical- ity ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Klerke et al., 2015)</ref>, etc.. Our work uses eye- tracking to predict the score given by a reader to a complete piece of text (rather than just a sen- tence as done by <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Klerke et al. (2015)</ref>) and show that the scoring is more reliable if the reader has understood the text.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Features</head><p>In order to predict the scores of the different prop- erties of the text, we use the following text and gaze features.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">Text-based Features</head><p>We use a set of text-based features to come up with a baseline system to predict the scores for different properties.</p><p>The first set of features that we use are length and count-based features, such as word length, word count, sentence length, count of transition phrases <ref type="bibr">6 etc. (Persing and Ng, 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b31">Zesch et al., 2015)</ref>.</p><p>The next set of features that we use are com- plexity features, namely the degree of polysemy, coreference distance, and the Flesch Reading Ease Score (FRES) <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Flesch, 1948)</ref>. These features help in normalizing the gaze features for text complex- ity. These features were extracted using Stan- ford CoreNLP ( , and Mor- phAdorner <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Burns, 2013)</ref>.</p><p>The third set of features that we use are stylis- tic features such as the ratios of the number of adjectives, nouns, prepositions, and verbs to the number of words in the text. These features are used to model the distributions of PoS tags in good and bad texts. These were extracted using NLTK <ref type="bibr">7</ref> ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Loper and Bird, 2002</ref>).</p><p>The fourth set of features that we use are word embedding features. We use the average of word vectors of each word in the essay, using Google News word vectors ( <ref type="bibr">Mikolov et al., 2013</ref>). The word embeddings are 300 dimensions. We also calculate the mean and maximum similarities be- tween the word vectors of the content words in ad- jacent sentences of the text, using GloVe word em- beddings 8 ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">Pennington et al., 2014</ref>).</p><p>The fifth set of features that we use are lan- guage modeling features. We use the count of words that are absent in Google News word vec- tors and misspelled words using the PyEnchant 9 library. In order to check the grammaticality of the text, we construct a 5-gram language model, using the Brown Corpus ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Francis and Kucera, 1979)</ref>.</p><p>The sixth set of features are sequence features. These features are particularly useful in modeling organization (sentence and paragraph sequence similarity) ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">Persing et al., 2010)</ref>, coherence and cohesion (PoS and lemma similarity). <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Pitler et al. (2010)</ref> showed that cosine similarity of adjacent sentences as one of the best predictors of linguis- tic quality. Hence, we also create vectors for the PoS tags and lemmas for each sentence in the text. The dimension of the vector is the number of dis- tinct PoS tags / lemmas.</p><p>The last set of features that we look at are en- tity grid features. We define entities as the nouns in the document, and do coreference resolution to resolve pronouns. We then construct an entity grid ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Barzilay and Lapata, 2005</ref>) -a 1 or 0 grid that checks whether an entity is present or not in a given sentence. We take into account sequences of entities across sentences that possess at least one 1, that are either bigrams, trigrams or 4-grams. A sequence with multiple 1s denote entities that are close to each other, while sequences with a soli- tary 1 denote that an entity is just mentioned once and we do not come across it again for a number of sentences.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">Gaze-based Features</head><p>The gaze-based features are dependent on the gaze behaviour of the participant with respect to interest areas.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Fixation Features</head><p>The First Fixation Duration (FFD) shows the time the reader fixates on a word when he / she first encounters it. An increased FFD intuitively could mean that the word is more complex and the reader spends more time in understanding the word <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">(Mishra et al., 2016)</ref>.</p><p>The</p><note type="other">Second Fixation Duration (SFD) is the duration in which the reader fixates on a partic- ular interest area the second time. This happens during a regression, when a reader is trying to link the word he / she just read with an earlier word. The Last Fixation Duration (LFD) is the du- ration in which the reader fixates on a particular interest area the final time. At this point, we be- lieve that the interest area has been processed.</note><p>The Dwell Time (DT) is the total time the reader fixates on a particular interest area. Like first fixation, this also measures the complexity of the word, not just by itself, but also with regard to the entire text (since it takes into account fixations when the word was regressed, etc.)</p><p>The Fixation Count (FC) is the number of fixa- tions on a particular interest area. A larger fixation count could mean that the reader frequently goes back to read that particular interest area.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Regression Features</head><p>IsRegression (IR) is the number of interest areas where a regression happened before reading ahead and IsRegressionFull (IRF) is the number of in- terest areas where a regression happened. The Re- gression Count (RC) is the total number of regres- sions. The Regression Time (RT) is the duration of the regressions from an interest area. These re- gression features could help in modeling semantic links for coherence and cohesion.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Interest Area Features</head><p>The Skip Count (SC) is the number of interest areas that have been skipped. The Run Count (RC) is the number of interest areas that have at least one fixation. A larger run count means that more interest areas were fixated on. Badly writ- ten texts would have higher run counts (and lower skip counts), as well as fixation counts, because the reader will fixate on these texts for a longer time to understand them.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Experiment Details</head><p>In this section, we describe our experimental setup, creation of the dataset, evaluation metric, classifier details, etc.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.1">Ordinal Classification vs. Regression</head><p>For each of the properties -organization, coher- ence and cohesion, we make use of a Likert scale, with scores of 1 to 4. Details of the scores are given in <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Table 2</ref>. For scoring the quality, we use the formula described in the Introduction. Since we used a Likert scale, we make use of ordinal classification, rather than regression. This is be- cause each of the grades is a discrete value that can be represented as an ordinal class (where 1 &lt; 2 &lt; 3 &lt; 4), as compared to a continuous real number.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.2">Evaluation Metric</head><p>For the predictions of our experiments, we use Co- hen's Kappa with quadratic weights -quadratic weighted Kappa (QWK) <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Cohen, 1968)</ref> because of the following reasons. Firstly, unlike accuracy and F-Score, Cohen's Kappa takes into account whether or not agreements happen by chance. Sec- ondly, weights (either linear or quadratic) take into account distance between the given score and the expected score, unlike accuracy and F-score where mismatches (either 1 vs. 4, or 1 vs.2) are penalized the same. Quadratic weights reward matches and penalize mismatches more than linear weights.</p><p>To measure the Inter-Annotator Agreement of our raters, we make use of Gwet's second-order agreement coefficient (Gwet's AC2) as it can han- dle ordinal classes, weights, missing values, and multiple raters rating the same document (Gwet, 2014).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.3">Creation of the Dataset</head><p>In this subsection, we describe how we created our dataset. We describe the way we made the texts, the way they were annotated and the inter- annotator agreements for the different properties.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Details of Texts</head><p>To the best of our knowledge there isn't a pub- licly available dataset with gaze features for tex- tual quality. Hence, we decided to create our own. Our dataset consists of a diverse set of 30 texts, from Simple English Wikipedia (10 articles), En- glish Wikipedia (8 articles), and online news ar- ticles (12 articles) <ref type="bibr">10</ref> . We did not wish to over- burden the readers, so we kept the size of texts to</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Property</head><p>Grade Guidelines Organization 1 Bad. There is no organization in the text. OK. There is little / no link between the paragraphs, but they each describe an idea. 3</p><p>Good. Some paragraphs may be missing, but there is an overall link between them. 4</p><p>Very Good. All the paragraphs follow a flow from the Introduction to Conclusion.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Coherence</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>1</head><p>Bad. The sentences do not make sense. 2</p><p>OK. Groups of sentences may make sense together, but the text still may not make sense. 3</p><p>Good. Most of the sentences make sense. The text, overall, makes sense. 4</p><p>Very Good. The sentences and overall text make sense.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Cohesion</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>1</head><p>Bad. There is little / no link between any 2 adjacent sentences in the same paragraph. 2 OK. There is little / no link between adjacent paragraphs. However, each paragraph is cohesive 3</p><p>Good. All the sentences in a paragraph are linked to each other and contribute in understanding the paragraph. 4</p><p>Very Good. The text is well connected. All the sentences are linked to each other and help in understanding the text. approximately 200 words each. The original arti- cles ranged from a couple hundred words (Simple English Wikipedia) to over a thousand words (En- glish Wikipedia). We first summarized the longer articles manually. Then, for the many articles over 200 words, we removed a few of the paragraphs and sentences. In this way, despite all the texts being published, we were able to introduce some poor quality texts into our dataset. The articles were sampled from a variety of genres, such as History, Science, Law, Entertainment, Education, Sports, etc.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Details of Annotators</head><p>The dataset was annotated by 20 annotators in the age group of 20-25. Out of the 20 annotators, the distribution was 9 high school graduates (current college students), 8 college graduates, and 3 anno- tators with a post-graduate degree. In order to check the eyesight of the annotators, we had each annotator look at different parts of the screen. While they did that, we recorded how their fixations were being detected. Only if their fixa- tions to particular parts of the screen tallied with our requests, would we let them participate in an- notation.</p><p>All the participants in the experiment were flu- ent speakers of English. A few of them scored over 160 in GRE Verbal test and/or over 110 in TOEFL. Irrespective of their appearance in such exams, each annotator was made to take an En- glish test before doing the experiments. The par- ticipants had to read a couple of passages, answer comprehension questions and score them for orga- nization, coherence and cohesion (as either good / medium / bad). In case they either got both com- prehension questions wrong, or labeled a good passage bad (or vice versa), they failed the test <ref type="bibr">11</ref>   <ref type="table">Table 3</ref>: Inter-Annotator Agreements (Gwet's AC2) for each of the properties.</p><p>In order to help the annotators, they were given 5 sample texts to differentiate between good and bad organization, coherence and cohesion. <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">Table  1</ref> has some of those texts 12 .</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Inter-Annotator Agreement</head><p>Each of the properties were scored in the range of 1 to 4. In addition, we also evaluated the partici- pant's understanding of the text by asking them a couple of questions on the text. <ref type="table">Table 3</ref> gives the inter-annotator agreement for each of the 3 prop- erties that they rated. The column Full shows the agreement only if the participant answered both the questions correct. The Overall column shows the agreement irrespective of the partici- pant's comprehension of the text.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.4">System Details</head><p>We conducted the experiment by following stan- dard norms in eye-movement research <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(Holmqvist et al., 2011</ref>). The display screen is kept about 2 feet from the reader, and the camera is placed mid- way between the reader and the screen. The reader is seated and the position of his head is fixed using a chin rest.</p><p>Before the text is displayed, we calibrate the camera by having the participant fixate on 13 rejected annotators failed the test, while the other 3 had bad eyesight. <ref type="bibr">12</ref> The texts for good and bad organization are too long to provide in this paper. They will be uploaded in supplemen- tary material.</p><p>points on the screen and validate the calibration so that the camera is able to predict the location of the eye on the screen accurately. After calibration and validation, the text is displayed on the screen in Times New Roman typeface with font size 23. The reader reads the text and while that happens, we record the reader's eye movements. The read- ers were allowed to take as much time as they needed to finish the text. Once the reader has fin- ished, the reader moves to the next screen.</p><p>The next two screens each have a question that is based on the passage. These questions are used to verify that the reader did not just skim through the passage, but understood it as well. The ques- tions were multiple choice, with 4 options 13 . The questions test literal comprehension (where the reader has to recall something they read), and in- terpretive comprehension (where the reader has to infer the answer from the text they read). After this, the reader scores the texts for organization, coherence and cohesion. The participants then take a short break (about 30 seconds to a couple of minutes) before proceeding with the next text. This is done to prevent reading fatigue over a pe- riod of time. After each break, we recalibrate the camera and validate the calibration again.</p><p>For obtaining gaze features from a participant, we collect gaze movement patterns using an SR Research Eye Link 1000 eye-tracker (monocular stabilized head mode, sampling rate 500Hz). It is able to collect all the gaze details that we re- quire for our experiments. Reports are generated for keyboard events (message report) and gaze be- haviour (interest area report) using SR Research Data Viewer software.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.5">Classification Details</head><p>We also process the articles for obtaining the text features as described in Section 4. Given that we want to show the utility of gaze features, we ran each of the following classifiers with 3 feature sets -only text, only gaze, and all features.</p><p>We split the data into a training -test split of sizes 70% and 30%. We used a Feed Forward Neural Network with 1 hidden layer containing 100 neurons <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Bebis and Georgiopoulos, 1994)</ref>  <ref type="bibr">14</ref> . <ref type="bibr">13</ref> Example Passage Text: The text in <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Figure 1</ref> Question: "How many states did Ronald Reagan win in both his Presidential campaigns?" Correct Answer: "93" (44+49) <ref type="bibr">14</ref> We also used other classifiers, like Naive Bayes, Logistic Regression and Random Forest. However, the neural network outperformed them.</p><p>The size of the input vector was 361 features. Out of these, there were 49 text features, plus 300 dimension word embeddings features, 11 gaze features, and 1 class label. The data was split using stratified sampling, to ensure that there is a similar distribution of classes in each of the train- ing and test splits. The Feed Forward Neural Net- work was implemented using <ref type="bibr">TensorFlow (Abadi et al., 2015</ref>) in Python. We ran the neural network over 10,000 epochs, with a learning rate of 0.001 in 10 batches. The loss function that we used was the mean square error.</p><p>In order to see how much the participant's un- derstanding of the text would reflect on their scor- ing, we also looked at the data based on how the participant scored in the comprehension questions after they read the article. We split the articles into 2 subsets here -F ull, denoting that the partici- pant answered both the questions correctly, and P artial, denoting that they were able to answer only one of the questions correctly. The read- ers showed F ull understanding in 269 instances and P artial understanding in 261 instances. We used the same setup here (same training -test split, stratified sampling, and feed forward neural net- work). We omit the remaining 70 instances where the participant got none of the questions correct, as the participant could have scored the texts com- pletely randomly. <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">Table 4</ref> shows the results of our experiments us- ing the feed forward neural network classifier. The first column is the property being evaluated. The next 3 columns denote the results for the Text, Gaze and Text+Gaze feature sets.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Results and Analysis</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Property</head><p>Text  The QWK scores are the predictions which we obtain with respect to the scores of all the 30 doc- uments, scored by all 20 raters. Textual features when augmented with gaze based features show significant improvement for all the properties. We check the statistical significance of im- provement of adding gaze based features for the results in <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">Table 4</ref>. To test our hypothesis -that adding gaze features make a statistically signifi- cant improvement -we run the t-test. Our null hy- pothesis: Gaze based features do not help in pre- diction, any more than text features themselves, and whatever improvements happen when gaze based features are added to the textual features, are not statistically significant. We choose a sig- nificance level of p &lt; 0.001. For all the improve- ments, we found them to be statistically significant above this α level, rejecting our null hypothesis.</p><p>We also evaluate how the participant's under- standing of the text affects the way they score the text. <ref type="table" target="#tab_5">Table 5</ref> shows the results of our experiments taking the reader's comprehension into account. The first column is the property being evaluated. The second column is the level of comprehension -F ull for the passages where the participant an- swered both the questions correctly, and P artial for the passages where the participant answered one question correctly. The next 3 columns show the results using the Text feature set, the Gaze fea- ture set, and both (Text+Gaze) feature sets. From this table, we see that wherever the gaze features are used, there is far greater agreement for those with F ull understanding as compared to P artial understanding.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Property</head><p>Comp   <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">Figure 2</ref> shows a clear relationship between some of the gaze features and the scores given by readers for the properties -organization, cohesion and coherence. In all the charts, we see that texts with the lowest scores have the longest durations (regression / fixation) as well as counts (of fixa- tions and interest areas fixated). <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">Figure 3</ref> shows the fixation heat maps for 3 texts whose quality scores were good (10), medium (6) and bad (3), read by the same participant. From these heat maps, we see that the text rated good has highly dense fixations for only a part of the text, as compared to the medium and bad texts. This shows that badly written texts force the readers to fixate a lot more than well-written texts.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.1">Ablation Tests</head><p>In order to see which of the gaze feature sets is important, we run a set of ablation tests. We ablate the fixations, regressions and interest area feature sets one at a time. We also ablated each of the individual gaze features.  <ref type="table">Table 6</ref>: Difference in QWK scores when ablat- ing three gaze behaviour feature sets for different properties. <ref type="table">Table 6</ref> gives the result of our ablation tests on the three feature sets -fixation, regression and interest area feature sets. The first column is the property that we are measuring. The next 3 columns denote the difference between the pre- dicted QWK that we got from ablating the fixation, regression and interest area feature sets. We found that the Interest Area feature set was the most im- portant, followed by fixation and regression.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Property Fixation Regression Interest Areas</head><p>Among the individual features, Run Count (RC) was found to be the most important for or- ganization and quality. First Fixation Duration (FFD) was the most important feature for coher- ence, and IsRegressionFull (IRF) was the most important feature for cohesion. We believe that this is because the number of interest areas that are fixated on at least once and the number of interest areas that are skipped play an important role in de- termining how much of the text was read and how much was skipped. However, for cohesion, regres- sion features are the most important, because they show a link between the cohesive clues (like lexis, references, etc.) in adjacent sentences.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7">Conclusion and Future Work</head><p>We presented a novel approach to predict reader's rating of texts. The approach estimates the over- all quality on the basis of three properties -orga- nization, coherence and cohesion. Although well defined, predicting the score of these properties for a text is quite challenging. It has been estab- lished that cognitive information such as gaze be- haviour can help in such subjective tasks <ref type="bibr">(Mishra et al., 2013</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b24">(Mishra et al., , 2016</ref>. We hypothesized that gaze behavior will assist in predicting the scores of text quality. To evaluate this hypothesis, we col- lected gaze behaviour data and evaluated the pre- dictions using only the text-based features. When we took gaze behaviour into account, we were able to significantly improve our predictions of or- ganization, coherence, cohesion and quality. We found out that, in all cases, there was an improve- ment in the agreement scores when the participant who rated the text showed full understanding, as compared to partial understanding, using only the Gaze features and the Text+Gaze features. This in- dicated that gaze behaviour is more reliable when the reader has understood the text.</p><p>To the best of our knowledge, our work is pi- oneering in using gaze information for predicting text quality rating. In future, we plan to use use approaches, like multi-task learning ( <ref type="bibr">Mishra et al., 2018)</ref>, in estimating gaze features and using those estimated features for text quality prediction.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: Sample text showing fixations, saccades and regressions. This text was given scores of 4, 4, and 3 for organization, coherence and cohesion. The circles denote fixations, and the lines are saccades. Radius of the circles denote the duration of the fixation (in milliseconds), which is centred at the centre of the circle. This is the output from SR Research Data Viewer software.</figDesc><graphic url="image-1.png" coords="3,72.00,62.81,453.54,173.67" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>2</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>Figure 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2: Relation between some of the different gaze features and the score. The gaze features are (a) RD, (b) SFD, (c) FC and (d) RC. For figures (a) and (b), the units on the y-axis are milliseconds. For figures (c) and (d) the numbers are a ratio to the number of interest areas in the text. The x-axis in all 4 graphs is the score given by the annotators.</figDesc><graphic url="image-2.png" coords="8,111.69,62.81,374.17,251.98" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head>Figure 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Figure 3: Fixation heatmap examples for one of the participants from SR Research Data Viewer software.</figDesc><graphic url="image-3.png" coords="9,91.95,62.81,136.06,84.70" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" validated="false"><head>Table 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Examples of coherence and cohesion 2 . 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" validated="false"><head>Table 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Annotation guidelines for different properties of text. 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" validated="false"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>. 11 25 annotators applied, but we chose only 20. 2 of the</figDesc><table>Property 
Full Overall 
Organization 0.610 
0.519 
Coherence 
0.688 
0.633 
Cohesion 
0.675 
0.614 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3" validated="false"><head>Table 4 :</head><label>4</label><figDesc>QWK scores for the three feature sets on different properties.</figDesc><table></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4" validated="false"><head>.</head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Text Gaze Text+Gaze 

Organization 
Full 
0.319 0.319 
0.563 
Partial 0.115 0.179 
0.283 

Coherence 
Full 
0.255 0.385 
0.601 
Partial 0.365 0.343 
0.446 

Cohesion 
Full 
0.313 0.519 
0.638 
Partial 0.161 0.155 
0.230 

Quality 
Full 
0.216 0.624 
0.645 
Partial 0.161 0.476 
0.581 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_5" validated="false"><head>Table 5 :</head><label>5</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>QWK scores for the three feature sets 
on different properties categorized on the basis of 
reader comprehension. 

</table></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> Refer supplementary material for example. We have placed it there due to space constraints.</note>

			<note place="foot" n="3"> The dataset can be downloaded from http://www. cfilt.iitb.ac.in/cognitive-nlp/</note>

			<note place="foot" n="4"> www.cogisen.com 5 https://www.sr-research.com/products/ eyelink-portable-duo/</note>

			<note place="foot" n="6"> https://writing.wisc.edu/Handbook/ Transitions.html 7 http://www.nltk.org/</note>

			<note place="foot" n="8"> We found that using GloVe here and Google News for the mean word vectors worked best. 9 https://pypi.python.org/pypi/ pyenchant/</note>

			<note place="foot" n="10"> The sources for the articles were https://simple. wikipedia.org, https://en.wikipedia.org, and https://newsela.com</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgements</head><p>We'd like to thank all the anonymous reviewers for their constructive feedback in helping us im-prove our paper. We'd also like to thank Anoop Kunchukuttan, a research scholar from the Centre for Indian Language Technology, IIT Bombay for his valuable input.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Modeling local coherence: An entity-based approach</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Regina</forename><surname>Barzilay</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mirella</forename><surname>Lapata</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="doi">10.3115/1219840.1219858</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.3115/1219840.1219858" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 43rd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL&apos;05)</title>
		<meeting>the 43rd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL&apos;05)<address><addrLine>Ann Arbor, Michigan</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="141" to="148" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Association for Computational Linguistics</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Feed-forward neural networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">George</forename><surname>Bebis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Georgiopoulos</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE Potentials</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="27" to="31" />
			<date type="published" when="1994" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Morphadorner v2: A java library for the morphological adornment of english language texts</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Philip</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Burns</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<pubPlace>Evanston, IL</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>Northwestern University</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Weighted kappa: Nominal scale agreement provision for scaled disagreement or partial credit</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jacob</forename><surname>Cohen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological bulletin</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">70</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">213</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1968" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Automatic features for essay scoring-an empirical study</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Fei</forename><surname>Dong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yue</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2016 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</title>
		<meeting>the 2016 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing<address><addrLine>Austin, Texas</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1072" to="1077" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A new readability yardstick</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rudolph</forename><surname>Flesch</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of applied psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">32</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">221</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1948" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The brown corpus: A standard corpus of present-day edited american english</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nelson</forename><surname>Francis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Henry</forename><surname>Kucera</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1979" />
			<pubPlace>Providence, RI</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>Department of Linguistics, Brown University</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
	<note>producer and distributor</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Using gaze to predict text readability</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ana</forename><surname>Valeria Gonzalez-Garduño</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Anders</forename><surname>Søgaard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://www.aclweb.org/anthology/W17-5050" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 12th Workshop on Innovative Use of NLP for Building Educational Applications. Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the 12th Workshop on Innovative Use of NLP for Building Educational Applications. Association for Computational Linguistics<address><addrLine>Copenhagen, Denmark</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="438" to="443" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Handbook of inter-rater reliability: The definitive guide to measuring the extent of agreement among raters</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Kilem</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Gwet</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Advanced Analytics, LLC</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Cohesion in english</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michael</forename><forename type="middle">Alexander</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kirkwood</forename><surname>Halliday</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ruqaiya</forename><surname>Hasan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1976" />
			<publisher>Longman Group Ltd</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Eye movement control during reading: Fixation measures reflect foveal but not parafoveal processing difficulty</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>John</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Fernanda</forename><surname>Henderson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Ferreira</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Canadian Journal of Experimental Psychology/Revue canadienne de psychologie expérimentale</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">47</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">201</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Eye tracking: A comprehensive guide to methods and measures</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kenneth</forename><surname>Holmqvist</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marcus</forename><surname>Nyström</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Richard</forename><surname>Andersson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Richard</forename><surname>Dewhurst</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Halszka</forename><surname>Jarodzka</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Joost</forename><surname>Van De Weijer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<publisher>OUP</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Oxford</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Nivvedan Senthamilselvan, and Pushpak Bhattacharyya</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Aditya</forename><surname>Joshi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Abhijit</forename><surname>Mishra</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="36" to="41" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Measuring sentiment annotation complexity of text</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A theory of reading: From eye fixations to comprehension</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Marcel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Patricia</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Just</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Carpenter</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">87</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">329</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1980" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Looking hard: Eye tracking for detecting grammaticality of automatically compressed sentences</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sigrid</forename><surname>Klerke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Anders</forename><surname>Héctor Martínez Alonso</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Søgaard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://www.aclweb.org/anthology/W15-1814" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 20th Nordic Conference of Computational Linguistics (NODALIDA 2015). Linköping University Electronic Press</title>
		<meeting>the 20th Nordic Conference of Computational Linguistics (NODALIDA 2015). Linköping University Electronic Press<address><addrLine>Sweden, Vilnius, Lithuania</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="97" to="105" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">A technique for the measurement of attitudes. Archives of psychology</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rensis</forename><surname>Likert</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1932" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Nltk: The natural language toolkit</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Edward</forename><surname>Loper</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Steven</forename><surname>Bird</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the ACL-02 Workshop on Effective tools and methodologies for teaching natural language processing and computational linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the ACL-02 Workshop on Effective tools and methodologies for teaching natural language processing and computational linguistics</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="63" to="70" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Association for Computational Linguistics</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Stanford CoreNLP natural language processing toolkit</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christopher</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Manning</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mihai</forename><surname>Surdeanu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">John</forename><surname>Bauer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jenny</forename><surname>Finkel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Steven</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Bethard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Mcclosky</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL) System Demonstrations</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="55" to="60" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Glove: Global vectors for word representation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jeffrey</forename><surname>Pennington</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Richard</forename><surname>Socher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christopher</forename><surname>Manning</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2014 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP). Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the 2014 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP). Association for Computational Linguistics<address><addrLine>Doha, Qatar</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1532" to="1543" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Modeling organization in student essays</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Isaac</forename><surname>Persing</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alan</forename><surname>Davis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Vincent</forename><surname>Ng</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2010 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</title>
		<meeting>the 2010 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing<address><addrLine>Cambridge, MA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="229" to="239" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Modeling argument strength in student essays</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Isaac</forename><surname>Persing</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Vincent</forename><surname>Ng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://www.aclweb.org/anthology/P15-1053" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 53rd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics and the 7th International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing</title>
		<meeting>the 53rd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics and the 7th International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing<address><addrLine>Beijing, China</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="543" to="552" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Long Papers). Association for Computational Linguistics</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Blind truth: An examination of grading bias</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Robert</forename><surname>Person</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Automatic evaluation of linguistic quality in multidocument summarization</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Emily</forename><surname>Pitler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Annie</forename><surname>Louis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ani</forename><surname>Nenkova</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://www.aclweb.org/anthology/P10-1056" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 48th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics. Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the 48th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics. Association for Computational Linguistics<address><addrLine>Uppsala, Sweden</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="544" to="554" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Eye movements in reading and information processing: 20 years of research</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Keith</forename><surname>Rayner</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological bulletin</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">124</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">372</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Leveraging annotators gaze behaviour for coreference resolution</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Joe Cheri</forename><surname>Ross</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Abhijit</forename><surname>Mishra</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Pushpak</forename><surname>Bhattacharyya</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 7th Workshop on Cognitive Aspects of Computational Language Learning</title>
		<meeting>the 7th Workshop on Cognitive Aspects of Computational Language Learning</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="22" to="26" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Handbook of automated essay evaluation: Current applications and new directions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Mark</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jill</forename><surname>Shermis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Burstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Routledge</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Lexical chaining for measuring discourse coherence quality in test-taker essays</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Swapna</forename><surname>Somasundaran</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jill</forename><surname>Burstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Martin</forename><surname>Chodorow</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of COLING 2014, the 25th International Conference on Computational Linguistics: Technical Papers. Dublin City University and Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>COLING 2014, the 25th International Conference on Computational Linguistics: Technical Papers. Dublin City University and Association for Computational Linguistics<address><addrLine>Dublin, Ireland</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="950" to="961" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Discourse generation using utility-trained coherence models</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Radu</forename><surname>Soricut</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Daniel</forename><surname>Marcu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://www.aclweb.org/anthology/P/P06/P06-2103" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the COLING/ACL 2006 Main Conference Poster Sessions. Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the COLING/ACL 2006 Main Conference Poster Sessions. Association for Computational Linguistics<address><addrLine>Sydney, Australia</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="803" to="810" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Robust Trait-Specific Essay Scoring Using Neural Networks and Density Estimators</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kaveh</forename><surname>Taghipour</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Ph.D. thesis</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A neural approach to automated essay scoring</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kaveh</forename><surname>Taghipour</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hwee Tou</forename><surname>Ng</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2016 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</title>
		<meeting>the 2016 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing<address><addrLine>Austin, Texas</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1882" to="1891" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Text and context explorations in the semantics and pragmatics of discourse</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Teun Adrianus Van</forename><surname>Dijk</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1980" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Task-independent features for automated essay grading</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Torsten</forename><surname>Zesch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Wojatzki</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dirk</forename><surname>Scholtenakoun</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://www.aclweb.org/anthology/W15-0626" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Tenth Workshop on Innovative Use of NLP for Building Educational Applications. Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the Tenth Workshop on Innovative Use of NLP for Building Educational Applications. Association for Computational Linguistics<address><addrLine>Denver, Colorado</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="224" to="232" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
