<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T11:50+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Give Me More Feedback: Annotating Argument Persuasiveness and Related Attributes in Student Essays</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date>July 15-20, 2018</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Winston</forename><surname>Carlile</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Human Language Technology Research Institute University of Texas at Dallas Richardson</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>75083-0688</postCode>
									<region>TX</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nishant</forename><surname>Gurrapadi</surname></persName>
							<email>Nishant.Gurrapadi@utdallas.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Human Language Technology Research Institute University of Texas at Dallas Richardson</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>75083-0688</postCode>
									<region>TX</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Zixuan</forename><surname>Ke</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Human Language Technology Research Institute University of Texas at Dallas Richardson</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>75083-0688</postCode>
									<region>TX</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Vincent</forename><surname>Ng</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Human Language Technology Research Institute University of Texas at Dallas Richardson</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>75083-0688</postCode>
									<region>TX</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Give Me More Feedback: Annotating Argument Persuasiveness and Related Attributes in Student Essays</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 56th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (Long Papers)</title>
						<meeting>the 56th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (Long Papers) <address><addrLine>Melbourne, Australia</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="621" to="631"/>
							<date type="published">July 15-20, 2018</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<note>621</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>While argument persuasiveness is one of the most important dimensions of argumentative essay quality, it is relatively little studied in automated essay scoring research. Progress on scoring argument persuasiveness is hindered in part by the scarcity of annotated corpora. We present the first corpus of essays that are simultaneously annotated with argument components , argument persuasiveness scores, and attributes of argument components that impact an argument&apos;s persuasiveness. This corpus could trigger the development of novel computational models concerning argument persuasiveness that provide useful feedback to students on why their arguments are (un)persuasive in addition to how persuasive they are.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>The vast majority of existing work on au- tomated essay scoring has focused on holis- tic scoring, which summarizes the quality of an essay with a single score and thus pro- vides very limited feedback to the writer (see <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">Shermis and Burstein (2013)</ref> for the state of the art). While recent attempts address this prob- lem by scoring a particular dimension of essay quality such as coherence ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Miltsakaki and Kukich, 2004</ref>), technical errors, relevance to prompt <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(Higgins et al., 2004;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Persing and Ng, 2014</ref>), or- ganization ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">Persing et al., 2010)</ref>, and thesis clar- ity ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Persing and Ng, 2013)</ref>, argument persuasive- ness is largely ignored in existing automated essay scoring research despite being one of the most im- portant dimensions of essay quality.</p><p>Nevertheless, scoring the persuasiveness of ar- guments in student essays is by no means easy.</p><p>The difficulty stems in part from the scarcity of persuasiveness-annotated corpora of student es- says. While persuasiveness-annotated corpora ex- ist for other domains such as online debates (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">Habernal and Gurevych (2016a;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b4">2016b)</ref>), to our knowledge only one corpus of persuasiveness- annotated student essays has been made publicly available so far ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Persing and Ng, 2015)</ref>.</p><p>Though a valuable resource, Persing and Ng's (2015) (P&amp;N) corpus has several weaknesses that limit its impact on automated essay scoring research. First, P&amp;N assign only one persuasive- ness score to each essay that indicates the persua- siveness of the argument an essay makes for its thesis. However, multiple arguments are typically made in a persuasive essay. Specifically, the ar- guments of an essay are typically structured as an argument tree, where the major claim, which is situated at the root of the tree, is supported by one or more claims (the children of the root node), each of which is in turn supported by one or more premises. Hence, each node and its children con- stitute an argument. In P&amp;N's dataset, only the persuasiveness of the overall argument (i.e., the ar- gument represented at the root and its children) of each essay is scored. Hence, any system trained on their dataset cannot provide any feedback to students on the persuasiveness of any arguments other than the overall argument. Second, P&amp;N's corpus does not contain annotations that explain why the overall argument is not persuasive if its score is low. This is undesirable from a feedback perspective, as a student will not understand why her argument is not persuasive if its score is low.</p><p>Our goal in this paper is to annotate and make publicly available a corpus of persuasive stu- dent essays that addresses the aforementioned weaknesses via designing appropriate annotation schemes and scoring rubrics. Specifically, not only do we score the persuasiveness of each ar-gument in each essay (rather than simply the per- suasiveness of the overall argument), but we also identify a set of attributes that can explain an ar- gument's persuasiveness and annotate each argu- ment with the values of these attributes. These an- notations enable the development of systems that can provide useful feedback to students, as the at- tribute values predicted by these systems can help a student understand why her essay receives a par- ticular persuasiveness score. To our knowledge, this is the first corpus of essays that are simultane- ously annotated with argument components, per- suasiveness scores, and related attributes. <ref type="bibr">1</ref> </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Related Work</head><p>While argument mining research has traditionally focused on determining the argumentative struc- ture of a text document (i.e., identifying its ma- jor claim, claims, and premises, as well as the re- lationships between these argument components) <ref type="bibr">Gurevych, 2014b, 2017a;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Eger et al., 2017)</ref>, researchers have recently begun to study new argument mining tasks, as described below.</p><p>Persuasiveness-related tasks. Most related to our study is work involving argument persua- siveness. For instance, <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Habernal and Gurevych (2016b)</ref> and <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">Wei et al. (2016)</ref> study the persua- siveness ranking task, where the goal is to rank two internet debate arguments written for the same topic w.r.t. their persuasiveness. As noted by Habernal and Gurevych, ranking arguments is a relatively easier task than scoring an argument's persuasiveness: in ranking, a system simply deter- mines whether one argument is more persuasive than the other, but not how much more persuasive one argument is than the other; in scoring, how- ever, a system has to determine how persuasive an argument is on an absolute scale. Note that ranking is not an acceptable evaluation setting for studying argument persuasiveness in the essay do- main, as feedback for an essay has to be provided independently of other essays.</p><p>In contrast, there are studies that focus on fac- tors affecting argument persuasiveness in internet debates. For instance, <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Lukin et al. (2017)</ref> exam- ine how audience variables (e.g., personalities) in- teract with argument style (e.g., factual vs. emo- tional arguments) to affect argument persuasive- ness. <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">Persing and Ng (2017)</ref> identify factors that negatively impact persuasiveness, so their factors, unlike ours, cannot explain what makes an argu- ment persuasive. Other argument mining tasks. Some of the at- tributes that we annotate our corpus with have been studied. For instance, <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">Hidey et al. (2017)</ref> ex- amine the different semantic types of claims and premises, whereas <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Higgins and Walker (2012)</ref> in- vestigate persuasion strategies (i.e., ethos, pathos, logos). Unlike ours, these studies use data from online debate forums and social/environment re- ports. Perhaps more importantly, they study these attributes independently of persuasiveness.</p><p>Several argument mining tasks have recently been proposed. For instance, <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">Stab and Gurevych (2017b)</ref> examine the task of whether an argument is sufficiently supported. Al <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">Khatib et al. (2016)</ref> identify and annotate a news editorial corpus with fine-grained argumentative discourse units for the purpose of analyzing the argumentation strategies used to persuade readers. <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">Wachsmuth et al. (2017)</ref> focus on identifying and annotating 15 logical, rhetorical, and dialectical dimensions that would be useful for automatically accessing the quality of an argument. Most recently, the Argument Rea- soning Comprehension task organized as part of SemEval 2018 has focused on selecting the cor- rect warrant that explains reasoning of an argu- ment that consists of a claim and a reason. <ref type="bibr">2</ref> </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Corpus</head><p>The corpus we chose to annotate is composed of 102 essays randomly chosen from the Argument Annotated Essays corpus <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">(Stab and Gurevych, 2014a)</ref>. This collection of essays was taken from essayforum 3 , a site offering feedback to students wishing to improve their ability to write persuasive essays for tests. Each essay is written in response to a topic such as "should high school make music lessons compulsory?" and has already been an- notated by Stab and Gurevych with an argument tree. Hence, rather than annotate everything from scratch, we annotate the persuasiveness score of each argument in the already-annotated argument trees in this essay collection as well as the at- tributes that potentially impact persuasiveness.</p><p>Each argument tree is composed of three types of tree nodes that correspond to argument compo- Each argument tree has three to four levels. The root is a major claim. Each node in the second level is a claim that supports or attacks its par- ent (i.e., the major claim). Each node is the third level is a premise that supports or attacks its par- ent (i.e., a claim). There is an optional fourth level consisting of nodes that correspond to premises. Each of these premises either supports or attacks its (premise) parent. <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">Stab and Gurevych (2014a)</ref> report high inter-annotator agreement on these an- notations: for the annotations of major claims, claims, and premises, the Krippendorff's α values <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Krippendorff, 1980)</ref> are 0.77, 0.70, and 0.76 re- spectively, and for the annotations of support and attack relations, the α values are both 0.81.</p><p>Note that Stab and Gurevych (2014a) determine premises and claims by their position in the argu- ment tree and not by their semantic meaning. Due to the difficulty of treating an opinion as a non- negotiable unit of evidence, we convert all sub- jective premises into claims to demonstrate that they are subjective and require backing. At the end of this process, several essays contain argu- ment trees that violate the scheme used by Stab and Gurevych, due to some premises supported by opinion premises, now converted to claims. Although the ideal argument should not violate the canonical structure, students attempting to im- prove their persuasive writing skills may not un- derstand this, and mistakenly support evidence with their own opinions.</p><p>Statistics of this corpus are shown in <ref type="table">Table 1</ref>. Its extensive use in argument mining research in re- cent years together with its reliably annotated ar- gument trees makes it an ideal corpus to use for our annotation task.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Annotation</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">Definition</head><p>Since persuasiveness is defined on an argument, in order to annotate persuasiveness we need to define precisely what an argument is. Following van <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Eemeren et al. (2014)</ref>, we define an argument as consisting of a conclusion that may or may not be supported/attacked by a set of evidences. Given an argument tree, a non-leaf node can be inter- preted as a "conclusion" that is supported or at- tacked by its children, which can therefore be in- terpreted as "evidences" for the conclusion. In contrast, a leaf node can be interpreted as an un- supported conclusion. Hence, for the purposes of our work, an argument is composed of a node in an argument tree and all of its children, if any.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">Annotation Scheme</head><p>Recall that the goal of our annotation is to score each argument w.r.t. its persuasiveness (see <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">Ta- ble 2</ref> for the rubric for scoring persuasiveness) and annotate each of its components with a set of pre- defined attributes that could impact the argument's persuasiveness. <ref type="table">Table 3</ref> presents a summary of the attributes we annotate. The rest of this subsection describes these attributes.</p><p>Each component type (MajorClaim, Claim, Premise) has a distinct set of attributes. All com- ponent types have three attributes in common: Eloquence, Specificity, and Evidence. Eloquence is how well the author uses language to convey ideas, similar to clarity and fluency. Specificity refers to the narrowness of a statement's scope. Statements that are specific are more believable because they indicate an author's confidence and depth of knowledge about a subject matter. Ar- gument assertions (major claims and claims) need not be believable on their own since that is the job of the supporting evidence. The Evidence score describes how well the supporting components support the parent component. The rubrics for scoring Eloquence, Evidence, Claim/MajorClaim Specificity, and Premise Specificity are shown in <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">Tables 4, 5</ref>, 6, and 7 respectively. MajorClaim Since the major claim represents the overall argument of the essay, it is in this com- ponent that we annotate the persuasive strategies employed (i.e., Ethos, Pathos and Logos). These Score Description 6 A very strong, clear argument. It would persuade most readers and is devoid of errors that might detract from its strength or make it difficult to understand. 5 A strong, pretty clear argument. It would persuade most readers, but may contain some minor errors that detract from its strength or understandability. 4</p><p>A decent, fairly clear argument. It could persuade some readers, but contains errors that detract from its strength or understandability. 3</p><p>A poor, understandable argument. It might persuade readers who are already inclined to agree with it, but contains severe errors that detract from its strength or understandability. 2</p><p>It is unclear what the author is trying to argue or the argument is poor and just so riddled with errors as to be completely unpersuasive. 1</p><p>The author does not appear to make any argument (e.g. he may just describe some incident without explaining why it is important). It could not persuade any readers because there is nothing to be persuaded of. It may or may not contain detectable errors, but errors are moot since there is not an argument for them to interfere with.  <ref type="table">Table 3</ref>: Summary of the attributes together with their possible values, the argument component type(s) each attribute is applicable to (MC: MajorClaim, C: Claim, P: Premise), and a brief description.</p><p>Score Description 5 Demonstrates mastery of English. There are no grammatical errors that distract from the meaning of the sentence. Exhibits a well thought out, flowing sentence structure that is easy to read and conveys the idea exceptionally well. 4</p><p>Demonstrates fluency in English. If there are any grammatical or syntactical errors, their affect on the meaning is negligible. Word choice suggests a broad vocabulary. 3</p><p>Demonstrates competence in English. There might be a few errors that are noticeable but forgivable, such as an incorrect verb tense or unnecessary pluralization. Demonstrates a typical vocabulary and a simple sentence structure. 2</p><p>Demonstrates poor understanding of sentence composition and/or poor vocabulary. The choice of words or gram- matical errors force the reader to reread the sentence before moving on. 1</p><p>Demonstrates minimal eloquence. The sentence contains errors so severe that the sentence must be carefully analyzed to deduce its meaning. There is no argument body for the given component. three attributes are not inherent to the text identi- fying the major claim but instead summarize the child components in the argument tree.</p><p>Claim The claim argument component pos- sesses all of the attributes of a major claim in ad- dition to a Relevance score and a ClaimType. In order for an argument to be persuasive, all sup- porting components must be relevant to the com- ponent that they support/attack. The scoring rubric for Relevance is shown in <ref type="table" target="#tab_7">Table 8</ref>. The ClaimType can be value (e.g., something is good or bad, im- portant or not important, etc.), fact (e.g. something Score Description 5</p><p>The claim summarizes the argument well and has a qualifier that indicates the extent to which the claim holds true. Claims that summarize the argument well must reference most or all of the supporting components. 4</p><p>The claim summarizes the argument very well by mentioning most or all of the supporting components, but does not have a qualifier indicating the conditions under which the claim holds true. Alternatively, the claim may moderately summarize the argument by referencing a minority of supporting components and contain qualifier. 3</p><p>The claim has a qualifier clause or references a minority of the supporting components, but not both. 2</p><p>The claim does not make an attempt to summarize the argument nor does it contain a qualifier clause. 1</p><p>Simply rephrases the major claim or is outside scope of the major claim (argument components were annotated incorrectly: major claim could be used to support claim). A broad statement. A statement with hedge words and without other redeeming factors such as explicit examples, or elaborate reasoning. Additionally, there are few adjectives or adverbs. 1</p><p>An extremely broad statement. There is no underlying explanation, qualifiers, or real-world examples. Anyone can see how the support relates to the parent claim. The relationship between the two components is either explicit or extremely easy to infer. The relationship is thoroughly explained in the text because the two components contain the same words or exhibit coreference. 5</p><p>There is an implied relationship that is obvious, but it could be improved upon to remove all doubt. If the relation- ship is obvious, both relating components must have high Eloquence and Specificity scores. 4</p><p>The relationship is fairly clear. The relationship can be inferred from the context of the two statements. One com- ponent must have a high Eloquence and Specificity scores and the other must have lower but sufficient Eloquence and Specificity scores for the relationship to be fairly clear. 3</p><p>Somewhat related. It takes some thinking to imagine how the components relate. The parent component or the child component have low clarity scores. The two statements are about the same topic but unrelated ideas within the domain of said topic. 2</p><p>Mostly unrelated. It takes some major assumptions to relate the two components. A component may also receive this score if both components have low clarity scores. 1</p><p>Totally unrelated. Very few people could see how the two components relate to each other. The statement was annotated to show that it relates to the claim, but this was clearly in error. is true or false), or policy (claiming that some ac- tion should or should not be taken).</p><p>Premise The attributes exclusive to premises are PremiseType and Strength. To understand Strength, recall that only premises can per- suade readers, but also that an argument can be composed of a premise and a set of sup- porting/attacking premises.</p><p>In an argument of this kind, Strength refers to how well the parent premise contributes to the persuasive- ness independently of the contributions from its children. The scoring rubric for Strength is shown in <ref type="table" target="#tab_8">Table 9</ref>. PremiseType takes on a discrete value from one of the following: real example, invented instance, analogy, testi- mony, statistics, definition, common knowledge, and warrant. Analogy, testimony, statistics, and definition are self-explanatory. A premise is la- beled invented instance when it describes a hypo- thetical situation, and definition when it provides a definition to be used elsewhere in the argument. A premise has type warrant when it does not fit any other type, but serves a functional purpose to ex- plain the relationship between two entities or clar- ify/quantify another statement. The real example premise type indicates that the statement is a his- torical event that actually occurred, or something that is verfiably true about the real world. A very strong premise. Not much can be improved in order to contribute better to the argument. 5</p><p>A strong premise. It contributes to the persuasiveness of the argument very well on its own. 4</p><p>A decent premise. It is a fairly strong point but lacking in one or more areas possibly affecting its perception by the audience. 3</p><p>A fairly weak premise. It is not a strong point and might only resonate with a minority of readers. <ref type="bibr">2</ref> A totally weak statement. May only help to persuade a small number of readers. 1</p><p>The statement does not contribute at all.  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3">Annotation Procedure</head><p>Our 102 essays were annotated by two native speakers of English. We first familiarized them with the rubrics and definitions and then trained  them on five essays (not included in our corpus). After that, they were both asked to annotate a randomly selected set of 30 essays and discuss the resulting annotations to resolve any discrep- ancies. Finally, the remaining essays were parti- tioned into two sets, and each annotator received one set to annotate. The resulting distributions of scores/classes for persuasiveness and the attributes are shown in <ref type="table" target="#tab_9">Table 10</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.4">Inter-Annotator Agreement</head><p>We use Krippendorff's α to measure inter- annotator agreement. Results are shown in Ta- ble 11. As we can see, all attributes exhibit an agreement above 0.5, showing a correlation much more significant than random chance. Persuasive- ness has an agreement of 0.688, which suggests that it can be agreed upon in a reasonably gen- eral sense. The MajorClaim components have the highest Persuasiveness agreement, and it declines as the type changes to Claim and then to Premise. This would indicate that persuasiveness is easier to articulate in a wholistic sense, but difficult to explain as the number of details involved in the explanation increases. The agreement scores that immediately stand out are the perfect 1.0's for Logos and Ethos. The perfect Logos score is explained by the fact that every major claim was marked to use logos. Al- though ethos is far less common, both annotators easily recognized it. This is largely due to the in- disputability of recognizing a reference to an ac- cepted authority on a given subject. Very few au- thors utilize this approach, so when they do it is extremely apparent. Contrary to Persuasiveness, Evidence agreement exhibits an upward trend as the component scope narrows. Even with this pat- tern, the Evidence agreement is always higher than Persuasiveness agreement, which suggests that it is not the only determiner of persuasiveness.</p><p>In spite of a rubric defining how to score Elo- quence, it remains one of the attributes with the lowest agreement. This indicates that it is diffi- cult to agree on exact eloquence levels beyond ba- sic English fluency. Additionally, Specificity pro- duced unexpectedly low agreement in claims and major claims. Precisely quantifying how well a claim summarizes its argument turned out to be a complicated and subjective task. Relevance agree- ment for premises is one of the lowest, partly be- cause there are multiple scores for high relevance, and no examples were given in the rubric.</p><p>All attributes but those with the highest agree- ment are plagued by inherent subjectivity, regard- less of how specific the rubric is written. There are often multiple interpretations of a given sen- tence, sometimes due to the complexity of natural language, and sometimes due to the poor writing of the author. Naturally, this makes it difficult to identify certain attributes such as Pathos, Claim- Type, and PremiseType.</p><p>Although great care was taken to make each at- tribute as independent of the others as possible, they are all related to each other to a minuscule degree (e.g., Eloquence and Specificity). While annotators generally agree on what makes a per- suasive argument, the act of assigning blame to the persuasiveness (or lack thereof) is tainted by this overlapping of attributes.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.5">Analysis of Annotations</head><p>To understand whether the attributes we annotated are indeed useful for predicting persuasiveness, we compute the Pearson's Correlation Coefficient (PC) between persuasiveness and each of the at- tributes along with the corresponding p-values. Results are shown in <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">Table 12</ref>. Among the cor- relations that are statistically significant at the p &lt; .05 level, we see, as expected, that Persuasive- ness is positively correlated with Specificity, Ev- idence, Eloquence, and Strength. Neither is it sur-  prising that support provided by a premise in the form of statistics and examples is positively cor- related with Persuasiveness. While Logos and in- vented instance also have significant correlations with Persuasiveness, the correlation is very weak. Next, we conduct an oracle experiment in an attempt to understand how well these attributes, when used together, can explain the persuasive- ness of an argument. Specifically, we train three linear SVM regressors (using the SVM light soft- ware (Joachims, 1999) with default learning pa- rameters except for C (the regularization param- eter), which is tuned on development data using grid search) to score an argument's persuasiveness using the gold attributes as features. The three regressors are trained on arguments having Ma- jorClaims, Claims, and Premises as parents. For instance, to train the regressor involving Major- Claims, each instance corresponds to an argument represented by all and only those attributes in- volved in the major claim and all of its children. <ref type="bibr">4</ref> Five-fold cross-validation results, which are Prompt: Government budget focus, young children or university? Education plays a significant role in a country's long-lasting prosperity. It is no wonder that governments throughout the world lay special emphasis on education development. As for the two integral components within the system, elementary and advanced education, there's no doubt that a government is supposed to offer sufficient financial support for both.</p><note type="other">Attribute P C p-value Specificity .5680 0 Relevance −.0435 .163 Eloquence .4723 0 Evidence .2658 0 Strength .9456 0 Logos −.1618 0 Ethos −.0616 .1666 Pathos −.0835 .0605 ClaimType:fact .0901 .1072 ClaimType:value −.0858 .1251 ClaimType:policy −.0212 .7046 PremiseType:real example .2414 0 PremiseType:invented instance .0829 .0276 PremiseType:analogy .0300 .4261 PremiseType:testimony .0269 .4746 PremiseType:statistics .1515 0 PremiseType:definition .0278 .4608 PremiseType:common knowledge −.2948 1.228 PremiseType:warrant .0198 .6009</note><p>Concerning that elementary education is the fundamental requirement to be a qualified citizen in today's society, gov- ernment should guarantee that all people have equal and convenient access to it. So a lack of well-established primary education goes hand in hand with a high rate of illiteracy, and this interplay compromises a country's future development. In other words, if countries, especially developing ones, are determined to take off, one of the key points governments should set on agenda is to educate more qualified future citizens through elementary education. . . .   <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">Table 14</ref> and the scores of their associated at- tributes: Persuasiveness, Eloquence, Specificity, Evidence, Relevance, Strength, Logos, Pathos, Ethos, claimType, and premiseType.</p><p>shown in <ref type="table" target="#tab_13">Table 13</ref>, are expressed in terms of two evaluation metrics, P C and M E (the mean ab- solute distance between a system's prediction and the gold score). Since P C is a correlation metric, higher correlation implies better performance. In contrast, M E is an error metric, so lower scores imply better performance. As we can see, the large P C values and the relatively low M E values provide suggestive evidence that these attributes, when used in combination, can largely explain the persuasiveness of an argument.</p><p>What these results imply in practice is that mod- els that are trained on these attributes for per- suasiveness scoring could provide useful feed- back to students on why their arguments are (un)persuasive. For instance, one can build a pipeline system for persuasiveness scoring as fol- lows. Given an argument, this system first pre- dicts its attributes and then scores its persuasive- ness using the predicted attribute values computed in the first step. Since the persuasiveness score of an argument is computed using its predicted at- tributes, these attributes can explain the persua- siveness score. Hence, a student can figure out which aspect of persuasiveness needs improve- ments by examining the values of the predicted at- tributes.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.6">Example</head><p>To better understand our annotation scheme, we use the essay in <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">Table 14</ref> to illustrate how we ob- tain the attribute values in <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">Table 15</ref>. In this es- say, Claim C1, which supports MajorClaim M1, is supported by three children, Premises P1 and P2 as well as Claim C2.</p><p>After reading the essay in its entirety and ac- quiring a holistic impression of the argument's strengths and weaknesses, we begin annotating the atomic argument components bottom up, starting with the leaf nodes of the argument tree. First, we consider P2. Its Evidence score is 1 because it is a leaf node with no supporting evidence. Its Elo- quence score is 5 because the sentence has no seri- ous grammatical or syntactic errors, has a flowing, well thought out sentence structure, and uses artic- ulate vocabulary. Its Specificity score is 3 because it is essentially saying that poor primary education causes illiteracy and consequently inhibits a coun- try's development. It does not state why or to what extent, so we cannot assign a score of 4. How- ever, it does explain a simple relationship with lit- tle ambiguity due to the lack of hedge words, so we can assign a score of 3. Its PremiseType is common knowledge because it is reasonable to as- sume most people would agree that poor primary education causes illiteracy, and also that illiter- acy inhibits a country's development. Its Rele- vance score is 6: its relationship with its parent is clear because the two components exhibit coref- erence. Specifically, P2 contains a reference to primary/elementary education and shows how this affects a country's inability to transition from de- veloping to developed. Its Strength is 4: though eloquent and relevant, P2 is lacking substance in order to be considered for a score of 5 or 6. The PremiseType is common knowledge, which is mediocre compared to statistics and real example. In order for a premise that is not grounded in the real world to be strong, it must be very specific. P2 only scored a 3 in Specificity, so we assign a Strength score of 4. Finally, the argument headed by P2, which does not have any children, has a Persuasiveness score of 4, which is obtained by summarizing the inherent strength of the premise and the supporting evidence. Although there is no supporting evidence for this premise, this does not adversely affect persuasiveness due to the stan- dalone nature of premises. In this case the persua- siveness is derived totally from the strength.</p><p>Next, the annotator would score C2 and P1, but for demonstration purposes we will examine the scoring of C1. C1's Eloquence score is 5 be- cause it shows fluency, broad vocabulary, and at- tention to how well the sentence structure reads. Its ClaimType is policy because it specifically says that the government should put something on their agenda. Its Specificity score is 4: while it contains information relevant to all the child premises (i.e., creating qualified citizens, whose role it is to pro- vide the education, and the effect of education on a country's development), it does not contain a qual- ifier stating the extent to which the assertion holds true. Its Evidence score is 4: C1 has two premises with decent persuasiveness scores and one claim with a poor persuasiveness score, and there are no attacking premises, so intuitively, we may say that this is a midpoint between many low qual- ity premises and few high quality premises. We mark Logos as true, Pathos as false, and Ethos as false: rather than use an emotional appeal or an ap- peal to authority of any sort, the author attempts to use logical reasoning in order to prove their point. Its Persuasiveness score is 4: this score is mainly determined by the strength of the supporting evi- dence, given that the assertion is precise and clear as determined by the specificity and eloquence. Its Relevance score is 6, as anyone can see how en- dorsement of elementary education in C1 relates to the endorsement of elementary and university education in its parent (i.e., M1).</p><p>After all of the claims have been annotated in the bottom-up method, the annotator moves on to the major claim, M1. M1's Eloquence score is 4: while it shows fluency and a large vocabulary, it is terse and does not convey the idea exceptionally well. Its persuasion strategies are obtained by sim- ply taking the logical disjunction of those used in its child claims. Since every claim in this essay re- lied on logos and did not employ pathos nor ethos, M1 is marked with Logos as true, Pathos as false, and Ethos as false. Its Evidence score is 3: in this essay there are two other supporting claims not in the excerpt, with persuasiveness scores of only 3 and 2, so M1's evidence has one decently persua- sive claim, one claim that is poor but understand- able, and one claim that is so poor as to be com- pletely unpersuasive (in this case it has no support- ing premises). Its Specificity score is 2 because it does not have a quantifier nor does it attempt to summarize the main points of the evidence. Fi- nally, its Persuasiveness score is 3: all supporting claims rely on logos, so there is no added persua- siveness from a variety of persuasion strategies, and since the eloquence and specificity are ade- quate, they do not detract from the Evidence score.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Conclusion</head><p>We presented the first corpus of 102 persuasive student essays that are simultaneously annotated with argument trees, persuasiveness scores, and at- tributes of argument components that impact these scores. We believe that this corpus will push the frontiers of research in content-based essay grad- ing by triggering the development of novel compu- tational models concerning argument persuasive- ness that could provide useful feedback to students on why their arguments are (un)persuasive in ad- dition to how persuasive they are.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" validated="true"><head>Table 2 : Description of the Persuasiveness scores.</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Attribute 
Possible Values 
Applicability Description 
Specificity 
1-5 
MC,C,P 
How detailed and specific the statement is 
Eloquence 
1-5 
MC,C,P 
How well the idea is presented 
Evidence 
1-6 
MC,C,P 
How well the supporting statements support their parent 
Logos/Pathos/Ethos yes,no 
MC,C 
Whether the argument uses the respective persuasive strategy 
Relevance 
1-6 
C,P 
The relevance of the statement to the parent statement 
ClaimType 
value,fact,policy C 
The category of what is being claimed 
PremiseType 
see Section 4.2 
P 
The type of Premise, e.g. statistics, definition, real example, 
etc. 
Strength 
1-6 
P 
How well a single statement contributes to persuasiveness 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3" validated="true"><head>Table 4 : Description of the Eloquence scores.</head><label>4</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Score Description 
6 
A very strong, very persuasive argument body. There are many supporting components that have high Relevance 
scores. There may be a few attacking child components, but these components must be used for either concession 
or refuting counterarguments as opposed to making the argument indecisive or contradictory. 
5 
A strong, persuasive argument body. There are sufficient supporting components with respectable scores. 
4 
A decent, fairly persuasive argument body. 
3 
A poor, possibly persuasive argument body. 
2 
A totally unpersuasive argument body. 
1 
</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4" validated="false"><head>Table 5 : Description of the Evidence scores.</head><label>5</label><figDesc></figDesc><table></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_5" validated="false"><head>Table 6 :</head><label>6</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Description of the Claim and MajorClaim Specificity scores. 

Score Description 
5 
An elaborate, very specific statement. The statement contains numerical data, or a historical example from the 
real world. There is (1) both a sufficient qualifier indicating the extent to which the statement holds true and an 
explanation of why the statement is true, or (2) at least one real world example, or (3) a sufficient description of a 
hypothetical situation that would evoke a mental image of the situation in the minds of most readers. 
4 
A more specific statement. It is characterized by either an explanation of why the statement is true, or a qualifier 
indicating when/to what extent the statement is true. Alternatively, it may list examples of items that do not qualify 
as historical events. 
3 
A sufficiently specific statement. It simply states a relationship or a fact with little ambiguity. 
2 
</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_6" validated="false"><head>Table 7 : Description of the Premise Specificity scores.</head><label>7</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Score Description 
6 
</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_7" validated="false"><head>Table 8 :</head><label>8</label><figDesc>Description of the Relevance scores.</figDesc><table></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_8" validated="true"><head>Table 9 : Description of the Strength scores.</head><label>9</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Attribute 
Value 
MC 
C 
P 
Specificity 
1 
0 
80 
64 
2 
73 
259 134 
3 
72 
155 238 
4 
32 
59 
173 
5 
8 
14 
98 
Logos 
Yes 
181 304 
No 
4 
263 
Pathos 
Yes 
67 
59 
No 
118 508 
Ethos 
Yes 
16 
9 
No 
169 558 
Relevance 
1 
1 
5 
2 
33 
45 
3 
58 
59 
4 
132 145 
5 
97 
147 
6 
246 306 
Evidence 
1 
3 
246 614 
2 
62 
115 
28 
3 
57 
85 
12 
4 
33 
80 
26 
5 
16 
35 
15 
6 
14 
6 
12 
Eloquence 
1 
3 
23 
24 
2 
19 
106 
97 
3 
116 320 383 
4 
42 
102 154 
5 
5 
16 
49 
ClaimType 
fact 
368 
value 
145 
policy 
54 
PremiseType 
real example 
93 
invented instance 
53 
analogy 
2 
testimony 
4 
statistics 
15 
definition 
3 
common know. 
493 
warrant 
44 
Persuasiveness 1 
3 
82 
8 
2 
62 
278 112 
3 
60 
84 
145 
4 
28 
74 
249 
5 
17 
39 
123 
6 
15 
10 
70 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_9" validated="false"><head>Table 10 :</head><label>10</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Class/Score distributions by component 
type. 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_11" validated="false"><head>Table 11 :</head><label>11</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Krippendorff's α agreement on each at-
tribute by component type. 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_12" validated="false"><head>Table 12 :</head><label>12</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Correlation of each attribute with Per-
suasiveness and the corresponding p-value. 

MC 
C 
P 
Avg 
P C 
.9688 .9400 .9494 .9495 
M E 
.0710 .1486 .0954 .1061 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_13" validated="false"><head>Table 13 :</head><label>13</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Persuasiveness scoring using gold at-
tributes. 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_14" validated="false"><head>Table 14 :</head><label>14</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>An example essay. Owing to space limitations, only its first two paragraphs are shown. 

P E S Ev R St Lo Pa Et cType pType 
M1 government is supposed to offer sufficient financial 
support for both 

3 
4 
2 
3 
T F F 

C1 
if countries, especially developing ones, are deter-
mined to take off, one of the key points governments 
should set on agenda is to educate more qualified fu-
ture citizens through elementary education 

4 
5 
4 
4 
6 
T F F policy 

P1 
elementary education is the fundamental require-
ment to be a qualified citizen in today's society 

4 
5 
3 
1 
6 
4 
A 

C2 
government should guarantee that all people have 
equal and convenient access to it 

2 
3 
1 
1 
6 
F F F policy 

P2 
a lack of well-established primary education goes 
hand in hand with a high rate of illiteracy, and this in-
terplay compromises a country's future development 

4 
5 
3 
1 
6 
4 
C 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_15" validated="false"><head>Table 15 :</head><label>15</label><figDesc>The argument components in the example in</figDesc><table></table></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="2"> https://competitions.codalab.org/competitions/17327 3 www.essayforum.com</note>

			<note place="foot" n="4"> There is a caveat. If we define features for each of the children, the number of features will be proportional to the number of children. However, SVMs cannot handle a variable number of features. Hence, all of the children will be represented by one set of features. For instance, the Specificity feature value of the children will be the Specificity values averaged over all of the children.</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>We thank the three anonymous reviewers for their detailed and insightful comments on an earlier draft of the paper. This work was supported in part by NSF <ref type="bibr">Grants IIS-1219142 and IIS-1528037.</ref> </p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A news editorial corpus for mining argumentation strategies</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Al</forename><surname>Khalid</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Henning</forename><surname>Khatib</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Johannes</forename><surname>Wachsmuth</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Matthias</forename><surname>Kiesel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Benno</forename><surname>Hagen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Stein</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of COLING 2016, the 26th International Conference on Computational Linguistics: Technical Papers</title>
		<meeting>COLING 2016, the 26th International Conference on Computational Linguistics: Technical Papers</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3433" to="3443" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
				<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Frans</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bart</forename><surname>Van Eemeren</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Garssen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Erik</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Francisca</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Krabbe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bart</forename><surname>Snoeck Henkemans</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jean</forename><forename type="middle">H M</forename><surname>Verheij</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Wagemans</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Handbook of Argumentation Theory</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Dordrecht</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Neural end-to-end learning for computational argumentation mining</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Steffen</forename><surname>Eger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Johannes</forename><surname>Daxenberger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Iryna</forename><surname>Gurevych</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 55th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the 55th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="11" to="22" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Long Papers)</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">What makes a convincing argument? Empirical analysis and detecting attributes of convincingness in Web argumentation</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ivan</forename><surname>Habernal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Iryna</forename><surname>Gurevych</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2016 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</title>
		<meeting>the 2016 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1214" to="1223" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Which argument is more convincing? Analyzing and predicting convincingness of Web arguments using bidirectional LSTM</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ivan</forename><surname>Habernal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Iryna</forename><surname>Gurevych</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 54th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the 54th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Long Papers</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1589" to="1599" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Analyzing the semantic types of claims and premises in an online persuasive forum</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christopher</forename><surname>Hidey</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Elena</forename><surname>Musi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alyssa</forename><surname>Hwang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Smaranda</forename><surname>Muresan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kathy</forename><surname>Mckeown</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 4th Workshop on Argument Mining</title>
		<meeting>the 4th Workshop on Argument Mining</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="11" to="21" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Ethos, logos, pathos: Strategies of persuasion in social</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Colin</forename><surname>Higgins</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Robyn</forename><surname>Walker</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">/environmental reports. Accounting Forum</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">36</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="194" to="208" />
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Evaluating multiple aspects of coherence in student essays</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Derrick</forename><surname>Higgins</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jill</forename><surname>Burstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Daniel</forename><surname>Marcu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Claudia</forename><surname>Gentile</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Human Language Technologies: The 2004 Annual Conference of the North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="185" to="192" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Making large-scale SVM learning practical</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Joachims</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Advances in Kernel MethodsSupport Vector Learning</title>
		<editor>B. Schölkopf, C. Burges, and A. Smola</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Cambridge, MA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>MIT Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="169" to="184" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Content Analysis: An Introduction to Its Methodology. Sage commtext series</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Klaus</forename><surname>Krippendorff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1980" />
			<pubPlace>Sage, Thousand Oaks, CA</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Argument strength is in the eye of the beholder: Audience effects in persuasion</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Stephanie</forename><surname>Lukin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Pranav</forename><surname>Anand</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marilyn</forename><surname>Walker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Steve</forename><surname>Whittaker</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 15th Conference of the European Chapter</title>
		<meeting>the 15th Conference of the European Chapter</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Long Papers</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="742" to="753" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Evaluation of text coherence for electronic essay scoring systems</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Eleni</forename><surname>Miltsakaki</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Karen</forename><surname>Kukich</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Natural Language Engineering</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="25" to="55" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Modeling organization in student essays</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Isaac</forename><surname>Persing</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alan</forename><surname>Davis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Vincent</forename><surname>Ng</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2010 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</title>
		<meeting>the 2010 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="229" to="239" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Modeling thesis clarity in student essays</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Isaac</forename><surname>Persing</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Vincent</forename><surname>Ng</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 51st Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the 51st Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Long Papers</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="260" to="269" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Modeling prompt adherence in student essays</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Isaac</forename><surname>Persing</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Vincent</forename><surname>Ng</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 52nd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the 52nd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Long Papers</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1534" to="1543" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Modeling argument strength in student essays</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Isaac</forename><surname>Persing</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Vincent</forename><surname>Ng</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 53rd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics and the 7th International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing</title>
		<meeting>the 53rd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics and the 7th International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Long Papers</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="543" to="552" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Why can&apos;t you convince me? Modeling weaknesses in unpersuasive arguments</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Isaac</forename><surname>Persing</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Vincent</forename><surname>Ng</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 26th International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence</title>
		<meeting>the 26th International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="4082" to="4088" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Handbook of Automated Essay Evaluation: Current Applications and New Directions</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Mark</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jill</forename><surname>Shermis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Burstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
			<publisher>Routledge Chapman &amp; Hall</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Annotating argument components and relations in persuasive essays</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christian</forename><surname>Stab</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Iryna</forename><surname>Gurevych</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 25th International Conference on Computational Linguistics: Technical Papers</title>
		<meeting>the 25th International Conference on Computational Linguistics: Technical Papers</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1501" to="1510" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Identifying argumentative discourse structures in persuasive essays</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christian</forename><surname>Stab</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Iryna</forename><surname>Gurevych</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2014 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</title>
		<meeting>the 2014 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="46" to="56" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Parsing argumentation structures in persuasive essays</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christian</forename><surname>Stab</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Iryna</forename><surname>Gurevych</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Computational Linguistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">43</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="619" to="659" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Recognizing insufficiently supported arguments in argumentative essays</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christian</forename><surname>Stab</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Iryna</forename><surname>Gurevych</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 15th Conference of the European Chapter</title>
		<meeting>the 15th Conference of the European Chapter</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="980" to="990" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Long Papers</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Computational argumentation quality assessment in natural language</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Henning</forename><surname>Wachsmuth</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nona</forename><surname>Naderi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yufang</forename><surname>Hou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yonatan</forename><surname>Bilu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Vinodkumar</forename><surname>Prabhakaran</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tim</forename><forename type="middle">Alberdingk</forename><surname>Thijm</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Graeme</forename><surname>Hirst</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Benno</forename><surname>Stein</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 15th Conference of the European Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the 15th Conference of the European Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Long Papers</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="176" to="187" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Is this post persuasive? Ranking argumentative comments in online forum</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Zhongyu</forename><surname>Wei</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yang</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yi</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 54th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the 54th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Short Papers</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="195" to="200" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
