<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T12:55+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Biomedical Document Retrieval for Clinical Decision Support System</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date>July 15-20, 2018</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jainisha</forename><surname>Sankhavara</surname></persName>
							<email>jainishasankhavara@gmail.com</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Dhirubhai Ambani Institute of Information and Communication Technology Gandhinagar</orgName>
								<address>
									<region>Gujarat</region>
									<country key="IN">India</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Irlp</forename><surname>Lab</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Dhirubhai Ambani Institute of Information and Communication Technology Gandhinagar</orgName>
								<address>
									<region>Gujarat</region>
									<country key="IN">India</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Biomedical Document Retrieval for Clinical Decision Support System</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of ACL 2018, Student Research Workshop</title>
						<meeting>ACL 2018, Student Research Workshop <address><addrLine>Melbourne, Australia</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="84" to="90"/>
							<date type="published">July 15-20, 2018</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<note>84</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>The availability of huge amount of biomedical literature have opened up new possibilities to apply Information Retrieval and NLP for mining documents from them. In this work, we are focus-ing on biomedical document retrieval from literature for clinical decision support systems. We compare statistical and NLP based approaches of query reformulation for biomedical document retrieval. Also, we have modeled the biomedical document retrieval as a learning to rank problem. We report initial results for statistical and NLP based query reformulation approaches and learning to rank approach with future direction of research.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction and Motivation</head><p>Medical and Healthcare related searches are hav- ing major focus of internet search now a days. The recent statistics shows that 61% of adults look online for health information <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Jones, 2009)</ref>. This demands proper search and retrieval systems for health related biomedical queries. Biomedical Information Retrieval (BIR) seeks special atten- tion due to the characteristics of biomedical termi- nologies. Major challenges in biomedical domain are in handling complex, ambiguous, inconsis- tent medical terms and their ad-hoc abbreviations. Many medical terms are very complex. The aver- age length of biomedical entities is much higher than general entities which makes entity identifi- cation task difficult for biomedical domain. En- tity identification and normalization helps to bet- ter solve the problems of retrieval and ranking of documents for medical search systems, biomedi- cal text summarization, biomedical text data visu- alization, etc.</p><p>As we are focusing here on biomedical docu- ment retrieval and ranking system, biomedical lit- erature should be in consideration. Biomedical lit- erature is an important source of study in medi- cal science. Thousands of articles are being added into biomedical literature each year. This large set of biomedical text articles can be used as a collection for Clinical Decision Support System where the related biomedical articles are extracted and suggested to medical practitioners to best care their patients. For this purpose, dataset from Clin- ical Decision Support (CDS) track is used which contains millions of full text biomedical articles from PMC (PubMed Central) <ref type="bibr">1</ref> . The statistics of CDS 2014, 2015 and 2016 datasets are given in the table 1. CDS 2 track focuses on retrieval of biomedical articles which are related to patient's medical case reports. These medical case reports which are being used as queries are case narra- tives of patients medical condition. They describes patients' medical condition i.e. medical history, symptoms, tests performed, treatments etc. For a given query/case report, the main problem is to find relevant documents from the available collec- tion and rank them.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Background</head><p>'Information Retrieval: A Health and Biomedical Perspective' <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Hersh, 2008)</ref> provides basic theory, implementation and evaluation of IR systems in health and biomedicine. The tasks of named en- tity recognition and relation and event extraction, summarization, question answering, and literature based discovery are outlined in Biomedical text mining: a survey of recent progress <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(Simpson and Demner-Fushman, 2012)</ref>.</p><p>Automatic processing of biomedical text also <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Dataset  CDS 2014  CDS 2015  CDS 2016  #Documents  733,138  733,138  1,255,259  Collection size  47.2 GB  47.2 GB  87.8 GB  #Total terms  1,600,536,286  1,600,536,286  2,954,366,841  #Uniq. terms  3,689,317  3,689,317  4,564,612  #Topics  30  30  30</ref>   <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(Maron and Kuhns, 1960;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Carpineto and Romano, 2012</ref>) which has a long history in information retrieval can be useful to deal with such problems. For instance, medical queries were expanded with other related terms from RxNorm, a drug dictionary, to improve the representation of a query for relevance estimation ). The emergence of medical domain specific knowledge like UMLS can contribute to the retrieval system to gain more understanding of the biomedical documents and queries. The Unified Medical Language System (UMLS) <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Bodenreider, 2004</ref>) is a metathesaurus for medical domain. It is maintained by National Library of Medicine (NLM) and it is the most comprehensive resource, unifying over 100 dictio- naries, terminologies, and ontologies. Various ap- proaches of information retrieval with the UMLS Metathesaurus have been reported: some with de- cline in results ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">Hersh et al., 2000</ref>) and some with gain in results <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Aronson and Rindflesch, 1997</ref>). The next section of this paper includes statistical approaches as well as NLP based approaches.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Query Reformulation for Biomedical Document Retrieval</head><p>Here, we present statistical and NLP based query reformulation approaches for biomedical docu- ment retrieval. Statistical approaches include feedback based query expansion and feedback document discovery based query expansion. An NLP based approach that is UMLS concept based query reformulation is also discussed here.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Automatic Query Expansion With Pseudo Relevance Feedback &amp; Relevance Feedback</head><p>Query Expansion (QE) is the process of reformu- lating a query to improve retrieval performance and efficiency of IR systems. QE is proved to be efficient in case of document retrieval <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Carpineto and Romano, 2012)</ref>. It helps to overcome vocabu- lary mismatch issues by expanding the user query with additional relevant terms and by re-weighting all terms. Query Expansion which uses the top re- trieved relevant documents is known as Relevance Feedback. It requires human judgment to iden- tify relevant documents from top retrieved docu- ments. While pseudo Relevance Feedback tech- nique assumes the top retrieved documents to be relevant and uses as feedback documents. It does not require human input at all. The Query ex- pansion based approaches for biomedical domain gives better results as compared to retrieval with- out query expansion ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Sankhavara et al., 2014)</ref>. <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">Table 2 and table 3</ref> shows the results of standard retrieval (without expansion), Pseudo-Relevance Feedback (PRF) based Query Expansion and Rel- evance Feedback (RF) based Query Expansion with BM25 and In expC2 retrieval models <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Amati et al., 2003)</ref> on <ref type="bibr">CDS 2014</ref><ref type="bibr">CDS , 2015</ref><ref type="bibr">CDS and 2016</ref> datasets. The retrieval model BM25 is a rank- ing function based on probabilistic retrieval frame- work while In expC2 is also a probabilistic but based on Divergence From Randomness (DFR). These models are available in Terrier IR Plate- form <ref type="bibr">3 (Ounis et al., 2005</ref>) which is developed at School of Computing Science, University of Glas- <ref type="bibr">CDS 2014</ref><ref type="bibr">CDS 2015</ref><ref type="bibr">CDS 2016</ref> 0.1071 0.1147 0.062 BM25+PRF <ref type="bibr">10</ref> 0.1542 (+44%) 0.1805 (+57.4%) 0.0769 (+24%) BM25+RF <ref type="bibr">10</ref> 0.205 (+91.4%) 0.1941 (+69.2%) 0.0984 (+58.7%) BM25+RF <ref type="bibr">50</ref> 0.2768 (+158.5%) 0.2283 (+99%) 0.1456 (+134.8%) In expC2 0.1096 0.1201 0.0632 In expC2+PRF <ref type="bibr">10</ref> 0.1623 (+48.1%) 0.1725 (+43.6%) 0.0754 (+19.3%) In expC2+RF <ref type="bibr">10</ref> 0.2117 (+93.2%) 0.1895 (+57.8%) 0.0992 (+57%) In expC2+RF <ref type="bibr">50</ref> 0.2587 (+136%) 0.2191 (+82.4%) 0.1275 (+101.7%)  Higher the value of evaluation measure, better the retrieval result of system. The result improves with PRF and RF based query expansion giving statistically significant results (p &lt; 0.05) as com- pared to no expansion. Here RF is giving 50-60% more improvement than PRF over no expansion. We argue that biomedical retrieval should be done keeping human in the loop. A small human inter- vention can increase the retrieval accuracy to 60% more.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>MAP</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Feedback Document Discovery for Query Reformulation</head><p>Feedback Document Discovery based query ex- pansion as described in (Sankhavara and Ma- jumder, 2017) learns to identify relevant docu- ments for query expansion from top retrieved doc- uments. The main aim is to use small amount of human judgement and learn pseudo judgement for other documents to reformulate the queries. One approach is based on classification. If we have hu- man judgements available for some of the feed- back documents, then it will serve as a training data for classification. The documents were repre- sented as a collection of bag-of-words, the TF-IDF scores of the words represent features and human relevance scores provides the classes. Then the relevance is predicted for other top retrieved feed- back documents. The second approach is based on and classification+clustering. It first applies classification in similar way as in first approach and then applies clustering on relevance predicted class by the classification method, thus filtering out more non-relevant documents from relevant ones. Since, the convergence of K-means cluster- ing depends on the initial choice of cluster cen- troids, the initial cluster centroids are chosen as the average of relevant documents vectors and the average of non-relevant documents vectors from training data.</p><p>Here we have used that approach with differ- ent features. The TF-IDF features are weighted based on type of words. CliNER tool ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Boag et al., 2015)</ref> has been used to identify medical entities of type 'problem', 'test' and 'treatment' from doc- uments, which was trained on i2b2 2010 dataset <ref type="bibr">(Uzuner et al., 2011</ref>   The features related to these entities in CDS docu- ments are weighted thrice, thus giving importance to these entities while learning to identify feed- back document. For feedback document discovery with weighted entities, we have used top 50 docu- ments and their corresponding relevance for train- ing, then the relevance was predicted for next top 200 documents and used for expansion of queries. For classification two methods, nearest neighbour classifier and neural net classifier, have been used and k-means is used for clustering with k=2 for relevant and non-relevant documents. In all cases, only relevant identified documents are used for expanding queries. The comparison of results of original queries without expansion, expansion with relevance feedback and expansion with two approaches of feedback document discovery (clas- sification and classification+clustering) for CDS 2014 dataset is given in table 4.</p><p>The results clearly indicates improvement over original queries and relevance feedback. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">Fig 1  shows</ref> query wise difference in infNDCG between {Neural net + k-means} 50 200 and Queries+RF 50 . Out of 30 queries of CDS 2014, 2 queries degrade performance but 7 queries improve.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3">UMLS Concepts Based Query Reformulation</head><p>Medical domain-specific knowledge can be in- corporated to the process of query reformulation in Biomedical IR system. There are knowledge based approaches proposed in the literature (Aron- son and <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Rindflesch, 1997;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b6">Hersh, 2008)</ref>. In the biomedical text re- trieval, medical concepts and entities are more in- formative than other common terms. Moreover, medical ontologies, thesaurus and biomedical en- tity identifiers are available to identify medical re- lated concepts.</p><p>Here we have used the resource UMLS. The following three query reformulation experiments are done using it. First: The UMLS concepts are identified from the query text and used with queries. Second: Along with the UMLS concepts, MeSH (Medical Subject Heading) terms are also identified and used in queries. MeSH is a hier- archically organized vocabulary of UMLS. Third: Medical entities are identified manually and used with queries. One example query with all these reformulations is presented in Appendix A. <ref type="table" target="#tab_6">Table 5</ref> shows the results of these reformulated queries of CDS 2014. PRF and RF based query expansion is also carried out on each form of the queries. The results shows clear improvement when using UMLS concepts in queries as com- pared to original queries. One more important ob- servation here to make is that, for no-expansion  and PRF, the manual entities fail to improve MAP when compared to UMLS entities but certainly give better results in terms of infNDCG.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Learning To Rank</head><p>Learning to rank (LTR) ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Liu et al., 2009</ref>) is an ap- plication of machine learning in the construction of ranking models for information retrieval sys- tems where retrieval problem is modeled as a rank- ing problem. LTR framework requires training data of queries and documents matching them to- gether with relevance degree of each match. Train- ing data is used by a learning algorithm to produce a ranking model which computes relevance of doc- uments for actual queries. The LTR framework is applied on CDS 2014 dataset where the features for query document pairs are computed similarly as the features used for OHSUMED LETOR dataset ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">Qin et al., 2010</ref>). These features are mainly based on TF, IDF and their normalized versions. Since the whole docu- ment pool is too large, document pooling has been done and top K documents (by BM25) for each query are used for feature extraction. SVMRank has been used as a machine learning framework. <ref type="table" target="#tab_8">Table 6</ref> shows the results of LTR when the fea- tures are computed on Title+Abstract part of the documents, on Title+Abstract+Content of the doc- uments (i.e. full documents). With these varia- tions of features, the experiments are carried out on original queries, queries with UMLS concepts and queries with manually identified medical con-   All these LTR experiments require human judgement for training. To overcome the need of manual judgement, pseudo judgements were con- sidered where out of k training documents, Top k/2 documents are considered to be relevant and other k/2 documents to be non-relevant.</p><p>As shown in table 7, the results of LTR trained using pseudo qrels are better than one with actual human judged qrels but the difference is not statis- tically significant. The results of LTR are compa- rable to retrieval using BM25.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Future Research Directions</head><p>Biomedical text processing and information re- trieval being a new field of research opens up many research directions. In this article, we have presented a preliminary study of statistical and NLP based biomedical document retrieval tech- niques for clinical decision support systems. It included query reformulation based information retrieval framework with pseudo relevance feed- back, relevance feedback, feedback document dis- covery and UMLS concept based reformulation for Biomedical domain. Standard IR frameworks PRF and RF works good enough for Clinical De- cision Support System. Feedback document dis- covery based query reformulation which is a sta- tistical approaches can be improvised in future for significant improvement. Another statistical model Learning to Rank is also having future scope for more improvement. The initial frame- work for NLP based approach UMLS concept based retrieval also shows improvement in the re- sults. Therefore, we plan to combine statistical and NLP based approaches and come up with new better model for biomedical document retrieval for Decision Support Systems. Also, we are planning to do feature weighting using NLP at entity level in feedback document discovery approach.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: Query wise difference graph of infNDCG for feedback document discovery and relevance feedback</figDesc><graphic url="image-1.png" coords="4,72.00,245.27,218.46,136.95" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" validated="false"><head>Table 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Results (MAP) of Query Expansion with PRF and RF 

infNDCG 
CDS 2014 
CDS 2015 
CDS 2016 
BM25 
0.1836 
0.2115 
0.171 
BM25+PRF 10 
0.2522 (+37.4%) 
0.283 (+33.8%) 
0.2047 (+19.7%) 
BM25+RF 10 
0.3355 (+82.7%) 
0.3028 (+43.2%) 
0.2428 (+42%) 
BM25+RF 50 
0.4186 (+128%) 
0.3478 (+64.4%) 
0.3094 (+80.9%) 
In expC2 
0.2002 
0.2132 
0.1785 
In expC2+PRF 10 
0.2724 (+36.1%) 
0.2734 (+28.2%) 
0.2018 (+13.1%) 
In expC2+RF 10 
0.3426 (+71.1%) 
0.3015 (+41.4%) 
0.245 (+37.3%) 
In expC2+RF 50 
0.4019 (+100.7%) 
0.339 (+59%) 
0.3219 (+80.3%) 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" validated="false"><head>Table 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Results (infNDCG) of Query Expansion with PRF and RF 

gow. Here, we have used terrier plateform for the 
experiments. Summary part of the query is used 
for retrieval with top 10 and 50 top documents for 
feedback in expansion. MAP and infNDCG are 
used as evaluation metrics (Manning et al., 2008). 
</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3" validated="false"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>). The i2b2 2010 dataset in- cludes discharge summaries from Partners Health- Care, from Beth Israel Deaconess Medical Cen- ter and from University of Pittsburgh Medical Center. These discharge summaries are fully de- identified and manually annotated for concept, as- sertion, and relation information. Here, we have CDS 2014 MAP infNDCG</figDesc><table>No feature 
weighting 

Feature 
weighting 
using CliNER 

No feature 
weighting 

Feature 
weighting 
using CliNER 
Original Queries 
0.1071 
0.1836 
Queries+RF 50 
0.2768 
0.4186 
{Nearest neighbors} 50 200 
0.2761 
0.2747 
0.4177 
0.4140 
{Nearest neighbors + k-means} 50 200 
0.2794 
0.2777 
0.4220 
0.4195 
{Neural net} 50 200 
0.2790 
0.2787 
0.4235 
0.4240 
{Neural net + k-means} 50 200 
0.2790 
0.2807 
0.4218 
0.4269 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4" validated="false"><head>Table 4 : Results of Feedback Document Discovery</head><label>4</label><figDesc></figDesc><table></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_6" validated="false"><head>Table 5 : Results of UMLS based query processing</head><label>5</label><figDesc></figDesc><table></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_8" validated="false"><head>Table 6 :</head><label>6</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Results of Learning to Rank with differ-
ent features 

infNDCG 
Retrieval (BM25) 
0.1836 
LTR using human judgements 
0.1769 
Pseudo LTR K=1000 
0.1849 
Pseudo LTR K=1500 
0.1872 
Pseudo LTR K=2000 
0.1859 
Pseudo LTR K=2500 
0.1865 
Pseudo LTR K=3000 
0.1865 

</table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_9" validated="false"><head>Table 7 :</head><label>7</label><figDesc></figDesc><table>Results Learning To Rank with pseudo 
judgements 

cepts. 

</table></figure>

			<note place="foot" n="1"> http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/ 2 http://www.trec-cds.org/</note>

			<note place="foot" n="3"> http://terrier.org</note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>A Example Query</head><p>&lt;topic number="1" type="diagnosis"&gt; &lt;summary&gt; 58-year-old woman with hypertension and obesity presents with exercise-related episodic chest pain radiating to the back. &lt;/summary&gt; &lt;UMLS entities&gt; hypertension obesity exercise related chest pain radiating back nos &lt;/UMLS entities&gt; &lt;MeSH entities&gt; Vascular Diseases Overnutrition Overweight Motor Activity Human Activities Torso Bone and Bones Neurologic Manifestations Sensation &lt;/MeSH entities&gt; &lt;manual entities&gt; woman hypertension obesity exercise-related episodic chest pain radiating back &lt;/manual entities&gt; &lt;/topic&gt; </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>B Example Document</head></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Probabilistic models for information retrieval based on divergence from randomness</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gianni</forename><surname>Amati</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Cornelis</forename><surname>Joost</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Van Rijsbergen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Query expansion using the umls metathesaurus</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Alan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Aronson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Thomas C Rindflesch</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the AMIA Annual Fall Symposium</title>
		<meeting>the AMIA Annual Fall Symposium</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1997" />
			<biblScope unit="page">485</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Cliner: A lightweight tool for clinical named entity recognition</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">William</forename><surname>Boag</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kevin</forename><surname>Wacome</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tristan</forename><surname>Naumann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Anna</forename><surname>Rumshisky</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">AMIA Joint Summits on Clinical Research Informatics</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>poster</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The unified medical language system (umls): integrating biomedical terminology</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Olivier</forename><surname>Bodenreider</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nucleic acids research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">32</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="267" to="270" />
			<date type="published" when="2004" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>suppl</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A survey of automatic query expansion in information retrieval</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Claudio</forename><surname>Carpineto</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Giovanni</forename><surname>Romano</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">ACM Computing Surveys (CSUR)</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">44</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A knowledge-based approach to medical records retrieval</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dina</forename><surname>Demner-Fushman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Swapna</forename><surname>Abhyankar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Antonio</forename><surname>Jimeno-Yepes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bastien</forename><surname>Russell F Loane</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">François-Michel</forename><surname>Rance</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Lang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Nicholas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Emilia</forename><surname>Ide</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alan</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Apostolova</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Aronson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">TREC</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Information retrieval: a health and biomedical perspective</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">William</forename><surname>Hersh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
			<publisher>Springer Science &amp; Business Media</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Assessing thesaurus-based query expansion using the umls metathesaurus</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">William</forename><surname>Hersh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Susan</forename><surname>Price</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Larry</forename><surname>Donohoe</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the AMIA Symposium</title>
		<meeting>the AMIA Symposium</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
			<biblScope unit="page">344</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The social life of health information</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Jones</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Pew research center</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<publisher>Pew Internet &amp; American Life Project</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Learning to rank for information retrieval</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tie-Yan</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Foundations and Trends R in Information Retrieval</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="225" to="331" />
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Introduction to information retrieval</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Prabhakar</forename><surname>Christopher D Manning</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hinrich</forename><surname>Raghavan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Schütze</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008" />
			<publisher>Cambridge university press</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">On relevance, probabilistic indexing and information retrieval</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Melvin</forename><surname>Earl Maron</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">John L</forename><surname>Kuhns</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of the ACM (JACM)</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="216" to="244" />
			<date type="published" when="1960" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Terrier information retrieval platform</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Iadh</forename><surname>Ounis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gianni</forename><surname>Amati</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Vassilis</forename><surname>Plachouras</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ben</forename><surname>He</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Craig</forename><surname>Macdonald</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Douglas</forename><surname>Johnson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">European Conference on Information Retrieval</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="517" to="519" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Letor: A benchmark collection for research on learning to rank for information retrieval</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tao</forename><surname>Qin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tie-Yan</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jun</forename><surname>Xu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hang</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Information Retrieval</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="346" to="374" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Biomedical information retrieval</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jainisha</forename><surname>Sankhavara</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Prasenjit</forename><surname>Majumder</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Working notes of FIRE 2017-Forum for Information Retrieval Evaluation</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="154" to="157" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Fusing manual and machine feedback in biomedical domain</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jainisha</forename><surname>Sankhavara</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Fenny</forename><surname>Thakrar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Prasenjit</forename><surname>Majumder</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Shamayeeta</forename><surname>Sarkar</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of The Twenty-Third Text REtrieval Conference</title>
		<meeting>The Twenty-Third Text REtrieval Conference<address><addrLine>Gaithersburg, Maryland, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014-11-19" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">2010 i2b2/va challenge on concepts, assertions, and relations in clinical text</title>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Matthew</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dina</forename><surname>Simpson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">;</forename><surname>Demner-Fushman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Brett</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Shuying</forename><surname>South</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Scott L</forename><surname>Shen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Duvall</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Mining text data</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer. ¨ Ozlem Uzuner</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">18</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="552" to="556" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Biomedical text mining: a survey of recent progress</note>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
