<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /home/ana/installs/grobid/grobid-0.5.1/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2019-04-18T10:59+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Beyond Multiword Expressions: Processing Idioms and Metaphors</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date>July 15-20, 2018</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Valia</forename><surname>Kordoni</surname></persName>
							<email>kordonie@anglistik.hu-berlin.de</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Humboldt-Universität zu Berlin</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Introduction</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Beyond Multiword Expressions: Processing Idioms and Metaphors</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Proceedings of the 56th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics-Tutorial Abstracts</title>
						<meeting>the 56th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics-Tutorial Abstracts <address><addrLine>Melbourne, Australia</addrLine></address>
						</meeting>
						<imprint>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="15" to="16"/>
							<date type="published">July 15-20, 2018</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<note>15</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract/>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Idioms and metaphors are characteristic to all ar- eas of human activity and to all types of dis- course. Their processing is a rapidly growing area in NLP, since they have become a big chal- lenge for NLP systems. Their omnipresence in language has been established in a number of cor- pus studies and the role they play in human rea- soning has also been confirmed in psychological experiments. This makes idioms and metaphors an important research area for computational and cognitive linguistics, and their automatic identi- fication and interpretation indispensable for any semantics-oriented NLP application.</p><p>This tutorial aims to provide attendees with a clear notion of the linguistic characteristics of id- ioms and metaphors, computational models of id- ioms and metaphors using state-of-the-art NLP techniques, their relevance for the intersection of deep learning and natural language processing, what methods and resources are available to sup- port their use, and what more could be done in the future. Our target audience are researchers and practitioners in machine learning, parsing (syn- tactic and semantic) and language technology, not necessarily experts in idioms and metaphors, who are interested in tasks that involve or could benefit from considering idioms and metaphors as a per- vasive phenomenon in human language and com- munication.</p><p>This tutorial consists of four parts. Part I starts with an introduction to MWEs and their linguis- tic dimensions, that is, idiomaticity, syntactic and semantic fixedness, specificity, etc., as well as their statistical characteristics (variability, recur- rence, association, etc.). The second half of this part focuses on the specific characteristics of id- ioms and metaphors (linguistic, conceptual and extended metaphor).</p><p>Part II surveys systems for processing idioms and metaphors which incorporate state-of-the-art NLP methods. The second half of this part is ded- icated to resources for idioms and metaphors, as well as evaluation.</p><p>Part III offers a thorough overview of how and where research on idioms and metaphors can con- tribute to the intersection of NLP and Deep Learn- ing, particularly focusing on recent advances in the computational treatment of MWEs in the frame- work of Deep Learning.</p><p>Part IV of the tutorial concludes with concrete examples of where idioms and metaphors treat- ment can contribute to language technology appli- cations such as sentiment analysis, educational ap- plications, dialog systems and digital humanities.   </p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>2</head><label></label><figDesc>Tutorial Outline 1. PART I -General overview: (a) Introduction to MWEs: linguistic di- mensions (idiomaticity, syntactic and semantic fixedness, specificity, etc.) and statistical dimensions (variability, recur- rence, association, etc.) (b) Linguistic characteristics of idioms (c) Linguistic characteristics of metaphors (linguistic, conceptual and extended metaphor) 2. PART II -Systems for processing idioms and metaphors, resources and evaluation (a) Machine learning for idioms and metaphors (b) Generation of idioms and metaphors (c) Multilingual processing and translation of idioms and metaphors (d) Annotation of idioms and metaphors in corpora (e) Idioms and metaphors in lexical re- sources</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>(</head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc></figure>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl/>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
